<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<Topic id="D0904A">
	<Sentences>
		<sentence DocIndex="4" Score="109.6169835642926">A city council candidate dropped out of the race Friday after it was disclosed that he posted comments to a white supremacist Internet bulletin board more than 4,000 times.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="9" Score="107.84034267912773">A crowd protesting a white supremacists' march turned violent, throwing baseball-sized rocks at police, vandalizing vehicles and stores, and setting fire to a neighborhood bar, authorities said.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="2" Score="105.00087616822432">White supremacists clashed with an angry crowd outside Faneuil Hall, where Holocaust survivors and their families were commemorating the liberation of Nazi concentration camps.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="7" Score="105.0">''</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="2" Score="101.36620757501231">&quot;Today of all days, to have white supremacists come here from Arkansas, is most disappointing,&quot; he said.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="1" Score="99.58928571428571">For Joan Humphrey Lefkow, the nightmare began shortly after her 2000 appointment as a federal judge, when an Oregon group's lawsuit to block white supremacists from using a name it had trademarked, World Church of the Creator, landed in her lap.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="3" Score="97.28188565145686">Joe Roy, chief researcher for the law center's magazine, the Intelligence Report, called Aryan Wear a &quot;hate-for-profit&quot; business, a kind of one-stop shopping for the fashion needs of white supremacists.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="10" Score="96.18449599465954">In the days leading up to a white supremacist march, ministers pleaded with residents in the predominantly black neighborhood to stay calm and community leaders organized peace rallies.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="6" Score="91.22344944774851">A white Republican lawmaker who contends he was excluded from a Black legislative group solely because of his race said Tuesday that the group is even more racist than the Ku Klux Klan.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="3" Score="89.84515717926935">In a small industrial park west of Keller, Texas, near sprawling neighborhoods and new schools, a storage facility routinely receives shipments of merchandise geared toward a certain clientele -- white supremacists and anti-Semites.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="8" Score="89.0142857142857">The violence broke out after a group of nearly 80 white  supremacists of the Virigina-based National Socialist Movement  assembled for a march against what they called black gang violence  against whites in the Toledo neighborhood.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="8" Score="88.96875">&quot;We were protesting black racial violence against white people  in that neighborhood,&quot; said White.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="4" Score="88.31648258283774">Doug Hanks said the postings were fictional and designed to win white supremacists' trust as he researched a novel he was writing.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="9" Score="88.14953271028037">&quot;I was shaking.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="6" Score="86.10981308411213">&quot;Very typically these days we see white supremacists, hate groups, trying to use the words of King and other civil rights leaders to try to advance their agendas,&quot; Potok said.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="5" Score="85.22222222222223">On the Internet, a forum posting from the Stormfront White Nationalist Community urged white supremacists to come to Crawford this weekend to speak out against the war.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="9" Score="79.17133956386292">said White, 29.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="6" Score="78.39252336448597">&quot;I definitely think they should allow white people in as members,&quot; Campfield said.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="10" Score="72.92426683854335">The neo-Nazi group, known as &quot;America's Nazi Party,&quot; said they came to the city because of a dispute between neighbors, one white and the other black.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="1" Score="72.17647058823529">Already, some white supremacists were celebrating the killings on the Internet, while others spun conspiracy theories that the crime was committed by Hale's enemies to poison the atmosphere before his sentencing next month.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="9" Score="71.2389018691589">&quot;It's exactly what they wanted,&quot; Ford said of the group that planned the march, which was canceled because of the rioting.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="5" Score="70.40625">A Sheehan spokesman said the white supremacists were not invited by anyone connected with Cindy Sheehan.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="1" Score="69.96875">Billy Roper, a friend of Hale's who is chairman of a group called White Revolution, disavowed the violence but offered a different parallel: the FBI's 1992 confrontation in Ruby Ridge, Idaho, with the white separatist Randall C. Weaver, whose wife and 14-year-old son wound up dead.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="6" Score="68.51316907391673">&quot;People just started going crazy about it,&quot; Campfield said.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="1" Score="68.36842105263159">Local and federal law enforcement officials said on Tuesday that they were investigating possible connections between the double murder and Matthew Hale, the white supremacist currently in federal prison for soliciting Lefkow's assassination, or his many sympathizers.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="9" Score="67.94859813084112">Rybczynski said.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="4" Score="66.41822429906543">White supremacists, he said, &quot;have more of a tendency to word of mouth, to say, 'Hey, you ought to pick this up.'&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="9" Score="65.62887358583374">&quot;I was chagrined that there were obvious mothers and children in the crowd with them,&quot; he said.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="7" Score="65.60526315789474">``There are black people who share the beliefs of white supremacists and who, by their actions, concede that white people hold the keys to everything we are and can become,'' he said in a telephone interview.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="3" Score="65.52012940330698">&quot;It doesn't have anything to do with hate,&quot; Reid said.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="9" Score="65.0238836967809">He said the white supremacists had left hours earlier.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="4" Score="64.58177570093459">He said the book was also meant to appeal to white supremacists.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="3" Score="61.737149532710276">Still, Anderson said, &quot;they are clearly tied to the white supremacist movement, if you look at the types of merchandise they're offering.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="10" Score="59.54416641543563">Much of the anger boiled over because people were upset that city leaders were willing to allow the supremacists to walk through the neighborhood and shout insults, residents and authorities said.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="2" Score="59.28443722064202">Outside, 10 to 15 members of the Arkansas-based group White Revolution were escorted by officers to a designated protest area across the street.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="3" Score="59.07476635514019">The reviewed called the boots &quot;Too White ...!&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="8" Score="57.5">Bob White, leader of the movement, said police forced his group  to disband after the protestors gathered around them and began to  throw stones.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="3" Score="57.43380062305297">The Web site's merchandise includes a T-shirt that declares, &quot;Deport Pedro,&quot; another with a picture of Adolf Hitler and the inscription &quot;I was right,&quot; and a third with a design similar to a Tide detergent logo but altered to say, &quot;Pride ... For a Whiter, Brighter Future!&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="9" Score="56.230307076101475">Organizers said they were demonstrating against black gangs they said were harassing white residents.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="4" Score="55.583177570093454">Hanks said his self-published novel, called &quot;Patriot Act,&quot; takes themes from &quot;The Turner Diaries&quot; _ the racist novel believed to have inspired Oklahoma City bomber Timothy McVeigh.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="3" Score="55.36520488856938">There are three &quot;primary&quot; owners, in Houston, Florida and New Jersey, and the new owners want to remain &quot;silent partners,&quot; Reid said.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="9" Score="55.32301401869159">Keith White, a black resident, criticized city officials for allowing the march in the first place.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="4" Score="55.09345794392524">&quot;I needed information for the book and some other writings I was doing,&quot; Hanks told The Associated Press on Friday.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="1" Score="53.25">&quot;Everyone associated with the Matt Hale trial has deserved assassination for a long time,&quot; reads an Internet essay posted on Tuesday by Bill White, editor of the Libertarian Socialist News.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="7" Score="52.9375">This is the consequence of our corrosive moral inconsistency: a dependence on the opposition of whites to give meaning and value to black life.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="3" Score="52.7022696929239">&quot;I think anytime anybody deals in that type of activity, it's a concern for law enforcement,&quot; Anderson said.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="9" Score="52.409417685118626">&quot;They let them come here and expect this not to happen?&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="7" Score="52.125">``You could abort every black baby in this country, and the crime rate would go down.''</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="1" Score="51.91935483870967">Hiram Grau, the department's deputy superintendent, said: &quot;The questions you have are the same ones we have and we are working around the clock to get them answered.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="2" Score="51.86523364485981">Inside the historic meeting house, Holocaust survivors, their children and grandchildren lit white candles to commemorate the estimated 6 million Jews killed by the Nazis.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="4" Score="51.50403568394223">&quot;I saw how successful these 'Turner Diaries' had been and that was the path to take,&quot; he told the AP.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="9" Score="51.42056074766355">&quot;We frankly could have made a couple hundred arrests easily,&quot; Navarre said.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="9" Score="51.42056074766355">When the rioting began, Ford tried to negotiate with those involved, but &quot;they weren't interested in that.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="4" Score="51.09262349799733">&quot;He's a man of total inner hatred in both his heart and soul, and it doesn't matter what party he's in,&quot; McCrory said.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="1" Score="50.53333333333333">&quot;I think she's very upset with herself, maybe, for being a judge and putting her family in this danger,&quot; said Laura Lefkow, 20, the third of the judge's five daughters, &quot;but there's no way she should have known.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="10" Score="50.234228971962615">&quot;They do have a right to walk on the Toledo sidewalks,&quot; said Mayor Jack Ford, who at one point confronted leaders of the mob and tried to settle them down.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="3" Score="49.77889818002952">&quot;I'm glad that authorities are aware of this operation and are keeping an eye on it,&quot; said Roy Brooks, a leader in the local African-American community and a member of the Tarrant County Commissioners Court.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="10" Score="49.21553738317757">The march had been called off because of the crowds, and the white supremacists had left.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="3" Score="49.10966705607477">Lori Bailey, a spokeswoman for the FBI in North Texas, said federal authorities are &quot;keenly aware&quot; of Aryan Wear because of its apparent association with the sometimes violent skinhead movement.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="8" Score="48.92307692307692">&quot;The police lost total control of the situation,&quot; he told AFP.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="2" Score="48.7601246105919">Mitt Romney, who attended the Faneuil Hall event, said he was disgusted by the presence of the supremacists.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="7" Score="48.25">No one at the conference jumped up to blame the white man.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="9" Score="48.22377985462098">They were mostly &quot;gang members who had real or imagined grievances and took it as an opportunity to speak in their own way,&quot; Ford said.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="1" Score="47.96428571428571">&quot;We saw what happened the last time Matt Hale got slapped in the face by the system: The price of that was two dead and nine severely wounded,&quot; said Mark Potok, director of intelligence for the Southern Poverty Law Center.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="6" Score="47.431046273079545">&quot;My understanding is that the KKK doesn't even ban members by race,&quot; Rep. Stacey Campfield, a lawmaker from Knoxville, told The Associated Press, adding that the KKK &quot;has less racist bylaws&quot; than the black lawmakers' group.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="1" Score="47.30769230769231">When Evola said, &quot;Consider it done,&quot; Hale responded, &quot;Good.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="3" Score="47.27703604806409">Aryan Wear, an online clothing, music and book outlet that opposes Jews and promotes white supremacy, keeps much of its merchandise in the storage stall near Fort Worth.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="3" Score="47.01869158878505">&quot;An outstanding product real skinheads can be proud to be associated with,&quot; one wearer said in a review on the Aryan Wear Web site.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="3" Score="46.88951935914553">Initially, Roy said, the boots were sold to make money for the National Alliance.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="3" Score="46.502002670226965">I wish we could,&quot; Brooks said.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="1" Score="46.470588235294116">Potok, of the Southern Poverty Law Center, said Hale's organization splintered and foundered upon his arrest, shrinking from a high in the 1990s of 88 chapters to just five in 2003, but jumped to at least 16 chapters last year and remains one of the nation's most violent groups.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="1" Score="45.90909090909091">&quot;She wasn't afraid,&quot; Sycamore said of the judge.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="6" Score="45.70093457943924">Tennessee Black Caucus member Rep. Larry Miller, a Democrat, said no white lawmaker has ever asked to join.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="2" Score="45.05957943925234">Two people were arrested during Sunday's confrontation, officer John Boyle said.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="1" Score="45.029411764705884">&quot;We can stand alongside the federal law enforcement community in saying just as they felt a deep regret and sadness over the death of Randy Weaver's family so we also feel a deep sense of regret and sadness over the death of Judge Lefkow's family,&quot; Roper said.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="4" Score="44.97688145597639">&quot;I did what I thought I needed to do to establish myself as a credible white nationalist.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="3" Score="44.83177570093458">A pilot who was until recently licensed to fly Boeing 737s commercially, Eynon, 30, declined to be interviewed, saying in his phone message that he had recently sold Aryan Wear and that &quot;there's just the finalization of paperwork right now.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="3" Score="44.80841121495327">&quot;It certainly bears watching.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="10" Score="44.548166786484536">&quot;They don't have the right to bring hate to my front yard,&quot; said Terrance Anderson, who lives near a bar that was destroyed.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="6" Score="44.208622249020195">He acknowledged the group's bylaws mention only black lawmakers but said it might consider admitting a white lawmaker _ not necessarily Campfield who is &quot;using this as a joke.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="10" Score="44.03525913338997">&quot;We knew during the preparation that it was going to be a tremendous challenge,&quot; Police Chief Mike Navarre said Sunday.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="3" Score="44.004672897196265">Roy said the boots were created by Eynon's friend Christopher Evans, who was connected with the violence-prone Confederate Hammerskins in Dallas and now lives in the Fort Worth area.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="6" Score="43.540406816932375">On Saturday, under the heading &quot;I too dream,&quot; Campfield posted long excerpts from the Rev.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="9" Score="43.15654205607477">When Mayor Jack Ford and a local minister tried to calm the rioting Saturday, they were cursed for allowing the march, and Ford said a masked gang member threatened to shoot him.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="9" Score="43.15654205607477">At least two dozen members of the National Socialist Movement, which calls itself &quot;America's Nazi Party,&quot; had gathered at a city park to march under police protection.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="1" Score="43.0">She was immediately vilified -- Hal Turner, an underground radio personality, said on his show that she was &quot;worthy of being killed,&quot; adding that &quot;it wouldn't be legal but in my opinion it wouldn't be wrong.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="1" Score="42.900000000000006">&quot;There is much speculation about possible links between this crime and the possible involvement of hate groups,&quot; he said at a news conference.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="10" Score="42.74138851802403">&quot;You can't allow people to come challenge a whole city and not think they weren't going to strike back,&quot; said Kenneth Allen, 47, who watched the violence begin near his home.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="10" Score="42.60168224299065">Police began receiving word midweek from officers on the street that gangs were going to descend on the neighborhood in protest, the police chief said.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="7" Score="41.27777777777778">``Our health is our responsibility,'' said Jackson L. Davis III, a urologist and coordinator of men's health initiatives at the D.C. Department of Health.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="6" Score="40.95895977245022">It's the same tactic white separatists often use, said Mark Potok, director of the Intelligence Project at the Southern Poverty Law Center.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="1" Score="40.875">&quot;Common sense would tell you, if he were into having somebody kill somebody -- which he is not -- would he have somebody go kill the judge's family just before he's sentenced?&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="5" Score="40.578947368421055">However, the potential appearance of white supremacists and the planned Sunday visit of activist and former presidential candidate Rev.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="10" Score="40.36565420560748">Other neighbors said the group had a right to have their say.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="10" Score="40.35150571131879">Navarre said the riots escalated because members of the National Socialist Movement took their protest to the neighborhood, which is predominantly black, instead of a neutral place.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="9" Score="39.91214953271028">Then they started on the building, breaking windows, ripping the bars off,&quot; he said.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="1" Score="39.88235294117647">&quot;He used to say he was rich in daughters and not much else,&quot; she laughed.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="3" Score="39.72046061415221">Roy said the boots were the alliance's biggest moneymaker until August 2003 when Eynon formed Aryan Wear as a Texas company and began selling the boots exclusively.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="9" Score="39.55427749820274">The mayor had appealed to residents the night before to ignore the march.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="6" Score="39.496139780576996">Experts on race and hate groups said Campfield hit a nerve when he used King's words to take on a black institution.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="1" Score="39.434210526315795">James Molloy, the Chicago Police Department's chief of detectives, said the murders happened between 10:30 a.m., when Lefkow's mother answered a telephone call from one of her granddaughters, and 5:30 p.m. when the judge returned home.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="9" Score="39.3816199376947">I feared for my life.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="7" Score="39.32608695652174">As I've noted before, even our immune system is compromised by the stress of such a frenzied, mothlike attraction to white slights.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="1" Score="39.276315789473685">Lefkow said that her father, a former cab driver, bus driver and substitute teacher, sought out the local courthouse, post office and Episcopal church wherever he went, because he saw them as the &quot;pillars of society.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="9" Score="39.25408878504673">&quot;We just didn't have the resources on hand to arrest all of them.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="5" Score="39.12">&quot;I am more worried about the heat than I am about anyone else out there,&quot; Plemons said, referring to triple-digit temperatures on Saturday.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="9" Score="38.56542056074766">Thomas Frisch, 76, said a large group of men destroyed the exterior of a gas station next to his home of 30 years.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="1" Score="38.36170212765957">&quot;He had nothing to do with what went on last night,&quot; Hutcheson said in a telephone interview from her home in East Peoria, Ill. &quot;My son is sitting in a hole where he's not allowed to even speak loud enough to be audible.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="2" Score="38.1410365335599">Police said Shireen Chambers, 36, of Boston, who is white, struck a black man, Jerome Higins, 25, of Everett, and he retaliated by spitting in her face and hitting her with a sign.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="9" Score="37.95327102803738">A spokesman for the National Socialist Movement blamed police for losing control of the situation.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="6" Score="37.745327102803735">There are 18 black state lawmakers in Tennessee and Campfield's request was deemed to have been made from a &quot;strange guy&quot; who was simply interested in stirring up trouble.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="10" Score="37.691588785046726">About 200 officers patrolled the neighborhood overnight after the riot, Navarre said.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="9" Score="37.69092122830441">The violence broke out about one-quarter of a mile away along the planned march route shortly before it was to begin.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="3" Score="37.67523364485982">Aryan Wear's signature product, however, is a high-laced boot with swastikas carved in the sole, allowing its wearer to leave an impression of the Nazi symbol on soft ground.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="3" Score="37.61495327102804">He denied that the business promotes hatred or that its products -- including the &quot;Happy Hitler Baby Doll&quot; T-shirt -- are overly radical.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="3" Score="37.515667949422756">He lives with his wife and young child in a well-established neighborhood -- down the street from a black family and a Hispanic family -- in a home no different from any other on the block until, neighbors say, the garage door rises, revealing a large Confederate flag on the wall.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="4" Score="37.26460280373832">In one June 1 posting, he said blacks should be treated like &quot;rabid beasts.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="9" Score="36.77431637244722">He said the city wouldn't give the Nazi group a permit to march in the streets but couldn't stop them from walking on the sidewalks.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="10" Score="36.75125808770669">&quot;Too bad the people couldn't ignore them,&quot; said Dee Huntley.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="1" Score="36.75">&quot;I guess because the FBI felt it seemed like there was no danger,&quot; said Laura Lefkow, a sophomore at Pomona College in Southern California.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="5" Score="36.724137931034484">&quot;Riots, like grass fire, start from the smallest little spark,&quot; said Bill Johnson, who owns the Yellow Rose, a prominent gift shop at Crawford's main intersection.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="10" Score="36.236315086782376">Authorities said there was little they could do to stop the group, because they did not apply for a parade permit and instead planned to walk along sidewalks.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="9" Score="36.20427236315087">At least 65 people were arrested on charges including assault, vandalism, failure to obey police and failure to disperse, Navarre said.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="5" Score="36.107142857142854">Sheehan has vowed to keep vigil near the president's vacation home until he agrees to meet with her to discuss bringing an end to the Iraq war.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="9" Score="36.02937249666222">Finally, police marched shoulder-to-shoulder down the street shouting to people to stay inside, and the crowd of several hundred broke up.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="1" Score="35.80434782608695">Federal officials refused to discuss the restrictions, but his mother, Evelyn Hutcheson, said that she and his father are the only people he is allowed contact with, and that they are limited to 15-minute phone calls each Thursday morning, and separate hourlong visits twice a month.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="7" Score="35.53448275862069">That is, until Bennett spoke of aborting ``black babies,'' and suddenly those fetuses become precious pre-born black people who must be saved from the evil Dr. Bill.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="7" Score="35.464285714285715">Jules P. Harrell, a professor and acting chairman of Howard's Department of Psychology, said African-Americans need to ``cultivate a new sense of body,'' one rooted in health and self-respect and not in popular culture, such as rap music videos.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="6" Score="35.44446859378395">Although Campfield said he still believes the blog is a good idea, it will now carry only his posts, along with a little biographical information _ such as his interests in judo and karate, and a listing of the Bible as his favorite book.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="3" Score="35.055355859094185">(Visit the Star-Telegram's online services on the World Wide Web: www.star-telegram.com) nn</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="8" Score="34.9">But a local politician said that the multi-ethnic neighborhood  was not particularly beset by violence.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="1" Score="34.8">It was always fine.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="6" Score="34.71028037383177">This use of King's speech infuriated some readers, and Campfield announced Monday that he was banning reader comments on his blog after some of the postings included death threats.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="10" Score="34.58189867191343">If the Nazi group tries to come back, Ford said he would seek a court order to stop them.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="6" Score="34.5260347129506">Martin Luther King's famous 1963 &quot;I Have a Dream&quot; speech in which King dreams of a day when his children &quot;will not be judged by the color of their skin but by the content of their character.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="1" Score="33.925925925925924">Hale said that he prefers to &quot;fight within the law&quot; but &quot;if you wish to, ah, do anything yourself, you can, you know?&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="10" Score="33.762349799732974">A gang member in a mask threatened to shoot him, and others cursed him for allowing the march, the mayor said.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="7" Score="33.63636363636363">To that end, we might welcome the controversy about abortion and black babies and the long-overdue focus it brings to the black womb -- home to hope unbound as well as unspeakable tragedy.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="3" Score="33.39532710280375">An FBI joint task force knows about the place and the people who operate it.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="1" Score="33.375">&quot;We gonna exterminate the rat?&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="1" Score="33.333333333333336">&quot;Then he asked her out for a beer, and she said maybe coffee.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="9" Score="33.12051155927202">He said people in the crowd swore at him and wanted to know why he was protecting the Nazis.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="1" Score="33.10526315789474">But on Monday night, federal marshals met Laura Lefkow's plane from Los Angeles, and they stood guard on Tuesday as the family planned Saturday funerals for Michael F. Lefkow, 64, an attorney who was a leader in the Episcopal church, and Donna Humphrey, 89, an ailing grandmother who hand-stitched quilts for each of her 23 descendants.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="5" Score="33.06818181818182">While the promise of this weekend's mass demonstrations have a few jittery, area law enforcement and activists are planning to defuse confrontations that could turn a verbal showdown into a physical brawl.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="10" Score="33.02705361534677">&quot;If this march had occurred in downtown Toledo, we wouldn't have had the unrest,&quot; he said.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="1" Score="32.85714285714286">Marshal's service, said that Lefkow had a special protective detail for &quot;a couple of weeks&quot; last year, but it was disbanded when the threats against her were deemed &quot;not viable.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="1" Score="32.41666666666667">&quot;They just didn't want it to affect their lives.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="5" Score="32.375">&quot;We need to prevent that spark.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="3" Score="32.30702197524627">A man identifying himself as Jim Reid, who lives near Austin, said in a recent telephone interview that Eynon is no longer associated with Aryan Wear and that he is the new president and chief executive officer.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="10" Score="32.258566978193144">Neighbors were divided about the city allowing the march.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="2" Score="32.06915887850468">Two people were charged with disturbing the peace after a scuffle outside the protest area.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="1" Score="31.88571428571429">Soon, Lefkow found her home address and family photographs posted along with violent threats on hate-filled Websites, and last April, one of the Aryan movement's most notorious leaders was convicted of plotting her murder.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="1" Score="31.821428571428573">Beth Sycamore, a publishing consultant who lives three houses away, said the Lefkows strolled the neighborhood, holding hands, and took the el train even amid the death threats.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="7" Score="31.6875">``At health fairs, when I ask our young people what are their top health concerns, they say, 'To go to school or a party and not get shot,' '' Davis said.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="6" Score="31.62616822429906">Earlier this year, Campfield was promptly rebuffed when he inquired about joining the Black Caucus.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="5" Score="31.578947368421055">Sheriff's deputies have depended on some level of self-policing by holding individual leaders responsible for groups of people.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="3" Score="31.448399284151918">I think this pretty much seals the deal,&quot; said a phone message left at the Fort Worth Star-Telegram by Tony Eynon, who is named as Aryan Wear's president and lone director in corporate records filed with the Texas secretary of state's office in Austin.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="9" Score="31.403271028037388">&quot;A whole big gang started to come in here.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="5" Score="31.15">The McLennan County Sheriff's Office, which has taken the lead in providing security and running interference, believes the weekend should be peaceful, as has been the last three weeks.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="7" Score="30.977272727272727">``The goal was to build a person who was going to be godlike; in other words, your whole focus is to be the best person you can be spiritually, and that impacts those around you and the community in which you live.''</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="3" Score="30.867708669029977">While most such groups' members are open about their views, the operators of Aryan Wear remain for the most part anonymous, letting their online sales pitches spread their message.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="3" Score="30.843457943925237">&quot;You don't really have my permission to use my name in your article pertaining to this.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="1" Score="30.799999999999997">On Tuesday, Lefkow sat sequestered under armed federal guard in an undisclosed location, mourning her husband of 30 years and her 89-year-old mother, whom she found dead of gunshots to the head in their basement the day before, sending her screaming into the quiet street.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="1" Score="30.444444444444446">The authorities cautioned that it is too soon to focus on any one theory of the crime, though they did not offer other possible scenarios or motives.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="2" Score="30.391355140186914">&quot;I wish they'd go back home where the came from and bury themselves under the rocks that they crawled out from.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="3" Score="30.200467289719626">&quot;We can't legislate good taste or human compassion.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="5" Score="30.166666666666664">Johnson, who is organizing pro-Bush rallies for Saturday, is among the event organizers who realize the perfect storm-in-the-making.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="3" Score="30.07320872274143">&quot;We want to basically present a positive image to the youth and the public in general.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="6" Score="30.05097706032285">Campfield posted a message on his Web journal, or blog, last week about his unsuccessful attempt to join the black lawmakers' group.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="3" Score="30.039719626168225">Incorporated by Fort Worth man, Aryan Wear is one of 10 hate and racially intolerant operations in Dallas-Fort Worth, according to the Southern Poverty Law Center, which is based in Montgomery, Ala., and tracks extremist groups.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="7" Score="30.0">``Traditional African education focused on integrity, and we need to refocus on that,'' Coppock said.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="4" Score="29.823925233644864">Hanks had filed papers seeking the Republican nomination for one of four at-large council seats, but formally withdrew Friday, said county elections director Michael Dickerson.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="10" Score="29.754283489096572">He said he didn't know if the man who threatened him was actually armed, but he blamed gangs for much of the violence.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="3" Score="29.714678394722377">Bailey said, however, that the FBI can do little because the business is not breaking the law.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="10" Score="29.62694704049844">It wasn't enough to stop an angry mob that included gang members from looting and burning a neighborhood bar, smashing the windows of a gas station and hurling rocks and bottles at police on Saturday.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="5" Score="29.608695652173914">Hundreds of peace and pro-Bush demonstrators are expected to pack Crawford and the areas near President Bush's ranch house over the weekend.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="8" Score="29.558823529411768">&quot;That neighborhood has never been known for racial tensions,&quot;  city councilman Robert McCloskey told Fox.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="6" Score="29.408099688473516">He had earlier said he wanted to join the group to find out how it spends its money.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="9" Score="29.2607476635514">At one point, the crowd reached 600 people, officials said.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="3" Score="29.192923898531376">Evans could not be reached for comment.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="1" Score="28.94871794871795">Molloy said the Chicago police also had stopped its practice of sending cars to her home for additional patrols, and Lefkow, her daughter, said the authorities had long ago removed the security cameras it had installed in their home.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="1" Score="28.838709677419356">Michael Lefkow, who ran unsuccessfully for Cook County judge in 2002 and 2004, argued two cases before the U.S. Supreme Court and worked for the Legal Aid Society and the U.S.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="5" Score="28.590909090909093">While there are no official crowd estimates, representatives for both camps believe hundreds will mass in Crawford in support of the president or Cindy Sheehan, the peace mom at the center of demonstrations.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="3" Score="28.432242990654206">So do the Tarrant County Sheriff's Department and a national watchdog group that monitors hate groups nationwide.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="5" Score="28.38095238095238">Al Sharpton should help foster the media circus that has been growing on the Texas prairie near the Western White House.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="10" Score="28.347728005156295">The crowds were eventually dispersed by police in riot gear after about four hours, and the mayor declared a state of emergency that remained in effect through the weekend.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="8" Score="28.21153846153846">Rioting erupted Saturday in an  impoverished neighborhood of Toledo, Ohio after hundreds of  counter-protestors broke up a planned march by a neo-Nazi group,  Toledo police confirmed.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="7" Score="28.130434782608695">If whites in blackface were filling the airways with degrading lyrics and minstrel shows, we'd at least shoot the TV and radio.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="9" Score="27.63855140186916">At least 65 people were arrested and several police officers were injured before calm was restored about four hours later.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="1" Score="27.333333333333332">&quot;This is but one facet of our investigation.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="10" Score="27.145134689389774">Authorities even delayed releasing the route so protesters wouldn't know where the group planned to march.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="7" Score="27.053571428571427">African-American women, who make up only 13 percent of the U.S. female population, accounted for 32 percent of the 1,293,000 abortions performed in the United States in 2002.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="1" Score="26.815789473684212">He spent every Sunday at St. Luke's in Evanston, flirting with the elderly women in the pews, and since 1992 had been a lay member of the governing committee of the Chicago Diocese of the Episcopal Church.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="1" Score="26.62857142857143">&quot;If it was the case that someone was misguided and thought that they were helping Matt Hale, then it would be similar in that other people had suffered for one person's mistake.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="10" Score="26.54964953271028">&quot;Anyone who would accuse us of being underprepared I would take exception with that.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="1" Score="26.424242424242426">&quot;He was just an optimist about everything, to the point where it was like, 'Oh my gosh, dad, come on,' and he would be like, 'It'll be fine,' and it was.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="1" Score="26.357142857142858">&quot;I don't feel bad that Judge Lefkow's family was murdered today.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="4" Score="26.142385926333148">Hanks' postings over the past three years were first reported by The Rhinoceros Times, a weekly newspaper.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="1" Score="26.000000000000004">Hale, who is representing himself, faces up to 40 years in prison, and has been held for two years in the Metropolitan Correctional Center here under special administrative measures, reserved for terrorists, that limited contact with the outside world.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="1" Score="26.0">&quot;She was doing a paper on Indonesia and he was doing a paper on Indonesia, and she had all his books,&quot; Laura Lefkow recalled of her parents' first encounter.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="9" Score="25.914330218068535">Louis Ratajski, 86, and his nephew, Terry Rybczynski, left Jim &amp; Lou's Bar as a crowd gathered in front pelting police with rocks and breaking the windows.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="7" Score="25.818181818181817">``The feeling is, 'Unless they change, we can't change.'</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="9" Score="25.404205607476637">Ford blamed the rioting on gangs taking advantage of a volatile situation.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="2" Score="25.398130841121496">Sunday was the 60th anniversary of the end of the Allied victory over Nazi Germany.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="7" Score="25.265625">Atiba Coppock, an educational psychologist based in the District, called on black men to assume their responsibilities as husbands and fathers and suggested new ways to build character in our black boys.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="1" Score="25.1">Joan Lefkow, a magistrate judge since 1982, was appointed to the U.S. District Court by President Clinton, and originally ruled in favor of Hale, dismissing the trademark case, in 2002.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="2" Score="24.714953271028037">Boyle said at least one officer was injured while arresting Chambers, who yelled racist epithets as she was dragged away.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="1" Score="24.54">The informant, Anthony Evola, provided an e-mail message in which Hale sought Lefkow's home address, and a tape recording of them discussing her fate.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="1" Score="24.53846153846154">&quot;Somebody has done this to make him get an enhanced sentence.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="9" Score="24.485981308411215">Then they overturned it.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="5" Score="24.444444444444443">The group is not only racist, but is anti-Semitic.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="9" Score="24.357107722577474">There was a report of a shooting but police hadn't found a victim, Police Chief Mike Navarre said.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="9" Score="24.179906542056074">About 150 police officers chased bands of young men through the area.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="1" Score="24.049999999999997">Laura's grandmother, Humphrey, who lived in a tan townhouse in Denver, had been staying with the judge's family since before Christmas as she recovered from a kidney infection.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="1" Score="24.0">Federal officials in Washington said agents were scrubbing Lefkow's entire caseload in search of suspects, with the main thrust on the hate groups that had targeted her before.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="7" Score="24.0">It's just a different twist to the same old story.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="1" Score="23.5">In fact, when I heard the story, I laughed.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="7" Score="23.357142857142858">Robert Woodson Sr., president of the National Center for Neighborhood Enterprise, puts it bluntly.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="7" Score="23.15625">That's 413,760 abortions performed on black women in one year -- or 1,133 a day.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="5" Score="22.78125">Many sheriff's deputies have been alongside Sheehan since she began her vigil on Aug. 6.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="8" Score="22.5">Scores of rioters rampaged through streets wrecking cars and  setting a building on fire in north Toledo after police fired tear  gas on the anti-Nazi group.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="9" Score="22.463226330759856">They climbed down a fire escape from the apartment where Ratajski lived over the bar and only later saw the fire on television.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="5" Score="22.454545454545453">They would be asked to leave if they set foot at Camp Casey II, which is on private property, the spokesman said.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="1" Score="22.45">&quot;Now Matt Hale is about to be sentenced, very probably, to most of his natural life to federal prison.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="6" Score="22.305295950155763">&quot;If we work together we might be able to pull things off and get things done.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="2" Score="22.30373831775701">Germany's consul-general to New England, Wolfgang Vorwerk, spoke of his country's role.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="1" Score="22.227272727272727">A flamenco dancer and tennis player, Lefkow met his future wife in the library of Wheaton College, where she was an undergraduate.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="10" Score="22.035907525823905">The neighborhood northwest of downtown, full of tree-lined streets and well-kept brick homes, once was a thriving Polish community.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="5" Score="21.642857142857142">Like many others in Crawford, Sheehan's supporters are hoping for a peaceful weekend.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="2" Score="21.600467289719624">The officers, many in riot gear, formed a barricade between the protesters and about 100 people who angrily shouted at them to leave Boston.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="10" Score="21.39252336448598">But within the last decade it's become home to poorer residents.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="1" Score="20.785714285714285">Shannon Metzger, a spokesman for the U.S.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="6" Score="20.747663551401867">On the Net:</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="1" Score="20.69767441860465">Experts who have spent years tracking Hale's organization -- now called Creativity -- also pointed to the upcoming sentencing, noting that one of his acolytes, Benjamin Smith, went on a shooting spree in 1999 after Hale was rejected by the Illinois bar.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="9" Score="20.67705088265836">Several officers and firefighters suffered minor injuries, Navarre said.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="3" Score="20.615887850467292">Local officials are not impressed.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="5" Score="20.57142857142857">Thaddeus DeJesus writes for the Waco Tribune-Herald.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="9" Score="20.445794392523364">Next thing you know, they're jumping on the car.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="5" Score="20.416666666666664">So far, only two people have been arrested in connection with disturbances at the peace camp protest site.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="8" Score="20.25">Six people were arrested, according to Fox News.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="3" Score="20.023567655424625">But the once-powerful neo-Nazi organization is now in turmoil, with declining membership, since the death of its longtime leader, William Pierce, in 2002.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="3" Score="19.998900494777352">Tarrant County Sheriff Dee Anderson agreed that he saw nothing illegal in Aryan Wear's business tactics.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="10" Score="19.891293654697492">The disturbances were confined to a 1-square-mile (2.6-square-kilometer) area, but the crowd swelled to about 600 people, overwhelming police.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="7" Score="19.76923076923077">But as along as it's just us acting a fool, who cares?</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="7" Score="19.76">In drumming up support for these actions, one e-mailer called Bennett a racist and eugenicist and declared, ``That's how Hitler got started.''</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="1" Score="19.515151515151516">Hale, who called himself Pontifex Maximus of the church that at one point claimed 30,000 members, was arrested in January 2003, after an FBI informant infiltrated the church to become his security chief.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="1" Score="19.25">We are looking in many, many directions.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="10" Score="19.18535825545171">In all, 114 people were arrested on charges including assault, vandalism, failure to disperse and overnight curfew violations.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="7" Score="19.166666666666668">Sorry, he ain't in it.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="1" Score="19.136363636363637">Casings from .22-caliber bullets were found at the scene, and the medical examiner cited the cause of death as multiple gunshot wounds.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="9" Score="18.896789922795612">He declared a state of emergency, set an 8 p.m. (0000 GMT) curfew through the weekend, and asked the Highway Patrol for help.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="7" Score="18.869565217391305">But it's not Bennett, whose comments illuminated a moral inconsistency in black America that is far more harmful than anything he said.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="7" Score="18.857142857142858">WASHINGTON -- A protest demonstration is scheduled for Wednesday at the Salem Radio Network in Arlington, Va., where William Bennett works.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="7" Score="18.684210526315788">If the Ku Klux Klan were killing blacks the way blacks kill blacks, we'd be up in arms.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="7" Score="18.666666666666664">And a boycott of the sponsors of his show is being organized.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="1" Score="18.555555555555557">But after an appeals court reversed her decision, Lefkow had little choice but to order Hale to remove the World Church name from his Web sites and printed material or face fines of $1,000 per day.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="7" Score="18.299999999999997">There is a problem here.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="7" Score="18.161290322580648">Who is responsible for the protection and care of this amazing uterine environment, where the most wonderful fetal programming can occur just by having a loving husband kiss his pregnant wife?</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="1" Score="17.9375">It's very possible that a Hale follower or sympathizer has decided to fight back.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="7" Score="17.86111111111111">Forget about Bennett's absurd crime cure -- a proposal he acknowledged would be morally wrong -- and just look at the most recent analysis of abortion data, released in July by the Alan Guttmacher Institute.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="1" Score="17.53846153846154">At 4 p.m., the Lefkows' youngest daughter, Margaret, 16, came home to get her gym bag and left without seeing anyone in the house, Molloy said.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="9" Score="16.669302659956866">One group of men pounded on a convenience store, and others overturned vehicles.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="5" Score="16.526315789473685">Chief Deputy Randy Plemons said they don't plan to change their standard game plan, which has mostly worked.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="9" Score="15.969118244616011">Officers wearing gas masks fired tear gas canisters and flash-bang devices designed to stun suspects, but the groups continued throwing rocks and bottles.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="5" Score="15.25">When that's not enough, lines of squad cars line up end-to-end to physically block opposing demonstrators from one another.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="1" Score="15.210526315789474">Neighbors in Denver said she played Solitaire and Scrabble on a computer and frequently cooked big meals for friends.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="7" Score="13.923076923076923">He spoke at a recent health conference for black men at Howard University.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="6" Score="13.598130841121492">On his blog, 37-year-old Campfield has also derided gay adoption and abortion.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="10" Score="13.063221550302364">Police reported no problems Sunday, but an 8 p.m. curfew was in effect for a second night.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="5" Score="12.444444444444445">The posting claims that the Iraq war bolsters Israel.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="5" Score="10.538461538461538">High temperatures, ratcheted rhetoric and crowds of people are sure to fuel tempers.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="7" Score="10.5">Bennett?</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="7" Score="10.461538461538462">And he meant all aspects of our health: mental, physical, emotional and spiritual.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="5" Score="10.45">Those leaders, in turn, keep others in check by keeping the anti-war and pro-Bush sides separated and discouraging verbal sparring.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="7" Score="10.428571428571429">Worst of all, we know better and still can't seem to stop ourselves.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="1" Score="10.0">she added.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="7" Score="9.636363636363637">No outcry over that because those were just disposable fetuses, right?</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="10" Score="9.04088785046729">Twelve officers were injured, one suffering a concussion when a brick flew through her cruiser window.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="1" Score="8.25">(STORY CAN END HERE.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="7" Score="7.75">-- William Bennett, radio talk show host and former U.S. education secretary</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="3" Score="7.71588785046729">Fort Worth Star-Telegram researcher Cathy Belcher contributed to this report.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="4" Score="5.815420560747663">Republican Mayor Pat McCrory condemned Hanks.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="1" Score="5.363636363636363">Postal Service before starting a solo firm about 20 years ago.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="7" Score="5.0625">(In Washington, half of all pregnancies ended in abortion, a higher percentage than in any state.)</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="1" Score="4.5">Evola asked.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="3" Score="3.6168224299065423">...</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="1" Score="2.0">Sympathizers abound.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="2" Score="1.8084112149532712">Gov.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="6" Score="1.6822429906542054">___</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="1" Score="1.6666666666666667">OPTIONAL MATERIAL FOLLOWS.)</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="5" Score="1.6666666666666667">E-mail: tdejesus@wacotrib.com</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="3" Score="1.5500667556742325">Jack Douglas Jr. (817) 390-7700 jld@star-telegram.com</sentence>
	</Sentences>
</Topic>
