<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<Topic id="D0901A">
	<Sentences>
		<sentence DocIndex="7" Score="129.97012022630832">Indian and Pakistani military  commanders were to discuss Wednesday Indian charges that Pakistan  fired mortar shells across the border into Indian-controlled Kashmir  in violation of a 14-month ceasefire.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="6" Score="121.49669966996699">The prime ministers of India and Pakistan plan to meet here Wednesday in an effort to find new grounds for compromise in the long-running conflict over Kashmir.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="8" Score="106.94740099009901">India's prime minister will  personally flag off the first bus to travel between the Indian and  Pakistan zones of divided Kashmir in almost six decades when the  service resumes next month, an official said Saturday.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="10" Score="90.4375">CHAKOTHI, Pakistan _ Sixty-year-old Khalid Hussain hugged the brother-in-law he had only seen before in photos after traveling from Indian- to Pakistani-controlled Kashmir on the bus service revived between the divided region after a half-century of conflict.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="7" Score="87.9097909790979">&quot;No one from Pakistan has fired and there is no ceasefire  violation by Pakistan,&quot; Pakistan military spokesman Major General  Shaukat Sultan told AFP in Islamabad.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="6" Score="80.28359264497878">Both countries have hinted that Aziz's meeting with Indian Prime Minister Manmohan Singh may produce agreement on opening bus service between the Indian- and Pakistani-controlled sections of Kashmir for the first time in 57 years of conflict over the Himalayan territory.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="5" Score="76.82376237623761">Pakistan says it would not accept the existing military line dividing Kashmir as an international border, and is playing down concern that India is irreconcilibly opposed to adjusting that frontier.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="6" Score="76.2948889483543">When the British pulled out of the subcontinent in August 1947, they told the Indian princes, including the Hindu maharajah who ruled the mainly Muslim territory of Jammu and Kashmir, to choose between joining India or Pakistan.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="5" Score="74.77682633128178">&quot;The fact is that Jammu and Kashmir is a dispute which Pakistan and India have to resolve through dialogue and negotiations,&quot; he was quoted as saying by state-run news agency the Associated Press of Pakistan.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="1" Score="74.20288914137316">Coinciding with the announcement made in the Indian capital New Delhi, Indian paramilitary police was battling it out with two suicide guerrillas that forced entry into their camp in Srinagar' s Dalgate area on the banks of the Dal lake that is regarded as one of the most secured places in Kashmir and the hub of the tourist activity in Kashmir.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="7" Score="73.57335733573358">On Wednesday, Islamabad denied it had violated the ceasefire in  the disputed Himalayan state of Kashmir, spark of two of three wars  between Indian and Pakistan, and over which they skirmished in  2002.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="2" Score="72.67986798679868">On Wednesday, Singh, the Indian leader, expressed a commitment to make peace with Pakistan, while Islamabad hailed India's withdrawal of some of India's troops in Kashmir _ a move hoped to spur the peace process.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="7" Score="71.17069306930692">Indian police said Tuesday at least one person was injured when  about 15 mortars were fired into India from Pakistan over the Line  of Control.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="9" Score="70.75960396039605">Pakistani and Indian officials will exchange passenger lists for a bus service next month across the divided Kashmir region, a Foreign Ministry official said Monday.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="10" Score="69.35454545454544">The peace process has also led to resumption of trains, buses and flights between India and Pakistan, but the launching of the bus link across Kashmir _ severed in 1948 _ is more resonant, holding out some hope of an end to the intractable conflict over the region, which is claimed by both countries in its entirety.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="5" Score="68.54950495049503">Kashmir is claimed in its entirety by both India and Pakistan, and the countries have fought two wars between over the territory since 1947.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="8" Score="67.88348656294201">India blames Pakistan for fomenting the insurgency in Kashmir  which has left at least 40,000 dead according Indian estimates,  though separatists put the toll at twice that number.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="1" Score="67.86534653465345">For most Kashmiris who have been fed up with the stiffening of Indian and Pakistan approaches on Kashmir, this appears to be the right argument.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="3" Score="66.62706270627064">The leader of moderate Kashmiri separatists warned Thursday that lasting peace between India and Pakistan would be impossible unless his people were seated at the negotiating table.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="9" Score="64.73267326732675">Pakistan's Foreign Ministry spokesman Jalil Abbas Jilani said Pakistani and Indian officials will on Tuesday exchange lists of passengers for the first buses.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="8" Score="63.62046204620463">&quot;The prime minister will be in (the Indian Kashmir summer  capital) Srinagar to flag off the first bus on April 7,&quot; Singh's  spokesman said.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="3" Score="63.59193776520509">A third round of talks with India's government can't start until it agrees to let Kashmiri leaders visit Pakistan to discuss peace proposals with its government and guerrilla commanders in the part of Kashmir under Pakistan's control, Farooq said.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="3" Score="62.20792079207921">During more than a year of talks with Pakistan, India has refused to let Kashmiri leaders have a direct role in deciding possible solutions to the 57-year conflict over Kashmir.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="4" Score="61.370297029702975">Kashmir is divided between India and Pakistan but both claim the region in its entirety.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="3" Score="59.86940935472858">Singh repeated here Wednesday that Kashmir is part of India and insisted any peace deal with Pakistan could not redraw international borders or divide Indian territory along religious lines.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="6" Score="58.96849684968497">Last week, Musharraf revived Pakistan's demand for the plebiscite, in the face of New Delhi's continued claim that Kashmir was its territory and that India's boundaries could not be redrawn.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="6" Score="58.743095362167786">Aziz's two-day visit comes amid mixed signals from India and Pakistan on their willingness to compromise on Kashmir.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="5" Score="57.980198019801975">&quot;Any solution based on the Line of Control will not be acceptable to Pakistan,&quot; Khan said.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="5" Score="57.747905559786744">During a rare visit to the Indian-controlled portion of Kashmir, Indian Prime Minister Manmohan Singh offered Wednesday to hold talks on Kashmir &quot;with anyone and everyone,&quot; but ruled out any redrawing of the Himalayan territory's frontier.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="2" Score="57.532906231799664">Families separated for decades by the Kashmir conflict shouted greetings over the noise of the fast-flowing river.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="5" Score="56.98366336633663">Singh's trip to Kashmir came as India began withdrawing some of its troops from the region, a goodwill gesture to war-weary Kashmiris and Pakistan ahead of planned talks between the nuclear armed rivals on the problem due next month.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="2" Score="56.50079846694348">Crying, waving and throwing letters wrapped around stones to each other, hundreds of Kashmiris gathered on either side of a river that separates the disputed Himalayan region between Pakistan and India.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="1" Score="56.04950495049505">This measure has obviously been taken to take care of the building tensions between the Indian army and local people who often come into unpleasant contact during encounters, crackdown operations and search and cordon exercises that have become so routine in Kashmir ever since the present armed struggle against the Indian rule started here 18 years back.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="5" Score="55.3055162659123">Pakistan and India began a peace process early this year, and are due to start formal talks on Kashmir next month.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="6" Score="55.16171617161715">Indian security forces said they were winning a war against the separatists in Kashmir, which began in 1989.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="10" Score="55.08620689655173">Raja Ferozuddin, 75, a retired government official from Muzaffarabad, was greeted in a village on the route to Srinagar by two of his Indian nephews after crossing from Pakistan.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="7" Score="54.91393754760091">The mortars came from across the border Tuesday evening and  landed in India's Durga Post area in the Poonch sector, an Indian  police spokesman said.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="7" Score="54.809405940594054">The time of the hotline call between the Indian and Pakistani  officials was not immediately known.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="7" Score="53.50082508250825">India and Pakistan began the ceasefire November 25, 2003, after  routinely exchanging artillery fire across the volatile Line of  Control, the de facto border separating their armies in Kashmir, as  part of a tentative peace process.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="9" Score="53.38366336633664">The first buses between Muzaffarabad, the capital of Pakistani Kashmir, and Srinagar, capital of Indian Kashmir, are scheduled to run on April 7 _ one bus with 30 passengers traveling in each direction.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="2" Score="53.297029702970306">Pakistan and India both claim Kashmir in its entirety and have fought two wars over it since their independence from British rule in 1947.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="6" Score="51.704902197536825">India tightened the noose around the insurgents by completing a 12-foot-high fence this year that runs 340 miles along its international border with Pakistan and a 1972 cease-fire line, or Line of Control, that divides the disputed region between the two.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="2" Score="51.14036109493303">Some Kashmiris have fled from the Indian to the Pakistan side, accused of involvement with the rebels.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="7" Score="50.50618811881188">The firing was front-page news in Indian newspapers.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="6" Score="50.21499292786421">Aziz has said he will use his visit with Indian leaders to seek progress in peace efforts that began last year.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="6" Score="50.12871287128712">The Indian military says so far this year it has blocked about 60 attempts by militants to infiltrate Indian-held territory from the Pakistani side.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="2" Score="49.98415841584159">The emotional reunion Wednesday across the Neelum River came on the final day of the Islamic holiday of Eid al-Fitr _ and as Indian Prime Minister Manmohan Singh paid a rare visit to Indian-controlled Kashmir, his country's only Muslim-majority state.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="6" Score="48.9995695221696">Within days of the war, the maharajah chose India, but Pakistan has long insisted that he did so under pressure and that the people of Kashmir should be allowed to decide their fate in a binding referendum promised in a 1948 United Nations Security Council resolution.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="2" Score="48.79207920792079">India accuses Pakistan of helping foment it, which Pakistan denies.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="6" Score="48.36329017517136">After the Sept. 11 terrorist attacks, the United States pressured Pakistan to rein in the militant groups, several of which were allies of the al-Qaida network.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="10" Score="48.313953488372086">&quot;I never thought I would see this day in my lifetime,&quot; said Zahir Uddin, 57, as he waited in Chakothi on the Pakistan side of the frontier for two uncles, both aged in their 80s, who took the bus from India.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="7" Score="48.17956795679568">&quot;The director generals of military operations will be talking  later today,&quot; an Indian government official said, declining to be  named.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="1" Score="47.96076966187184">It is possible the solution ahs already been drafted and both India and Pakistan are slowly but surely moving in that direction step by step so that the people of the two countries are not taken by surprise when the final agreement is signed, said Samad Sheikh, 71, a village headman in Kashmir.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="10" Score="47.54716981132076">The bus service _ heralded by Indian Prime Minister Manmohan Singh as a &quot;a caravan of peace&quot; _ will only run once every two weeks, but it's the most concrete sign that a yearlong peace process aimed at burying the historic enmity between the nuclear-armed rival nations is bearing fruit for Kashmiris.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="2" Score="47.1980198019802">The conflict has only deepened since an Islamic insurgency began on the Indian side in 1989.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="2" Score="47.1460396039604">&quot;Both the countries have not been allowing us to meet,&quot; said Raja Azhar Khan, a 55-year-old refugee, whose wife and son live on the Indian side of the Neelum River.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="6" Score="47.039223153084535">The two countries also are said to be near a deal on a $4.2 billion pipeline to deliver natural gas from Iran to India through Pakistan.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="6" Score="46.96200160556596">Pakistan will only drop its demand for a vote ``if India is prepared to show flexibility,'' Musharraf told an interviewer last week, adding that ``at the moment ... we don't see that.''</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="8" Score="46.837216074548635">Indian Kashmir is in the grip of a 15-year-old insurgency that  has so far left thousands dead.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="9" Score="46.735228361545836">Pakistan and India agreed in February to re-establish a bus link between the Indian- and Pakistan-controlled portions of Kashmir as part of moves to improve relations between the two longtime rivals.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="1" Score="45.684731631057836">Interestingly, Indian Home Minister Shivraj Patil, who had recently visited Kashmir for three-days, told reporters in Delhi that he was yet to submit his report to the Prime Minister about his perceptions of the ground situation in Kashmir.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="1" Score="45.51440144014401">Markets are overcrowded, traffic jam is heavy and the shops are jostling with shoppers in the capital city of Srinagar in the Indian-administered Kashmir as the holy Moslem festival of Eid approaches here.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="8" Score="45.47961560861969">India and Pakistan agreed last month that Kashmiri residents  would not need passports to cross the divided state by bus but would  use permits issued by the civil administration after being cleared  by police.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="2" Score="45.37663366336634">Indian soldiers were preventing people from getting too close, and on the Pakistan side, police said authorities had not given formal permission for the reunions.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="2" Score="45.27249246663798">The Pakistani and Indian portions of Kashmir are separated by a heavily militarized cease-fire line where skirmishes were once common between their forces.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="6" Score="45.038189533239034">But as the guerrillas lose their strength, Pakistan loses leverage on the Kashmir issue.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="5" Score="44.91558103178739">Pakistan's Foreign Ministry spokesman Masood Khan said that Singh's comments did not necessarily represent an intractable position.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="10" Score="44.64">India has long accused Pakistan of fomenting a separatist insurgency in Kashmir that has left more than 66,000 people dead over the past 15 years.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="1" Score="44.53663366336634">Indian Prime Minister Manmohan Singh, who arrives here on a two- day visit next week, announced on Thursday that orders had been given for the reduction of troops inside Kashmir.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="4" Score="44.29782178217822">Singh's two-day trip came as India began withdrawing some of its troops on the border, a goodwill gesture to war-weary Kashmiris and rival Pakistan.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="4" Score="44.22002200220022">India accuses Pakistan of arming Muslim insurgents fighting for the region's independence or merger with Islamic Pakistan.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="1" Score="43.533946251768036">Interestingly, Pakistan President Pervez Musharraf had recently put forth a new formula on Kashmir that was seen as a climb down from the previous Pakistan position on Kashmir.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="1" Score="43.30693069306931">This also is the reason that many locals believe the Indian government is acting under international pressure.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="3" Score="42.35820367751061">``Kashmiris have expressed themselves in red-hot blood for the last 15 years, and this reality cannot be ignored, neither by India nor Pakistan,'' said Farooq, who heads a loose alliance of separatist groups called the All Party Hurriyat Conference.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="3" Score="42.28255902513329">Kashmiri leader Mirwaiz Omar Farooq insisted Thursday that ``historic realities,'' such as a guerrilla war against Indian rule that began in 1989, meant three-way talks were the only way to end the dispute over the divided territory.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="5" Score="41.56668608037274">In a shift in stance, Pakistani President Gen. Pervez Musharraf last month suggested that some areas of Kashmir be made independent, placed under joint Indian and Pakistani control, or put under United Nations administration.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="2" Score="41.46094609460946">They are allowing people to meet each other at Wagha (the main land border between Indian and Pakistan).</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="8" Score="40.58757255035849">Indian authorities last week said some 150 permits had been  issued to applicants from Indian-Kashmir to travel by the bus  linking Srinagar to Muzaffarabad, capital of the  Pakistan-administered zone.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="8" Score="40.38861386138614">The bus service was suspended in 1947 after the first  India-Pakistan war over Kashmir.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="10" Score="40.125">All that changed Thursday, when two buses, carrying about 50 people in all, many of them elderly, shuttled in each direction between Srinagar and Muzaffarabad, the capitals of the Indian and Pakistan-administered Kashmir, for 15-day stays.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="3" Score="40.078217821782175">Almost 1,600 people have died in the conflict this year.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="5" Score="39.86138613861386">We are asking for a solution that is acceptable to the people of Pakistan, India and the Kashmiris.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="7" Score="39.86138613861386">&quot;Pakistan  opens fire across Line of Control,&quot; said The Hindu.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="3" Score="39.26237623762376">In January, former Indian Prime Minister Atal Behari Vajpayee's government began the first talks with Kashmiri separatist leaders, but two rounds of discussions showed little progress.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="3" Score="39.23688118811881">Indian Prime Minister Manmohan Singh has been slow to resume negotiations with Kashmiri leaders since defeating Vajpayee in May elections.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="8" Score="39.23465346534654">Pakistan denies supporting the rebels though it admits to  extending moral, political and diplomatic support to the Kashmiris'  freedom struggle.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="3" Score="37.41216407355021">Farooq said Hurriyat leaders would travel to New Delhi next week to meet Pakistan's Prime Minister Shaukat Aziz, who is expected to discuss new efforts to advance a peace process that began last year.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="10" Score="37.285714285714285">Minutes later he embraced his wife's brother, Asif Solaria, who lives on the Pakistan side and came to meet him.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="10" Score="37.27777777777778">Until a year-and-a-half ago, the two armies would routinely shell each other, often killing civilians who were displaced from their homes in their thousands by the conflict.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="4" Score="37.245827439886845">But Singh shrugged off a suggestion by Pakistani President Gen. Pervez Musharraf last month that some areas of Kashmir be made independent, placed under joint Indian and Pakistani control, or put under United Nations administration.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="1" Score="37.01150655606101">It must also be mentioned that the Indian army on Friday suspended and took into custody an officer who had been accused of having raped a woman and her daughter in a north Kashmir village last week.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="3" Score="36.882838283828384">``And we are ready to discuss all three, with both the Indian and Pakistan governments, so that a way forward can be charted that is acceptable to all.''</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="1" Score="36.84653465346535">For Kashmiris the recent developments and the fact that the bilateral ceasefire on the borders between the two countries was holding for the last one year are indications that their troubles might soon end.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="2" Score="36.5940594059406">&quot;The two countries are getting friendly.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="9" Score="36.49621432731509">The passengers on the first bus route will include men and women, as well as elderly people who have not seen relatives on the other side of the frontier for 50 years, he said.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="2" Score="36.442844284428446">The two countries are due to start formal talks on Kashmir next month, and people on both sides are eager for a long-standing proposal for a bus service between Muzaffarabad and Srinagar, the summer capital of Indian-held Kashmir, to finally get off the ground.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="3" Score="36.07549504950495">According to Farooq, Aziz plans to discuss recent proposals by President Pervez Musharraf for a settlement, which included granting autonomy to the divided region and putting parts of it under joint rule by India and Pakistan.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="5" Score="36.03630363036304">The proposals have been greeted with little enthusiasm by India, although it has since announced its troop withdrawal.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="3" Score="35.523102310231025">``The Hurriyat has three road maps for resolving the Kashmir issue,'' Farooq said, without providing details.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="7" Score="35.37936425221469">Indian army officer Major General D. Samanwar told NDTV news  channel the incident was tantamount to a ceasefire violation.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="2" Score="34.80748074807481">Nosheen Akhtar, 22, and her mother, Khonshad Begum, 40, burst into tears, wailed and beat their chests _ unable to meet Begum's mother on the Indian side.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="8" Score="34.665912305516265">The bus service is the first tangible result of 14 months of  dialogue between the nuclear-armed neighbours who have fought three  wars including two over Kashmir, which each hold in part but claim  in full.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="10" Score="33.0">Fifty-seven years of conflict has divided thousands of Kashmiri families.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="3" Score="32.72234179939733">The official death toll in the Kashmir insurgency is more than 45,000, but Kashmiris say the real number is more than twice that.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="10" Score="32.48571428571429">Some migrated in the aftermath of the bloody partition of the subcontinent in 1947, many more fled to the Pakistani side when a separatist insurgency took hold in the Indian portion of Kashmir in 1989.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="8" Score="31.606008876749748">Of the 150 applicants, 60 will be short-listed for the first two  trips -- the first on April 7 and the second a fortnight later -- an  official said.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="4" Score="31.497878359264497">India has cited a decline in separatist violence as the main reason for its troop withdrawal, which reportedly will be about 40,000 of the half-million stationed in Kashmir.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="1" Score="31.123312331233123">Significantly, Musharraf had suggested withdrawal of Indian troops from Kashmir region.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="1" Score="31.054455445544555">Patil was obviously trying to suggest that the Prime Minister Singh had taken the decision to reduce the troops inside Kashmir on his own.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="1" Score="31.054455445544555">Kashmir is a very tricky situation.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="8" Score="30.332673267326733">Prime Minister Manmohan Singh's visit to Kashmir in April will  be his third since he assumed office in May.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="3" Score="29.625247524752478">After hearing Kashmiri leaders' views, Aziz will formally present the proposals to India's government, said Farooq, who called Musharraf's suggestions ``a step in the right direction.''</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="10" Score="29.43333333333333">Previously, the only way to reunite was through the long and difficult process of applying for a visa to the other country _ or, during lulls in the violence, by yelling greetings across the roar of the water at the riverine frontier when authorities permitted it.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="7" Score="29.248939179632245">&quot;Yes, it certainly is a violation.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="4" Score="29.028538147932444">Earlier, Singh offered to hold talks on Kashmir &quot;with anyone and everyone&quot; but ruled out any redrawing of the disputed territory's frontier, which separates Indian- and Pakistan-controlled portions of the region.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="6" Score="28.36290936785986">Musharraf is the first Pakistani leader to publicly suggest that the dispute might be resolved without a vote by Kashmiris -- if India makes significant concessions.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="4" Score="28.05940594059406">Prime Minister Manmohan Singh met with Kashmiri political leaders on Thursday during a rare visit to the Himalayan region aimed at ending half a century of separatist violence that has claimed tens of thousands of lives.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="2" Score="27.653465346534656">But Kashmiris are impatient for progress that will allow them to reunite with relatives across the cease-fire line, known as the Line of Control.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="5" Score="27.48019801980198">Khan said the two prime ministers would discuss &quot;all issues.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="7" Score="27.437057991513438">&quot;The Pakistani side has denied firing.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="1" Score="27.405040504050408">It is, therefore, clear that the Prime Minister's decision has not been influenced by any dramatic improvement in the ground situation.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="4" Score="27.287128712871283">Singh _ on his first visit as prime minister to India's Jammu-Kashmir state _ also announced a four-year, multibillion-dollar development plan he promised would result in thousands of jobs for people in the region.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="7" Score="26.876237623762375">Let's see.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="4" Score="26.845827439886843">&quot;Any redrawing of the international borders is not something that is going to be acceptable to us,&quot; Singh said.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="3" Score="26.820792079207923">Indian authorities said about half the dead were militants, 456 were civilians and 269 were members of the security forces.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="4" Score="26.4976897689769">Singh indicated his government also would press to end tensions with Kashmiri militants and Pakistan.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="7" Score="26.27227722772277">The two sides have been engaged in formal peace talks to  normalise relations since January 2004.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="2" Score="25.99009900990099">Authorities on both sides were restricting access to the riverside at Karin, 90 kilometers (55 miles) north of Muzaffarabad, the capital of Pakistan-held Kashmir.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="5" Score="25.7018701870187">Pakistani Prime Minister Shaukat Aziz is due to make his first trip to India next week since taking office in August, and will hold talks with Singh.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="5" Score="25.64944306930693">On Thursday, Pakistani Foreign Minister Khursheed Kasuri advised India to avoid controversial statements, saying the relations between the two nations were at a &quot;very delicate stage and required careful nurturing.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="6" Score="25.64944306930693">Pakistani Prime Minister Shaukat Aziz arrived here Tuesday on a tour of regional capitals as head of the South Asian Association for Regional Cooperation, which promotes closer economic ties within the region.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="6" Score="25.321039603960394">``Let me tell you that I have no reason to believe that there has been any lack of effort in infiltration attempts from across the border,'' India's chief of army staff, Gen. Nirmal Chander Vij, said Monday.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="4" Score="25.313531353135314">But a gunbattle launched by militants hours before Singh's visit underscored the fragile security of the region.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="4" Score="24.933521923620933">Talks with Kashmiri separatists began last year under Singh's predecessor, Atal Bihari Vajpayee.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="10" Score="24.857142857142858">Pakistan says it gives political backing to the rebels but denies giving military support.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="6" Score="24.762376237623762">The number climbed in recent weeks as Musharraf pressed Singh to move more quickly on negotiations over Kashmir.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="3" Score="24.6362688900469">``So if anybody believes that you can have a bilateral agreement on Kashmir, they are highly mistaken.''</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="5" Score="24.4">&quot;This is very clear.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="4" Score="24.286787299419597">&quot;The ban will not apply to Jammu-Kashmir since youth in the state are facing hardships in getting jobs,&quot; Singh told a crowd of about 15,000 in Jammu.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="7" Score="23.8015301530153">The director-generals of military operations of the  nuclear-armed neighbours were slated to talk by telephone about the  incident that occurred late Tuesday.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="4" Score="23.734653465346536">Although Singh's visit was largely welcomed by Kashmiris, many were inconvenienced after security forces barricaded the main streets of Jammu, the state's winter capital, ahead of his arrival.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="2" Score="23.495049504950497">&quot;I want to jump into the river.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="1" Score="23.447266465777012">But, around this Eid festival, there is more to the happy public mood than just the urge to over spend during the festival.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="10" Score="22.92857142857143">&quot;I was eight years old when I left this place,&quot; Ferozuddin said.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="4" Score="22.71782178217822">Creating employment for young people in Jammu-Kashmir was also a priority, Singh said, adding a ban on recruitment for government jobs will be lifted.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="1" Score="22.57128712871287">Kashmiris are known as incorrigible festive shoppers and because of that reputation, unscrupulous shopkeepers have been minting money by over-charging the locals for everything from a chop of mutton to the chickens and hosiery items that the locals must buy to protect themselves from the biting cold of the winter.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="1" Score="22.47964796479648">That is why the prime minister has said that together with the reduction in the number of troops in Kashmir, there would be no lowering of vigil.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="6" Score="22.4014401440144">But he also has suggested that India is hardening its position.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="10" Score="21.661764705882355">It was an event treated with pomp on both sides and observed with glee by thousands of Kashmiri villagers scattered on the steep mountainsides of the Jehlum Valley despite storm clouds, rain and lightning.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="6" Score="21.645940594059407">As the king delayed, the two neighboring nations went to war over the region in October of that year, and it has been divided since.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="3" Score="21.14980628497632">``Both things have to be addressed,'' he told reporters here, after insisting Hurriyat leaders were not setting conditions for resuming negotiations.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="7" Score="20.937293729372936">It's the first time it has  happened but we've exercised full restraint,&quot; he said, adding troops  had been put on alert.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="10" Score="20.413043478260867">The bus service was launched despite an attack Wednesday in Srinagar by suspected militants on a government tourism complex where passengers were staying.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="10" Score="20.272727272727273">Many more lined the road on both sides of the frontier.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="1" Score="19.75618811881188">Does this mean that both Musharraf and Singh are simply trying to play roles that have been scripted for them by the international community?</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="10" Score="19.539473684210527">&quot;We are so happy we can't express how we feel,&quot; Hussain said Thursday after crossing a narrow bridge over a rushing river that spans the military Line of Control that cleaves the disputed Himalayan region.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="6" Score="19.528052805280524">``During the current month alone, there have been eight such attempts, including two taking place during the last two to three days.''</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="5" Score="19.512566641279513">The Indian- and Pakistan-controlled portions are separated by the so-called Line of Control.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="4" Score="19.423942394239425">&quot;I have come here with the realization and hope that I can understand what your aspirations and desires are,&quot; he said, barely visible as he spoke from behind a bulletproof screen.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="4" Score="18.453361125586245">On Thursday, Singh met with members of the state Cabinet to discuss ways to implement the economic aid package.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="2" Score="18.2970297029703">The guns have fallen silent for the past year amid the thaw in relations, and since then there have been several opportunities for family reunions _ albeit at a distance of 25 meters (yards) across the river.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="2" Score="17.964356435643566">Why are we Kashmiris not being allowed to meet?&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="6" Score="17.439356435643564">After insisting for months that they were ready to give up entrenched positions and make lasting peace, leaders of both countries in recent days have repeated hard-line views on the disputed region.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="4" Score="17.16171617161716">Singh announced an economic development plan for Kashmir that would spend 71 billion rupees (US$1.5 billion, euro1.16 billion) next year, part of a 240 billion rupee (US$5.3 billion, euro4.1 billion) outlay over four years.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="5" Score="16.593017196456486">&quot;Let us not read too much into these statements because, as you can see, we have this track of confidence-building and dialogue, and there is no definitiveness in these statements,&quot; Khan told a news conference Thursday.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="8" Score="16.045544554455446">The second was in 1965.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="10" Score="15.9375">I want to embrace all this into my heart _ the trees, the hills, the rocks.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="4" Score="15.627256843331391">The countrywide ban on government hiring was part of measures to downsize India's bloated public sector.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="4" Score="15.445544554455445">He was also scheduled to meet with army and paramilitary force commanders to review a decision to reduce troops deployed in India's Jammu-Kashmir state.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="2" Score="14.90869086908691">Despite easing tensions between South Asia's nuclear rivals, Kashmiris are still forbidden from crossing the watery border.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="4" Score="14.464875058934465">Two militants were killed and two soldiers and a civilian wounded in the attack near the rally site, security forces said.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="2" Score="14.365436543654367">My mother is there and I cannot go over to meet with her,&quot; said Begum, her relatives holding her back.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="10" Score="14.142857142857142">&quot;It's taken a long time.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="6" Score="13.129573826947912">Pakistani President Pervez Musharraf insisted again last week that the guerrillas were freedom fighters acting without anything but moral support from his country.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="10" Score="13.047619047619047">On Thursday, white flags fluttered at either side of the &quot;peace bridge,&quot; its approaches recently cleared of land mines.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="4" Score="12.510891089108911">Singh also Wednesday addressed a rally of some 12,000 people.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="4" Score="12.356435643564357">The funds would go to building new roads and schools, and developing infrastructure for water, power and health care.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="3" Score="12.237623762376238">Kashmiri leaders feared those were new condset out specific proposals for negotiation.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="4" Score="12.150495049504952">Some of the money will come from international financial institutions.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="10" Score="12.083333333333334">The three kissed and wept with joy as they held each other.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="4" Score="11.801980198019802">The initiatives are expected to create 24,000 new jobs, including 14,000 for women.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="10" Score="11.571428571428571">It should have happened much sooner.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="4" Score="11.491485148514853">Children and office workers trudged to their schools and offices after public buses were halted as part of the stringent security measures in the city.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="10" Score="11.3">&quot;All this has happened very late in my life.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="10" Score="10.714285714285715">Eds: Associated Press Writer Mujtaba Ali Ahmad in Salamabad, India, contributed to this report.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="1" Score="9.623762376237623">And that has given them new hope to celebrate the forthcoming Eid with more joy and confidence.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="1" Score="8.382178217821783">One grenade blast can put things back by months here.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="6" Score="6.03960396039604">(End optional trim)</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="10" Score="5.866666666666666">They traveled anyway the following day, apparently undeterred and making a small piece of history.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="4" Score="3.7755775577557755">Islamabad denies that.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="6" Score="3.01980198019802">(Begin optional trim)</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="10" Score="1.5">____</sentence>
	</Sentences>
</Topic>
