<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<Topic id="D0922D">
	<Sentences>
		<sentence DocIndex="2" Score="132.3270460358056">&quot;Neither the Anti-Lobbying Act nor the appropriations provision prohibited the attorney general and the U.S. attorneys from making public speeches conveying DOJ's view regarding the merits of the Patriot Act and discussing the DOJ's use of the law's provisions,&quot; Fine said.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="8" Score="128.07897603485839">Long wary of the act's enhanced police powers, the conservatives announced they had formed the organization Patriots for Checks and Balances with the liberal American Civil Liberties Union in time for hearings in the Republican-controlled Congress next month on whether it should renew 16 Patriot Act provisions that expire at year's end.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="9" Score="120.97647058823529">Washington -- An unusual left-right coalition opened a campaign Tuesday to sharply curtail controversial provisions of the USA Patriot Act, showing that Congress and President Bush face a pointed debate over renewing the law enacted just 45 days after the Sept. 11, 2001, terrorist attacks.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="5" Score="117.15921945701359">President Bush on Monday urged the nation to stay the course in its &quot;urgent mission&quot; to fight terrorism, and he called on Congress to move quickly to extend sweeping law enforcement powers under the USA Patriot Act.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="6" Score="116.81951871657753">President George W. Bush on Monday urged Congress to reauthorize the USA Patriot Act, the Justice Department's widely criticized anti-terrorism law.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="3" Score="103.13327205882354">A senior Bush administration official defended the Patriot Act on Tuesday as a &quot;smart, ordinary and constitutional&quot; tool in fighting terrorism and rejected attacks on it as rash and misinformed.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="8" Score="102.84179316888046">Conservative libertarians launched a campaign Tuesday to persuade President Bush and Congress to fix the sections of the anti-terrorism Patriot Act that they say intrude on privacy and harm civil liberties.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="3" Score="102.59045504994451">The comments by James B. Comey Jr., the deputy attorney general, coming in a speech before the American Bar Association on the third anniversary of the passage of the Patriot Act, offered a preview of what is likely to be a fierce fight in Congress next year over the future of the law.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="8" Score="100.81372549019608">Bob Barr, the group's chair and a former Republican representative from Georgia who voted for the act in 2001, said the sunsetting of the provisions and the hearings in the House and Senate provide a ``unique opportunity'' to add checks and balances to the act.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="10" Score="98.62630718954249">The American Civil Liberties Union, the American Conservative Union, Americans for Tax Reform and the Free Congress Foundation are among several groups that formed a coalition _ Patriots to Restore Checks and Balances _ to lobby Congress to repeal three key provisions of the USA Patriot Act.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="2" Score="95.58012170385396">Attorney General John Ashcroft did not violate anti-lobbying laws when he gave a series of speeches last year promoting the anti-terror Patriot Act, Justice Department internal investigators have concluded.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="10" Score="91.31830495356037">The coalition highlighted the provisions in a letter to the president which also said, &quot;We agree that much of the Patriot Act was necessary to provide law enforcement with the resources they need to defeat terrorism.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="7" Score="85.08235294117648">Fran Townsend said White House support for extending the entire USA Patriot Act, which expires at the end of the year, is &quot;unequivocal.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="8" Score="83.02668845315904">Justice Department spokeswoman Tasia Scolinos said her agency ``has spearheaded the call for active discussion and meaningful dialogue on the reauthorization of the Patriot Act.''</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="9" Score="82.58970588235294">&quot;It is not, and never should be necessary, to surrender our rights under the Bill of Rights to fight the war on terrorism,&quot; said Barr, who as a House member voted for the Patriot Act, which passed overwhelmingly in the House and provoked only one dissenting Senate vote.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="10" Score="81.17182662538701">Administration officials have said the Patriot Act has kept America safe, but opponents have called the law intrusive and contend that it undermines civil liberties and threatens to let the government snoop into the lives of innocent Americans.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="10" Score="81.04493464052288">President Bush and Attorney General Alberto Gonzales have called for renewal of the Patriot Act, the government's post-Sept. 11, 2001, law that expanded its surveillance and prosecutorial powers against suspected terrorists, their associates and financiers.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="10" Score="81.03168767507003">Having people from all sides of the political spectrum working together will keep politicians from calling Patriot Act opponents un-American or willing to help terrorists, which happened during the original debate over the law, the groups said at a news conference Tuesday.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="3" Score="80.24715370018976">With key elements of the Patriot Act set to expire at the end of 2005, President Bush has urged Congress to renew the law as a valuable weapon in tracking terrorists.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="9" Score="79.76470588235294">Mueller said the Patriot Act is a key part of the FBI's new post-Sept. 11 approach.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="2" Score="78.81512605042018">The Patriot Act, passed by Congress a few weeks after the Sept. 11, 2001, terror attacks, gave federal law enforcement officials broader powers of surveillance and prosecution against suspected terrorists, their financiers and their sympathizers.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="6" Score="78.22166427546628">The Patriot Act, passed in the wake of the Sept. 11 terrorist attacks, bolstered FBI surveillance and law-enforcement powers in terror cases, increased use of material witness warrants to hold suspects incommunicado for months, and allowed secret proceedings in immigration cases.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="3" Score="77.32398897058825">Comey's own defense of the Patriot Act was significant both because of his current position as the second-ranking official at the Justice Department and because of his prospects for a promotion.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="7" Score="75.04743833017079">&quot;In the debate over the Patriot Act, we often hear about that delicate balance that we rightly must make between freedom and security,&quot; Townsend told the American Bar Association.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="3" Score="73.48692810457517">In his speech to the bar association, Comey defended two aspects of the Patriot Act that he said have come under unfair attack: a provision that allows authorities to conduct so-called &quot;sneak and peek&quot; searches without immediately notifying the target; and a separate section allowing them to demand business records on terror and espionage suspects from bookstores, libraries and other institutions.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="10" Score="70.91295415224914">The coalition wants Congress to repeal or let expire prosecutors' Patriot Act ability to easily obtain records in terrorism-related cases from businesses and other entities, including libraries; the provision that allows &quot;sneak and peek&quot; searches conducted without a property owner's or resident's knowledge and with warrants delivered afterward; and what they called an overbroad definition of &quot;terrorists&quot; that could include non-terrorism suspects.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="9" Score="69.1204292527822">President Bush campaigned last year in favor of renewing the Patriot Act, and Attorney General Alberto Gonzales has indicated he doesn't favor any changes except, perhaps, to increase the government's powers in a few instances.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="7" Score="68.32785467128028">Civil liberties groups and privacy advocates have lambasted the Patriot Act because they believe it undermines freedom.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="6" Score="67.36928104575163">The Patriot Act was pushed by Gonzales' predecessor, John Ashcroft, who was in the audience as Gonzales took his oath from Supreme Court Justice Sandra Day O'Connor.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="7" Score="66.26916221033868">Section 215 of the Patriot Act does not specifically mention bookstores or libraries, but permits secret warrants for &quot;books, records, papers, documents and other items&quot; from businesses, hospitals or other organizations.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="1" Score="65.55882352941177">It's time -- past time -- to rein in the excesses of the USA Patriot Act.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="7" Score="64.0216718266254">Congress has rejected attempts to bar the FBI from using Patriot Act authority to obtain library and bookstore records.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="5" Score="62.90189075630252">A number of measures in the act that expand the government's ability to conduct secret surveillance and use other law enforcement powers will expire at the end of the year unless Congress extends them.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="9" Score="62.03921568627452">At a recent House hearing, FBI Director Robert Mueller praised the Patriot Act and said he'd like to see it expanded to include administrative subpoena power in terrorism cases, something the FBI has in organized crime and health- care fraud investigations.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="1" Score="61.71428571428572">In the shaky, uncertain weeks after the Sept. 11 attacks, Congress passed an anti-terrorism bill that gave the government broad powers to peer into the lives of Americans.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="3" Score="60.95713634290925">&quot;It's ironic that the same Department of Justice that has misled the public about the Patriot Act would complain that the public has been misled,&quot; said Gregory Nojeim, associate director of the American Civil Liberties Union's Washington legislative office.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="5" Score="56.75">&quot;To protect the American people, Congress must promptly renew all provisions of the Patriot Act this year.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="7" Score="55.47737556561086">Townsend said she said she recently asked an audience to indicate how many people were concerned about the &quot;library records provision&quot; in the act.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="10" Score="52.891875602700104">&quot;We don't want this argument to be obscured by those who would suggest that anyone who is for more and more government power is somehow on the side of the right, and those who are against it or are skeptical of such grants are on the side of the wrong,&quot; said David Keene of the American Conservative Union.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="3" Score="52.351481017939086">Comey's speech came on the same day that Attorney General John Ashcroft, in an op-ed piece in The Wall Street Journal, called the Patriot Act &quot;an indispensable tool&quot; in fighting terrorism and said it &quot;is often portrayed in an outright false light.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="9" Score="51.59024064171123">So far, almost 400 local and state governments have passed resolutions opposing the act, or some of its provisions, the ACLU says.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="7" Score="50.90539215686275">&quot;And people were really stunned that there is nowhere in the Patriot Act the mention of library records.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="9" Score="50.209033613445385">Barr, leader of the new group dubbed Patriots to Restore Checks and Balances, concedes that the group faces a difficult fight in making changes to the 4-year-old law.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="10" Score="49.35819327731093">&quot;There have been no verified civil liberties violations filed against the Patriot Act.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="10" Score="47.72159090909092">Conservative and liberal groups normally at each other's throats over the direction of government are finding common cause in wanting to gut major provisions of the U.S. government's premier anti-terrorism law.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="5" Score="47.00023342670402">In taking on the subject of the Patriot Act once again, he showed no signs of backing away from that approach.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="9" Score="45.643137254901966">The Senate and House Judiciary Committees plan Patriot Act hearings starting later in the spring.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="8" Score="45.53235294117647">At a news conference Tuesday, ACLU Washington director Laura Murphy underscored the importance of raising the profile in the debate of such prominent conservatives as Grover Norquist of Taxpayers United, David Keene of the American Conservative Union and Paul Weyrich of the Free Congress Foundation.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="1" Score="45.46153846153846">The provision also bars the companies from disclosing that they've been subpoenaed via a pre-Patriot Act instrument known as a &quot;national security letter.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="9" Score="44.68300653594772">The law's supporters, many of whom point out that the United States hasn't been hit by another terrorist attack since Sept. 11, say it has proven effective and that many of the complaints offered by civil libertarians have nothing to do with the act's provisions.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="2" Score="43.82135076252724">He also noted that a review of Ashcroft's speeches found he never urged audience members to contact members of Congress on behalf of the Patriot Act.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="9" Score="42.92892156862745">And I've yet to hear a strong argument as to why the Patriot Act should not be reauthorized.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="10" Score="42.8406862745098">&quot;Any suggestion of civil liberties violations is an effort to shift the focus of the discussion away from the facts,&quot; Scolinos said.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="9" Score="42.30763116057234">&quot;If the Constitution stands for anything, it's that government does not have the power to peer into our private lives without evidence of wrongdoing,&quot; said Laura Murphy, of the ACLU's Washington legislative office.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="6" Score="42.205147058823535">&quot;We must not allow the passage of time or the illusion of safety to weaken our resolve in this new war&quot; on terrorism, Bush said at a swearing-in ceremony for Attorney General Alberto Gonzales at the Justice Department.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="10" Score="41.90060851926978">The coalition &quot;is seeking modest changes to only a few extreme sections of the law,&quot; said former Republican lawmaker Bob Barr of Georgia, the coalition's chairman.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="6" Score="40.87394957983193">He noted that many key elements of the law are set to expire at the end of the year and said Congress must act quickly to renew it.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="5" Score="40.21530330882353">&quot;We must not allow the passage of time or the illusion of safety to weaken our resolve in this new war,&quot; Bush said in a speech at the Justice Department.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="8" Score="40.152872777017784">Bush and new Attorney General Alberto Gonzales have said in recent speeches that one of their priorities this year is to win congressional renewal of all expiring sections of the controversial anti-terrorism law, enacted just weeks after the Sept. 11, 2001 terror attacks.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="8" Score="39.97217806041336">Barr and his group said that they find hope in Gonzales' remarks that he will be more open to discussion that his predecessor, John Ashcroft, who not only staunchly defended the act but sought to expand it.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="3" Score="39.550000000000004">In the face of frequent attacks on the law, Bush administration officials have mounted an increasingly aggressive and public defense of the legislation and railed against what they regard as distortions about what it does.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="8" Score="39.31260504201681">``Given the number of folks in this room wearing elephant lapel pins, I don't think the administration can easily discount our message,'' said Murphy, referring to the symbol of the Republican Party.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="2" Score="39.25919117647059">Conyers, who could not be reached immediately for comment, had asked Fine to investigate after a Government Accountability Office report showed that Ashcroft's tour and a pro-Patriot Act Internet site had cost more than $208,000 and also had involved activities by 80 of the 93 U.S. attorneys.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="5" Score="39.224264705882355">&quot;The president and the attorney general must realize that security and liberty are not -- and cannot -- be mutually exclusive,&quot; the group said in a statement</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="9" Score="39.0514705882353">&quot;We have changed the way we address terrorism since Sept. 11 to ensure that we have exploited every possibility to gather intelligence about the motivations, the capabilities of these individuals or groups in our communities before we go ahead and make the arrest,&quot; he told a House panel.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="3" Score="38.975935828877006">Critics challenged the Justice Department's aggressive defense of the law.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="5" Score="38.66789215686275">Bush's renewed call for an extension met with skepticism from the American Civil Liberties Union, which called on &quot;cooler heads&quot; in Congress to scrutinize and fine-tune the law to meet civil liberties concerns.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="9" Score="38.537114845938376">But they were among those at a Washington press conference held to assail such Patriot Act provisions as those allowing law enforcement agents to look at library users' records or to conduct unannounced &quot;sneak-and-peek&quot; searches on homes or private offices.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="5" Score="37.65529411764707">The president's remarks came at the formal swearing-in of his friend and longtime adviser, Alberto R. Gonzales, as the nation's 80th attorney general.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="9" Score="37.536332179930795">Instead of seeking wholesale changes, the coalition is focusing on three of the law's most-controversial provisions.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="1" Score="37.1">&quot;We believe the act to be completely consistent with the United States Constitution,&quot; he told The Associated Press.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="8" Score="36.618172268907564">The ACLU has worked with conservative libertarians for the past decade with to insist on the inclusion of judicial review and other safeguards for privacy in anti-terrorism laws.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="5" Score="35.987804878048784">Bush, speaking at the Justice Department's Great Hall before an audience of visiting officials and Justice Department employees, said that Gonzales was joining them in &quot;an urgent mission -- to protect the United States from another terrorist attack.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="6" Score="35.54117647058823">But Bush said the act &quot;has been vital to our success in tracking terrorists and disrupting their plans.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="6" Score="35.27294117647059">The president also argued that the Senate must give his nominees for the federal bench up-or-down votes without delay to fill vacancies in the courts.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="10" Score="34.66200980392157">Justice Department spokeswoman Tasia Scolinos said the law &quot;contains strong civil liberties safeguards and has a proven track record of being an effective tool in the war on terror.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="9" Score="34.14926470588236">Grover Norquist, the conservative activist who heads Americans for Tax Reform, noted the unlikely coalition of conservatives and the ACLU.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="5" Score="33.04852941176471">Bush built his re-election campaign last year around the assertion that he was the candidate best able to defend the country against another terrorist attack.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="1" Score="32.8875">Last week, a federal judge in Manhattan struck down a provision in the 342-page act that enables federal authorities -- without court review -- to force Internet service providers to turn over personal information about subscribers and their online activities.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="7" Score="31.970907928388744">The White House's homeland security adviser asked attorneys Thursday to help foster an honest debate over whether to reauthorize controversial anti-terror laws.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="1" Score="31.767857142857146">For the long-term health of our nation, it's essential to strike a more sensitive balance between the pursuit of security and the preservation of our basic freedoms.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="1" Score="31.625000000000004">Attorney General John Ashcroft said the Justice Department would appeal the ruling.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="1" Score="31.3">Judge Marrero drew a far different conclusion, saying the provision and the latitude it gives the government to conduct unchecked searches have &quot;no place in an open society.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="10" Score="31.098297213622292">For liberals, partnering with conservatives will ensure that the Republican-dominated Congress and President George W. Bush's administration will have to listen to their concerns, said Laura W. Murphy, outgoing director of the ACLU's Washington legislative office.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="6" Score="30.879506641366227">Gonzales, who served as White House counsel during the last four years, said he would be a part of Bush's team but his first allegiance will be to the Constitution.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="10" Score="30.746904024767804">&quot;This is an important question of all Americans on the left, the right or in the middle.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="7" Score="30.654255319148938">Critics says among the law's more controversial powers is the FBI's ability to obtain library and bookstore records in terrorism cases, and so-called &quot;sneak and peek&quot; search warrants in which agents need not immediately tell suspects their home or business had been searched.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="10" Score="30.600490196078432">Period.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="5" Score="29.96463585434174">Many Democrats and some Republicans have voiced skepticism or outright opposition to an extension, and some lawmakers have offered competing proposals that would restrict the ability of federal agents to demand records from libraries and use other powers granted by the act.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="6" Score="29.95294117647059">Civil liberties groups and privacy advocates lambasted the law because they said it undermines freedom.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="9" Score="29.618512110726645">The group wants similar limits on the provision allowing secret searches of homes, businesses and personal property.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="9" Score="28.949690402476783">&quot;For too long, conservatives assumed it was someone else's job&quot; to protect civil liberties, Norquist said.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="9" Score="28.934256055363328">&quot;Debate about government exercise of powers that might infringe upon privacy or civil liberties, I think that's an appropriate debate,&quot; he told a recent meeting of the National Association of Counties.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="3" Score="28.77690100430416">Many officials inside and out of the Justice Department say they do not expect Ashcroft to return for a second term as attorney general if Bush is re-elected, and Comey is thought to be on the short list of possible successors.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="7" Score="28.76131221719457">That law, which was passed in the wake of the Sept. 11 terror attacks, gives the government broad surveillance and law enforcement powers in terror cases.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="2" Score="28.724789915966387">The agency's inspector general, Glenn A.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="3" Score="27.668382352941176">But civil liberties advocates, who have pushed for the repeal of secret intelligence warrants under the library records provision, argue that federal authorities can already use standard criminal warrants at libraries if they have evidence linking a suspect to terrorism.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="9" Score="27.668382352941176">Key provisions of the bill are scheduled to expire Dec. 31, so Congress must deal with the issue this year.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="8" Score="27.051983584131328">Those are the so-called ``sneak-and-peek'' Section 213, which allows agents to enter a place without first notifying the owner; Section 215, which permits agents to get business and library records more easily; and Section 802, which broadly defines terrorists and terrorism.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="2" Score="26.987058823529416">&quot;In addition, given the DOJ's responsibility to enforce criminal laws, we do not believe they could be considered `purely partisan,'&quot; Fine wrote.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="2" Score="26.66377005347594">The inspector general's conclusions were in a letter to Rep. John Conyers of Michigan, senior Democrat on the House Judiciary Committee.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="6" Score="26.199726402188784">&quot;I am confident that in the days and years ahead we in the department will work together tirelessly to address terrorism and other threats to our nation and to confront injustice with integrity and devotion to our highest ideals,&quot; Gonzales said.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="10" Score="26.178792569659446">&quot;These changes will secure the important powers of the law while placing reasonable limits on their use.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="1" Score="26.166666666666664">U.S. District Judge Victor Marrero ruled that the provision violates the Fourth Amendment protections against unreasonable searches and the First Amendment protections against prior restraint on speech.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="7" Score="26.135026737967916">&quot;Probably 70 percent of hands went up,&quot; Townsend said.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="9" Score="25.865728900255757">And group members want the language of the section that allows surveillance of protests rewritten to require a definite connection with suspected terrorism.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="9" Score="25.676944971537004">It was a Washington rarity to see the American Civil Liberties Union line up with conservative lions like David Keefe of the American Conservative Union and former Rep. Bob Barr, R-Ga.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="7" Score="24.787990196078432">&quot;I encourage you to keep that debate honest,&quot; Townsend said.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="8" Score="24.451680672268907">In a letter sent to the president Tuesday, Barr and his group asked Bush ``to reconsider your unqualified support'' for three specific provisions, only one of which is set to expire without reauthorization.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="2" Score="23.464117647058824">In his letter, Fine said that the attorney general and U.S. attorneys, as presidential appointees, are exempt from prohibitions against executive branch lobbying of Congress.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="9" Score="23.172385620915033">The group wants the section giving access to library, medical and firearm-ownership records modified to require that law enforcement officials present evidence to a federal judge supporting a link with suspected terrorism before warrants are served.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="1" Score="23.029411764705884">As the judge points out, &quot;Sometimes a right, once extinguished, may be gone for good.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="2" Score="22.367880485527547">Fine, said the trips to 16 cities in August and September of 2003 did not run afoul of laws barring executive branch officials from engaging in grass-roots lobbying or prohibiting the spending of government money on unauthorized &quot;publicity or propaganda.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="9" Score="22.077731092436977">&quot;These provisions sweep far too broadly.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="10" Score="22.056197478991596">Lawmakers set a 2006 expiration date on many of the wiretapping and surveillance measures, and will begin holding hearings starting in April on whether they should be renewed.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="10" Score="21.698529411764707">On the Net:</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="5" Score="21.1421568627451">Gonzales won Senate confirmation 11 days ago by a vote of 60 to 36 after a sharp debate that focused on the administration's terrorism policies and their impact on the treatment of prisoners</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="9" Score="21.01736694677871">And rather than push for their repeal, the group wants the wording clarified to establish that the intention is to fight terrorists -- not let law enforcement agencies engage in fishing expeditions or silence dissent.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="1" Score="20.11111111111111">The challenge was raised by the American Civil Liberties Union on behalf of an unnamed Internet service provider.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="5" Score="19.50232198142415">The White House, however, has signaled that it will veto any effort by Congress to rein in counterterrorism powers.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="8" Score="19.165686274509806">Barr says he also consults for the American Conservative Union.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="3" Score="19.145801910507796">But liberals and some conservatives in Congress have repeatedly raised concerns about whether the law has given the federal government too much power and have urged a go-slow approach in considering whether it should be renewed in its entirety.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="2" Score="17.64027149321267">Congress next year must decide whether to renew major parts of the law.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="8" Score="17.448529411764707">Last year, the ACLU paid Barr $150,000 to be a consultant and lobbyist, Senate records show.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="2" Score="17.423351158645275">The letter, dated Friday, was obtained Monday by The Associated Press.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="9" Score="16.93417366946779">&quot;But it's got to be a real debate, one based on facts.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="7" Score="16.83921568627451">&quot;I value that debate.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="7" Score="15.95294117647059">The president values that debate.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="7" Score="15.50980392156863">And it is important.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="7" Score="13.549773755656108">&quot;...We really should try to divorce this from partisan politics.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="5" Score="13.114495798319327">Gonzales echoed that theme, pledging that department employees would &quot;work together tirelessly to address terrorism and other threats to our nation, and to confront injustice with integrity and devotion to our highest ideals.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="9" Score="12.740196078431373">Whenever people ram through legislation with broad and vague authority, it eventually will be abused,&quot; Barr said.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="9" Score="12.239028944911299">The subpoenas, which require recipients to disclose information, are signed by an FBI agent without prior judicial or grand jury review.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="7" Score="9.859803921568629">What is equally important is that we not permit this valuable tool to be caught up in unnecessary rhetoric.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="6" Score="7.518716577540108">Bush lauded Ashcroft's tireless efforts to make America safer as he oversaw a drop in violent crime besides his counterterrorism work.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="10" Score="1.6691176470588236">___</sentence>
	</Sentences>
</Topic>
