<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<Topic id="D0927E">
	<Sentences>
		<sentence DocIndex="4" Score="168.34109972041006">Peter Jennings revealed that he is suffering from lung cancer and plans to continue on &quot;World News Tonight&quot; as much as possible after beginning chemotherapy next week.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="1" Score="166.008445945946">&quot;World News Tonight&quot; anchor Peter Jennings has lung cancer, ABC announced Tuesday, but plans to remain on the job throughout his treatment.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="9" Score="163.28571428571428">The news that Peter Jennings will be absent from &quot;World News Tonight&quot; for an indeterminate period while he is being treated for lung cancer has, at least from a business perspective, had its most profound impact on Jennings' ultimate boss, David Westin, the president of ABC News.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="1" Score="161.78378378378378">&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="10" Score="157.35135135135135">''</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="10" Score="157.35135135135135">''</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="10" Score="152.39949324324326">Peter Jennings, in a statement read Friday night on ABC's ``World News Tonight,'' shared with viewers his feelings about his battle with lung cancer and expressed gratitude for the support he has received from fans and friends.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="6" Score="141.95523648648648">ABC News anchor Peter Jennings has been diagnosed with lung cancer, the network announced Tuesday, and will immediately begin a round of outpatient chemotherapy that is expected to keep him from the anchor desk at times in the coming months.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="3" Score="140.84652509652508">Peter Jennings, the sole anchor of the ABC evening newscast for the past 22 years, announced Tuesday that he was suffering from lung cancer and had begun treatment.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="5" Score="132.9509400705053">Peter Jennings, the last of the three long-dominant network anchors still on the job, said Tuesday he has been diagnosed with lung cancer.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="2" Score="131.13359073359072">Peter Jennings, the last of the three major anchors of his era who is still working on a nightly newscast, revealed Tuesday that he has lung cancer and that he will begin chemotherapy next week.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="8" Score="123.74756756756756">The first message was posted just six minutes after the news broke April 5 that ABC anchor Peter Jennings had been diagnosed with lung cancer.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="4" Score="113.29054054054055">&quot;Peter is an old friend,&quot; Brokaw said Tuesday.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="10" Score="105.96283783783784">``He's a tougher man than I am,'' Jennings said.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="4" Score="98.67936117936118">&quot;I will continue to do the broadcast,&quot; he said.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="6" Score="98.27027027027027">Jennings called the diagnosis ``quite a surprise'' and expressed gratitude for his colleagues.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="2" Score="97.66795366795365">E-mail messages released Tuesday by Jennings and ABC News president David Westin stressed that Jennings, who is 66 and who has anchored ABC's &quot;World News Tonight&quot; since 1983, will continue to work during treatment, provided he feels well enough.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="6" Score="97.35257985257986">``Peter's been given a tough assignment,'' Westin added.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="6" Score="93.04054054054055">Jennings joined ABC News in 1964.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="8" Score="92.0052310374891">``We are enormously grateful for the loyalty of our audience, and we expect they will continue to get their news from Peter Jennings,'' ABC News spokesman Jeffrey Schneider said.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="1" Score="91.57722007722008">Jennings joined ABC News in 1964 and served as the anchor of &quot;ABC Evening News&quot; from 1965 to 1968.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="6" Score="88.58704292527823">ABC News President David Westin told the network's staff that he and Jennings expect the anchor to continue the newscast during his treatment ``to the extent he can do so comfortably.''</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="2" Score="88.58230958230956">&quot;Your initial reaction is you wish Peter Jennings well,&quot; said J. Max Robins, editor in chief at Broadcasting &amp; Cable magazine.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="3" Score="87.74447174447174">ABC News emphasized that Jennings would remain its evening news anchor.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="4" Score="86.92368839427664">While still in his 20s, Jennings anchored ABC's evening news for two years in the 1960s.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="8" Score="86.32923832923834">``Network news is in a big pickle,'' he said.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="8" Score="84.9054054054054">ABC executives stress that Jennings is still the anchor of ``World News Tonight'' and will do the broadcast whenever he feels up to it.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="4" Score="84.25061425061425">Jennings said he was surprised at how fast the news traveled and at the kindness he had received from so many people.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="10" Score="83.85876198779425">That kind of testimony from a public figure like Jennings can make a ``huge difference'' in peoples' lives, Brace said last night after hearing Jennings' remarks on the newscast.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="10" Score="83.80067567567569">``What we see in Peter Jennings is a role model,'' said Suzanne Brace, executive director of HopeWell Cancer Support in Lutherville, Md.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="4" Score="83.24679943100995">Charles Gibson, Vargas and others will substitute for Jennings from time to time, said ABC News President David Westin.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="4" Score="82.42628992628993">&quot;I think it sets the right example,&quot; Johnson said.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="3" Score="79.28040540540539">ABC said Jennings, 66, would work as often as he could during his course of treatment.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="10" Score="79.22972972972973">Whew!''</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="10" Score="79.22972972972973">Jennings added.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="7" Score="78.82142857142858">The future of the iconic American anchorman was on the minds of many this week as the news that Peter Jennings had been diagnosed with lung cancer raised concerns that he wouldn't be able to continue as anchor at ABC News.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="5" Score="78.590990990991">``Peter is part of the DNA of ABC News,'' said spokesman Jeffrey Schneider.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="10" Score="77.1981981981982">Jennings has not anchored the newscast since April 1.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="8" Score="76.92594594594594">Charles Gibson, co-host of ``Good Morning America,'' and ``20/20'' co-anchor Elizabeth Vargas, who are filling in for Jennings temporarily, are considered possible permanent replacements for the longtime anchor, along with ``World News Tonight Saturday'' anchor Bob Woodruff and chief White House correspondent Terry Moran.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="9" Score="76.36363636363636">Even as he began treatment last week as an outpatient, Jennings remained a presence on &quot;World News Tonight,&quot; albeit backstage.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="2" Score="76.24324324324323">&quot;Lung cancer in general is aggressive,&quot; Swanson added.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="10" Score="74.7972972972973">Jordan sent Jennings a book titled ``No Such Thing as a Bad Day.''</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="3" Score="73.92686804451509">Jennings was unable to anchor the ABC newscast on Tuesday night, though he had originally planned to.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="4" Score="73.58108108108107">&quot;Jennings has served American broadcast news with a graceful internationalist intelligence,&quot; said Rich Hanley, director of graduate programs at Quinnipiac University's school of communications.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="8" Score="73.55100261551874">Indeed, there was ample evidence last week that viewers greatly value the intimacy and confidence they have felt with Jennings, who has anchored ``World News Tonight'' for 22 years.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="10" Score="71.80540540540541">Chemo strikes,'' Jennings wrote.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="6" Score="70.89987714987714">``But we should also expect him to be off the broadcast from time to time, depending on how he feels,'' Westin wrote in an e-mail to the entire staff, adding that Charlie Gibson and Elizabeth Vargas, among others, would substitute for Jennings.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="8" Score="70.781981981982">``They feel rootless.''</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="3" Score="70.08946877912395">He added that Jennings would undergo outpatient treatment in New York and would continue to work on the newscast &quot;to the extent he can do so comfortably.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="2" Score="70.04324324324323">In his e-mail to the staff, Westin said that when Jennings is unable to work, Vargas and &quot;Good Morning America&quot; cohost Charles Gibson would be among the substitutes.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="5" Score="69.91128084606346">Since Brokaw's departure in December, Jennings has brought his newscast close to the top-rated ``NBC Nightly News'' in the Nielsens.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="4" Score="68.77702702702703">Jennings is the last of the anchor troika that dominated U.S. broadcast network news divisions over the last two decades.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="1" Score="68.75307125307125">In his e-mail, Westin wrote, &quot;It's both Peter's and my expectation that he will anchor 'World News Tonight' during the period of treatment to the extent he can do so comfortably; but, we should also expect him to be off the broadcast from time to time, depending on how he feels.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="1" Score="68.7027027027027">Charles Gibson, Elizabeth Vargas and others will substitute for Jennings as necessary.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="2" Score="68.37837837837837">In his own e-mail to his colleagues, Jennings said: &quot;There will be good days and bad, which means that some days I may be cranky and some days really cranky!</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="1" Score="67.85532591414946">The news comes at a time when Jennings remains virtually the last of the longtime network anchors.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="4" Score="67.81727379553467">Jennings, ABC's chief anchorman since 1983, was replaced by Elizabeth Vargas on Tuesday but taped a message telling viewers about his diagnosis.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="1" Score="67.7054054054054">Westin called the news &quot;a tough assignment,&quot; while Jennings, 66, said it was &quot;quite a surprise.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="4" Score="66.4475051975052">&quot;Finally,&quot; he said, &quot;I wonder if other men and women ask their doctors right away: `OK, doc, when does the hair go?&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="6" Score="66.15158636897768">``In all the years I have worked here I have had the most outstanding support from this news division,'' he wrote.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="2" Score="65.97972972972973">He added: &quot;We expect him to be the anchor for many years to come.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="8" Score="65.85917496443813">An Ohio mother said she and her children say, ``Good night, Peter'' every night after the newscast.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="5" Score="65.57233704292528">In a note to his staff, Jennings wrote, ``Almost 10 million Americans are living with cancer.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="2" Score="65.54848966613672">&quot;Obviously this is a very emotional day at ABC News,&quot; said a spokesman, Jeffrey Schneider.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="1" Score="65.35859073359073">Jennings wrote of his coming treatment: &quot;There will be good days and bad, which means that some days I may be cranky and some days really cranky!</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="4" Score="65.06756756756756">Jennings has been ABC's sole evening anchor ever since.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="10" Score="64.54729729729729">She's right.''</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="2" Score="64.21780604133544">ABC's &quot;World News Tonight&quot; is currently in second place in the nightly news wars, but it has been breathing down the neck of the ratings leader, &quot;NBC Nightly News.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="7" Score="63.42857142857143">``And that's the way it is,'' asserted the decisive Walter Cronkite.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="6" Score="63.13748531139836">Jennings' announcement provoked sadness and dismay among his colleagues at ABC, where the anchor plays a central role in leading the news division.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="8" Score="62.97837837837839">Schneider insisted that ABC executives are focused on Jennings' recovery.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="1" Score="62.78223938223939">As a coach for aspiring broadcasters, Castengera has told his students to watch Jennings' broadcasts, &quot;because he has such a relaxed, personable style that makes him very easy to relate to,&quot; he says.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="5" Score="62.57340294840296">Jennings, 66, plans to begin chemotherapy and to continue to anchor ABC's ``World News Tonight'' when he can, but specialists said the decision to forgo surgery suggests a more advanced form of cancer for which long-term survival rates are relatively low.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="2" Score="62.41891891891891">Dr. Scott Swanson, a thoracic surgeon at New York's Mount Sinai Medical Center who specializes in lung cancer, said of Jennings: &quot;He seems pretty healthy now.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="5" Score="61.909700398072495">The winner of 14 Emmy Awards, he has reported from all 50 states and hosted specials such as ``Peter Jennings Reporting,'' ``The Search for Jesus,'' ``The Kennedy Assassination -- Beyond Conspiracy'' and, more recently, one on UFOs.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="8" Score="61.82432432432432">Jennings still hopes to lead the newscast throughout his chemotherapy.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="1" Score="61.56925675675676">Last week, Jennings' ABC colleague Ted Koppel announced he will leave &quot;Nightline&quot; this December.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="5" Score="61.278116826503926">``Peter has always been healthy as a horse and shows up for everything,'' said an ABC staffer who requested anonymity because network employees have been asked not to comment.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="10" Score="60.642109851787275">``Thousands of you have spoiled me rotten with your attention in the last couple of weeks,'' Jennings said in a statement that was read on air by Elizabeth Vargas.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="4" Score="60.578298887122415">&quot;He's already bringing to this new challenge the courage and strength we've seen so often in his reporting from the field and in anchoring ABC News,&quot; Westin told ABC staffers.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="5" Score="60.539232781168266">Jennings added a similarly light note on Tuesday night's broadcast, smiling several times and noting that he was ``a little surprised at the kindness today from so many people.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="9" Score="60.0">On March 31, less than a week before Jennings disclosed his cancer, Westin announced that Ted Koppel would be leaving &quot;Nightline&quot; and the network in December.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="5" Score="59.26319176319177">Jennings had planned to anchor Tuesday night's newscast, but decided an hour before airtime that his voice was too weak.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="3" Score="59.145145145145136">That treatment worked for a time, but as Jennings acknowledged in his commentary on Tuesday night, he returned to regular smoking after the terrorist attacks in 2001.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="10" Score="58.72972972972973">``He's had cancer four times.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="9" Score="58.72727272727273">&quot;He's e-mailing; he's suggesting stories,&quot; Banner said.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="6" Score="58.6427732079906">Jennings, who has anchored ``World News Tonight'' since 1983, led the newscast Friday and is expected to do so again tonight.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="2" Score="58.46246246246245">&quot;Almost 10 million Americans are living with cancer.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="5" Score="58.317889317889325">ABC News President David Westin said in a note to the staff that ``Peter's been given a tough assignment.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="1" Score="57.99099099099099">&quot;Almost 10 million Americans are living with cancer.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="7" Score="57.95454545454545">``Good night and good luck,'' said Edward R. Murrow.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="10" Score="57.21993243243243">By allowing his feelings to be expressed on air, Jennings gave viewers an unusually personal glimpse of what it is like to have the disease as well as offering what may be solace to cancer patients, support group leaders said.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="6" Score="57.16216216216216">he wrote.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="1" Score="57.14398881640262">A former smoker who quit some years ago, Jennings will begin outpatient chemotherapy treatment next week in New York, but he intends to continue broadcasting as his health permits.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="5" Score="56.73492723492724">After a four-month period in which Tom Brokaw retired at NBC, Dan Rather relinquished the anchor chair at CBS and Ted Koppel said he was leaving ABC, Jennings's illness underscored the generational shift underway at the broadcast networks.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="2" Score="56.28298887122416">While making Jennings's condition public, the network did not provide details about the diagnosis or prognosis.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="4" Score="56.16998577524893">With his very visible position on television each night, Jennings could be an inspiration for many others going through a similar fight, said Dr. David Johnson, chief of oncology and hematology at the Vanderbilt University School of Medicine.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="6" Score="55.99882491186839">``There will be good days and bad, which means that some days I may be cranky and some days really cranky!''</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="9" Score="55.96875">Jennings has also been encouraged by Westin and Banner to come in and reclaim the anchor chair on any night he feels up to it, with as little as 45 minutes' notice.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="5" Score="55.73648648648649">Such was Jennings' longevity that he was in Germany when the Berlin Wall went up and when it came down.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="5" Score="55.641047297297305">Jennings has been the face of ABC News for much of his 40-year career there, first as anchor from 1965 to 1968, in what he has described as an unsuccessful tenure, then as part of a three-man anchor team in 1978 before becoming solo anchor again in 1983.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="1" Score="55.599324324324336">He and ABC News President David Westin sent e-mails to their newsroom colleagues about the diagnosis, which Jennings received Monday.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="5" Score="55.58378378378379">Jennings, who had not been feeling well for months, got the diagnosis Monday afternoon and told his staff that night.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="8" Score="55.310545839957605">While the announcement of Jennings' illness hit the already unsettled world of network news with even more turbulence, it also jolted television viewers, stripping them -- at least for a time -- of the last of the three familiar faces that had anchored the evening news for the past two decades.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="5" Score="55.129591129591134">Alex Jones, director of Harvard's Shorenstein media center, said that when he interviewed Jennings two decades ago, ``he was embarrassed that he had not finished high school and worked all the harder to be a superb journalist.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="9" Score="54.86065573770492">In the short run, the absence of Jennings threatens to undermine one of the chief goals Westin has set for his news division this year: to overtake its main rival, &quot;NBC Nightly News,&quot; at a moment of potential vulnerability for NBC -- just as Brian Williams has lost some of the audience he inherited in December from Tom Brokaw.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="3" Score="54.52390852390852">Jennings had been a heavy smoker until the mid- to late-1980s, colleagues said.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="6" Score="54.46911196911197">Jennings did not go to Rome to cover Pope John Paul II's death.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="5" Score="53.541385135135144">ABC executives refused to provide medical details of the type or state of Jennings's cancer.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="2" Score="53.19605319605319">Jennings decided late Tuesday not to anchor Tuesday night's program and was replaced by &quot;20/20&quot; coanchor Elizabeth Vargas.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="3" Score="52.33693693693694">&quot;Peter will once again lead the way but we will stand with him at every turn,&quot; Westin said.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="8" Score="52.06538796861378">Stuart Fischoff, a professor emeritus of media psychology at California State University, Los Angeles, said he is not surprised by the emotional responses to Jennings' absence from the newscast last week.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="2" Score="52.05067567567567">The health of Jennings, a former smoker, surfaced as an issue late last year, when he was unable to travel abroad for coverage of the devastating tsunami in southern and Southeast Asia.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="10" Score="51.52702702702703">``I won't soon forget an encounter as I was leaving the hospital.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="1" Score="51.151700087183954">&quot;Peter Jennings is one of the few anchors that people almost invariably say, 'Yes, I could see sitting down and having a drink with him and talking casually about issues.'</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="9" Score="50.85714285714286">&quot;It's a very dynamic time at ABC News,&quot; said Paul Slavin, a senior vice president in the division.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="10" Score="50.51126126126127">Jennings offered a further update on his treatment Friday in a letter posted on the abcnews.com Web site.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="3" Score="50.07313195548489">He said: &quot;The National Cancer Institute says that we are survivors from the moment of diagnosis.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="4" Score="49.25675675675676">A Canadian who proudly became a U.S. citizen in 2003, the urbane Jennings dominated the ratings from the late 1980s to the mid-'90s, when Brokaw surpassed him.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="10" Score="48.94780987884437">Jennings went on to describe notes and messages he had received from Sen. Arlen Specter, R-Pa., and Hamilton Jordan, former chief of staff in the administration of President Carter.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="5" Score="48.63349713349714">ABC anticipated Brokaw's resignation by kicking off a promotional campaign for Jennings with the tag line: ``Trust is earned.''</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="8" Score="48.26044226044226">``The simple fact is that the generation is changing.''</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="6" Score="48.14785373608904">Peter will once again lead the way, but we will stand with him at every turn.''</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="8" Score="47.55717255717256">Jennings' diagnosis forces ABC executives to begin contemplating the question of succession, too -- a matter most had assumed would be at least several years off.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="5" Score="46.8491891891892">Michael Thun, vice president of epidemiology for the American Cancer Society, said that ``the most effective treatment for localized lung cancer is surgical removal.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="4" Score="46.376244665718346">A former smoker who quit 20 years ago, Jennings resumed smoking briefly after the Sept. 11, 2001, terrorist attacks.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="8" Score="46.36199836199836">``There is research that shows when you remove pivotal people on television from a person's daily life, they feel like they've had a death in the family,'' he said.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="7" Score="46.125">It was around this time that Cronkite earned his sobriquet as ``the most trusted man in America,'' not as impressive as it sounds given the competition.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="3" Score="45.830445830445825">In an e-mail message to his staff on Tuesday, David Westin, the president of ABC News, praised Jennings for his leadership of the news division over the years and expressed the division's support as he encountered this challenge.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="1" Score="45.63763763763764">He was foreign desk anchor for &quot;World News Tonight&quot; from 1978 to 1983, the year he was named the program's anchor and senior editor.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="10" Score="45.61711711711712">You knew this was coming.''</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="5" Score="45.40360360360361">``He's very strong and he's a fighter.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="5" Score="45.374517374517374">Everyone's first, second and third thoughts are for Peter's speedy recovery.''</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="4" Score="45.13030888030889">Gibson is in Rome for coverage of the pope's funeral, an assignment that Jennings, a former Rome and London correspondent for ABC News, normally would have taken.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="4" Score="45.0">&quot;I'm heartbroken, but he's also a tough guy.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="8" Score="44.741375521863326">A second-grade teacher from Wilmington, N. C., said Jennings' demeanor ``gave your viewers a sense of peace, that everything would eventually be better than it was at that moment'' and helped ``explain the unexplainable to our children.''</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="1" Score="44.72255067567568">&quot;This will probably be a momentous year for network news,&quot; says Michael Castengera, a lecturer at the University of Georgia's Grady College of Journalism and an independent media consultant.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="2" Score="44.57297297297297">&quot;Everybody is rallying around Peter, and we are here to help him get through this and beat this.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="10" Score="44.54594594594595">``I was thinking back to when Betty Ford first went public with her breast cancer, and what a difference that made,'' Brace said.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="8" Score="43.31743508214097">``This is a body blow to ABC and to aficionados of evening news,'' he said.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="6" Score="42.63513513513514">At the time, ABC said Jennings had a severe upper respiratory infection, and the network sent Diane Sawyer.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="5" Score="42.57166257166257">``For Peter not to be there for the pope truly did leave everyone saying there must be something terribly wrong.''</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="6" Score="42.43243243243243">``Almost 10 million Americans are living with cancer.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="7" Score="42.27777777777778">After the long goodbye of NBC's Tom Brokaw (who served from 1983 until December), and the forced retirement of CBS' besieged Dan Rather (in harness from 1981 until March), the departure of the 66-year-old Jennings (sole anchor since 1978) would complete a clean sweep of the venerable troika from the erstwhile Big Three.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="10" Score="41.91539365452409">In a note, Specter told the anchorman, ``the only way to get through chemo is to work your way through it.''</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="7" Score="41.833333333333336">Cronkite had to wait until 1962 before taking the reins of ``The CBS Evening News'' away from Douglas Edwards, but 1963 was his breakout year.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="2" Score="41.832046332046325">The dramatic news - which comes on the heels of last week's announcement that &quot;Nightline&quot; host Ted Koppel will leave at year's end and which follows the recent departures of CBS and NBC anchors Dan Rather and Tom Brokaw - reinforces the idea that a chapter in television journalism is coming to an end.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="2" Score="41.66189719130895">Schneider said the diagnosis has not caused the network to focus more intently on the Jennings succession.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="8" Score="41.60875160875161">Viewer after viewer cited Jennings' handling of coverage of the Sept. 11 attacks as a welcome balm during a horrific day.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="8" Score="41.3993993993994">``Please take the time to now look out for yourself.''</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="8" Score="41.24513987671883">But TV news veterans said the network must consider who will take over if Jennings is unable to continue.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="5" Score="41.11404586404587">A younger generation of anchors mostly lacks that depth of experience -- Jennings as a Middle East-based correspondent for seven years, Rather as a White House correspondent and ``60 Minutes'' contributor, Brokaw as a White House reporter and ``Today'' host.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="10" Score="41.0">Lung cancer.'</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="3" Score="40.624917600527354">But the network, which has seen the recent replacement of anchors at NBC and CBS as an opportunity for Jennings to vault into the ratings leadership, is planning to use substitute anchors, including Charles Gibson and Elizabeth Vargas, in his absence.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="6" Score="40.51258154706431">He broke the news to his senior staff at ``World News Tonight'' in an e-mail Tuesday morning, saying he hoped to continue to anchor throughout his treatment.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="5" Score="40.4944944944945">Because of his limited education, Jones said, ``he took that spot as anchor with some trepidation.''</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="6" Score="40.08225616921269">Another television veteran, Ted Koppel, announced last week that he was leaving ABC and ``Nightline'' at the end of the year.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="4" Score="40.02111486486486">There are effective ways to treat lung cancer, but its mortality rate is so high because so many patients aren't diagnosed until their disease is in an advanced stage, Connery said.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="5" Score="39.773727215587684">Jennings, Rather and Brokaw once dominated the media landscape, to a degree unimaginable today, because beginning in the early 1980s they reached about half the television audience, unchallenged by cable news -- then in its infancy -- or talk radio or the Internet.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="6" Score="39.57990599294947">The 66-year-old newsman, who smoked when he was younger, had been feeling ill during the last several days and was diagnosed Monday afternoon.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="2" Score="39.487661574618095">Until now, there has not been much public discussion about an eventual successor to Jennings, who has worked at ABC News since 1964.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="4" Score="39.36330561330561">Doctors said most lung cancer patients can continue to work throughout treatment, but need flexibility to take it easy on days they are not feeling well.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="8" Score="39.08892763731474">``Our old and trusted friend, you have looked out for all of us for so long, and comforted us in our time of need,'' wrote Peggi and Ron Barratt.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="5" Score="39.034628378378386">The son of a Canadian broadcaster, Jennings got dual U.S. citizenship after the 2001 terrorist attacks.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="8" Score="38.90810810810811">But transferring viewer affection to new anchors is not a simple matter, media experts said.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="5" Score="38.32538420773715">Koppel, who plans to leave ABC in December over plans to make ``Nightline'' a live, hour-long broadcast, has filled in for Jennings but never expressed interest in being a permanent evening anchor.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="8" Score="38.23294723294723">``It signals the transition that ABC inevitably is going to have to make,'' said Charles Bierbauer, a former CNN and ABC correspondent who serves as dean of the University of South Carolina's College of Mass Communications and Information Studies.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="5" Score="38.20960960960961">Westin said Charlie Gibson, Elizabeth Vargas and others would fill in for Jennings when necessary.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="5" Score="38.02297297297297">ABC, despite a stable of high-priced stars like Koppel and Barbara Walters, never groomed an obvious young successor to Jennings.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="5" Score="37.95220830586685">Norman Edelman, chief medical officer of the American Lung Association, said a decision by patients not to seek surgery for lung cancer ``suggests they believe it's already spread to a point where surgery does not offer a cure.''</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="10" Score="37.52792792792793">Vargas and Charles Gibson, co-host of ``Good Morning America,'' have substituted for him.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="8" Score="37.31941031941032">CBS Chairman and Chief Executive Leslie Moonves has called the traditional ``voice of God'' anchor an antiquated concept and suggested that his network may roll out a more irreverent, multi-anchor format.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="4" Score="37.195945945945944">&quot;On good days, my voice will not always be like this.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="6" Score="37.11556383970177">``He's already bringing to this new challenge the courage and strength we've seen so often in his reporting from the field and in anchoring ABC News.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="4" Score="36.833976833976834">&quot;I know that all of us will give him every bit of support that he needs and asks for.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="5" Score="36.309309309309306">If it's already spread, then surgery is not an option.''</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="8" Score="36.120393120393125">``Nights when they don't see him physically on the air, they know his steady hand is on the tiller.''</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="7" Score="36.09375">Cronkite's iconic bearing of the bad news (``From Dallas, Texas, a flash, apparently official.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="9" Score="35.975">But if ABC News makes any long-term strategic or personnel moves, including grooming a successor for the anchor chair, it could appear to be preparing for a future without Jennings, who, at 66, maybe the news network's biggest star.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="5" Score="35.936036036036036">But, the staffer added, ``this is a man who will have no time and no patience for pity.''</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="8" Score="35.812312312312315">``We have these really intense, interpersonal connections with these stars.''</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="3" Score="35.66795366795366">Lung cancer is usually difficult to treat.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="8" Score="35.5985985985986">``Those days are over where you have that guy sitting behind the desk that everybody believes to the nth degree,'' he told reporters in January.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="6" Score="35.57432432432432">``Hundreds of you have been like family.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="1" Score="35.52464228934817">In Rather's absence, CBS executives have discussed experimenting with the time-honored &quot;voice-of-God,&quot; single-anchor format.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="8" Score="35.38">``The illusion that television has created is that we experience events, and the people that bring us through, that are our guides, are the network anchors,'' said Gary Edgerton, a professor at Old Dominion University in Norfolk, Va., and co-editor of the Journal of Popular Film and Television.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="4" Score="35.10810810810811">&quot;I think it says you shouldn't stop your life if you have cancer.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="7" Score="35.07352941176471">The anchor's roots reach back to the birth of modern broadcast journalism in 1938, when CBS Radio launched its ``World News Roundup'' just in time to track Hitler marauding across Europe.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="4" Score="34.74903474903475">Certainly, it's been a long time.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="8" Score="34.62162162162162">``These are the type of interactions that have to be developed over time,'' said Jeffrey McCall, a professor of communications at Depauw University in Greencastle, Ind., who noted that competitive pressures from all-news cable channels, the Internet and other news sources limit the amount of time new anchors have to bond with their audiences.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="8" Score="33.88888888888889">``Life won't be the same till you're back in the living rooms of America every night,'' wrote a woman identified as Marilyn L.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="8" Score="33.82782782782783">But Robert Zelnick, chairman of Boston University's Department of Journalism and a former ABC News correspondent, said it would be hard to find an adequate replacement.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="10" Score="33.65878378378379">The 66-year-old anchorman had announced on April 6 that he was diagnosed with the disease and shortly thereafter began treatment.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="9" Score="33.55">With estimated annual advertising revenue of more than $100 million, &quot;World News Tonight&quot; is big business for ABC.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="7" Score="33.34615384615385">Murrow, of course, was the prototype for this new breed of broadcast journalist.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="2" Score="32.687818253035644">&quot;Overall, we're still having a hard time with it, mainly because we're not finding it in an early phase.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="8" Score="32.47837837837838">Viewer reaction to his illness underscored the challenge facing the networks as they usher in a new generation of evening news anchors: replicating the strong bonds that have developed between audiences and the iconic faces of ABC, NBC and CBS.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="2" Score="32.43363363363363">Westin wrote that the anchor would undergo outpatient treatment in New York and that &quot;we should also expect him to be off the broadcast from time to time.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="4" Score="32.244932432432435">Lung cancer is the leading cancer killer in the United States, and roughly four out of five people diagnosed with the disease die within five years, said Dr. Cliff Connery, chief of thoracic surgery at St. Luke's-Roosevelt Hospital in Manhattan.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="4" Score="32.22972972972973">I'm counting on him getting through this very difficult passage.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="3" Score="31.917631917631915">Certainly, it's been a long time.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="9" Score="31.8">If Westin continues to simply patch together a lineup of substitute anchors while waiting for Jennings to recover his health, the network could squander the momentum it has already generated.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="8" Score="31.710178263369755">``I think it's a mistake for anybody to think anchors are no longer as important as they once were, because when there's a crisis in America, or affecting America, people turn to someone they trust,'' said Dean, who worked at CBS and ABC.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="9" Score="31.38095238095238">&quot;Quite frankly, I think some of my colleagues might be surprised at how he's getting involved in scripts.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="10" Score="31.373310810810814">``Yesterday, I decided to go to the office; I live only a few blocks away.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="8" Score="31.274365274365277">He's been such a big part of our lives.''</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="5" Score="31.015615615615616">Although the five-year survival rate for men with operable lung cancer is 45 percent, he said, it is under 14 percent for more advanced cancer that cannot be removed.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="5" Score="30.926685305995655">He's already bringing to this new challenge the courage and strength we've seen so often in his reporting from the field and in anchoring ABC News.''</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="5" Score="30.70128022759602">I will continue to do the broadcast; on good days my voice will not always be like this.''</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="5" Score="30.418378378378378">He added: ``There will be good days and bad, which means that some days I may be cranky and some days really cranky!''</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="9" Score="30.142857142857142">&quot;There is a constant stream of big decisions coming down the road.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="1" Score="30.12039312039312">Once the main source of news for TV watchers, these network anchors have lost viewers over the past decade because of the proliferation of alternate news resources on cable TV and the Internet.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="10" Score="29.65818759936407">People think, `If he can go public with his employers about his cancer, maybe I can, too.'</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="5" Score="29.522522522522525">Still, ``chemotherapy can absolutely prolong life,'' said Edelman, who teaches at the State University of New York at Stony Brook.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="7" Score="29.482758620689655">Like Murrow, Cronkite spent his capital carefully, trading on his cheerleading for NASA to cover his flanks when he turned against the Vietnam War after the 1968 Tet offensive.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="8" Score="29.422037422037427">``I've been walking around for days feeling a lump of sadness.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="3" Score="28.052052052052048">He quit at that time, though the colleagues said it was an enormous struggle for him and periodically he was known to sneak a cigarette or two.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="4" Score="28.02825552825553">The 66-year-old anchor was too ill to work Saturday during the network's special report on Pope John Paul II's death.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="10" Score="27.97972972972973">``So many experiences have meant something special.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="8" Score="27.884551217884553">But he was unable to deliver the news last week because of a hoarse voice, and it remains unclear how frequently he will be on the air.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="10" Score="27.56418918918919">I got as far as the bedroom door.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="1" Score="27.446985446985448">&quot;As the struggle continues to win viewers, people at very high levels at the networks are going to have to make some tough decisions.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="8" Score="27.111111111111114">``They can't afford to let whoever takes over the time to grow into the role.''</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="2" Score="27.04599336178283">At CBS, Rather's announcement last November that he would step down, which followed a furor over the flawed &quot;60 Minutes Wednesday&quot; report on President Bush's military record, left that network scrambling for a successor.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="4" Score="26.91891891891892">It may take your life, but you shouldn't let it control your life.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="5" Score="26.722972972972975">Jennings was the first to establish a television bureau in the Middle East and one of three western journalists to witness Saddam Hussein's first appearance in an Iraqi court last year.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="1" Score="26.594594594594597">Steve Murray writes for The Atlanta Journal-Constitution.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="2" Score="26.43843843843844">(For the week that ended April 1, ABC's newscast averaged almost 9.5 million viewers, compared with 10 million for NBC.)</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="7" Score="26.4">During the TV coverage of the 1952 presidential conventions, CBS News President Sig Mickelson coined the term ``anchorman'' for his primary on-air reporter.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="6" Score="26.39517896274653">His illness may sideline, at least temporarily, one of the last remaining lions of network news, coming on the heels of the departures of NBC anchor Tom Brokaw and CBS anchor Dan Rather from their evening newscasts.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="7" Score="26.224137931034484">The dinnertime newscast -- once de rigueur from coast to coast -- became a missable feast for Americans who had been munching all day on cable and the Internet.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="8" Score="26.09342676009343">ABC's Web site was flooded with emotional testimonials from people about his effect on their lives, many referring to him as a member of the family.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="6" Score="26.016451233842538">Jennings has won 14 national Emmys, several Alfred I. duPont-Columbia University awards, several Overseas Press Club awards and a George Foster Peabody award.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="6" Score="25.98280098280098">I am sure I will learn from them how to cope with the facts of life that none of us anticipated.''</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="3" Score="25.85328185328185">I will continue to do the broadcast.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="8" Score="25.702009702009704">A Cincinnati viewer wrote that ``when the nation circles its wagons, you are the wagon master that provides us with a sense of calm.''</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="4" Score="25.675675675675677">And I hope it goes without saying that a journalist who doesn't value _ deeply _ the audience's loyalty should be in another line of work.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="3" Score="25.54798276537407">At one point, Jennings and his executive producer then, Paul Friedman, visited a hypnotist in Boston seeking to break their addictions to cigarettes.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="6" Score="25.429975429975432">It feels good to have such a family right now.''</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="10" Score="25.090733590733592">``Do I detect a knowing but sympathetic smile on many of your faces?</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="8" Score="25.02948402948403">NBC eased the transition from Tom Brokaw to Brian Williams in December by announcing the move two years ahead of time and giving viewers ample opportunities to watch Williams as a substitute anchor.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="4" Score="24.912816041848302">&quot;His manner of news delivery stood in contrast to but not in opposition of the gentle Midwestern aesthetic expressed by Tom Brokaw and the don't-mess-with-Texas eccentricity of Dan Rather.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="7" Score="24.833333333333336">As an anchor, Murrow was a bit of a bust, but another candidate was waiting in the wings.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="5" Score="24.823977823977824">``Good Morning America'' co-host Diane Sawyer, as well as Gibson, would be part of any shortlist, but both seem happy with their current situations.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="10" Score="24.447635135135137">``Whenever someone like that goes public, it gives others permission to talk about their cancers.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="10" Score="24.37837837837838">He tells me, as have many others, that when it gets really bad, it will get better.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="5" Score="24.1975051975052">NBC planned best for the inevitable succession, anointing Brian Williams, 45, who has held onto the ratings lead, 21/2 years before he took over in December.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="3" Score="23.88319353836595">And I hope it goes without saying that a journalist who doesn't value -- deeply -- the audience's loyalty should be in another line of work.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="2" Score="23.865683865683863">I am sure I will learn from them how to cope with the facts of life that none of us anticipated.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="4" Score="23.771498771498774">He hasn't been feeling well the past few months, and didn't travel under doctor's orders after December's tsunami because of what was described then as an upper respiratory infection.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="1" Score="23.673218673218674">I am sure I will learn from them how to cope with the facts of life that none of us anticipated.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="10" Score="23.673218673218674">``This does give people a way to say, `Me too.'</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="5" Score="23.66891891891892">He also anchored the New Year's Eve broadcast at the turn of the millennium that won a Peabody Award.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="4" Score="23.594594594594593">NBC's Tom Brokaw stepped down last year and CBS' Dan Rather left last month.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="5" Score="23.439864864864866">By the time newer and faster technological rivals, including bloggers who often criticized them, came on the scene, the Big Three anchors were well-established figures from having chronicled so many national and global stories, from war to impeachment to terrorism.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="5" Score="23.123552123552127">Obviously this is an emotional day here.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="6" Score="23.006756756756758">And he stayed back from Asia after the disastrous tsunami in December.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="2" Score="22.98069498069498">In terms of the chemotherapy stopping him, most people do work through chemotherapy.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="5" Score="22.974190406622842">This was always a man who had a more graceful humor and air of sophistication, which came from his days as a foreign correspondent when he looked like something from a 1940s movie, handsome and dashing.''</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="5" Score="22.92854217854218">This is either because the cancer is at too advanced a stage or because it is a form called small-cell cancer -- which occurs in about a quarter of such cases -- and has already spread to other parts of the body, he said.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="8" Score="22.704247104247106">By the end of the week, more than 3,400 e-mails offering him prayers and good wishes had filled the network's online message board -- many of them expressing an intensely personal sense of grief.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="3" Score="22.44389844389844">On good days, my voice will not always be like this.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="2" Score="22.34234234234234">&quot;You really wonder, if given this kind of narrowcasting environment, we'll ever see people of this iconic stature again in the news business.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="6" Score="22.147937411095306">I know that all of us will give him every bit of support that he needs and asks for.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="8" Score="21.92702702702703">But TV news correspondent and anchor Morton Dean dismissed the idea that audiences no longer seek that kind of relationship.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="6" Score="21.89189189189189">He begins treatment in New York next week.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="5" Score="21.74856674856675">I am sure I will learn from them how to cope with the facts of life that none of us anticipated.''</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="3" Score="21.28728728728729">While the prognosis depends on the type of lung cancer, the overall cure rate is just 16 percent.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="5" Score="21.155686936936938">In a videotaped message, he disclosed the diagnosis in a raspy voice, saying, ``Yes, I was a smoker until about 20 years ago, and I was weak and smoked over 9/11.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="5" Score="20.767567567567568">Vargas is viewed as a rising star within the network.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="9" Score="20.357142857142858">He was in regular e-mail contact with Westin; Jonathan Banner, the program's executive producer; and others, going so far as to comment on scripts for upcoming shows.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="7" Score="20.274193548387096">Over the years, American anchormen derived their authoritative profile less from anything they did than from the simple fact of prolonged exposure, repeated ceremonially for years, in a hegemonic media environment.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="5" Score="19.972543972543974">He was the courtliest of the Big Three anchors, the most frequently married -- four times -- and the least self-promotional.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="1" Score="19.945945945945947">NBC's Tom Brokaw signed off in December.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="8" Score="19.921171171171174">When he can't, he still plans to exert a strong force in shaping the newscast.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="1" Score="19.835135135135133">Dan Rather left his desk at CBS a month ago.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="4" Score="19.8">He returned to the desk in 1978 when third-place ABC tried a multi-anchor format, which was abandoned in 1983 when Frank Reynolds died from cancer.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="5" Score="19.775000000000002">CBS had no replacement ready when Rather, under pressure from his botching of the story about President Bush's military service, stepped down last month, although Bob Schieffer, 68, has won praise as interim anchor for his more conversational style.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="2" Score="19.755334281650068">NBC completed a lengthy and smoothly choreographed transition in December when Brian Williams succeeded Brokaw in the anchor chair.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="2" Score="19.689189189189186">At the time, ABC insiders thought he was battling a lingering flu or a similar ailment.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="5" Score="19.487773487773488">The National Cancer Institute says that we are survivors from the moment of diagnosis.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="4" Score="19.33783783783784">He did go to Iraq in January for the elections.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="5" Score="19.181602655286866">They have been losing audience share for two decades but still reach 30 million people with their evening newscasts.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="7" Score="18.954545454545453">...'') has long since become audiovisual shorthand for the moment of impact: pulling off his glasses, choking up, stoically going forward.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="5" Score="18.861611611611615">Some in the industry had been sniping at him for not going to Asia to cover the tsunami and not anchoring coverage of the pope's final hours Friday and Saturday or heading off to Rome.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="7" Score="18.833333333333332">(From their high-water mark in the late 1960s, ratings for the network newscasts have plummeted by 60 percent.)</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="7" Score="18.72972972972973">In 1981, the same year that Rather edged out the eminence gris, a more significant milestone in the annals of anchordom appeared on screen: CNN, the beginning of 24-hour news and the end of the networks' monopoly.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="7" Score="18.55263157894737">Tellingly, the most traumatic day in U.S. broadcasting history -- 9/11 -- bequeathed no equivalent to Cronkite's JFK moment: The images of disaster are indelible, but no face, gesture or remark from a single newscaster stands out.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="7" Score="18.375">Closing out the night watch, his signature sign-off sounds like a benediction.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="3" Score="18.35263835263835">He later quit again, a colleague said.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="5" Score="18.324324324324326">I wonder if other men and women ask their doctors right away, `OK, Doc, when does the hair go?'''</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="7" Score="18.0">Anchorman: The very word suggests security and gravitas.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="10" Score="17.920782851817336">Instinctively, immediately, we gave each other a hug -- a real hug -- and went on our respective ways knowing that we had been strengthened by the connection.''</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="9" Score="17.782608695652176">One morning last week, he even participated via conference call in the program's 9 a.m. editorial meeting, his voice hoarse but strong.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="2" Score="17.734234234234233">The announcement Tuesday seemed to stun the network.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="10" Score="17.496443812233284">A middle-aged couple was going into the building and as they passed me, I heard my name and turned.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="5" Score="17.11053361053361">And the evening news franchise itself, less lucrative than the popular morning shows, is often derided as an anachronism with an aging core of loyal viewers.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="7" Score="16.653846153846153">Yet it also is hard not to get a little sentimental over the end of a tradition that well-served the news, and, on occasion, the nation.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="2" Score="16.639165481270744">Veteran correspondent Bob Schieffer was picked to fill the slot on an interim basis when Rather departed last month.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="8" Score="16.486486486486488">Some executives actually view the turnover as an opportunity to radically remake the broadcasts in hopes of appealing to a younger demographic.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="10" Score="16.28066528066528">A woman in my building who is a cancer survivor showed up at my front door so that we could see that bald really is beautiful.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="6" Score="16.266891891891895">Times staff writers Scott Collins and Mary MacVean contributed to this report.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="6" Score="16.25307125307125">A network spokeswoman declined to identify the location, citing his privacy.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="7" Score="16.147058823529413">By the 1990s, from the Gulf War through O.J.-TV to the massacre at Columbine High School, a multiplicity of news options and a dizzying cast of faces were available to bear the bad tidings.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="7" Score="15.903225806451612">When he moved from radio to TV, his visible presence only intensified the emotional link: the movie star looks, the patrician manner, the cigarette smoke swirling around his head like incense.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="7" Score="15.75">Serious but sympathetic, the timbre of his voice is a firm tenor or a stentorian baritone, perhaps a bit tense in dire straits, but never panicky.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="8" Score="15.560929350403034">CBS tapped a veteran newsman, Bob Schieffer, to temporarily replace Dan Rather when he left the newscast last month.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="8" Score="15.282711282711285">A college student wrote that she never misses his broadcasts and that she used to watch it nightly with her father.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="10" Score="15.00982800982801">The woman stepped right in my face and said, `Me too.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="7" Score="14.931034482758621">In this sense, it is hard to lament the transfer of power from the great and powerful men in front of the curtain to every munchkin with a modem.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="7" Score="14.90625">The anchor was always careful not to run too far ahead of his Nielsen demographic -- maybe a few feet ahead of the fashion curve, but never out on the cutting edge.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="5" Score="14.761261261261263">But whatever the reason, the news does slow you down a bit.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="7" Score="14.25">That September, first CBS and then NBC expanded their news broadcasts from 15 minutes to 30.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="7" Score="14.142857142857142">The man Mickelson picked was Walter Cronkite.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="5" Score="13.997747747747749">He often described himself as a terrible interview.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="3" Score="13.852252252252251">Sixty percent of lung cancer patients die within a year of diagnosis, and nearly 75 percent die within two years.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="7" Score="13.161290322580646">Even more significant, it would mark the end of a special kind of personality-driven news experience -- the last unique legacy (reruns not included) of the classic age of broadcast television.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="5" Score="12.797940797940798">Vargas got the last-minute call Tuesday night.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="5" Score="12.698435277382645">Nine in 10 lung cancer cases are related to smoking, and a diminishing risk continues even after someone quits.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="8" Score="12.537871204537872">The audience for the three major evening newscasts has shrunk considerably amid growing competition, yet they still combine to attract upward of 26 million people each weeknight.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="7" Score="11.772727272727273">The declamatory style of the town-crier announcer (familiar as the so-called Voice of God in the Hollywood newsreels) soon gave way to a new reportorial model in which the journalist became a commentator as well, guiding the listener through strange doings and complex geopolitics.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="9" Score="11.25">Westin faces a far bigger dilemma in the long run.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="7" Score="11.115384615384615">Then, over a vertiginous four days that November, the Kennedy assassination sent millions of Americans to the anchor to calm their nerves and soothe their souls.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="7" Score="10.821428571428571">On March 9, 1954, when Murrow delivered a slashing broadside at Sen. Joseph McCarthy, he was cashing in a lifetime of moral capital accrued from Munich to Panmunjom.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="1" Score="10.748648648648649">Born in Toronto, he became a U.S. citizen in 2003.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="2" Score="9.528351881293057">Others likely to fill in include chief White House correspondent Terry Moran and network correspondent Bob Woodruff.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="3" Score="8.739798622151563">He did tape a brief commentary to close the newscast, speaking in a hoarse and strained voice.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="10" Score="7.018018018018018">It also offers encouragement and courage.</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="1" Score="5.171171171171172">E-mail: stmurray@ajc.com</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="5" Score="3.0540540540540544">...</sentence>
		<sentence DocIndex="5" Score="3.0540540540540544">...</sentence>
	</Sentences>
</Topic>
