<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<Topic id="D0906B">
	<Sentences>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="18.529411764705884" PS="2.476027397260274" SM="49">As stormy weather continued to pound Southern California on Saturday, about 170 people were freed from cars near Big Bear where they had been trapped for up to 15 hours in deep snow, several of the state's major arteries were closed and rescue workers pulled two people from raging streams.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="13.761904761904763" PS="1.6506849315068495" SM="3">Serious concerns remained about how the water-logged region would hold up with storms expected to continue at least through Sunday evening.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="19.6875" PS="1.1004566210045663" SM="14">Although there appeared to be no major flooding or mudslides, the day was not without drama.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="10.36111111111111" PS="1.6506849315068495" SM="59">Rescue workers used snowplows, snowcats and snowmobiles to free people from a 6-mile stretch of California Highway 18 in the San Bernardino Mountains after a combination of snow, rain, sleet and fog created a 200-vehicle logjam.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="14.210526315789474" PS="1.1004566210045663" SM="15">Although many of those stuck along the route spent the night in their cars, there were no major injuries.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="8.368421052631579" PS="1.6506849315068495" SM="0">In Rosemead, rescuers plucked a woman from a wash after water carried her nearly a quarter of a mile.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="12.4" PS="1.1004566210045663" SM="1">San Bernardino County firefighters used a bulldozer to rescue a man from a swollen waterway.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="17.0" PS="1.1004566210045663" SM="14">Several of the state's major arteries were closed because of snow, rock slides and weather-related accidents.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="17.571428571428573" PS="1.6506849315068495" SM="13">Cities along the coast received from 1 to 4 inches of rain, while mountain regions reported as much as 8 inches.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="17.6" PS="1.6506849315068495" SM="48">The California Highway Patrol reported 430 accidents as of 6 p.m. in Southern California -- double last Saturday's total for the same time period.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="10.9" PS="1.6506849315068495" SM="11">Forecasters expected rain to continue most of Sunday before diminishing.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="18.115384615384617" PS="1.1004566210045663" SM="36">A flood watch remained in effect for Los Angeles, Orange, San Diego, Santa Barbara and Ventura counties, and flash flood warnings remained for San Bernardino County.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="4.380952380952381" PS="1.6506849315068495" SM="25">Times staff writers Jason Felch, Jack Leonard, David Pierson and Joel Rubin and staff photographer Rob Gauthier contributed to this report.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="17.29268292682927" PS="2.578767123287671" SM="70">A fourth day of thrashing thunderstorms began to take a heavier toll on southern California on Sunday with at least three deaths blamed on the rain, as flooding and mudslides forced road closures and emergency crews carried out harrowing rescue operations.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="12.5" PS="1.7191780821917808" SM="23">In Elysian Park, just north of downtown, a 42-year-old homeless man was killed and another injured when a mudslide swept away their makeshift encampment.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="18.076923076923077" PS="1.1461187214611872" SM="25">Another man was killed on Pacific Coast Highway in Malibu when his sport utility vehicle skidded into a mud patch and plunged into the Pacific Ocean.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="9.275862068965518" PS="1.1461187214611872" SM="2">Ventura County officials reported Sunday that a 20-year-old man died north of Ojai as he tried to cross a rain-gorged creek Saturday, wearing a harness attached to a wire.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="24.22222222222222" PS="1.7191780821917808" SM="0">For others, it was a day of close calls.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="11.416666666666666" PS="1.7191780821917808" SM="1">Dozens of people fled threatened neighborhoods from Santa Clarita to San Dimas.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="9.736842105263158" PS="1.1461187214611872" SM="13">In the Hollywood Hills, a family narrowly survived as their two-story home collapsed, apparently in a torrent of mud.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="7.75" PS="1.1461187214611872" SM="0">Hundreds of motorists skidded into minor traffic accidents.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="15.482758620689655" PS="1.7191780821917808" SM="13">Unresolved Sunday was the fate of a Highland man who remained stranded but safe in a San Bernardino County cave as raging waters outside prevented rescuers from reaching him.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="19.25" PS="1.1461187214611872" SM="7">``The only way to get to the cave is to cross this water, (but) it's flowing too heavily.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="26.38888888888889" PS="1.1461187214611872" SM="2">It's too dangerous,'' said Cindy Beavers, a spokeswoman for the San Bernardino County Sheriff's Department.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="19.128205128205128" PS="1.7191780821917808" SM="8">The storms had stalled over an area of the Pacific Ocean on Sunday evening, a few hundred miles off the coast of Point Conception, west of Santa Barbara, said Bruce Rockwell, a weather specialist with the National Weather Service.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="27.31578947368421" PS="1.7191780821917808" SM="27">``It's stationary off the coast and constantly pumps in moist water from the south,'' he said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="20.4" PS="1.7191780821917808" SM="24">Forecasters had originally said some areas of southern California might receive more than 20 inches of precipitation over the weekend.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="7.333333333333333" PS="1.1461187214611872" SM="12">Although they later reduced that estimate, a campground near Mount Wilson, Opids Camp, received 20.8 inches of precipitation just between 4 p.m. Saturday and 4 p.m. Sunday.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="14.516129032258064" PS="1.7191780821917808" SM="22">In that same time period, downtown Los Angeles received 4.5 inches of rain, Beverly Hills 7.8 inches, Santa Monica 4.7 inches, Chatsworth 5.8 inches, Claremont 7.5 inches and Lancaster 2.4 inches.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="21.833333333333332" PS="1.7191780821917808" SM="7">Continued downpours were expected through Tuesday, when the jet stream airflow from the north was expected to start pushing the storm inland toward Nevada.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="11.666666666666666" PS="1.7191780821917808" SM="45">Southern California has been drenched by a string of storms that began in late December and have been only sporadically interrupted by clear skies.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="19.0" PS="1.7191780821917808" SM="4">The current dousing, which began Thursday, has been the heaviest.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="16.0" PS="1.1461187214611872" SM="36">On average, Los Angeles receives 18 inches of rain in the first six months of each year, but more than 15 inches have fallen in the first nine days of 2005.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="13.08695652173913" PS="1.7191780821917808" SM="14">All across the Southland, residents dealt with rockslides, debris flows, downed trees, power outages and mandatory evacuations, though there were few serious injuries.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="15.708333333333334" PS="1.7191780821917808" SM="48">Mudslides, a sinkhole and other water damage forced Metrolink and Amtrak to cancel some train routes serving Los Angeles and Ventura Counties on Monday.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="7.277777777777778" PS="1.7191780821917808" SM="47">In Orange County, a combination of storm runoff and big surf caused health officials to close Corona del Mar State Beach in Newport Beach and Capistrano County Beach in Dana Point because of sewage pipe leaks.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="12.846153846153847" PS="1.7191780821917808" SM="25">More than 300 miles away in the Eastern Sierra, skiers and snowboarders glided atop 48 inches of snow that has fallen on Mammoth Mountain since Friday.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="21.071428571428573" PS="1.1461187214611872" SM="0">``We've just been pounded,'' said Joani Lynch, a Mammoth Mountain spokeswoman.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="16.714285714285715" PS="1.1461187214611872" SM="11">Some ski runs were closed at Big Bear Mountain Resorts because of heavy rains.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="17.954545454545453" PS="1.7191780821917808" SM="26">In Los Angeles County, the Department of Water and Power reported thousands of power outages in homes from Echo Park to Bel-Air.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="14.925925925925926" PS="1.1461187214611872" SM="16">A rain-related accident on Mount Wilson tore down transmission lines, interrupting the broadcast of the Indianapolis Colts and Denver Broncos playoff game on KCBS for two hours.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="14.75" PS="1.7191780821917808" SM="46">And in Arcadia, eight of nine horse races at Santa Anita Park were canceled for the first time in 10 years because of rain.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="17.045454545454547" PS="1.1461187214611872" SM="13">``If it gets slippery, it could potentially be dangerous to horses, jockeys and all involved,'' said park spokesman Vince Bruun.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="17.88888888888889" PS="1.7191780821917808" SM="50">Heavy rain fell in other parts of California, but the storms in the Southland presented the biggest challenges.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="14.837837837837839" PS="1.7191780821917808" SM="28">The 42-year-old homeless man who died in Elysian Park had been living with a younger acquaintance in a tent on top of a hill on the 1700 block of Stadium Way, just north of the Pasadena Freeway.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="16.703703703703702" PS="1.7191780821917808" SM="3">The man, identified as Jeffrey Lynn Earwood, was trapped under hundreds of pounds of thick mud, according to Los Angles City Fire Department spokesman Brian Humphrey said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="23.307692307692307" PS="1.1461187214611872" SM="0">When rescue workers arrived, they said, only one of his limbs was visible.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="17.647058823529413" PS="1.1461187214611872" SM="13">Humphrey said firefighters dug him out in less than 10 minutes, but he died at the scene.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="24.88888888888889" PS="1.7191780821917808" SM="2">The other man, who was unidentified, received minor injuries.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="19.96" PS="1.7191780821917808" SM="43">The victim in the Malibu traffic accident died after the SUV he was traveling in skidded off the road in the 19700 block of PCH.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="22.789473684210527" PS="1.1461187214611872" SM="8">Los Angeles County fire rescue workers recovered the man's body about 500 feet from where the vehicle went into the water off Tuna Canyon Beach, said Lt. Randall Dickey of the Malibu Lost Hills Sheriff's Station.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="19.9" PS="1.7191780821917808" SM="13">Four passengers in the car sustained minor injuries, Dickey said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="19.22222222222222" PS="1.1461187214611872" SM="14">Names and ages of the victims were not released.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="15.263157894736842" PS="1.7191780821917808" SM="13">On Laurel Canyon Boulevard, three people were safe after their 5,000-square-foot house collapsed, apparently the result of a mudslide.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="16.9375" PS="1.1461187214611872" SM="4">An unidentified motorist helped the father pull his 5-year-old daughter out of the rubble, authorities said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="26.166666666666668" PS="1.1461187214611872" SM="2">Firefighters rescued the man's 10-year-son.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="27.857142857142858" PS="1.1461187214611872" SM="2">The family was hospitalized with minor injuries.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="22.428571428571427" PS="1.7191780821917808" SM="11">Humphrey said this was one of a number of areas where mudslides caused problems.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="18.22222222222222" PS="1.1461187214611872" SM="25">``Choose your street with `Canyon' in the name, and that likely has been impacted by mud.''</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="16.678571428571427" PS="1.7191780821917808" SM="13">Around 4 p.m., ``tons of mud'' from a hillside slid into the third floor of a home in Silver Lake, , trapping a man inside, he said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="16.375" PS="1.1461187214611872" SM="30">Firefighters had to break a window in the home in the 1900 block of North Lucile Avenue to reach the man, who was uninjured.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="18.77777777777778" PS="1.1461187214611872" SM="2">The fire department also evacuated three other nearby homes.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="24.17391304347826" PS="1.7191780821917808" SM="15">In Tujunga, five people were evacuated from the 6200 block of Gyral Drive after a mudslide near the Angeles National Forest, Humphrey said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="27.555555555555557" PS="1.1461187214611872" SM="0">No one was injured, though one house was damaged.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="18.916666666666668" PS="1.1461187214611872" SM="14">People in 15 houses farther down the street were advised to leave.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="19.27777777777778" PS="1.7191780821917808" SM="22">Humphrey estimated that more than 100 roads in Los Angeles had seen flooding or mudslides or downed trees.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="18.473684210526315" PS="1.1461187214611872" SM="27">``Most of the incidents are minor, and people do their civic duty with shovels in the mud.''</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="2.9642857142857144" PS="1.7191780821917808" SM="13">Times staff writers Nancy Cleeland, Erika Hayasaki, Daniel Hernandez, Fred Alvarez, David Reyes, Seema Mehta, Jennifer Mena, Terril Jones, Eric Bailey and Eric Slater contributed to this story.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="17.024390243902438" PS="2.476027397260274" SM="56">Los Angeles will get a much-needed break early Monday from the unforgiving rain that has pounded Southern California since Thursday, but a new front will move in Monday night, bringing with it an additional 2 inches to 4 inches of rain.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="14.12" PS="1.6506849315068495" SM="25">It will be the last storm at least for a while and forecasters say Southern Californians will see sunshine Tuesday, ending a wave of storms.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="13.9375" PS="1.1004566210045663" SM="69">The latest storm wave on Sunday alone dumped 4 1/2 inches of rain downtown, 6 inches in Burbank and Chatsworth, 3.29 inches in Woodland Hills and nearly 8 inches in Beverly Hills.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="20.04" PS="1.6506849315068495" SM="1">&quot;We'll begin to see some normalcy come back on Tuesday, but it's still winter,&quot; said National Weather Service meteorologist Bill Hoffer.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="17.444444444444443" PS="1.1004566210045663" SM="4">&quot;We should see clear to partly cloudy skies from Tuesday all the way out to Saturday.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="14.666666666666666" PS="1.6506849315068495" SM="49">While there might be blue skies on the horizon, the relentless storm system that has hovered over Southern California since Thursday caused massive flooding, mudslides, power outages, several evacuations, school closures and disrupted commuter rail service.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="15.933333333333334" PS="1.6506849315068495" SM="18">The heavy rainfall is being attributed to a sluggish, low-pressure system that collided with a stream of tropical moisture from the southern Pacific known as a &quot;Pineapple Express.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="13.02127659574468" PS="1.6506849315068495" SM="51">On the third consecutive day of heavy downpours Sunday, the skies dumped up to 2 inches of rain an hour in some areas -- turning some streets in hillside communities into raging rivers and stranding dozens of motorists who had to be rescued by overtaxed emergency workers.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="10.78048780487805" PS="1.6506849315068495" SM="23">At Sun Valley's infamous intersection -- San Fernando Road and Tuxford Street -- a swift-water rescue team plucked 20-year-old Amber Pitts from her car after she became stuck in as much as 4 feet of water at about 6 p.m.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="26.692307692307693" PS="1.6506849315068495" SM="2">&quot;It was the fourth rescue we have made at that intersection (Sunday).</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="31.307692307692307" PS="1.1004566210045663" SM="0">Luckily, she was OK,&quot; said Los Angeles Fire Department spokesman Brian Humphrey.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="19.3" PS="1.1004566210045663" SM="24">&quot;That intersection is always flooded when it rains, and some people decide to try to make it through.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="11.8" PS="1.6506849315068495" SM="15">In the Ventura County community of Bardsdale, just south of Fillmore, resident Doug Bofolo and his family had to evacuate their house just east of Highway 23 when a massive water flow overtook his property.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="44.8" PS="1.6506849315068495" SM="2">&quot;The water was chest-deep.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="39.666666666666664" PS="1.1004566210045663" SM="0">Everything was floating,&quot; Bofolo said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="12.833333333333334" PS="1.1004566210045663" SM="14">&quot;We've got a 5-foot block wall and we can't even see the top of it.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="19.083333333333332" PS="1.1004566210045663" SM="13">This is even worse than the flooding we got in 1969.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="16.7" PS="1.6506849315068495" SM="29">In Santa Clarita, residents of the Polynesian Mobile Home Park at San Fernando Road and Sierra Highway were evacuated when saturated hillsides and roadbeds gave way to the nonstop flooding.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="15.45" PS="1.6506849315068495" SM="26">Thirty engine companies, the Urban Search and Rescue teams and county lifeguards were deployed with more than 200 firefighters responding.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="33.25" PS="1.6506849315068495" SM="2">&quot;The whole (Santa Clarita) valley (was) on alert,&quot; Los Angeles County Fire Department Capt.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="26.571428571428573" PS="1.1004566210045663" SM="0">Dave Peterson said during Sunday's deluge.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="18.55" PS="1.6506849315068495" SM="15">The Fire Department reported flooding as high as second-story windows at cabins along Bouquet Canyon in the Angeles National Forest.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="15.619047619047619" PS="1.1004566210045663" SM="24">By midafternoon, department resources were stretched thin and there was not much more that could be done to hold back mudslides.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="19.6" PS="1.6506849315068495" SM="12">Flooding was reported at Bouquet Canyon Road and Vasquez Canyon Road, causing a road closure.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="18.93103448275862" PS="1.6506849315068495" SM="26">In Saugus, firefighters led a dozen people to high ground after they were stranded on San Francisquito Canyon Road by flooding and mudslides from the rain-swelled San Francisquito Creek.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="14.08695652173913" PS="1.6506849315068495" SM="27">Four adults and eight children were rescued by helicopter and taken to safety at a church at the mouth of San Francisquito Canyon.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="7.85" PS="1.6506849315068495" SM="27">Gary Brynjegard and sons Peter, 16, and Garrison, 13, of Castaic had headed into the canyon earlier to survey damage.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="15.555555555555555" PS="1.1004566210045663" SM="14">Brynjegard works for the Los Angeles Department of Water and Power, which operates two plants along winding, two-lane San Francisquito Canyon Road just north of Santa Clarita.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="20.0" PS="1.6506849315068495" SM="24">&quot;We drove up to look around, then saw a mudslide and I said, We better get out of here,&quot; Brynjegard said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="24.23076923076923" PS="1.1004566210045663" SM="2">&quot;We ran like crazy; the mountains were sliding down around us.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="15.857142857142858" PS="1.6506849315068495" SM="3">In Fillmore, 145 people had to be evacuated from the El Dorado Mobile Home Park, where floodwaters began breaching their homes.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="14.928571428571429" PS="1.6506849315068495" SM="47">A mudslide closed Highway 126 between Fillmore and Piru, and Highway 23 between Fillmore and Moorpark was closed by a massive water flow that was a quarter-mile wide.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="17.685714285714287" PS="1.6506849315068495" SM="59">Emergency notifications in Ventura County indicated that all schools in the Fillmore Unified School District would be closed Monday, and Metrolink said its Ventura County line will be closed Monday because of flooding and mudslides.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="21.266666666666666" PS="1.6506849315068495" SM="0">Metrolink said its trains will not be operating from stations at Camarillo, Oxnard or Montalvo.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="9.428571428571429" PS="1.1004566210045663" SM="6">Passengers are being asked to go to the Oxnard station, where buses will be provided to take them to Moorpark station.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="19.405405405405407" PS="1.6506849315068495" SM="6">In Ventura, fire crews rescued six residents of the evacuated Emma Wood State Beach RV park who were trapped on a rock on the Santa Clara River bottom near the West Main Street Bridge on Sunday morning.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="17.652173913043477" PS="1.6506849315068495" SM="35">Elsewhere in Ventura County, Sheriff's Department officials reported flooding in the Arroyo Vista Mobile Home Park in Moorpark, where residents were evacuated.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="15.523809523809524" PS="1.6506849315068495" SM="11">Late Saturday, a man drowned after being washed away by a swollen river north of Ojai in Ventura County, officials said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="17.94736842105263" PS="1.6506849315068495" SM="36">Sunday was a long day for L.A. city and county firefighters, who responded to numerous mudslides, collapses and rescues.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="8.818181818181818" PS="1.6506849315068495" SM="45">A mudslide in Elysian Park buried a makeshift homeless encampment, killing one man and injuring another while they slept in a tent.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="16.555555555555557" PS="1.1004566210045663" SM="23">One person died and four people were hurt in a single-car crash on Pacific Coast Highway near Malibu.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="17.433333333333334" PS="1.6506849315068495" SM="41">A two-story home collapsed in the Studio City area above the San Fernando Valley, and a 33-year-old man and his two children were pulled from the rubble with minor injuries.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="16.80952380952381" PS="1.1004566210045663" SM="27">Fire officials said the house rolled down the hill and collapsed into a pile of debris in a matter of seconds.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="15.625" PS="1.6506849315068495" SM="50">The rain caused a hillside to give way in the 6200 block of Gyral Drive in Sunland, damaging a home and prompting authorities to evacuate five people from three residences, Humphrey said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="17.323529411764707" PS="1.6506849315068495" SM="63">And in Los Feliz, a man was rescued from a three-story home built into a hillside in the 1900 block of Lucille Drive when a mudslide overran the patio and flowed into the house.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="32.888888888888886" PS="1.6506849315068495" SM="13">The roads in Los Angeles County were equally frustrating.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="22.8" PS="1.1004566210045663" SM="14">Dozens of roads and highways were closed throughout the day.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="12.115384615384615" PS="1.1004566210045663" SM="27">Authorities reported scores of traffic crashes and ordered scattered road closings, including the southbound side of Interstate 5 at the Pasadena Freeway because of a mudslide.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="10.88888888888889" PS="1.6506849315068495" SM="25">In Malibu, a rain-related, single-vehicle crash in the 19700 block of Pacific Coast Highway left a man dead and four other people injured just before 8 a.m.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="21.61111111111111" PS="1.1004566210045663" SM="17">The vehicle ended up in the ocean, said sheriff's Lt. Randall Dickey of the Malibu-Lost Hills station.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="25.272727272727273" PS="1.1004566210045663" SM="4">The conditions of the four other people were not immediately known.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="11.173913043478262" PS="1.6506849315068495" SM="17">The storm drew a number of curious Southlanders out to hard-hit canyon areas, further complicating the work of firefighters and other rescue workers.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="15.7" PS="1.1004566210045663" SM="5">Humphrey urged people to stay off the roads if they can over the next day or two of wet weather.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="29.85" PS="1.6506849315068495" SM="2">&quot;Many people have been found sightseeing,&quot; which Humphrey said was &quot;hampering the efforts of emergency officials.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="10.0" PS="1.6506849315068495" SM="0">As many as 12,000 DWP customers lost power Sunday morning.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="16.68421052631579" PS="1.1004566210045663" SM="2">Pacific Gas &amp; Electric spokesman David Eisenhauer said 11,000 customers remained without power, scattered throughout the company's service area.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="11.476190476190476" PS="1.1004566210045663" SM="44">Southern California Edison, which has 4.6 million customers in a 50,000-square-mile service area in five counties, reported only minor power outages.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="20.5" PS="1.6506849315068495" SM="6">Several Los Angeles-area radio stations were knocked off the air for hours Sunday after trouble with transmitters on Mount Wilson, which was assumed to be related to the stormy weather.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="8.9" PS="1.6506849315068495" SM="0">Monday, Topanga Elementary School at 141 N. Topanga Canyon Blvd.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="19.35" PS="1.1004566210045663" SM="13">in Topanga will be closed because of storm-related road damage, said Stephanie Brady of the Los Angeles Unified School District.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="31.7" PS="1.6506849315068495" SM="2">It was unknown when the school will reopen, she said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="13.083333333333334" PS="1.1004566210045663" SM="2">Parents seeking more information should contact the school or its Web site.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="14.81081081081081" PS="1.6506849315068495" SM="54">The storm wreaked havoc in Northern California and Nevada as well, piling snow deeper across the Sierra Nevada, stranding an Amtrak train, knocking out service at the Reno airport and shutting down major highways across the mountains.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="16.333333333333332" PS="1.6506849315068495" SM="17">Forecasters called the series of storms the snowiest in the Reno-Lake Tahoe area since 1916.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="16.92" PS="1.6506849315068495" SM="12">&quot;I've lived here for almost 40 years and I've never seen anything like it,&quot; Peter Walenta, 69, of Stateline said Sunday.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="12.633333333333333" PS="1.6506849315068495" SM="2">An avalanche knocked a 13-year-old boy from a ski lift at the Las Vegas Ski &amp; Snowboard Resort, 45 miles northwest of Las Vegas, said Clark County fire spokesman Bob Leinbach.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="15.074074074074074" PS="1.6506849315068495" SM="14">Forecasters extended a winter storm warning into Tuesday across the Sierra and parts of northern Nevada, where as much as 2 more feet of snow was expected.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="14.782608695652174" PS="1.1004566210045663" SM="41">The latest storm had left up to 6 1/2 feet of snow in the Sierra and 2 1/2 feet in the Reno area.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="6.083333333333333" PS="1.6506849315068495" SM="13">Carol Rock, Patricia Farrell Aidem and wire services contributed to this report.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="15.96551724137931" PS="2.5890410958904106" SM="59">Usually sunny southern California has  been whipped the past few days by storms that have killed at least  two and caused floods, mudslides, power blackouts and deadly traffic  accidents.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="23.393939393939394" PS="1.7260273972602738" SM="61">A man died and another was injured in Los Angeles' Elysian Park  when a hillside collapsed and buried the two in the tent in which  they were sleeping on Saturday night, officials said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="28.321428571428573" PS="1.7260273972602738" SM="19">The victims &quot;were sleeping in a tent at the top of the hill when  the hill gave way,&quot; Los Angeles Fire Department spokesman Brian  Humphrey said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="20.916666666666668" PS="1.7260273972602738" SM="28">In Malibu, on the Pacific coast, an accident caused by the rain  sent a car into the ocean, leaving one dead and four wounded.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="16.68" PS="1.7260273972602738" SM="37">A man and his two children were rescued from the rubble of their  hillside home in Studio City after it collapsed in a heavy  downpour.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="22.0" PS="1.7260273972602738" SM="3">The three were taken to hospital with minor injuries.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="17.75" PS="1.7260273972602738" SM="4">Residents of Santa Clarita had to be evacuated due to floods  while the Coldwater Canyon neighborhood of Los Angeles was strewn  with fallen trees.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="21.0" PS="1.7260273972602738" SM="50">The latest storm started Thursday and was predicted to continue  Monday with more rain and, in the mountains, snow.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="17.88235294117647" PS="1.7260273972602738" SM="24">Hundreds of cars were stranded in the snow in San Bernardino  National Forest, east of Los Angeles.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="33.3" PS="1.1506849315068493" SM="0">About 12,000 Los Angeles  residents were without power, officials said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="18.2" PS="1.7260273972602738" SM="3">&quot;This is something we only see about every five to 10 years,&quot;  National Weather Service Meteorologist Dan Keeton said of the  turbulent weather.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="15.62962962962963" PS="2.7123287671232874" SM="25">Super-saturated land tumbled down a mountain Monday in the coastal community of La Conchita, Calif., killing at least one person and injuring many more, fire officials said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="25.61904761904762" PS="1.8082191780821917" SM="14">``We have one dead and numerous injuries,'' said Myrna Raya, fire information officer for the Ventura County Fire Department.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="32.7" PS="1.8082191780821917" SM="2">Rescuers were searching through the mud for survivors, she said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="24.058823529411764" PS="1.2054794520547945" SM="1">It was unknown how many people were trapped; at least six people were taken to area hospitals.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="17.642857142857142" PS="1.8082191780821917" SM="42">The death brought to 10 the number of people killed in Southern California during the past weekend's storm, one of three bringing record precipitation across the state.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="13.5" PS="1.8082191780821917" SM="14">Mike and Barbara Bell, residents of La Conchita since 1983, said the landslide struck without warning about 1:15 p.m. PST.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="29.136363636363637" PS="1.2054794520547945" SM="6">The Bells, who live on a street away from the slide, said they were cleaning up mud when they heard the slide.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="25.8125" PS="1.8082191780821917" SM="26">``We were standing on the street and just talking and somebody said, `Oh my God!'</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="26.1" PS="1.2054794520547945" SM="14">and then the hill came down,'' Mike Bell said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="19.346153846153847" PS="1.2054794520547945" SM="18">``It covered the same three or four houses it hit the first time, then came across the street and hit six or seven more houses.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="7.75" PS="1.2054794520547945" SM="0">It clearly destroyed them.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="8.4" PS="1.2054794520547945" SM="0">It just blew them apart.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="5.066666666666666" PS="1.8082191780821917" SM="14">''Now I've got to get a backhoe and try to save my own house.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="20.46153846153846" PS="1.2054794520547945" SM="29">The mudslide's at the other end of the street, but every time we get a torrential rain the mud flow comes right down my street.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="15.75" PS="1.2054794520547945" SM="2">I've got to go if I'm going to save my house,`` he said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="16.583333333333332" PS="1.8082191780821917" SM="15">Kathleen Wood, who has lived in the community since 1985, was taking a walk with a friend through La Conchita when the slide occurred.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="3.5555555555555554" PS="1.2054794520547945" SM="12">''I looked up and saw a cloud of dust.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="19.11111111111111" PS="1.2054794520547945" SM="12">It was silent and then it really came down.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="30.75" PS="1.2054794520547945" SM="2">It snapped the retaining wall,`` she said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="4.333333333333333" PS="1.8082191780821917" SM="0">(Begin optional trim)</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="15.357142857142858" PS="1.8082191780821917" SM="18">Sam and Cynthia Ficklend, whose family had been going up to La Conchita on vacation for the last 50 years, moved to the seaside community two years ago.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="12.4375" PS="1.2054794520547945" SM="36">They were going home to put things in crates and boxes and looking for their cat.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="16.09090909090909" PS="1.8082191780821917" SM="1">''We thought we'd retired to paradise,`` Cynthia Ficklend said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="17.6" PS="1.2054794520547945" SM="0">''Well, paradise is over.``</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="6.666666666666667" PS="1.8082191780821917" SM="0">(End optional trim)</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="13.055555555555555" PS="1.8082191780821917" SM="0">La Conchita is a small community fronted by U.S. 101, about 60 miles north of downtown Los Angeles.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="16.1" PS="1.2054794520547945" SM="11">It was also struck by a major landslide in 1995.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="18.37037037037037" PS="1.8082191780821917" SM="65">The fifth day of thrashing storms took a heavy toll on Southern California as the rain swelled streams and rivers and undermined the integrity of the ground.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="4.333333333333333" PS="1.8082191780821917" SM="0">(Begin optional trim)</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="16.75" PS="1.8082191780821917" SM="16">A slackening rainfall was expected to bring some relief for evening commuters, a step up from the morning drive, which was a treacherous game of stop and go.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="22.8" PS="1.8082191780821917" SM="12">Delays and some closures were reported on most major roads.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="23.176470588235293" PS="1.2054794520547945" SM="4">Because many secondary roads were closed, traffic was forced onto the highways, further clogging the principal routes.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="19.1875" PS="1.2054794520547945" SM="11">Where roads were open, sizable delays of more than an hour were reported in many areas.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="23.0" PS="1.8082191780821917" SM="16">Schools in some parts of the region were forced to close for the day.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="7.0" PS="1.2054794520547945" SM="11">Glendale Community College canceled evening classes because of a nearby mudslide.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="6.666666666666667" PS="1.8082191780821917" SM="0">(End optional trim)</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="19.0" PS="1.8082191780821917" SM="11">An estimated 6,000 customers in Los Angeles were reported without power Monday afternoon.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="15.363636363636363" PS="1.8082191780821917" SM="24">Earlier , Monday, the body of a 2-year-old girl was recovered in Palmdale, a high desert town in far northeastern Los Angeles County.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="17.675675675675677" PS="1.8082191780821917" SM="17">The toddler plunged to her death after slipping from her mother's grasp as they were being lifted to safety by rescuers, who responded when the family's vehicle became stuck in a flooded wash Sunday night.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="17.71794871794872" PS="1.8082191780821917" SM="15">Authorities said the girl's mother, whose name was not released, drove around a barrier, one of several put up by county employees in the area because of dangerously swirling creek waters caused by two weeks of stormy weather.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="31.666666666666668" PS="1.8082191780821917" SM="0">Los Angeles County Sheriff's Sgt.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="14.681818181818182" PS="1.2054794520547945" SM="13">Michael Handley said cars are swept away all too often when people mistakenly think they can ford swollen waterways in the area.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="32.5" PS="1.2054794520547945" SM="2">''It happens all the time,`` he said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="12.166666666666666" PS="1.2054794520547945" SM="2">''I don't know what it is, the lemming mentality or something.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="18.047619047619047" PS="1.2054794520547945" SM="2">They're so intent on getting where they're going that they think they can drive through the flood waters.``</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="26.305555555555557" PS="1.8082191780821917" SM="51">Roads were clogged with rain and mud, and at least 720 crashes were reported Sunday, more than three times the number of accidents during the previous Sunday when streets were dry, the California Highway Patrol said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="18.6" PS="1.2054794520547945" SM="22">Fire officials estimated that 100 roads in Los Angeles saw flooding, mudslides or downed trees.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="20.68" PS="1.8082191780821917" SM="14">By Monday morning, the National Weather service reported that downtown Los Angeles received 5.16 inches since Friday and more than 2.5 inches on Sunday alone.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="13.615384615384615" PS="1.2054794520547945" SM="27">Beverly Hills received 7.79 inches, the L.A. community of Eagle Rock 3.8 inches, Santa Monica 4.7 inches, and Chatsworth, in the San Fernando Valley, 5.81 inches.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="17.0" PS="1.8082191780821917" SM="3">According to the weather service, Los Angeles has received almost 21 inches of precipitation since July 1.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="10.4" PS="1.2054794520547945" SM="4">That surpasses the average annual rainfall of 15.14 inches with five months yet to go.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="20.63157894736842" PS="1.8082191780821917" SM="16">The rain was expected to let up Monday afternoon, , but the region will have little time to dry out.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="22.6" PS="1.2054794520547945" SM="22">Substantial rains were forecast for Monday night and through Tuesday.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="17.77777777777778" PS="1.2054794520547945" SM="0">A real break was expected by Wednesday, when clearing should take place for a few days at least.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="3.7777777777777777" PS="1.8082191780821917" SM="13">Times staff writers Jia-Rui Chong, Amanda Covarrubias, Richard Fausset, Wendy Thermos and Michael Muskal contributed to this story.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="8.714285714285714" PS="2.3630136986301373" SM="24">Part of a rain-saturated hillside gave way on Monday, sending a Mississippi-like torrent of earth and trees onto four blocks of this oceanfront town and killing two men.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="18.0" PS="1.5753424657534247" SM="1">At least 12 people were known to be missing.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="19.2" PS="1.5753424657534247" SM="18">A spokesman for the Ventura County Fire Department, Joe L. Luna, said that nine people had been recovered from the wreckage of their homes and that seven of them had been taken to a hospital to be treated for injuries.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="11.6875" PS="1.0502283105022832" SM="12">A helicopter took a 62-year-old man to a hospital, where he was listed in critical condition.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="15.692307692307692" PS="1.5753424657534247" SM="13">La Conchita was the site of a similar but smaller landslide in 1995.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="21.0" PS="1.5753424657534247" SM="24">&quot;This one came down quickly and suddenly, and very violently,&quot; Luna said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="20.25" PS="1.0502283105022832" SM="1">&quot;It impacted 15 to 20 homes.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="23.470588235294116" PS="1.5753424657534247" SM="37">The disaster was the latest caused by rain and snow that has battered California since Dec. 25.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="17.3125" PS="1.0502283105022832" SM="43">Meteorologists say Southern California has not been hit by this much rain in nearly 40 years.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="24.257142857142856" PS="1.0502283105022832" SM="13">Downtown Los Angeles has had more than 15 inches of rain since Jan. 1, more than its average rainfall for an entire year, including 2.6 inches on Sunday, a record, the National Weather Service said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="31.636363636363637" PS="1.5753424657534247" SM="13">Officials said they were concerned about the possibility of more mudslides.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="21.25" PS="1.0502283105022832" SM="5">Rescuers expected to work through the night searching for the missing people.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="25.428571428571427" PS="1.5753424657534247" SM="12">&quot;It's very sad,&quot; said Kirk Peterson, who has lived here for a year and whose house was undamaged.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="19.375" PS="1.0502283105022832" SM="0">&quot;We've lost a few friends.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="24.46153846153846" PS="1.5753424657534247" SM="0">His wife, Dawn, said, &quot;We're hoping they're not buried.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="13.782608695652174" PS="1.5753424657534247" SM="16">La Conchita is a sliver of a town between the Pacific Ocean and scenic bluffs just south of the Santa Barbara County line.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="19.571428571428573" PS="1.0502283105022832" SM="16">The bluffs, saturated by Pacific-borne storms that began on Friday, were known to be unstable, and Ventura County fire officials asked residents on Monday morning to leave voluntarily.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="19.333333333333332" PS="1.0502283105022832" SM="2">About 200 complied, boarding government-provided buses, Myra Raya, a spokeswoman for the Fire Department, said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="23.428571428571427" PS="1.5753424657534247" SM="1">&quot;Most people chose to leave, but a few did not,&quot; Raya said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="20.57894736842105" PS="1.5753424657534247" SM="48">Rescue workers, including a search-and-rescue team from neighboring Los Angeles County, worked through the gloom of the fading afternoon, combing the debris for the living and dead and keeping a wary eye on the hillside and the sky.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="15.558823529411764" PS="1.5753424657534247" SM="36">A 2-year-old drowned on Sunday in Palmdale, in the desert, after slipping from her mother's grasp when helicopter rescuers tried to lift them from a car that had been swallowed in a torrent.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="22.1" PS="1.0502283105022832" SM="2">The child's body was recovered a few hours later.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="15.26923076923077" PS="1.5753424657534247" SM="18">The authorities are considering bringing charges against the mother, whose name they did not release, because she had driven around barricades and into the rushing water.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="17.5" PS="1.5753424657534247" SM="24">In Los Angeles, a saturated hillside gave way in Elysian Park, burying a homeless man who was waiting out the weather in his encampment.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="27.5" PS="1.0502283105022832" SM="0">His companion was injured.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="21.555555555555557" PS="1.5753424657534247" SM="18">Also on Sunday, a motorist drowned near Malibu when he hit a mud patch on the Pacific Coast Highway and skidded off the road into the ocean.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="12.173913043478262" PS="1.0502283105022832" SM="24">A 20-year-old in Ventura County died on Sunday when he tried to cross a raging creek in a harness attached to a wire.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="30.46153846153846" PS="1.5753424657534247" SM="19">Road accidents on Sunday numbered 720, more than three times the total of the previous Sunday, when the roads were dry, the California Highway Patrol said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="20.31578947368421" PS="1.0502283105022832" SM="35">One hundred roads and highways in Los Angeles County were closed because of flooding and rock slides, clogging traffic.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="7.0" PS="1.5753424657534247" SM="0">(STORY CAN END HERE.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="3.6666666666666665" PS="1.0502283105022832" SM="0">OPTIONAL MATERIAL FOLLOWS.)</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="18.142857142857142" PS="1.5753424657534247" SM="21">A confluence of tropical air from the South Pacific and a cold front barreling down from the north have combined to create the extraordinary weather across the West.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="12.0" PS="1.0502283105022832" SM="11">On Friday, Las Vegas was coated in a freak snow squall.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="14.352941176470589" PS="1.5753424657534247" SM="14">The Sierras have had 4 feet of snow, and forecasters expect an additional 5 feet by midweek.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="18.9" PS="1.0502283105022832" SM="15">The Reno airport was closed two times in a week, the region not having seen so much snow since 1916.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="21.333333333333332" PS="1.0502283105022832" SM="24">More than 6,000 houses were without power on Monday in Los Angeles, where county officials estimate the property damage in excess of $19 million.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="16.296296296296298" PS="1.5753424657534247" SM="31">The downpours are part of the fundamentally chaotic and occasionally extreme nature of the atmosphere, said William Patzert, an oceanographer at the Jet Propulsion Laboratory in Pasadena.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="16.565217391304348" PS="1.0502283105022832" SM="26">He said Los Angeles had not seen such intensity and such a pattern of winter downpours since the fall and winter of 1889-90.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="22.074074074074073" PS="1.5753424657534247" SM="51">Patzert said that the snowpack in the north could help bolster water supplies for Southern California but that the torrential rains would not slake the longstanding drought.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="19.125" PS="1.0502283105022832" SM="1">&quot;It's like trying to fill a glass full of water when someone is shooting a fire hose at you,&quot; he said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="18.833333333333332" PS="1.0502283105022832" SM="14">&quot;Seventy-five to 80 percent will end up in the ocean.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="27.166666666666668" PS="1.5753424657534247" SM="34">Southern California, it is widely said, has two seasons: fire and flood.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="10.2" PS="1.0502283105022832" SM="0">Landslides are not freak occurrences.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="15.3125" PS="1.0502283105022832" SM="13">La Conchita was the victim of a 600,000-ton slide in 1995 destroying or damaging 14 houses.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="7.888888888888889" PS="1.0502283105022832" SM="1">Even then, despite warnings to leave, some residents stayed.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="24.0" PS="1.0502283105022832" SM="0">No one then was killed.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="31.11111111111111" PS="1.5753424657534247" SM="2">After the slide on Monday, evacuation was made mandatory.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="8.607142857142858" PS="2.3630136986301373" SM="24">Part of a rain-saturated hillside gave way on Monday, sending a Mississippi-like torrent of earth and trees onto four blocks of this oceanfront town and killing three men.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="20.75" PS="1.5753424657534247" SM="1">About 12 people were known to be missing.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="22.766666666666666" PS="1.5753424657534247" SM="15">A spokesman for the Ventura County Fire Department, Joe L. Luna, said 10 people were injured and all but one or two had been taken to a hospital for treatment.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="11.6875" PS="1.0502283105022832" SM="12">A helicopter took a 62-year-old man to a hospital, where he was listed in critical condition.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="24.863636363636363" PS="1.5753424657534247" SM="21">At least three or four people were pulled alive from the debris over the course of the day, including a woman in the early evening who was &quot;pretty seriously injured,&quot; Eric Nishimoto, a spokesman for the Ventura County sheriff's department, said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="15.692307692307692" PS="1.0502283105022832" SM="13">La Conchita was the site of a similar but smaller landslide in 1995.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="21.0" PS="1.5753424657534247" SM="24">&quot;This one came down quickly and suddenly, and very violently,&quot; Luna said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="27.375" PS="1.0502283105022832" SM="1">Fifteen to 20 homes were hit, he said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="23.789473684210527" PS="1.5753424657534247" SM="39">The disaster was the latest problem caused by the rain and snow that have battered California since Dec. 25.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="17.3125" PS="1.0502283105022832" SM="43">Meteorologists say Southern California has not been hit by this much rain in nearly 40 years.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="24.257142857142856" PS="1.0502283105022832" SM="13">Downtown Los Angeles has had more than 15 inches of rain since Jan. 1, more than its average rainfall for an entire year, including 2.6 inches on Sunday, a record, the National Weather Service said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="31.636363636363637" PS="1.5753424657534247" SM="13">Officials said they were concerned about the possibility of more mudslides.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="21.25" PS="1.0502283105022832" SM="5">Rescuers expected to work through the night searching for the missing people.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="25.428571428571427" PS="1.5753424657534247" SM="12">&quot;It's very sad,&quot; said Kirk Peterson, who has lived here for a year and whose house was undamaged.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="19.375" PS="1.0502283105022832" SM="0">&quot;We've lost a few friends.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="24.46153846153846" PS="1.5753424657534247" SM="0">His wife, Dawn, said, &quot;We're hoping they're not buried.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="18.294117647058822" PS="1.5753424657534247" SM="25">Terrin Wharton was in her house with her husband and two children when the hill came down.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="21.72222222222222" PS="1.0502283105022832" SM="5">She said the rubble had stopped just to the side of her house but engulfed her neighbor's.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="18.944444444444443" PS="1.0502283105022832" SM="14">&quot;The cops put a hole in our wall&quot; to search for survivors next door, Wharton said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="13.782608695652174" PS="1.5753424657534247" SM="16">La Conchita is a sliver of a town between the Pacific Ocean and scenic bluffs just south of the Santa Barbara County line.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="19.571428571428573" PS="1.0502283105022832" SM="16">The bluffs, saturated by Pacific-borne storms that began on Friday, were known to be unstable, and Ventura County fire officials asked residents on Monday morning to leave voluntarily.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="19.333333333333332" PS="1.0502283105022832" SM="2">About 200 complied, boarding government-provided buses, Myra Raya, a spokeswoman for the Fire Department, said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="23.428571428571427" PS="1.5753424657534247" SM="1">&quot;Most people chose to leave, but a few did not,&quot; Raya said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="23.441176470588236" PS="1.5753424657534247" SM="48">Rescue workers, including a team from neighboring Los Angeles County, worked into the evening, combing the debris for the living and the dead and keeping a wary eye on the hillside and the sky.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="23.333333333333332" PS="1.5753424657534247" SM="12">On Monday evening, the rain returned.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="17.19047619047619" PS="1.0502283105022832" SM="16">Fearing another slide, officials ordered some crews to move to the coastal highway, which was closed from Ventura and Santa Barbara.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="14.542857142857143" PS="1.5753424657534247" SM="36">Elsewhere, a 2-year-old drowned on Sunday in Palmdale, in the desert, after slipping from her mother's grasp when helicopter rescuers tried to lift them from a car that had been swallowed in a torrent.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="22.1" PS="1.0502283105022832" SM="2">The child's body was recovered a few hours later.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="15.26923076923077" PS="1.5753424657534247" SM="18">The authorities are considering bringing charges against the mother, whose name they did not release, because she had driven around barricades and into the rushing water.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="17.5" PS="1.5753424657534247" SM="24">In Los Angeles, a saturated hillside gave way in Elysian Park, burying a homeless man who was waiting out the weather in his encampment.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="27.5" PS="1.0502283105022832" SM="0">His companion was injured.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="21.555555555555557" PS="1.5753424657534247" SM="18">Also on Sunday, a motorist drowned near Malibu when he hit a mud patch on the Pacific Coast Highway and skidded off the road into the ocean.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="12.173913043478262" PS="1.0502283105022832" SM="24">A 20-year-old in Ventura County died on Sunday when he tried to cross a raging creek in a harness attached to a wire.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="30.46153846153846" PS="1.5753424657534247" SM="19">Road accidents on Sunday numbered 720, more than three times the total of the previous Sunday, when the roads were dry, the California Highway Patrol said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="20.31578947368421" PS="1.0502283105022832" SM="35">One hundred roads and highways in Los Angeles County were closed because of flooding and rock slides, clogging traffic.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="7.0" PS="1.5753424657534247" SM="0">(STORY CAN END HERE.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="3.6666666666666665" PS="1.0502283105022832" SM="0">OPTIONAL MATERIAL FOLLOWS.)</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="19.384615384615383" PS="1.5753424657534247" SM="20">A confluence of tropical air from the South Pacific and a cold front barreling down from the north have created the extraordinary weather across the West.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="12.0" PS="1.0502283105022832" SM="11">On Friday, Las Vegas was coated in a freak snow squall.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="15.875" PS="1.5753424657534247" SM="14">The Sierras have had 4 feet of snow, and forecasters expect 5 feet more by midweek.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="16.181818181818183" PS="1.0502283105022832" SM="24">The airport in Reno, Nev., was closed twice in a week.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="20.3" PS="1.0502283105022832" SM="2">The region has not had so much snow since 1916.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="21.44" PS="1.0502283105022832" SM="24">More than 6,000 houses were without power on Monday in Los Angeles, where county officials estimate the property damage is in excess of $19 million.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="16.296296296296298" PS="1.5753424657534247" SM="31">The downpours are part of the fundamentally chaotic and occasionally extreme nature of the atmosphere, said William Patzert, an oceanographer at the Jet Propulsion Laboratory in Pasadena.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="16.565217391304348" PS="1.0502283105022832" SM="26">He said Los Angeles had not seen such intensity and such a pattern of winter downpours since the fall and winter of 1889-90.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="23.428571428571427" PS="1.5753424657534247" SM="51">Patzert said that the snowpack in the north could help bolster water supplies for Southern California but that the torrential rains would not slake the longstanding drought. &quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="17.347826086956523" PS="1.5753424657534247" SM="1">It's like trying to fill a glass full of water when someone is shooting a fire hose at you,&quot; he said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="18.833333333333332" PS="1.0502283105022832" SM="14">&quot;Seventy-five to 80 percent will end up in the ocean.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="27.166666666666668" PS="1.5753424657534247" SM="34">Southern California, it is widely said, has two seasons: fire and flood.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="10.2" PS="1.0502283105022832" SM="0">Landslides are not freak occurrences.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="16.4" PS="1.0502283105022832" SM="25">The 1995 slide in La Conchita was 600,000 tons and destroyed or damaged 14 houses.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="7.888888888888889" PS="1.0502283105022832" SM="1">Even then, despite warnings to leave, some residents stayed.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="31.11111111111111" PS="1.5753424657534247" SM="2">After the slide on Monday, evacuation was made mandatory.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="12.948717948717949" PS="2.3630136986301373" SM="70">Rescue workers using sensitive listening devices and cadaver dogs probed for buried victims on Tuesday in a 25-foot-deep mountain of mud and debris left by Monday's mudslide as the rains finally ended and desperate family members kept vigil.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="18.7" PS="1.5753424657534247" SM="6">Bob Roper, the Ventura County fire chief, said Tuesday afternoon that monitoring equipment was still picking up faint sounds of life from the debris pile, raising the possibility of survivors.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="21.555555555555557" PS="1.5753424657534247" SM="0">&quot;We're looking for any movement,&quot; Capt.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="30.75" PS="1.0502283105022832" SM="2">Conrad Quintana of the county fire department said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="17.833333333333332" PS="1.0502283105022832" SM="0">&quot;A part of an arm.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="8.0" PS="1.0502283105022832" SM="0">A finger tapping.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="11.5" PS="1.0502283105022832" SM="0">A cough.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="2.5" PS="1.0502283105022832" SM="0">Someone crying.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="11.875" PS="1.0502283105022832" SM="11">Any indication someone is alive in there.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="11.580645161290322" PS="1.5753424657534247" SM="16">The missing included the wife and three children of Jimmie Wallet, a carpenter who left them briefly on Monday just before a 500-foot-high rain-saturated hillside above this tiny coastal hamlet collapsed.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="22.02777777777778" PS="1.5753424657534247" SM="16">&quot;He was running toward the mountain while people were running away from it,&quot; said Wallet's mother, Linda Silva, who came to La Conchita on Tuesday to await word of her daughter-in-law and grandchildren.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="12.818181818181818" PS="1.0502283105022832" SM="12">&quot;He ran up there and started digging with his hands.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="14.444444444444445" PS="1.0502283105022832" SM="1">He was yelling, 'I have to get my kids!</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="18.666666666666668" PS="1.0502283105022832" SM="0">My kids!&quot;'</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="21.176470588235293" PS="1.5753424657534247" SM="5">Rescuers pulled three more bodies from the mud on Tuesday, bringing the official death count to six.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="15.527777777777779" PS="1.5753424657534247" SM="72">The collapse of the hillside here was a deadly coda to five days of merciless rains across Southern California that have left 20 dead and driven thousands from their homes under threat of floods and mudslides.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="17.620689655172413" PS="1.5753424657534247" SM="27">Even as skies cleared on Tuesday, 4,000 people were evacuated from the banks of a surging creek in the Orange County communities of San Juan Capistrano and Dana Point.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="17.88" PS="1.0502283105022832" SM="36">And a hiker who had been trapped for three days in a cave by raging floodwaters in the San Bernardino Mountains was rescued by helicopter.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="17.5" PS="1.5753424657534247" SM="61">Among the dead across the region were a man whose body was found wedged in a tree in a canyon, a woman who was run over by her husband, who could not see her in the driving rain, and an 18-year-old woman who was killed when her car hit a fallen tree.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="18.235294117647058" PS="1.0502283105022832" SM="25">Here in La Conchita, where as many as 12 people were missing, 14 people were also injured, two of them critically, and roughly half of the town's houses were destroyed or badly damaged.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="14.733333333333333" PS="1.0502283105022832" SM="2">Dozens of roads around the area remained closed because of mud or deep standing water.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="21.166666666666668" PS="2.25" SM="13">The New York Times said in an editorial for Wednesday, Jan. 12:</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="12.34375" PS="1.5" SM="114">Here we are, three weeks into winter, and the season has delivered almost every kind of weather it has to deliver: waterspouts off Ventura, Calif., ice storms in the central Plains, glacial fog in the Texas Panhandle, profound depths of snow in the Sierra Nevada, flooding in the Ohio Valley and an all too familiar mix of ice, snow and rain in the Northeast.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="17.5" PS="1.5" SM="33">Nowhere has winter been more impressive this year than in Southern California.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="21.84" PS="1.0" SM="14">Los Angeles has already had some 5 inches more than its annual rainfall in the last two weeks, including a record 2.6 inches on Sunday.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="16.8" PS="1.0" SM="7">The numbers do not really convey the effect of all that water, combined with powerful storm surges along the coast.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="13.5" PS="1.0" SM="35">Mudslides have closed freeways and caused evacuations and some deaths.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="10.772727272727273" PS="1.0" SM="15">Every creek and river -- dry streambeds for most of the year -- has swollen to a dangerous tide of dark water.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="18.23076923076923" PS="1.0" SM="14">Vast stretches of the Mojave Desert have been inundated by the unstinting rain.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="16.6875" PS="1.0" SM="17">In the Central Valley, water stands in the fields, washing out the hope of some crops.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="13.89655172413793" PS="1.0" SM="36">In Bakersfield, which averages less than 6 inches of rainfall a year, the rain fell in sheets on Sunday and Monday, turning highways into long columns of vehicle-beaten spray.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="7.8" PS="1.5" SM="0">There is temporary respite coming.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="14.941176470588236" PS="1.0" SM="36">Good weather will hit Southern California later this week, and the Northeast has enjoyed some mild intervals.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="13.210526315789474" PS="1.0" SM="27">And this much moisture in the arid West always promises good news, despite the chaotic way it has come.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="13.6" PS="1.0" SM="15">But no matter how good the weather gets for a few days in mid-January, the bulk of winter lies ahead.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="12.222222222222221" PS="1.0" SM="1">It's hard to imagine what it may bring.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="19.90909090909091" PS="2.578767123287671" SM="46">Shippers scrambled for alternative routes Wednesday as Union Pacific Corp. struggled to overcome what it said was a ``probably unprecedented'' disruption of service in Southern California because of the recent rains.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="16.613636363636363" PS="1.7191780821917808" SM="44">Mother Nature might be to blame for Union Pacific's latest woes, but the recurring problems the railroad has had moving goods in and out of the region, coupled with recent backlogs at local ports, could threaten the economy, shipping experts and economists said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="12.44186046511628" PS="1.7191780821917808" SM="51">``If I'm a shipper, I'm starting to get disturbed about being able to use Southern California as a base to get stuff into the country and out to my stores,'' said John Husing, an independent economist in Redlands, Calif.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="14.826086956521738" PS="1.7191780821917808" SM="37">Citing mudslides and washed-out tracks and bridges, Union Pacific closed four of its five main rail lines out of the Los Angeles Basin.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="14.285714285714286" PS="1.1461187214611872" SM="16">That brought the railroad's freight traffic in the region to a near standstill.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="21.166666666666668" PS="1.1461187214611872" SM="16">The company said it was racing to make track repairs and hoped to resume limited service on Thursday.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="14.055555555555555" PS="1.7191780821917808" SM="74">Union Pacific's troubles included 23 mudslides that covered tracks in the Cajon Pass east of Los Angeles, a key passageway from Southern California to Las Vegas and Salt Lake City, and eventually to the Midwest.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="15.829268292682928" PS="1.7191780821917808" SM="16">``We have been told that the route from Los Angeles to Chicago has effectively been closed,'' said Scott Dailey, a spokesman for APL, a leading shipper of intermodal cargo containers and a unit of Neptune Orient Lines of Singapore.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="15.414634146341463" PS="1.7191780821917808" SM="17">The fresh disruption -- coming on top of last year's gridlock at local ports and railways -- persuaded APL to decide to permanently send ``a lot of our transcontinental cargo'' to Seattle rather than Los Angeles, he said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="21.714285714285715" PS="1.1461187214611872" SM="0">``That is a major shift.''</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="16.08695652173913" PS="1.7191780821917808" SM="64">Decisions like that and Union Pacific's not-infrequent difficulties, in addition to bottlenecks at the ports, ``certainly should cause people to think about the whole infrastructure'' in Southern California, said Jim McKenna, president of the Pacific Maritime Association, which represents West Coast shipping lines.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="23.13888888888889" PS="1.7191780821917808" SM="9">Husing said the ``real damage is the continuing problems we have, whether it's 93 ships tied up off the coast or Union Pacific not being able to get its cargo through the area.''</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="21.6875" PS="1.7191780821917808" SM="11">Union Pacific, which was suffering major congestion problems on its tracks before the heavy rainfall, is the nation's largest railroad, with 33,000 miles of track from the West to the Midwest.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="15.615384615384615" PS="1.7191780821917808" SM="44">Based in Omaha, Neb., it is one of two railroads that ferry goods from the ports of Los Angeles and Long Beach -- the world's busiest port complex -- north and east to the rest of the country.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="15.125" PS="1.1461187214611872" SM="2">The other is Burlington Northern Santa Fe Corp.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="15.03225806451613" PS="1.7191780821917808" SM="62">About half of the raw materials and finished goods that arrive at the Los Angeles and Long Beach ports, mostly from Asia, are transported by truck to destinations in Southern California.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="11.65" PS="1.1461187214611872" SM="14">The rest is forwarded nationwide by rail, with Union Pacific and Burlington Northern each handling about half of that freight.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="20.85" PS="1.7191780821917808" SM="14">Burlington Northern suffered no major setbacks from the storms, a spokesman said, and is carrying some freight for Union Pacific.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="13.214285714285714" PS="1.7191780821917808" SM="14">Some analysts wondered why the nasty weather affected Union Pacific and not Burlington Northern.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="13.941176470588236" PS="1.1461187214611872" SM="4">In the Cajon Pass, for instance, the railroads' tracks nearly parallel each other west of Interstate 15.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="18.285714285714285" PS="1.7191780821917808" SM="35">But Union Pacific tracks are higher in elevation than Burlington Northern's are, Union Pacific spokesman John Bromley said, and thus were first to be hit by mudslides.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="26.84375" PS="1.1461187214611872" SM="31">The damage was even more pronounced, Bromley said, because ``the slides have occurred in areas where we've had all the forest fires and the ground cover was burned off.''</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="14.375" PS="1.7191780821917808" SM="3">Union Pacific's stock fell 38 cents Wednesday to $63.96 on the New York Stock Exchange.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="6.166666666666667" PS="1.7191780821917808" SM="13">Times staff writers Debora Vrana and Evelyn Iritani contributed to this report.</sentence>
	</Sentences>
</Topic>
