<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<Topic id="D0907B">
	<Sentences>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="11.695652173913043" PS="2.25" SM="4">A Justice Department lawyer wrote a secret memo to the White House in 2001 concluding that President George W. Bush has the authority to wage preemptive war against terrorists and countries even if they were not linked to the September 11 attacks, Newsweek magazine reported Saturday.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="16.128205128205128" PS="1.5" SM="3">According to the memo there are effectively &quot;no limits&quot; on the presidents authority to wage war, Newsweek reports, noting that it seems to lay the legal groundwork for Bush to invade Iraq even without approval Congressional approval.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="15.878048780487806" PS="1.5" SM="5">&quot;The President may deploy military force preemptively against terrorist organizations or the states that harbor or support them, whether or not they can be linked to the specific terrorist incidents of Sept. 11,&quot; the memo reads, according to Newsweek.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="17.113636363636363" PS="1.5" SM="5">The memo, titled &quot;The Presidents Constitutional Authority to Conduct Military Operations against Terrorists and Nations Supporting Them,&quot; argues that the president should be allowed to order whatever military action &quot;in his best judgment&quot; are necessary to protect the United States.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="21.72222222222222" PS="1.5" SM="3">The presidents decisions to use force &quot;are for him alone and are unreviewable,&quot; the memo reads.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="16.541666666666668" PS="1.5" SM="24">The 15-page document, dated September 25, 2001, was written by conservative Justice Department lawyer John Yoo and addressed to White House counsel Alberto Gonzales.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="18.181818181818183" PS="1" SM="12">Yoo has since left government and is a university law professor.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="18.105263157894736" PS="1.5" SM="3">&quot;There was a general awareness after Sept. 11 that the enemy was not simply Al-Qaeda -- but militant Islam in general,&quot; Brad Berenson, who served in the White House counsels office at the time, told Newsweek.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="15.03225806451613" PS="1.5" SM="5">The memo was aimed at granting Bush authority to attack groups such as the Abu Sayef rebels in the Philippines or the militant Shiite Muslim group Hezbollah, Berenson told the magazine.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="15.565217391304348" PS="2.25" SM="7">Alberto R. Gonzales, the White House counsel, intervened directly with Justice Department lawyers in 2002 to obtain a legal ruling on the extent of the president's authority to permit extreme interrogation practices in the name of national security, current and former administration officials said Tuesday.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="15.392857142857142" PS="1.5" SM="6">Gonzales' role in seeking a legal opinion on the definition of torture and the legal limits of how much force could be used on terrorist suspects in captivity is expected to be a central issue in the Senate Judiciary Committee confirmation hearings, which are scheduled to begin on Thursday on his nomination to be attorney general.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="16.864864864864863" PS="1.5" SM="7">The request by Gonzales produced the much-debated Aug. 1, 2002, memorandum by the Justice Department that defined torture narrowly and said that Bush could circumvent domestic and international prohibitions against torture in the name of national security.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="17.733333333333334" PS="1.5" SM="5">Until now, administration officials have been unwilling to provide details about what role Gonzales had in the production of the memorandum by the Justice Department's Office of Legal Counsel.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="13.631578947368421" PS="1" SM="3">He has spoken of the memo as a response to questions, without saying that most of them were his.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="17.25" PS="1.5" SM="2">Current and former officials who talked about the memorandum have been provided with first-hand accounts about how it was prepared.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="11.818181818181818" PS="1" SM="2">Some discussed it in an attempt to clear up what they viewed as a murky record in advance of Gonzales' confirmation hearing.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="17.157894736842106" PS="1" SM="5">Others spoke of the matter apparently believing that the Justice Department had unfairly taken the blame for the memo.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="17.94871794871795" PS="1.5" SM="4">A White House spokeswoman, Erin Healy, said Tuesday that while Gonzales personally requested the August opinion, he was only seeking &quot;objective legal advice and did not ask the Office of Legal Counsel to reach any specific conclusion.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="17.264705882352942" PS="1.5" SM="6">As the White House's chief lawyer, Gonzales supervised the production of a raft of legal memorandums that shaped the administration's legal framework for conducting its battle against al-Qaida and other terrorist groups.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="19.133333333333333" PS="1" SM="3">Of the documents that have been made public, Gonzales is the author of only one.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="12.45" PS="1" SM="1">In that January 2002 memorandum he advised Bush that the Geneva Conventions did not apply to fighters captured in Afghanistan.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="15.40625" PS="1.5" SM="6">As a result, a major area of questioning at his confirmation hearing is expected to be the role he played in the production of the other documents, like the August 2002 memorandum.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="13.619047619047619" PS="1" SM="1">The memo concluded that interrogators had great leeway to question detainees using coercive techniques that they could assert were not torture.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="17.14" PS="1.5" SM="4">The Justice Department last week formally rescinded that memorandum and in its place issued a legal opinion saying that torture should be more broadly defined and that there was no need to say Bush had the authority to sanction torture because he has unequivocally said that it is not permitted.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="21.166666666666668" PS="1.5" SM="3">The revision stated that &quot;Torture is abhorrent both to American law and values and international norms.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="18.555555555555557" PS="1" SM="3">It rejected the language in the earlier memo that said only &quot;organ failure, impairment of bodily function or even death&quot; constituted torture punishable by law.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="17.483870967741936" PS="1.5" SM="3">Administration officials said over the last few days that Gonzales had played a role in the decision to issue the new legal opinion as well, but they did not offer specifics.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="18.98076923076923" PS="1.5" SM="7">Gonzales' request for the original August 2002 memorandum was somewhat unusual, the officials said, because he went directly to lawyers at the Office of Legal Counsel, bypassing the deputy attorney general's office, which is often notified of sensitive requests for legal opinions made by executive branch agencies, including the White House.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="18.88235294117647" PS="1.5" SM="4">The memorandum has become one of the most hotly debated legal documents in the war on terror.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="6.357142857142857" PS="1" SM="3">Democrats and human rights groups have complained that it created a permissive atmosphere that led eventually to serious abuses of detainees in Iraq, Afghanistan and Guantanamo Bay, Cuba.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="20.5" PS="1" SM="7">The memorandum was addressed to Gonzales and was signed by Jay S. Bybee, then the head of the Office of Legal Counsel at the Justice Department.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="20.11764705882353" PS="1.5" SM="2">Officials dispute how much senior Justice Department officials knew of the memorandum as it was being prepared.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="14.342857142857143" PS="1" SM="15">A former and a current official said that neither Attorney General John Ashcroft nor his deputy, Larry D. Thompson, were aware of the memorandum until it was about to be submitted to the White House.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="14.8125" PS="1" SM="1">Another former official said, however, that they were given progress reports as the memorandum took shape.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="20.56" PS="1.5" SM="26">John Yoo, a senior Justice Department lawyer who wrote much of the memorandum, exchanged draft language with lawyers at the White House, the officials said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="16.5" PS="1" SM="16">Yoo, now a law professor at the University of California at Berkeley, said in an article published Sunday in the San Jose Mercury News that Gonzales did not apply any pressure on him to tailor the memorandum to accommodate the White House.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="17.76923076923077" PS="1.5" SM="12">Instead, Yoo said that Gonzales was merely seeking to &quot;understand all available options&quot; in a perilous time when the United States faced unprecedented threats.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="13.68" PS="1.5" SM="4">But a senior administration official disagreed, saying that the memorandum's conclusions appeared to align closely with the prevailing White House view of interrogation practices.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="15.129032258064516" PS="1" SM="4">These officials said the memo raised questions about whether the Office of Legal Counsel had maintained its longstanding tradition of dispensing objective legal advice to its clients in executive branch agencies.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="17.137254901960784" PS="1.5" SM="4">While the nature of Gonzales' specific discussions with the Justice Department remains unclear, administration officials said that Gonzales' customary way of dealing with Justice Department lawyers was to pose questions about issues rather than offer his own conclusions, although one said his preferences could sometimes be easily inferred from his questions.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="16.416666666666668" PS="1.5" SM="7">.......................... Department officials said that the timing of the revised memorandum, which was posted on the Justice Department's Internet site without announcement late on Dec. 30, was the result of instructions from James B. Comey, the deputy attorney general.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="17.352941176470587" PS="1.5" SM="5">Comey, the officials said, told lawyers to complete the revised opinion before the end of the year.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="16.514285714285716" PS="1" SM="6">At the same time, officials said that they were mindful that issuance of the new opinion might help neutralize the issue for Gonzales even as it served as a sharp critique of the earlier opinion.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="5.0" PS="1.5" SM="0">(STORY CAN END HERE.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="3.3333333333333335" PS="1" SM="0">OPTIONAL MATERIAL FOLLOWS.)</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="15.823529411764707" PS="1.5" SM="6">Gonzales talked about the 2002 memo in a meeting with reporters last June, when the White House sought to defend its actions at the height of the uproar over abuses of prisoners in Iraq.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="19.522727272727273" PS="1" SM="8">Without discussing his own role in soliciting the document, Gonzales said that the memo was not a policy directive to officials in the field, but a response to questions about the scope of the federal law prohibiting torture and the international convention on torture.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="20.708333333333332" PS="1.5" SM="1">&quot;The president has given no order or directive that would immunize from prosecution anyone engaged in conduct that constitutes torture,&quot; Gonzales said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="21.333333333333332" PS="1" SM="1">&quot;All interrogation techniques actually authorized have been carefully vetted, are lawful, and do not constitute torture.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="16.217391304347824" PS="1.5" SM="5">Sen. Patrick J. Leahy, D-Vt., the ranking Democrat on the Judiciary Committee, who has signaled he intends to vigorously question Gonzales about his role in the memorandums, said Tuesday that he has been continually frustrated by the White House in trying to obtain answers and documents.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="11.355555555555556" PS="1.5" SM="1">In a letter Tuesday to Gonzales, Leahy said that &quot;I am disappointed that, contrary to your promises to me to engage in an open exchange and answer my questions in connection with your confirmation process, you have not answered my letters&quot; requesting documents.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="16.35" PS="1.5" SM="3">But Sen. Arlen Specter, R-Pa., who is the new chairman of the committee, said that Leahy's complaints appeared unjustified.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="19.88" PS="1" SM="2">He said that one document was for a final version of a Jan. 25, 2002, memorandum because the one available is marked &quot;draft.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="19.466666666666665" PS="1" SM="1">He said that there is no evidence that there is any document but the draft.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="21.210526315789473" PS="1.5" SM="1">Other requests from Leahy, he said, were for documents that did not directly bear on Gonzales' actions or views.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="17.41176470588235" PS="1.5" SM="1">The Jan. 25, 2002 memorandum is an unsigned draft from Gonzales to Bush dated Jan. 25, 2002.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="24.941176470588236" PS="1" SM="2">In it, Gonzales, wrote that the fight against terrorism had made the Geneva Conventions &quot;obsolete.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="12.65" PS="1" SM="2">In addition, he said the conventions' prisoner-of-war protections need not apply to al-Qaida suspects and Taliban members captured in Afghanistan.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="17.703703703703702" PS="2.25" SM="3">Attorney General nominee Alberto Gonzales is promising senators that he will abide by treaties prohibiting the torture of prisoners, despite deriding the restraints as relics in 2002.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="14.742857142857142" PS="1.5" SM="3">White House counsel Gonzales, in line to become the first Hispanic attorney general, had a hand in much of the White House's post-Sept. 11 terrorism policies as President George W. Bush's top lawyer.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="15.73913043478261" PS="1.5" SM="3">His confirmation hearing Thursday offered Democrats on the Senate Judiciary Committee a fresh chance to criticize Gonzales and the advice he gave Bush.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="19.5625" PS="1" SM="3">Among the most contentious matters is a memo Gonzales wrote in January 2002 in which he argued that the fight against terrorism &quot;renders obsolete&quot; the Geneva Conventions' prohibitions against torture.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="18.17391304347826" PS="1.5" SM="2">A month later, Bush signed an order declaring he had the authority to bypass the accords &quot;in this or future conflicts.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="21.48148148148148" PS="1" SM="3">Bush's order also said the Geneva treaty's references to prisoners of war did not apply to al-Qaida or &quot;unlawful combatants&quot; from the Taliban.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="13.088235294117647" PS="1.5" SM="6">Some of Gonzales' critics say that decision and his memo lead to the torture scandal at Iraq's Abu Ghraib prison and abuses of detainees in U.S. custody in Afghanistan and Guantanamo Bay, Cuba.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="18.394736842105264" PS="1.5" SM="2">In testimony prepared for his hearing, Gonzales said Bush has made clear that the government will defend Americans from terrorists &quot;in a manner consistent with our nation's values and applicable law, including our treaty obligations.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="16.666666666666668" PS="1.5" SM="2">Gonzales added, &quot;I pledge that, if I am confirmed as attorney general, I will abide by those commitments,&quot; according to the testimony obtained Wednesday by The Associated Press.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="17.708333333333332" PS="1.5" SM="4">Last June, the Justice Department withdrew its 2002 memos arguing that the president's wartime authority supersedes laws and treaties governing treatment of prisoners.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="17.375" PS="1" SM="1">On Wednesday, former Justice Department officials sought to distance the White House from its legal conclusions.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="22.142857142857142" PS="1.5" SM="27">John Yoo, who helped write the memos while at the department's Office of Legal Counsel, said that while Gonzales was briefed on drafts, he and other officials did not attempt to influence the content.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="21.317073170731707" PS="1.5" SM="17">&quot;The idea that the Office of Legal Counsel was providing advice that was dictated, demanded or influenced by the White House, that's just flatly untrue,&quot; said Yoo, now a law professor at the University of California at Berkeley.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="28.0" PS="1.5" SM="0">Gonzales has repudiated torture before.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="26.416666666666668" PS="1" SM="1">&quot;The president has stated that this administration does not condone torture.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="16.16" PS="1" SM="0">If anyone engages in such conduct, he or she will be held accountable,&quot; Gonzales said in a White House online event on July 7.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="14.333333333333334" PS="1.5" SM="0">Democrats, not satisfied with just those statements, planned to question Gonzales extensively.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="22.128205128205128" PS="1.5" SM="4">&quot;It is clear he was in the chain receiving this critical documentation relative to changing American standards on the treatment of prisoners, so he was not a bystander, he was part of it,&quot; said Sen. Richard Durbin.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="17.615384615384617" PS="1.5" SM="1">Scott McClellan, the White House press secretary, said Bush firmly backs Gonzales' nomination.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="18.066666666666666" PS="1.5" SM="3">&quot;Judge Gonzales is a very trusted adviser to the president (and is) doing an outstanding job,&quot; McClellan told reporters traveling Wednesday with the president aboard Air Force One.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="19.181818181818183" PS="1.5" SM="1">Democrats are expecting Gonzales to be confirmed by the Republican-majority Senate.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="16.818181818181817" PS="1.5" SM="0">&quot;I have found him someone I could work with when he wasn't simply pursuing an agenda that was thrust upon him,&quot; said Sen. Charles Schumer, a Democrat from New York.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="13.384615384615385" PS="1.5" SM="13">Freshman Sen. Ken Salazar of Colorado, who is Hispanic, was expected to join Sen. John Cornyn, a Republican from Texas, in introducing Gonzales at the hearing.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="17.818181818181817" PS="1.5" SM="2">Civil rights and humanitarian groups have portrayed Gonzales as the person responsible for abuses by Americans against terrorism suspects held as prisoners.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="17.102564102564102" PS="1.5" SM="9">&quot;Mr. Gonzales bears much of the responsibility for creating the legal framework and permissive atmosphere that led to the torture and abuse at Guantanamo and elsewhere,&quot; said Anthony Romero, executive director of the American Civil Liberties Union.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="18.677419354838708" PS="1.5" SM="4">Gonzales' memo from Jan. 25, 2002, argued that the terrorism fight &quot;renders obsolete Geneva's strict limitations on questioning of enemy prisoners and renders quaint some of its provisions.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="19.434782608695652" PS="1.5" SM="3">In his prepared Senate testimony, Gonzales was repeating the contention that terrorists are not soldiers and thus are not covered by the conventions.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="14.222222222222221" PS="1" SM="1">Nonetheless, according to his testimony, &quot;We must be committed to preserving civil rights and civil liberties.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="11.805555555555555" PS="1.5" SM="4">Democrats wanted to ask Gonzales about other terrorism issues, including the government's detention of Jose Padilla, a U.S. citizen who the government alleges was part of an al-Qaida plot to set off a radiological bomb.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="10.6" PS="1" SM="3">Arrested after the 2001 attacks, Padilla later was designated an enemy combatant, brought to the brig in South Carolina and prevented from challenging his detention.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="14.666666666666666" PS="1" SM="0">He has sued over his detention.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="8.785714285714286" PS="1.5" SM="1">Some Republicans say Democrats are just setting up arguments to use against Gonzales in case Bush decides to elevate him to the Supreme Court, should a vacancy occur.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="1.0" PS="1.5" SM="0">___</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="14.333333333333334" PS="1.5" SM="1">On the Net:</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="13.085714285714285" PS="2.25" SM="3">Senate Judiciary Democrats and liberal allies have been hoping for months to get their mitts on internal administration documents relating to torture and prison abuses -- some of them involving attorney general nominee Alberto Gonzales.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="10.25" PS="1.5" SM="1">There's little or no chance they'll get any of them.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="13.26086956521739" PS="1" SM="3">The American Civil Liberties Union, for example, last week listed CIA, Pentagon, Justice Department and other memos and cables it wanted made public.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="14.81578947368421" PS="1" SM="25">One item was described as a ``memorandum from James Ho, attorney-advisor, (Justice Department) Office of Legal Counsel, to John Yoo, deputy assistant attorney general, OLC, re: interpretation of Geneva Conventions' Common Article 3 (Feb. 1, 2002).''</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="8.0" PS="1.5" SM="0">Most unlikely they'll find out what that one says.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="16.11111111111111" PS="1" SM="13">Besides, Ho and Yoo have both left the department.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="22.2" PS="1" SM="11">Yoo is teaching law at Berkeley, although Ho is said to be in this area.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="1.3333333333333333" PS="1.5" SM="0">Wait a minute!</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="15.823529411764707" PS="1" SM="11">Who was that good-looking guy sitting behind Sen. John Cornyn, R-Texas, during Gonzales's hearing on Thursday?</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="0.5" PS="1" SM="1">Son of a gun.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="17.307692307692307" PS="1" SM="1">It's James Ho, now Cornyn's chief counsel on the Constitution subcommittee.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="7.666666666666667" PS="1.5" SM="1">Maybe the Judiciary Committee Dems ought to interview him?</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="14.86046511627907" PS="2.25" SM="3">The question Democratic senators put to Condoleezza Rice last week seemed easy enough to answer: Did the secretary of State nominee consider interrogation practices such as ``water-boarding,'' in which a prisoner is made to believe he will drown, to be torture?</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="2.5" PS="1.5" SM="0">She declined to answer.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="20.444444444444443" PS="1.5" SM="1">``I'm not going to speak to any specific interrogation techniques,'' Rice said, adding that it was up to the Justice Department to define torture.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="15.482758620689655" PS="1.5" SM="2">About the same time, senators on another committee were asking nearly identical questions and receiving nearly identical answers from Alberto R. Gonzales, President Bush's choice for attorney general.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="14.25" PS="1.5" SM="3">The back-to-back confirmation flare-ups spotlight a problem the Bush administration faces in its policies for detaining and interrogating terrorism suspects.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="18.772727272727273" PS="1.5" SM="4">In the months since the Abu Ghraib prison scandal, the administration has insisted that America does not and will not use torture.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="12.59375" PS="1" SM="5">At the same time, the government has attempted to preserve maximum leeway in the interrogation of terrorism suspects by not drawing a clear line between where rough treatment ends and torture begins.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="21.761904761904763" PS="1.5" SM="25">``What the administration is saying is we're not going to torture people,'' said John C. Yoo, a University of California, Berkeley law professor who as a deputy assistant attorney general during Bush's first term worked on torture policies.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="20.161290322580644" PS="1.5" SM="4">``What the administration does not want to say, and I think for good reasons too, is what methods the United States might or might not use short of torture.''</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="13.055555555555555" PS="1.5" SM="2">Opponents say it is a moral, political and tactical mistake for the United States to blur that line.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="11.454545454545455" PS="1" SM="2">They charge that the administration, while condemning outright torture, deliberately has sought loopholes in laws and treaties that would allow U.S. intelligence officers to use extreme interrogation methods on terrorism suspects held abroad.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="13.542857142857143" PS="1.5" SM="6">To protest the administration's Iraq and anti-terror policies -- and what they charged was the evasiveness of Rice and Gonzales under questioning -- Democratic senators have delayed both confirmation votes until later this week .</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="13.357142857142858" PS="1" SM="5">As a result, the full Senate likely will debate the definition of torture in a session that could embarrass the administration and provide fodder for its international critics.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="19.071428571428573" PS="1.5" SM="2">Ambiguity on prisoner treatment is causing discomfort among some of the administration's allies.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="9.833333333333334" PS="1" SM="3">Current and former military officers in particular fear it will result in the mistreatment of captured American soldiers.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="14.361702127659575" PS="1.5" SM="4">``We've dramatically undermined the war effort by getting on the slippery slope in terms of playing cute with the law, because it's come back to bite us,'' Sen. Lindsey Graham, R-S.C., a former military judge, told Gonzales during a hearing earlier this month.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="20.526315789473685" PS="1.5" SM="4">Graham said he was an ``ardent'' Iraq war supporter and agreed with the controversial administration view that the Geneva Convention -- which bans not only torture but also cruel treatment -- should not apply to terrorists.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="21.4" PS="1" SM="2">However, Graham said, ``Humane treatment is the way to go, the only way we can win this war.''</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="16.208333333333332" PS="1.5" SM="1">Others say the Bush administration is right to preserve some secrecy about its methods for interrogating prisoners, lest terrorists learn how to thwart them.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="21.916666666666668" PS="1.5" SM="12">``The only way we can stop future attacks by al-Qaida is by learning from (captured suspects) what their plans are,'' Yoo said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="17.4375" PS="1" SM="1">``It doesn't make sense to take options off the table at this time.''</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="13.666666666666666" PS="1.5" SM="2">Others have questioned the effectiveness of harsh interrogation methods.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="14.583333333333334" PS="1" SM="3">The FBI has said that the aggressive techniques its agents witnessed at Guantanamo Bay, Cuba, and elsewhere were not effective in producing usable information.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="11.875" PS="1.5" SM="3">The United States has recovered al-Qaida training manuals that tell members what to expect if captured and instruct how not to crack under pressure -- just as the U.S. military trains its members on how to withstand questioning if captured.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="17.0" PS="1.5" SM="12">``The last thing you'd want to do is publicly disclose how you interrogate people, because it would allow them to prepare their people to resist interrogations,'' Yoo said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="16.75" PS="1.5" SM="2">Gonzales made the same argument in a written response to senators' questions after he was faulted for dodging the question during his oral testimony.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="12.625" PS="1.5" SM="3">A web of laws and treaties governs how prisoners are dealt with at home and abroad.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="27.0" PS="1" SM="2">The torture convention bans torture and ``cruel, inhumane or degrading'' treatment.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="12.916666666666666" PS="1" SM="3">The U.S. military code bans cruel treatment of prisoners, and CIA officials can be prosecuted for crimes such as assault when they are abroad.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="12.636363636363637" PS="1" SM="3">The Constitution prohibits cruel and unusual punishment within the United States.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="19.263157894736842" PS="1.5" SM="2">Congress has defined torture as conduct intended to cause ``severe'' pain or suffering, according to the Justice Department, which noted in its latest memo that ``there is no clear, objective, consistent measurement'' of pain.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="11.875" PS="1.5" SM="3">But legal experts differed last week over whether cruel treatment that falls short of torture is prohibited in the case of foreigners held abroad.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="16.223880597014926" PS="1.5" SM="16">In an attempt to clarify American standards on torture and interrogation, Sen. John McCain, R-Ariz. -- who was tortured as a POW in North Vietnam -- and Sen. Joe Lieberman, D-Conn., wrote an unambiguous definition last fall: ``No prisoner shall be subject to torture or cruel, inhumane or degrading treatment or punishment that is prohibited by the Constitution, laws or treaties of the United States.''</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="17.6875" PS="1.5" SM="1">But the language, included in an intelligence bill, was dropped after Rice wrote a letter saying it ``provides legal protections to foreign prisoners to which they are not now entitled.''</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="12.794871794871796" PS="1.5" SM="2">Under fierce confirmation questioning from Sen. Barbara Boxer, D-Calif., Rice offered a different justification for removing the provision: She said it was unnecessary because similar language was already included in a defense spending bill that the president had signed.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="11.444444444444445" PS="1.5" SM="1">But Boxer said that provision had eliminated a specific prohibition on cruelty committed by intelligence officers, who have been implicated in abuses in Iraq, Afghanistan and elsewhere.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="5.666666666666667" PS="1.5" SM="0">(Begin optional trim)</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="10.61111111111111" PS="1.5" SM="4">Human Rights First, a New York-based group, said more than 30 detainees have died in U.S. custody in Iraq and Afghanistan, although not all under the control of intelligence officers or as a result of interrogation.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="23.615384615384617" PS="1.5" SM="0">``Nobody condones or excuses what happened at Abu Ghraib,'' Rice said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="13.416666666666666" PS="1" SM="3">``The problem of how to deal with unlawful combatants, though, in a different kind of war, is frankly a very difficult problem.''</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="14.909090909090908" PS="1.5" SM="0">Rice appears to have had little input on U.S. torture policies.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="16.31578947368421" PS="1.5" SM="3">Moreover, according to Kenneth Roth, executive director of the New York-based Human Rights Watch, it was Rice who in 2003 pushed the Pentagon's general counsel to reaffirm its ban not only on torture but also on cruelty.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="6.666666666666667" PS="1.5" SM="0">(End optional trim)</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="12.666666666666666" PS="1.5" SM="1">Rice and Gonzales are expected to win Senate approval.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="19.956521739130434" PS="1" SM="2">But the battle over what constitutes ``cruel, inhumane or degrading treatment'' -- and whether it is ever allowed -- will continue.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="16.416666666666668" PS="2.25" SM="1">The New York Times said in an editorial for Saturday, Feb. 19:</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="18.72340425531915" PS="1.5" SM="29">Of all the claims of an electoral mandate made by President Bush's supporters, none were as bizarre as the one offered by John Yoo, a former Justice Department lawyer who helped draft the cynical justifications for the illegal detention and torture of &quot;unlawful combatants.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="29.88888888888889" PS="1" SM="14">&quot;The debate is over,&quot; Yoo told The New Yorker, adding: &quot;The issue is dying out.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="30.714285714285715" PS="1" SM="1">The public has had its referendum.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="15.097560975609756" PS="1.5" SM="13">It's hard to know what is most outrageous about those comments -- that Yoo actually believes Americans voted for torturing prisoners or that an official who was at the heart of this appalling mess feels secure enough to say that.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="15.083333333333334" PS="1" SM="2">Certainly the worst possibility is that the public has, indeed, lost interest.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="18.5" PS="1.5" SM="2">The White House has done everything it can to bury the issue.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="12.8" PS="1" SM="5">Nearly a year after the Abu Ghraib scandal broke, the administration still drags its feet on public disclosure, stonewalls congressional requests for documents and suppresses the results of internal investigations.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="25.75" PS="1.5" SM="1">But the issue is as urgent as ever.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="6.769230769230769" PS="1" SM="3">Hundreds of men remain imprisoned at Guantanamo Bay, years after any information they had might have been useful and in defiance of two Supreme Court decisions.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="7.222222222222222" PS="1" SM="2">American soldiers hold thousands of Afghan and Iraqi prisoners under rules that remain murky, to put it charitably.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="13.44" PS="1.5" SM="1">American intelligence is still secretly detaining prisoners -- a practice that has become embarrassing enough for the Central Intelligence Agency to fret publicly about it.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="14.826086956521738" PS="1" SM="5">And the administration continues to insist that the president has an imperial right to sweep aside the law and authorize whatever he wants.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="11.142857142857142" PS="1" SM="0">That includes flouting treaties that prohibit sending prisoners to other countries to be tortured.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="8.833333333333334" PS="1" SM="2">That abhorrent practice has become more common since 9/11 and is reported to include sending prisoners to Syria, a repressive nation counted by Washington as a state sponsor of terrorism.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="13.583333333333334" PS="1.5" SM="1">Members of Congress from both parties are proposing new laws on interrogations.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="7.8" PS="1" SM="1">Their intentions are honorable, and new legislation may be needed.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="13.833333333333334" PS="1" SM="4">But drafts of these measures risk endorsing some terrible practices, as well as the idea that the president can declare himself above the law.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="15.736842105263158" PS="1" SM="1">Anyway, it's too soon for new laws; we still don't know what happened and who approved it.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="14.409090909090908" PS="1.5" SM="3">But that task is now way beyond the purview of the Senate Armed Services Committee, which held important hearings on prisoner abuse.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="11.0" PS="1" SM="0">Republican congressional leaders have made it painfully clear that they will not hold a real investigation.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="11.631578947368421" PS="1" SM="4">And no probe by the executive branch can be credible because the stain of prisoner abuse spreads so far.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="21.375" PS="1" SM="3">The Justice Department can't do it; Attorney General Alberto Gonzales was part of the problem.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="11.25" PS="1.5" SM="3">We strongly agree with the American Bar Association, which wrote to President Bush on Feb. 1 to urge the appointment of an independent, bipartisan commission with subpoena power.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="8.115384615384615" PS="1" SM="2">The bar association talked about Iraqi civilians in military custody, but we believe that a panel should look at all detention centers and all government agencies.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="10.170212765957446" PS="1.5" SM="12">Only a full accounting can begin to heal the nation's image in the world, clarify the rules, punish those responsible, and clear the names of the hundreds of thousands of other uniformed Americans who risk their lives to preserve human dignity and the rule of law.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="11.86111111111111" PS="2.25" SM="27">John Yoo doesn't come across like a war criminal, though that's one of the more flamboyant charges leveled against the smooth young law professor from the University of California, Berkeley's storied Boalt Hall.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="16.72340425531915" PS="1.5" SM="10">With his even tones and calm demeanor, his natty suits and warm charm, the 37-year-old constitutional scholar is the embodiment of ``reasonable,'' not the first person you'd expect to find at the heart of an international fight over terrorism, torture and the American way.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="15.404761904761905" PS="1.5" SM="20">But while working for the Department of Justice after the Sept. 11 terrorist attacks, Yoo helped write a series of legal memos redefining torture and advising President Bush that the Geneva Convention does not apply to members of al-Qaida and the Taliban.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="16.170212765957448" PS="1.5" SM="15">Sen. Edward M. Kennedy, D-Mass., demanded from the Senate floor last month that Yoo and other civilian officials be held accountable for their part in what he called the ``torture scandal'' over treatment of Iraqi detainees by American soldiers at Abu Ghraib prison in Iraq.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="15.647058823529411" PS="1.5" SM="15">Legal scholar Scott Horton, president of the New York-based International League for Human Rights, called last month for Yoo and others to be investigated as war criminals for their part in drafting the memos.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="18.537037037037038" PS="1.5" SM="30">And in a lengthy analysis to be published in the Columbia Law Review this fall, Jeremy Waldron, an author, scholar and Yoo's former colleague at the UC Berkeley School of Law, said that the ``defense of torture'' by Yoo and other prominent lawyers had caused ``dishonor for our profession.''</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="13.685714285714285" PS="1.5" SM="4">A year after the abuses at Abu Ghraib came to light, nearly a year after the torture memos were leaked, debate over how the U.S. government should treat its prisoners shows no sign of abating.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="14.1" PS="1.5" SM="11">``If you read the history of philosophy from the Greeks to the present day, the question of when should we be willing to do something terrible in pursuit of some social good is always posed,'' said Martha Nussbaum, professor of philosophy and law at the University of Chicago.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="18.0" PS="1" SM="0">``It would surprise me very much that it would go away.''</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="25.125" PS="1.5" SM="15">But as Yoo defends the memos, a measured messenger for some of the Bush administration's most controversial policies, he said he is surprised that ``the issue has staying power.''</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="17.857142857142858" PS="1.5" SM="18">The memos about the Geneva Convention and torture are probably the two most controversial documents Yoo worked on with a team of other lawyers when he was a deputy assistant attorney general with the Office of Legal Counsel from 2001 to 2003.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="14.91304347826087" PS="1" SM="15">The former bears Yoo's name; the latter, that of then-Assistant Attorney General Jay S. Bybee, who now sits on the 9th U.S.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="1.5" PS="1" SM="1">Circuit Court of Appeals.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="13.708333333333334" PS="1.5" SM="2">Some human rights advocates argue that the administration commissioned the memos to provide legal cover for increasingly coercive interrogation techniques used against suspected terrorists.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="10.6" PS="1" SM="11">Yoo vehemently denies such accusations.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="18.714285714285715" PS="1" SM="7">The administration has downplayed the memos' import and said that Bush never embraced the views of the lawyers who wrote them.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="14.808510638297872" PS="1.5" SM="19">At the Council on Foreign Relations and West Point, at Columbia Law School and at his own leafy, liberal campus, Yoo argues that the world as America knew it ended on Sept. 11, 2001, and that the rules of war have changed because the enemy has changed.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="17.51219512195122" PS="1.5" SM="13">``Al Qaeda as a non-state terror organization is not covered'' by laws, such as the Geneva Convention, that are honored when the United States fights a bona fide state, Yoo argued earlier this month during a debate at Berkeley.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="16.666666666666668" PS="1" SM="1">Thus, ``our leaders have the option to decide what system ought to apply.''</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="14.857142857142858" PS="1.5" SM="35">The debate was a two-on-one bruising in front of an audience that politely applauded Yoo while cheering his detractors, an event in which a law student dressed as an Iraqi torture victim greeted spectators with a sign that read, ``War criminal John Yoo facilitated torture: He belongs in a prison not a law school.''</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="11.0" PS="1.5" SM="3">But a funny thing happened near the end of the forum.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="13.161290322580646" PS="1" SM="5">Tom Farer, dean of the Graduate School of International Studies at the University of Denver, was deep into a verbal salvo when he exhausted his allotted time but not his argument.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="8.8125" PS="1" SM="12">Yoo gave up one of his own precious minutes so that Farer could continue pummeling him.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="18.235294117647058" PS="1.5" SM="11">``John cedes a minute,'' Farer said with a smile before launching back into his attack.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="35.5" PS="1" SM="11">``John is a mensch.''</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="11.1" PS="1.5" SM="0">Farer would find little argument, at least on that point.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="10.461538461538462" PS="1" SM="15">Yoo inspires deep loyalty in friends, mute collegiality in many fellow scholars (``You know, I'd really rather not talk about him'') and an awkward mixture of kindness and dread in some of his most vocal critics.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="9.67741935483871" PS="1.5" SM="13">And although Boalt students circulated a petition last year demanding that Yoo recant his positions or resign, he also has charmed many of his liberal pupils with a ready classroom wit.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="9.542857142857143" PS="1" SM="3">Others have been disappointed after signing up for one of his courses so they could hear what a fire-breathing conservative actually sounds like only to find a mild-mannered professor at the lectern, accessible and friendly.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="17.964285714285715" PS="1.5" SM="4">``A lot of the concern is that people think he's dead wrong,'' said Ralph Steinhardt, professor of law and international affairs at George Washington University.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="17.727272727272727" PS="1" SM="3">``But you have to understand, from a personal standpoint, he's a nice guy, has a good sense of humor, dresses nicely and is as smart as the day is long.''</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="5.666666666666667" PS="1.5" SM="0">(Begin optional trim)</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="12.771428571428572" PS="1.5" SM="14">A Korean immigrant who came to this country with his parents when he was 3 months old, Yoo has been a prolific writer of journalism and scholarship since his undergraduate days on the Harvard Crimson.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="8.791666666666666" PS="1" SM="4">He is a regular contributor to the opinion pages of major newspapers, including the Los Angeles Times, New York Times and Wall Street Journal.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="12.75" PS="1.5" SM="12">Yoo began teaching constitutional and international law at UC Berkeley in 1993.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="10.588235294117647" PS="1" SM="4">But he has spent many of the subsequent years bouncing back and forth between academia and government.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="11.588235294117647" PS="1" SM="12">Shortly after Yoo took the Berkeley job, Supreme Court Justice Clarence Thomas tapped him for a clerkship.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="15.625" PS="1.5" SM="3">When his clerkship with Thomas ended, he headed to the U.S. Senate Committee on the Judiciary, where he served as general counsel and helped Sen. Orrin G. Hatch, R-Utah, with his speeches.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="26.6" PS="1" SM="12">Hatch describes Yoo as ``a terrific human being.''</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="24.375" PS="1" SM="11">Yoo calls Hatch ``a genuine softie.''</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="10.511627906976743" PS="1.5" SM="28">Yoo completed a public service trifecta -- working in all three branches of government -- with a stint in the Office of Legal Counsel, part of the Department of Justice overseen by then-Attorney General John Ashcroft, before returning to Boalt Hall last year.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="13.0" PS="1.5" SM="13">It was there in the uncertain months after Sept. 11 that Yoo worked on the memos that transformed him from a rising star in conservative legal circles to a lightning rod for international controversy.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="6.666666666666667" PS="1.5" SM="0">(End optional trim)</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="10.903225806451612" PS="1.5" SM="5">Many legal scholars and human rights activists -- along with Berkeley students -- draw a straight line linking the memos and alleged prisoner abuses in Iraq and Afghanistan and at Guantanamo.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="14.454545454545455" PS="1" SM="11">Yoo argues that they do not understand how government really works.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="16.82758620689655" PS="1.5" SM="12">``It's a stretch to say that a very limited, tightly held memo somehow translated into orders that soldiers on the ground violated human rights,'' Yoo said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="27.9" PS="1" SM="2">``That's the difference between law and policy.''</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="17.736842105263158" PS="1.5" SM="16">To his critics, such an argument is disingenuous, but Yoo continues to defend the memos because he feels ``some sense of obligation to explain to the public why government reached some of the conclusions it did.''</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="19.375" PS="1.5" SM="1">``No one goes into government wanting to address these kinds of questions,'' he said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="20.0" PS="1" SM="0">``But we were attacked on Sept. 11 with devastating results.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="13.733333333333333" PS="1" SM="1">Our government has to think about these things in order to protect the country.''</sentence>
	</Sentences>
</Topic>
