<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<Topic id="D0908B">
	<Sentences>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="9.227272727272727" PS="3.00765306122449" SM="38">The leader of Nepal, King Gyanendra, unexpectedly dissolved the government and claimed absolute power Tuesday, justifying the moves as necessary to restore peace and democracy in the face of a Maoist insurgency that has spread to nearly every corner of the picturesque Himalayan nation.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="6.125" PS="2.0051020408163267" SM="1">Political opponents described the action as a coup.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="5.68" PS="1.336734693877551" SM="2">International air service was suspended, phone and Internet connections were cut and the army was reported to be patrolling streets in the capital of Katmandu.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="7.0" PS="1.336734693877551" SM="2">Security personnel surrounded the home of the prime minister, Sher Bahadur Deuba, according to news agency reports.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="9.2" PS="2.0051020408163267" SM="13">In a rare televised address, Gyanendra, 58, said he had decided to dissolve the government -- the second time he has done so in the past three years -- because it had failed in its duty to hold parliamentary elections or end the Maoist rebellion.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="10.291666666666666" PS="1.336734693877551" SM="1">He said he would form a new cabinet under his leadership and vowed to restore ``effective democracy within the next three years.''</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="6.3428571428571425" PS="2.0051020408163267" SM="14">But the king also imposed a state of emergency and suspended a number of constitutional liberties, including the rights to free speech, assembly and privacy, according a statement that was summarized by the Associated Press.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="8.79245283018868" PS="2.0051020408163267" SM="3">Taken together, the moves added to the sense in the region that Nepal is in a downward spiral, with no clear path toward repairing its dysfunctional politics or bringing an end to the violence that has claimed an estimated 10,000 lives since the Maoists launched their ``people's war'' in 1996.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="8.6" PS="2.0051020408163267" SM="24">Gyanendra's announcement poses a policy challenge for the United States, which has provided Nepali security forces with about $22 million in light weaponry and other forms of military aid during the past several years.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="8.395348837209303" PS="1.336734693877551" SM="3">Human rights groups have condemned both sides in the conflict for widespread abuses, but U.S. officials have justified the aid on the grounds that without it, the Maoists might win -- and Nepal could join the roster of failed states hospitable to terrorism.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="13.2" PS="2.0051020408163267" SM="1">In Katmandu this afternoon, the U.S. Embassy issued a statement expressing concern at the ``apparent setback for democracy'' and said its diplomats would be ``consulting with Washington'' on an appropriate response.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="8.853658536585366" PS="2.0051020408163267" SM="15">The conflict is also of deep concern to neighboring India, which is waging its own struggle against Maoist rebels -- some with links to the Nepali insurgents -- in a number of eastern states and has provided Nepal with military aid.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="13.685714285714285" PS="1.336734693877551" SM="17">In a strongly worded statement Tuesday, India's Foreign Ministry condemned Gyanendra's announcement as ``a serious setback to the cause of democracy in Nepal'' and ``a cause of grave concern.''</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="5.933333333333334" PS="2.0051020408163267" SM="2">With no phone or Internet links to Katmandu, details of the situation there were sketchy.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="8.971428571428572" PS="1.336734693877551" SM="1">A New Delhi-based Western diplomat who spoke with a colleague in Katmandu Tuesday afternoon said the colleague had described the city as ``relatively calm,'' with streets filled with traffic and shops operating normally.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="7.666666666666667" PS="1.336734693877551" SM="0">But the mood was clearly tense.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="4.258064516129032" PS="1.336734693877551" SM="2">Anticipating possible unrest, residents formed long lines at grocery stores and gas stations to stock up on supplies, and armored vehicles with mounted machine guns patrolled the streets, news agencies reported.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="4.92" PS="2.0051020408163267" SM="0">Against that backdrop, some international air carriers canceled their flights into the capital, while others were turned back by Nepalese authorities before they could land.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="12.36" PS="2.0051020408163267" SM="13">For the past two centuries, Gyanendra's family has dominated Nepal, a country of 25 million people that is as impoverished as it is breathtaking.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="13.357142857142858" PS="1.336734693877551" SM="48">The king's action Tuesday effectively restored the monarchy to the position of absolute power it occupied before Gyanendra's elder brother, King Birendra, established democracy in 1990.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="4.54054054054054" PS="2.272959183673469" SM="3">China respects the choice of  Nepalese in developing their own country and sincerely wishes the  nation to realize social security, economic development and ethnic pacification, Foreign Ministry spokesman Kong Quan told a regular  press conference here Tuesday.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="14.153846153846153" PS="1.5153061224489794" SM="27">He made this remark when asked to comment on Nepal's King  Gyanendra's Tuesday announcement of dissolving the coalition  government led by Prime Minister Sher Bahadur Deuba and forming a  new government under his own &quot;chairmanship&quot;.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="12.88888888888889" PS="1.5153061224489794" SM="4">Calling this decision &quot;an internal affair of Nepal,&quot; Kong said  that China will respect Nepalese people's option on how to develop their own country.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="10.555555555555555" PS="1.5153061224489794" SM="13">Deuba was appointed prime minister by Gyanendra on June 2, 2004, and sworn in on July 5, 2004.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="10.472222222222221" PS="2.272959183673469" SM="26">UN Secretary General Kofi Annan on  Tuesday expressed deep concern over events in Nepal and urged a  return to democracy, after King Gyanendra dismissed the country's  coalition government and imposed an indefinite state of emergency.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="10.577777777777778" PS="1.5153061224489794" SM="4">&quot;The secretary general is deeply concerned at the actions taken  by the constitutional monarchy in Nepal on Tuesday to dissolve the  government, impose a state of emergency and suspend civil liberties  and freedom of expression,&quot; UN spokesman Fred Eckhard said in a  statement.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="11.76" PS="2.25" SM="12">The British government expressed grave concerns Tuesday about political developments in Nepal, after the king dismissed the prime minister and declared a state of emergency.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="12.761904761904763" PS="1.5" SM="25">Foreign Office Minister Douglas Alexander summoned the Nepalese ambassador in London and conveyed Britain's concern at King Gyanendra's actions.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="14.826086956521738" PS="1.5" SM="16">&quot;I am extremely concerned to hear of the king of Nepal's dismissal of his prime minister this morning,&quot; said Alexander.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="9.772727272727273" PS="1.5" SM="2">&quot;This action will increase the risk of instability in Nepal, undermining the institutions of democracy and constitutional monarchy in the country.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="8.391304347826088" PS="1.0" SM="2">We call for the immediate restitution of multiparty democracy, and appeal for calm and restraint on all sides during this difficult time.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="10.955555555555556" PS="1.5" SM="49">It was the second time in three years that the king has taken control of the tiny South Asian constitutional monarchy, a throwback to the era of absolute power enjoyed by Nepal's monarchs before King Birendra, Gyanendra's elder brother, introduced democracy in 1990.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="9.478260869565217" PS="1.5" SM="23">King Gyanendra denied his takeover was a coup, although soldiers surrounded the houses of Prime Minister Sher Bahadur Deuba and other government leaders.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="2.6923076923076925" PS="1.0" SM="0">Telephone and Internet lines were snapped, flights diverted and civil liberties severely curtailed.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="15.625" PS="2.272959183673469" SM="24">The United States said Tuesday it was  &quot;deeply troubled&quot; by an apparent setback to democracy in Nepal,  where King Gyanendra has dismissed the government and imposed a  state of emergency.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="10.837837837837839" PS="2.5255102040816326" SM="34">Nepal's King Gyanendra named a new Cabinet Wednesday, a day after dismissing the government and declaring absolute power in a surprise move that he said was aimed at restoring democracy and ending a nine-year Maoist rebellion.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="6.761904761904762" PS="1.683673469387755" SM="2">Contact with the outside world remained limited and telephone and Internet service, severed on Tuesday, had yet to be fully restored.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="4.45" PS="1.1224489795918366" SM="1">Dozens of politicians have been arrested and many others have gone into hiding, an opposition politician told the Associated Press.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="5.0" PS="1.1224489795918366" SM="0">Soldiers and riot police patrolled the capital, Katmandu.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="5.0" PS="1.683673469387755" SM="3">There were no reports of serious unrest, however, and international flights to Katmandu resumed on a limited basis.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="4.647058823529412" PS="1.1224489795918366" SM="1">Traffic was moving normally in the crowded capital and most shops were open, according to news reports.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="9.666666666666666" PS="1.683673469387755" SM="11">State radio said that Gyanendra would head the 10-member Cabinet but gave few other details.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="13.130434782608695" PS="1.1224489795918366" SM="11">``The king has expressed confidence that everyone will support and cooperate with the new Cabinet,'' the palace said in a statement.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="10.686274509803921" PS="1.683673469387755" SM="13">In announcing his decision on Tuesday, Gyanendra said he was dissolving the government and firing the prime minister -- for the second time in three years -- because the government had failed in its duty to hold parliamentary elections and curb the Maoist insurgency, in which about 10,000 people have died.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="6.875" PS="1.1224489795918366" SM="1">He vowed to restore democracy in three years.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="13.466666666666667" PS="1.683673469387755" SM="2">Nepal's new home minister, Dan Bahadur Shahi, who was sworn in on Wednesday, said the government would soon begin laying the groundwork for resuming peace talks with the Maoists.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="14.214285714285714" PS="1.1224489795918366" SM="13">``The king has the chief executive authority now, so it will be easier for the rebels to come for peace talks,'' Shahi said on state radio.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="12.777777777777779" PS="1.1224489795918366" SM="0">``It is what they have been wanting.''</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="13.105263157894736" PS="1.683673469387755" SM="26">Gyanendra's power grab has been widely condemned by Nepal's allies, including the United States, Britain and India, all of which have been providing the government with various forms of aid in its struggle against the rebels.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="9.25925925925926" PS="1.1224489795918366" SM="14">India's Foreign Ministry announced Wednesday that Prime Minister Manmohan Singh would not attend a regional summit in Bangladesh, where Gyanendra had been planning to represent Nepal.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="5.333333333333333" PS="1.1224489795918366" SM="0">Bangladesh postponed the summit in response.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="7.368421052631579" PS="1.683673469387755" SM="14">In addition to dissolving the government, Gyanendra suspended a number of key civil liberties, including freedom of the press.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="7.9393939393939394" PS="1.1224489795918366" SM="2">Such measures ``put the Nepalese people at even greater risk of human rights abuses,'' said a statement issued jointly by Amnesty International, Human Rights Watch and the International Commission of Jurists.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="10.74074074074074" PS="2.548469387755102" SM="27">The European Union on Wednesday joined  international condemnation of Nepalese King Gyanendra's dismissal of  his government and swearing in of a new cabinet dominated by  royalists.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="13.4" PS="1.6989795918367347" SM="2">The EU's Luxembourg presidency called for a &quot;speedy&quot; return to  multi-party democracy.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="14.193548387096774" PS="1.6989795918367347" SM="24">&quot;The EU is deeply concerned about the dissolution of the  multiparty government in Nepal and the decision by the king to  assume executive powers,&quot; it said in a statement.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="8.88888888888889" PS="1.6989795918367347" SM="1">&quot;This represents a serious setback to multiparty democracy.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="16.466666666666665" PS="1.1326530612244898" SM="0">The  EU has consistently supported multiparty democracy and  constitutional monarchy in Nepal,&quot; it said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="9.548387096774194" PS="1.6989795918367347" SM="15">Gyanendra said he fired the government of Prime Minister Sher  Bahadur Deuba for failing to hold elections or to bring peace to a  country racked by an increasingly deadly Maoist revolt.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="7.333333333333333" PS="1.6989795918367347" SM="3">The monarch, vaulted to the throne four years ago by a palace  massacre that wiped out most of the royal family, pledged to  &quot;restore democracy and law and order in the country in the next  three years.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="11.875" PS="1.6989795918367347" SM="0">The EU said this was not good enough.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="9.214285714285714" PS="1.1326530612244898" SM="1">&quot;In the present situation,  the EU sees no alternative to a broad-based government.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="2.0" PS="1.1326530612244898" SM="0">...</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="13.291666666666666" PS="1.1326530612244898" SM="3">The EU  calls for the speedy restoration of multiparty democracy in Nepal to  better meet the aspirations of the Nepalese people,&quot; it said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="8.659090909090908" PS="1.6989795918367347" SM="5">&quot;The EU continues to judge that there can be no acceptable  military solution to Nepal's problems and that any search for a  solution by military means by either side will only add to and  prolong the suffering of the Nepalese people.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="11.84" PS="2.502551020408163" SM="25">Pakistani Prime Minister Shaukat  Aziz on Thursday had a telephonic conversation with King Gyanendra Bir Bikram Shah Dev of Nepal, a Foreign Office spokesman said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="7.411764705882353" PS="1.6683673469387754" SM="3">Matters relating to the holding of the 13th South Asian  Association for Regional Cooperation (SAARC) Summit as well as  Pakistan-Nepal relations were discussed, the spokesman said in a  press release issued here on Thursday.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="10.391304347826088" PS="1.6683673469387754" SM="26">King Gyanendra shared Prime Minister Shaukat Aziz's  disappointment over the postponement of the SAARC Summit and  expressed full confidence in Pakistan to set up new dates for the  summit and assured that he would certainly come to represent Nepal at the summit, the spokesman said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="8.0" PS="1.6683673469387754" SM="1">Prime Minister Shaukat Aziz is the current chairman of SAARC.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="15.842105263157896" PS="1.6683673469387754" SM="23">The prime minister conveyed to King Gyanendra that recent  developments in Nepal were its internal matter, the spokesman said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="7.333333333333333" PS="1.6683673469387754" SM="4">Pakistan strictly adheres to the principles of non-intervention on and non-interference in the internal affairs of states and  Pakistan has consistently upheld these principles, Shaukat Aziz  said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="12.56" PS="1.6683673469387754" SM="26">The prime minister also assured King Gyanendra of Pakistan's  support for the unity, sovereignty, territorial integrity and  political independence of the Kingdom of Nepal.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="8.9375" PS="1.6683673469387754" SM="2">Pakistan and Nepal share the objective of combating terrorism  in all its forms and manifestations, the spokesman said, adding  Pakistan will continue to assist Nepal in the economic, social and technical fields.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="11.172413793103448" PS="2.548469387755102" SM="37">Japan, the top donor to aid-dependent  Nepal, on Thursday voiced concern at King Gyanendra's power grab and  urged him to restore democracy and release any detained political  leaders.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="13.692307692307692" PS="1.6989795918367347" SM="16">Joining a chorus of international condemnation over the king's  sacking of the government, Japan said it hoped &quot;Nepal will recover  its peace and stability as soon as possible on the basis of  democracy and constitutional monarchy.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="9.375" PS="1.6989795918367347" SM="2">&quot;If political leaders are being detained, the government of  Japan is deeply concerned about the situation and strongly urges  that they be released and that the freedom guaranteed by the  constitution restored promptly,&quot; a foreign ministry statement said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="9.058823529411764" PS="1.6989795918367347" SM="2">Japan also urged Maoist rebels fighting to overthrow the  monarchy &quot;to achieve peace through dialogue.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="6.594594594594595" PS="1.6989795918367347" SM="2">Japan gave Nepal close to four billion yen (38.5 million  dollars) in grant aid in the 2003 fiscal year and the following year  relieved 21 billion yen (202.5 million dollars) of its debt, the  Japanese government says.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="12.4" PS="1.6989795918367347" SM="23">King Gyanendra on Tuesday sacked prime minister Sher Bahadur  Deuba for the second time in three years and assumed control.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="5.578947368421052" PS="1.1326530612244898" SM="2">He  accused elected leaders of failing to control the Maoist uprising  which has claimed some 11,000 lives since 1996.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="11.552631578947368" PS="2.548469387755102" SM="36">A power grab by Nepal's King Gyanendra provoked condemnation from his most influential allies, the United States and India, but China remained neutral _ a sign of Beijing's growing ties with the Himalayan nation, some analysts say.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="15.96" PS="1.6989795918367347" SM="14">Beijing said Gyanendra's move to dismiss the government and impose a state of emergency in Nepal last Tuesday was an &quot;internal matter.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="9.803921568627452" PS="1.6989795918367347" SM="28">China's reaction, coupled with a recent move by Gyanendra to close the Nepal office of the Tibetan spiritual leader-in-exile, the Dalai Lama _ whom Beijing despises and labels a dangerous separatist _ has prompted speculation among Indian analysts that the king wants to enlist China's support in fighting the Maoist rebels.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="10.807692307692308" PS="1.6989795918367347" SM="12">Gyanendra &quot;must have factored in China into his calculations,&quot; said Kalim Bahadur, a Nepal expert and retired professor of international relations in New Delhi.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="12.333333333333334" PS="1.6989795918367347" SM="2">&quot;Any intelligent ruler in Nepal would try to take advantage of its strategic position,&quot; he said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="15.25" PS="1.1326530612244898" SM="11">&quot;And Gyanendra is a clever man.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="11.844444444444445" PS="1.6989795918367347" SM="6">China's Foreign Ministry spokesman Kong Quan said on Thursday he had no information on whether Nepal _ a mountainous nation sandwiched between India and China _ had asked for Beijing's help in the fight against the rebels, but he was quick to condemn the guerrillas.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="10.26086956521739" PS="1.6989795918367347" SM="2">Although Nepal's Maoist rebels claim to be inspired by Chinese revolutionary leader Mao Zedong, Beijing has long distanced itself from the insurgents.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="10.923076923076923" PS="1.6989795918367347" SM="2">&quot;They steal the name ... (of) China's great leader, Mao Zedong.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="13.833333333333334" PS="1.1326530612244898" SM="0">We feel angry,&quot; Kong said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="10.947368421052632" PS="1.6989795918367347" SM="1">He added that as &quot;a close neighbor of Nepal, China considers its peace and stability most important.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="1.0" PS="1.6989795918367347" SM="0">S.D.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="11.911764705882353" PS="1.1326530612244898" SM="14">Muni, a former Indian ambassador to Nepal, said Beijing has become increasingly concerned by growing U.S.-Nepal ties, which the government of Prime Minister Sher Bahadur Deuba _ dismissed by Gyanendra on Tuesday _ had actively sought.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="13.166666666666666" PS="1.6989795918367347" SM="1">&quot;They (the Chinese) viewed Deuba as too close to India and the United States,&quot; he said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="10.433333333333334" PS="1.6989795918367347" SM="15">The closing of the Dalai Lama's office and a recent crackdown on Tibetan refugees _ both at the instigation of the king _ could reflect closer ties with Beijing, Muni said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="1.4285714285714286" PS="1.6989795918367347" SM="0">Communist troops marched into Tibet in 1950.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="7.368421052631579" PS="1.1326530612244898" SM="2">Beijing says it has been part of China for centuries and has spent decades trying to suppress pro-independence sentiment.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="7.95" PS="1.1326530612244898" SM="3">In the past, Katmandu had been tolerant of Tibetans fleeing China's communist rule, with thousands of them settling there.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="11.1875" PS="1.6989795918367347" SM="23">Gyanendra's shift toward China echoes similar moves his father, King Mahendra, made in the 1960s.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="7.590909090909091" PS="1.1326530612244898" SM="3">Mahendra, himself an absolute monarch, also sought to forge closer ties with China to counter India's dominance in the Himalayan kingdom.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="9.461538461538462" PS="1.6989795918367347" SM="0">At the time, Beijing was eager for improved relations with Nepal as a wedge against India with whom it fought a brief border war in 1962.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="11.4" PS="1.6989795918367347" SM="39">But if the king hopes to get China on board against the rebels, he'll have to do so without offending Nepal's biggest backers _ India and the United States, both of which have strongly criticized Gyanendra's power play.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="10.133333333333333" PS="1.6989795918367347" SM="5">The United States has given Katmandu millions of dollars in military and development aid since Nepal signed on to Washington's war on terror following the Sept. 11, 2001 attacks.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="7.714285714285714" PS="1.6989795918367347" SM="2">So far, the Americans haven't made any decision on the continuation of aid.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="12.588235294117647" PS="1.1326530612244898" SM="1">&quot;It's a fluid situation,&quot; said David Kennedy, spokesman at U.S. Embassy in New Delhi.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="16.333333333333332" PS="1.6989795918367347" SM="15">Kennedy said the U.S. ambassador met the king's newly appointed foreign minister and conveyed Washington's &quot;concerns about the setback to democracy in Nepal.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="12.136363636363637" PS="1.6989795918367347" SM="3">India has also held off commenting on the status of military aid to Nepal and has established contacts with the new government.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="11.631578947368421" PS="1.6989795918367347" SM="2">New Delhi wants to secure its border and minimize links between Nepal's rebels and its own Maoist insurgents.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="9.621621621621621" PS="1.1326530612244898" SM="2">India's interests in the Himalayan nation actually go beyond strategic concerns, drawing from the two neighbors' historical ties, and it is unlikely to back away from support for Nepal in its fight against the Maoist rebels.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="14.25" PS="1.6989795918367347" SM="12">&quot;India will try to engage the king.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="7.55" PS="1.1326530612244898" SM="1">It will not do anything dramatic,&quot; said Udai Bhaskar at the New Delhi-based Institute of Defense and Strategic Analysis.</sentence>
	</Sentences>
</Topic>
