<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<Topic id="D0903A">
	<Sentences>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="14.03448275862069" PS="2.6767241379310347" SM="26">Spain has provided a US$54.4 million (euro43.4 million) long-term loan to fund a solar power project for remote villages in the central and southern Philippines, officials said Friday.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="10.447368421052632" PS="1.7844827586206897" SM="7">The four-year project, which began in 2003, will initially cover communities that have benefited from the government's agrarian reform program in 16 provinces on the main southern island of Mindanao, acting Land Reform Secretary Nasser Pangandaman said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="16.657894736842106" PS="1.7844827586206897" SM="30">The project will provide electricity for the first time to more than 277,900 rural households, plus schools, potable water systems and health, village and livelihood centers, said Dioscora Tobias of the government's Solar Power Technology Support project.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="15.32" PS="1.7844827586206897" SM="5">The Philippines will provide a US$8.7 million (euro6.9 million) counterpart fund for the project, which will also help the country diversify its energy sources.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="16.166666666666668" PS="1.7844827586206897" SM="26">Tobias, who monitors and evaluates the solar power project, said it also will provide schools in remote areas with television sets and video players to be used as teaching aids.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="16.4" PS="1.7844827586206897" SM="37">A rural household with a solar panel installed typically will have enough electricity to power four light bulbs and backup batteries to provide power for a week of bad weather.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="18.666666666666668" PS="1.1896551724137931" SM="1">Health centers also will be provided with refrigerators for vaccines, Tobias said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="14.11111111111111" PS="2.7155172413793105" SM="25">As prices for coal, natural gas and oil have soared, solar power has been getting perhaps its most serious look from investors since President Carter pulled on a cardigan and asked Americans to damp their furnaces.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="16.533333333333335" PS="1.8103448275862069" SM="15">The new interest means that the handful of domestic solar stocks has been surging, too.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="19.83783783783784" PS="1.8103448275862069" SM="41">Over the last year, the shares of Evergreen Solar, DayStar Technologies, Energy Conversion Devices and Spire -- all small domestic companies that make equipment for converting solar power into electricity -- have more than doubled in price.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="14.125" PS="1.206896551724138" SM="2">In August, Cypress Semiconductor said it would try to raise as much as $100 million in an initial public offering for its SunPower subsidiary.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="15.975" PS="1.8103448275862069" SM="19">&quot;The solar market is projected to grow 35 percent a year for the next three to five years,&quot; said Walter V. Nasdeo, managing director of Ardour Capital, an investment bank in New York that specializes in energy companies.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="15.052631578947368" PS="1.206896551724138" SM="11">&quot;As these technologies get better, we're seeing things being developed like solar panels integrated into roofing tiles.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="11.0" PS="1.206896551724138" SM="0">That way, they don't look like a science project hanging on your roof.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="13.115384615384615" PS="1.8103448275862069" SM="8">Back in the days of Carter's cardigan, the country was mired in an energy crisis, with an oil embargo and long lines at gas stations.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="7.214285714285714" PS="1.206896551724138" SM="3">Today, tumult in oil-producing places like the Middle East and Venezuela is roiling markets.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="11.8125" PS="1.206896551724138" SM="6">Strong demand for electricity has contributed to increases in the prices of coal and natural gas.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="7.666666666666667" PS="1.206896551724138" SM="4">And Hurricane Katrina, of course, has worsened the situation.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="17.869565217391305" PS="1.206896551724138" SM="14">Yet these dire developments have been a boon for companies that make devices like silicon wafers and rooftop panels that convert solar energy.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="15.066666666666666" PS="1.8103448275862069" SM="15">Until recently, the economics of the solar business did not tempt many consumers or investors.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="8.942857142857143" PS="1.206896551724138" SM="5">Without government or utility subsidies, the $20,000 to $25,000 that it costs to buy and install a typical home solar-power system may be too high to be recouped at the end of a 30-year mortgage.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="21.3125" PS="1.8103448275862069" SM="14">But government help, combined with the recent climb in energy prices, has made solar more appealing.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="8.058823529411764" PS="1.206896551724138" SM="5">Some states offer big subsidies, helping to defray much of the initial cost of a home system.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="11.5" PS="1.8103448275862069" SM="0">Some electric utilities also offer incentives.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="9.0" PS="1.206896551724138" SM="1">In theory, solar-energy systems free them from having to invest in additional generating capacity.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="14.580645161290322" PS="1.206896551724138" SM="24">Homeowners typically connect their systems to the power grid and buy electricity when their panels do not produce enough power; they sell electricity to their utility when they have a surplus.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="14.294117647058824" PS="1.8103448275862069" SM="47">Federal law requires utilities to buy excess power generated by consumers using solar power, although rates vary from state to state, said Joseph E. Schwartz, chief executive and technical editor of Home Power magazine.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="12.387096774193548" PS="1.206896551724138" SM="10">And the new federal energy law, signed by President Bush last month, includes a tax credit of as much as $2,000 for the purchase and installation of a residential solar-power system.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="13.644444444444444" PS="1.8103448275862069" SM="29">&quot;Despite all of the concerns about imported oil and climate change, most people make their decision to install solar based on whether they're going to save money,&quot; said Steven C. Taub, director of emerging power generation technologies at Cambridge Energy Research Associates.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="27.0" PS="1.8103448275862069" SM="23">In states with generous subsidies, he said, solar power may be attractive for many consumers.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="12.766666666666667" PS="1.206896551724138" SM="6">In New Jersey, for example, subsidies can cover as much as 70 percent of the cost, leaving consumers with a net cost of about $6,000 on a typical home system.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="14.925925925925926" PS="1.8103448275862069" SM="18">Though the four little domestic solar-power companies stand to benefit from new demand for power, they account for only a fraction of the world's solar-device production.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="11.647058823529411" PS="1.206896551724138" SM="7">The biggest of the four, Energy Conversion Devices, has a market capitalization of only about $1.1 billion.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="14.142857142857142" PS="1.8103448275862069" SM="17">Giants like BP and Royal Dutch Shell in the energy industry, or Sharp and Kyocera in electronics, make most solar gear.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="18.363636363636363" PS="1.206896551724138" SM="28">Last year, the solar industry produced 1,195 megawatts of new electricity-generation capacity, about the equivalent of one large power plant, Taub said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="17.555555555555557" PS="1.206896551724138" SM="1">Sharp alone accounted for about 325 megawatts, he said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="15.666666666666666" PS="1.8103448275862069" SM="15">Yet solar energy conversion is a tiny part of these hefty companies' sales, so the little independents are a purer play.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="14.85" PS="1.206896551724138" SM="28">The business lines of Evergreen and DayStar are almost entirely related to solar power (as are those of Cypress' SunPower).</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="19.0" PS="1.206896551724138" SM="13">Energy Conversion Devices has other products, but its largest subsidiary, United Solar Ovonics, also known as Uni-Solar, is a solar-power business.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="18.0" PS="1.206896551724138" SM="20">And Spire's solar division accounted for an average of 40 percent of the company's sales in 2003 and 2004.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="6.333333333333333" PS="1.8103448275862069" SM="1">Of course, investing in small-capitalization stocks can be risky.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="9.722222222222221" PS="1.206896551724138" SM="4">Besides being microbes in an industry dominated by giants, none of the four independents were profitable last year.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="8.61111111111111" PS="1.206896551724138" SM="2">Two have short histories as public companies: Evergreen went public in 2002, and DayStar did so last year.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="15.263157894736842" PS="1.206896551724138" SM="12">All but Spire are developing new solar technologies, and there is no guarantee that customers will embrace their innovations.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="18.214285714285715" PS="1.8103448275862069" SM="26">Understanding their plans requires a bit of knowledge about the way solar power works.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="19.103448275862068" PS="1.206896551724138" SM="17">The most popular means of converting the sun's energy into electricity -- silicon-based solar panels -- has progressed over the last three decades but has not changed radically.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="19.846153846153847" PS="1.206896551724138" SM="11">Silicon is used to make wafers, which are wired to create solar cells.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="17.0" PS="1.206896551724138" SM="15">These form the building blocks for solar panels, which look like big storm windows as they sit atop roofs and soak up the sun.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="12.387096774193548" PS="1.8103448275862069" SM="4">A silicon shortage has driven up the cost of solar-grade silicon by more than 60 percent over the last two years, said Michael Rogol, an analyst at Credit Lyonnais Securities Asia.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="11.904761904761905" PS="1.206896551724138" SM="1">That offers an opportunity to companies like Evergreen and SunPower that have devised more efficient ways to use silicon, he said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="11.285714285714286" PS="1.8103448275862069" SM="1">Evergreen's wafer-making method consumes about a third less silicon than usual, said Richard M. Feldt, its president and chief executive.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="5.3" PS="1.206896551724138" SM="4">Many competitors slice blocks of silicon into wafers; that creates waste in the same way a lumberyard spits out sawdust.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="9.444444444444445" PS="1.206896551724138" SM="3">Evergreen's method, which draws out long ribbons of silicon and slices them with lasers, produces less waste.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="5.117647058823529" PS="1.8103448275862069" SM="3">Executives at Cypress Semiconductor in Sunnyvale, Calif., declined to be interviewed because of an impending stock offering.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="15.074074074074074" PS="1.206896551724138" SM="15">But Rogol said its SunPower unit makes the industry's most efficient cells, yielding 210 watts of power a square meter, versus 180 for a typical cell.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="13.714285714285714" PS="1.8103448275862069" SM="1">DayStar, for its part, uses no silicon, while Uni-Solar uses far less than average.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="8.0" PS="1.206896551724138" SM="14">DayStar, based in Halfmoon, N.Y., applies a thin film of several elements, including copper, to backings such as titanium foil to create flexible solar cells.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="12.714285714285714" PS="1.8103448275862069" SM="1">Uni-Solar marries the thin-film method with silicon.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="19.3" PS="1.206896551724138" SM="1">&quot;Our panels are typically 18 feet long with an adhesive on the back,&quot; said Subhendu Guha, its president.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="16.666666666666668" PS="1.206896551724138" SM="1">&quot;You can stick it directly onto the roof.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="15.416666666666666" PS="1.206896551724138" SM="2">With the traditional product, you have to have a support structure.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="16.181818181818183" PS="1.8103448275862069" SM="12">Spire, in Bedford, Mass., produces neither silicon wafers nor solar cells.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="26.0" PS="1.206896551724138" SM="13">It makes machinery for building and testing solar panels.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="9.25" PS="1.206896551724138" SM="4">In 1999, that enabled it to work with the city of Chicago to equip and run a panel factory there.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="11.333333333333334" PS="1.206896551724138" SM="6">Roger G. Little, Spire's chairman and chief executive, says he sees the Chicago venture as a harbinger of Spire's future; he aims to increase panel production over the next two years.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="9.428571428571429" PS="1.8103448275862069" SM="0">That would return Spire to its roots.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="15.916666666666666" PS="1.206896551724138" SM="2">The company started in 1969; early on, it concentrated on solar-power conversion.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="17.863636363636363" PS="1.206896551724138" SM="30">It diversified into biomedical equipment and electronics after the energy crisis of the late 1970s abated and enthusiasm for solar power cooled.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="17.285714285714285" PS="1.206896551724138" SM="1">&quot;The market tanked,&quot; Little recalled.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="5.8" PS="1.206896551724138" SM="0">Even so, he remained confident.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="19.105263157894736" PS="1.8103448275862069" SM="11">&quot;I've always believed that solar is a freight train that can't be stopped,&quot; he said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="15.210526315789474" PS="1.206896551724138" SM="4">&quot;It started small, but the compound annual growth rate for the last 10 years has been 20 percent.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="19.25" PS="1.206896551724138" SM="2">This year, there's a $10 billion worldwide market for systems.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="20.923076923076923" PS="2.6767241379310347" SM="28">Portugal, one of the most oil-dependent  nations in Europe, will begin work on the world's biggest solar  energy power station next year, officials said Tuesday.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="15.487179487179487" PS="1.7844827586206897" SM="40">The plant will have 350,000 solar panels spread over 114  hectares (280 acres) near the southern town of Moura and will be  able to produce 62 megawatts, more than six times the largest  existing solar power station in Germany.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="12.333333333333334" PS="1.7844827586206897" SM="5">&quot;The construction of the station will begin in 2006, it is  irreversible,&quot; Moura mayor Jose Maria Pos-de-Mina was quoted as  saying by Lusa news agency.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="8.727272727272727" PS="1.7844827586206897" SM="5">The plant is expected to be completed in 2009 and will have a  total cost of 250 million euros (307 million dollars).</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="13.941176470588236" PS="1.7844827586206897" SM="21">It will be built by BP Solar, a unit of energy giant BP, and it  is expected to create 240 permanent jobs in the southern province of  Alentejo, one of Europe's poorest regions.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="16.161290322580644" PS="1.7844827586206897" SM="17">&quot;This is a unique project and the world's most ambitious in  terms of final capacity,&quot; said BP Solar commercial director for  southern Europe, Francisco Conesa, according to Lusa.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="21.047619047619047" PS="1.7844827586206897" SM="15">Southern Portugal's thinly populated Alentejo region has been  identified as one of Europe's most promising regions for solar  energy.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="22.761904761904763" PS="1.7844827586206897" SM="41">The town of Moura owns the majority of the firm which will  oversee the solar power station project, Amper Central Solar.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="15.735294117647058" PS="1.7844827586206897" SM="28">Under the United Nations Kyoto Protocol, the international  treaty on global warming which Lisbon has signed, Portugal must  generate 39 percent of its electricity needs through renewable  energy sources like solar and wind power.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="8.0" PS="2.4827586206896552" SM="0">It was an invention just waiting to be patented.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="10.473684210526315" PS="1.6551724137931034" SM="4">With electronic devices hitting the trails, someone had to put on the market a neat, portable source of electricity.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="1.0" PS="1.6551724137931034" SM="0">Voila!</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="51.0" PS="1.103448275862069" SM="12">The solar backpack.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="11.083333333333334" PS="1.103448275862069" SM="2">It sounds ungainly, but two companies have made a go of it.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="11.227272727272727" PS="1.6551724137931034" SM="3">Clear Blue Hawaii offers the Blue Sun Solarpac ($260, battery not included) and Voltaic Systems offers the Voltaic Backpack ($229, battery included).</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="11.533333333333333" PS="1.6551724137931034" SM="17">Both can charge your GPS unit and other gadgets while you hike, bike or sit using an internal battery, and both can charge direct from the solar cells in daylight.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="9.4" PS="1.103448275862069" SM="1">They are also the same size -- 1,850 cubic inches.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="15.3125" PS="1.6551724137931034" SM="3">But beyond these similarities, the packs are quite different, which can be challenging for the consumer.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="16.846153846153847" PS="1.103448275862069" SM="14">First, Blue Sun's solar panel, batteries and harness can be removed and used with other Clear Blue Hawaii products, saving $200 on a second bag.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="12.125" PS="1.103448275862069" SM="3">The same items in the Voltaic are fixed.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="10.4375" PS="1.6551724137931034" SM="1">Second, while both packs operate with an internal lithium-ion battery, each battery option is slightly different.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="10.617647058823529" PS="1.103448275862069" SM="4">The Blue Sun can accept a $50 or $150 lithium-ion battery; the $150 battery stores more electricity and has a wider output (up to 12 volts) than the $50 battery (up to 7.2 volts).</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="12.45" PS="1.103448275862069" SM="3">Voltaic's battery, which ranges from 3.5- to 7.2-volts, can't match Blue Sun's $150 battery in output or output range, nor can it match Blue Sun's $50 battery in overall output but bests it in output range.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="22.0" PS="1.6551724137931034" SM="26">Blue Sun's solar panel yields twice the power of Voltaic's three panels when tested in identical conditions.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="15.666666666666666" PS="1.103448275862069" SM="3">In addition, the type of panel that Blue Sun uses is more energy-efficient than Voltaic's monocrystalline panels.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="17.428571428571427" PS="1.6551724137931034" SM="15">All that said, given the fact that the Blue Sun has a better solar panel and batteries that yield more output, I would recommend the Blue Sun pack.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="10.0" PS="1.103448275862069" SM="4">With its $50 battery, you can charge most of your hand-helds, and if you purchase the $150 battery, you will be able to recharge a 12-volt device, such as a satellite phone.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="15.285714285714286" PS="1.103448275862069" SM="11">But this recommendation assumes you've got your heart set on a solar backpack.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="10.241379310344827" PS="1.6551724137931034" SM="5">The truth is, the limited size of these packs makes them impractical for anything beyond overnight outings, where you could easily pack extra batteries to meet your electrical needs.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="11.159090909090908" PS="1.6551724137931034" SM="4">But on outings lasting a week or more, these packs could save users from having to haul 10 pounds or so in batteries (even though you couldn't use the packs because you wouldn't have enough space for the provisions you'd need).</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="14.392857142857142" PS="1.6551724137931034" SM="16">When Clear Blue Hawaii and Voltaic Systems produce solar packs at least three times the size of these, they will have a product with real appeal to backpackers.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="10.954545454545455" PS="1.103448275862069" SM="5">Until then, the Blue Sun and Voltaic backpacks are little more than novelty items with the promise of useful packs to come.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="20.933333333333334" PS="2.4827586206896552" SM="28">With well-developed wafer and semiconductor industries, Taiwan has great promise in solar energy development, the chief executive officer of Taiwan's leading crystalline silicon solar cell manufacturing company said Monday.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="15.371428571428572" PS="1.6551724137931034" SM="17">Speaking in an interview with CNA, Motech Industries Inc. President Leo Cheng said he urged the government to invest more in solar energy research when his company began investing in the field seven years ago.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="19.5" PS="1.6551724137931034" SM="27">&quot;Taiwan is very suitable for solar power development because it has the world's best wafer fabrication plants and a large number of skilled engineers.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="19.4" PS="1.103448275862069" SM="12">With this precious asset, I see no other country better equipped than Taiwan to develop solar energy,&quot; Cheng said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="16.96551724137931" PS="1.6551724137931034" SM="18">In the past two years, Cheng said, more and more local companies have got involved in solar energy development, enhancing the possibility of forming a comprehensive industry supply chain.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="19.903225806451612" PS="1.6551724137931034" SM="16">&quot;So long as we can develop a complete supply chain, the solar energy industry will become yet another of Taiwan's star industries like the electronics industry,&quot; Cheng said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="5.28" PS="1.6551724137931034" SM="4">Motech Industries Inc., founded in 1981 and formerly known as Meter International Corp., is a leading Taiwanese manufacturer specializing in high-end test and measurement instruments.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="10.433333333333334" PS="1.103448275862069" SM="7">Over the past 20 years, Motech Industries has expanded its product base to become one of the most reputable test and measurement manufacturers in Taiwan, with a growing international presence.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="20.4" PS="1.6551724137931034" SM="24">In 1998, Motech received permission to set up its Solar Electricity Division (Motech Solar) in the South Taiwan Science Park.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="26.8125" PS="1.6551724137931034" SM="27">Motech Solar is Taiwan's first manufacturer specializing in the production of crystalline silicon solar cells.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="13.5" PS="1.6551724137931034" SM="16">Its main products include multi- and mono-crystalline silicon solar cells with dimensions of 125mm x 125mm and 156mm x 156mm.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="19.875" PS="1.6551724137931034" SM="16">Cheng said Motech Solar plans to further expand its production capacity by the end of 2005.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="17.333333333333332" PS="1.6551724137931034" SM="17">Motech Solar has also started a pilot production line for wafer slicing to reduce cost and increase the supply of silicon wafers, Cheng said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="17.56" PS="1.6551724137931034" SM="29">Moreover, Cheng went on, Motech Solar plans to begin the construction of a second factory building for future expansion in solar wafer and cell manufacturing.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="21.157894736842106" PS="1.6551724137931034" SM="16">&quot;One of our goals is to become the lowest-cost solar cell manufacturer in the world,&quot; Cheng said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="18.045454545454547" PS="1.6551724137931034" SM="17">With the Kyoto Protocol taking effect and crude oil prices skyrocketing, Cheng said there is a resurgence of interest in solar energy.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="18.11111111111111" PS="1.103448275862069" SM="28">As a result, upstream solar energy materials have been in short supply and he predicted that investment in upstream solar energy materials production will reap certain dividends.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="16.87878787878788" PS="1.6551724137931034" SM="29">He urged the government to invest more in solar energy research and provide incentives to encourage private investment in the field so that Taiwan can develop a complete solar energy supply chain soon.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="21.55" PS="1.103448275862069" SM="13">Cheng further said his company is expected to rank among the world's top five solar energy firms by 2008.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="12.548387096774194" PS="2.25" SM="1">A team from Holland, known  more for its windmills than its sunshine, on Wednesday won a  four-day international solar-powered car race across Australia's  deserts, notching up their third straight victory.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="8.897435897435898" PS="1.5" SM="8">High-tech cars from Australia, the United States and Japan were  hot on its heels as the sliver-shaped, space-age Nuna 3 arrived in  the southern city of Adelaide after the 3,000 kilometre (1,860 mile)  race, organiser Chris Selwood told AFP.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="11.8" PS="1.5" SM="16">Shunning petrol, sucking up the sun and racing at speeds up to  120 kilometres (74 miles) an hour, 20 cars from 10 countries set out  from Darwin in Australia's far north on Sunday in the eighth World  Solar Challenge.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="9.035714285714286" PS="1.5" SM="6">The Dutch team behind Nuna 3 appeared to have broken its own  record of 30 hours and 54 minutes set during the last race in 2003,  Selwood said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="10.083333333333334" PS="1.5" SM="23">The &quot;Challenge&quot;, to design and build a car capable of crossing  Australia on the power of daylight, was launched in 1987 and teams  and individuals from corporations and universities throughout the  world take part.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="12.045454545454545" PS="1.5" SM="20">Australian entry Aurora 101, which came second in the last two  races, was holding on to the same position this year while a car  from the University of Michigan, which won the North American Solar  Challenge in July, was in third place, Selwood said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="8.3" PS="1.5" SM="1">A team from Ashiya University in Osaka, Japan, which qualified  fastest with its Sky Ace Tiga car, was running fourth.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="8.0" PS="1.5" SM="2">Tail-enders still making their way through the vast Outback  could reach the finish line a day later.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="8.631578947368421" PS="1.5" SM="6">The teams raced from 8:00 am to 5:00 pm each day through some of  Australia's most forbidding terrain on the main Stuart Highway from  Darwin to Adelaide before camping each night where they were in the  desert.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="12.8125" PS="1.5" SM="2">Event spokeswoman Rowena Austin said the challenge was an  important testing ground for alternative fuel technologies.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="22.555555555555557" PS="1.5" SM="2">&quot;It's particularly relevant with the oil price where it is at  the moment,&quot; she said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="11.541666666666666" PS="2.463362068965517" SM="4">The solar-power industry  needed stability to become competitive, the Vice President of  Royal Dutch Shell's Hydrogen Business Jeremy Bentham said here on  Wednesday.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="16.8125" PS="1.6422413793103448" SM="14">Jeremy Bentham told the World Petroleum Congress in  Johannesburg: &quot;The solar industry needs stable markets.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="22.647058823529413" PS="1.0948275862068966" SM="24">With fair  and good incentives we can have solar power competitive in ten  year's time.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="9.875" PS="1.6422413793103448" SM="5">He said over the course of time different companies gave  different incentives to get markets moving, and that these  incentives changed, upsetting the industry.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="12.88888888888889" PS="1.6422413793103448" SM="10">Reasons for countries to shift to renewable sources of energy  included the need to preserve energy independence as well as the  increase of air pollution in cities.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="15.428571428571429" PS="1.6422413793103448" SM="5">Renewable energy production would be on the same level as gas  production by 2030, and as oil by 2040, Bentham predicted.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="16.625" PS="1.6422413793103448" SM="0">&quot;We are not constrained by capital, but by opportunities as we  grow,&quot; Bentham said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="17.25" PS="1.6422413793103448" SM="13">Electricity generation from wind power was reaching its target  of being competitive.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="7.611111111111111" PS="1.0948275862068966" SM="6">Turbines in the Thames estuary were  providing electricity to a quarter of homes in the greater London  area.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="7.517241379310345" PS="1.6422413793103448" SM="8">Bentham stressed that government policies would play a major  role in advancing the use of renewable energy, and that fact-based and not emotion-based discussions were required around the issue.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="12.578947368421053" PS="2.269396551724138" SM="4">Soaring energy prices and bright sunny days are giving new meaning to the gold in &quot;Golden State.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="11.0" PS="1.5129310344827585" SM="26">On a day when their morning newspapers reported a projected 70 percent increase in natural gas bills, more than 160 central San Joaquin Valley residents spent Saturday checking out the possibilities of generating their own electricity through solar power.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="8.066666666666666" PS="1.5129310344827585" SM="4">As the sun pushed temperatures into the 80s and low 90s, these conservation-minded citizens toured nine homes and two commercial locations that are converting sunlight to electricity through photovoltaic cells.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="16.28" PS="1.0086206896551724" SM="14">People taking the tour said they were concerned about rising energy bills and wanted to see how much money they could save by going solar.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="21.73913043478261" PS="1.5129310344827585" SM="16">&quot;It's about cost and future costs,&quot; said Randy Neely of Fresno, when asked about his interest in solar energy systems.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="19.794117647058822" PS="1.0086206896551724" SM="19">&quot;If the break-even point for solar systems is 12-13 years in today's dollars, imagine what it's going to be in the future if the price of oil keeps going up.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="17.846153846153847" PS="1.5129310344827585" SM="30">Neely said that with the possibility of a solar power system paying for itself in fewer years, given the current energy price situation, he and his wife, Nola, are seriously considering installing photovoltaic roof panels on their next house.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="21.0" PS="1.5129310344827585" SM="1">&quot;That's why the tour is so beneficial,&quot; said Nola Neely.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="12.3" PS="1.0086206896551724" SM="3">&quot;You get to take a look at real homes and ask the homeowners what is good about their systems and what they wish they would have done differently.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="16.6875" PS="1.5129310344827585" SM="30">Allen and Mary Jones of Fresno have long been aware of the benefits of solar power.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="27.90909090909091" PS="1.0086206896551724" SM="13">For years, Allen Jones has used a solar oven for cooking.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="20.64" PS="1.5129310344827585" SM="24">&quot;I've been looking at solar power systems for a long time but so far I haven't seen the payoff,&quot; he says.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="15.833333333333334" PS="1.0086206896551724" SM="11">When he does, Jones says, he won't hesitate to go solar.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="20.28" PS="1.5129310344827585" SM="17">With energy costs on the rise, more and more people will be looking for ways to reduce their power bills, said Jeff Adolph of Fresno.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="13.413793103448276" PS="1.5129310344827585" SM="9">Adolph, the facilities energy manager for Pacific Gas and Electric Co., has done all he can to reduce his home energy bill, including taking advantage of PG&amp;E's time-of-use rates, which are lower when electricity is not used from noon to 6 p.m. For years, Adolph's family has gone without air conditioning during hot summer afternoons.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="19.227272727272727" PS="1.5129310344827585" SM="14">&quot;I'm looking into solar energy as a way to be a little more comfortable in the summer,&quot; he says.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="21.42105263157895" PS="1.5129310344827585" SM="45">Saturday's self-guided solar home tour, the first of its kind in the central San Joaquin Valley, was sponsored by the city of Fresno, American Solar Energy Society, Northern California Solar Energy Association and the Great Valley Center.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="16.772727272727273" PS="1.5129310344827585" SM="18">Interest in solar energy is increasing rapidly in California, said Mark Stout, a clean-energy consultant from Fresno and coordinator of the tour.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="22.88235294117647" PS="1.5129310344827585" SM="15">&quot;In 2001, we were generating 10 megawatts of solar electricity in the state,&quot; he said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="23.75" PS="1.0086206896551724" SM="0">&quot;Today it's over 100 megawatts.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="16.0" PS="1.5129310344827585" SM="14">A megawatt is 1 million watts of electricity, or enough energy to power 300 homes.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="12.903225806451612" PS="1.5129310344827585" SM="16">Stout said there are some 500 solar electricity systems in operation in Fresno and Madera counties, up dramatically from a few years ago when there were just a handful of installations.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="15.657142857142857" PS="1.5129310344827585" SM="41">Given increasing electric rates, decreasing costs of solar panels and economic incentives available to homeowners through tax credits and rebates, Stout expects installations of solar power systems to increase rapidly in the next few years.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="20.06896551724138" PS="1.5129310344827585" SM="25">Using the sun to generate electricity is producing big energy savings for OK Produce, said general manager Brady Matoian, whose massive commercial solar power system drew several visitors Saturday.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="11.6" PS="1.0086206896551724" SM="7">In 2002, the company installed 35,000 square feet of photovoltaic cells on the roof of its building in downtown Fresno.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="14.208333333333334" PS="1.0086206896551724" SM="10">The system, the largest of its kind in the Valley, has reduced energy consumption by nearly half and produced an annual savings of $65,000.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="15.727272727272727" PS="1.5129310344827585" SM="28">Matoian participated in the tour as a way to help get the word out to people about the benefits of solar power.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="33.45454545454545" PS="1.5129310344827585" SM="14">&quot;Solar energy works perfectly in the Valley,&quot; he said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="8.88888888888889" PS="1.0086206896551724" SM="2">&quot;We get nine months of sunshine every year.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="19.0" PS="1.0086206896551724" SM="1">Our agriculture is based on the sun.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="16.636363636363637" PS="1.0086206896551724" SM="2">What we're doing on the roof is farming the sun.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="11.8" PS="1.0086206896551724" SM="0">It makes perfect sense.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="13.235294117647058" PS="2.4827586206896552" SM="19">The first Saturday in October was clear, dry and drenched in bright sunlight -- ideal for the solar panels converting light to electricity at Harry Kubetz and Gary Burton's home in Northport, N.Y.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="23.1" PS="1.6551724137931034" SM="22">&quot;Today is a peak power day,&quot; Burton said, looking up at a rooftop covered with 80 solar panels.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="17.0" PS="1.103448275862069" SM="13">&quot;We're probably producing enough power to meet our demand for the day.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="14.956521739130435" PS="1.6551724137931034" SM="7">In fact, according to the digital meter on the side of the house, the panels were making more electricity than the house needed.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="10.4" PS="1.103448275862069" SM="12">A small black arrow pointed left, indicating that excess electricity was being sent back to the Long Island Power Authority.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="20.1875" PS="1.6551724137931034" SM="15">The Northport home was one of 67 stops on a solar energy tour across Long Island.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="16.482758620689655" PS="1.103448275862069" SM="17">The free tour, set up by Renewable Energy Long Island, an alternative energy advocacy group, was self-guided, covering residences and businesses with solar systems in Nassau and Suffolk Counties.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="20.90625" PS="1.6551724137931034" SM="38">Lower prices for solar equipment, higher efficiency and tax and rebate incentives from government and utility companies have caused more Long Islanders to look to lower their energy costs with solar power.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="22.566666666666666" PS="1.6551724137931034" SM="17">Over the last year, demand &quot;has skyrocketed&quot; for these systems, said Jonathan Lane, who owns Quad State Solar, the company that installed the system for Kubetz and Burton.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="12.923076923076923" PS="1.103448275862069" SM="10">&quot;Within the last three months, there has been a huge increase in the number of inquiries and in the number of sales,&quot; he said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="14.9" PS="1.6551724137931034" SM="14">Another sign that prices are going down and demand is increasing is the lower rebate offered by the power authority.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="10.533333333333333" PS="1.103448275862069" SM="2">Kubetz and Burton received $5 per watt for their 10 kilowatt system -- or $50,000.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="13.166666666666666" PS="1.6551724137931034" SM="0">Their system cost $81,000 to install.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="4.580645161290323" PS="1.103448275862069" SM="9">Of that, a total of $27,250 came out of their pockets after the rebate and a state tax credit of $3,750, a maximum that will rise to $5,000 in September 2006.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="14.48" PS="1.103448275862069" SM="19">A federal tax credit of 30 percent of the cost of a solar system, up to $2,000 for homes, will also apply after Jan. 1.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="16.693548387096776" PS="1.6551724137931034" SM="56">But today, with 560 homes and businesses powered by solar energy on Long Island, the LIPA rebate is down to $4 per watt, and the utility expects to lower it further to $3.75 in mid- to late 2006 if solar system prices continue to go down, said Daniel Zaweski, the director of energy efficiency and distributed generation programs at the power authority.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="13.583333333333334" PS="1.6551724137931034" SM="16">The average 5 kilowatt residential solar system costs nearly $40,000 to buy and install, according to Gordian Raacke, director of Renewable Energy Long Island.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="6.529411764705882" PS="1.103448275862069" SM="3">The homeowner would pay about $15,000 after a $20,000 LIPA rebate and state and federal tax credits.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="15.634146341463415" PS="1.6551724137931034" SM="33">Such a system can reduce electric bills by 20 to 100 percent, according to Sharon Laudisi of the Long Island Power Authority, depending on the amount and duration of sunlight hitting the solar panels and on electricity use in the home.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="21.90909090909091" PS="1.6551724137931034" SM="24">Solar energy systems, also called &quot;PVs,&quot; short for photovoltaic cells, convert sunlight to electricity without combustion, creating power without pollution.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="25.1" PS="1.103448275862069" SM="13">There are also solar systems for heating water and pools.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="23.38888888888889" PS="1.6551724137931034" SM="14">Solar panels do not store energy, and they supply electricity only when the sun is shining on them.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="17.885714285714286" PS="1.103448275862069" SM="16">Since most homes have their solar systems connected to the LIPA grid, they draw energy back from the authority at night or on cloudy days, using the credits earned while supplying electricity during the day.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="14.619047619047619" PS="1.6551724137931034" SM="17">Kubetz and Burton like the modern look that the sleek reflective solar panels add to the back of their suburban ranch.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="13.066666666666666" PS="1.103448275862069" SM="3">Besides saving about $2,000 a year on utility bills, there's the matter of conscience.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="14.708333333333334" PS="1.6551724137931034" SM="1">&quot;I could personally afford to pay a larger bill,&quot; Kubetz said, &quot;but I think Americans consume way too much energy.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="10.25" PS="2.25" SM="0">Italy has unveiled Europe's first  solar-power train, according to Italian News Agency ANSA on  Thursday.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="25.956521739130434" PS="1.5" SM="16">The solar panels on the train's roof do not drive it but  provide energy for its air conditioning, illumination and safety  systems.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="15.136363636363637" PS="1.5" SM="5">Italian Environment Minister Altero Matteoli said the first ten prototypes would pave the way for &quot;significant&quot; developments in  the future.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="19.625" PS="1.5" SM="26">The CEO of Italian train company Trenitalia, Roberto Testore,  said it was &quot;looking with interest to the solar power sector, with a view to producing vehicles on an industrial scale.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="17.928571428571427" PS="1.5" SM="25">Solar panels are already used to provide a portion of train  power in Japan.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="27.0" PS="1.0" SM="24">A miniature railway in Wales is wholly powered by  solar energy.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="11.157894736842104" PS="1.5" SM="1">At Thursday's presentation, Testore also said Trenitalia was  investing heavily to renew its fleet and raise safety levels.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="12.933333333333334" PS="1.5" SM="5">He said the number of accidents had dropped by half in the last eight years.</sentence>
	</Sentences>
</Topic>
