<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<Topic id="D0916C">
	<Sentences>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="21.724137931034484" PS="2.3349056603773586" SM="39">The Christian Science Monitor on  Monday named a US journalist kidnapped in Iraq as freelancer Jill  Carroll, who was on assignment for the US-based paper when she was  seized.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="24.44" PS="1.5566037735849056" SM="19">Carroll was abducted in western Baghdad on Saturday, by  kidnappers who killed her Iraqi interpreter, the paper said in a  statement, calling for her release.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="17.571428571428573" PS="1.5566037735849056" SM="14">The incident had previously been reported from Baghdad, but  Carroll had not been identified.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="19.444444444444443" PS="2.844339622641509" SM="42">The Christian Science Monitor  newspaper on Monday pleaded for the release of American reporter  Jill Carroll, seized in Baghdad by abductors who gunned down her  Iraqi translator.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="15.925925925925926" PS="1.8962264150943395" SM="18">Carroll, 28, a freelancer filing for the  Boston,Massachusetts-based paper, was abducted in western Baghdad on  Saturday, apparently on the way to interview a prominent Sunni  politician.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="16.583333333333332" PS="1.8962264150943395" SM="16">&quot;We are urgently seeking information about Ms. Carroll and are  pursuing every avenue to secure her release,&quot; said Monitor editor  Richard Bergenheim.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="17.710526315789473" PS="1.8962264150943395" SM="38">&quot;The Monitor joins Jill's colleagues -- Iraqi and foreign -- in  the Baghdad press in calling for her immediate and safe release,&quot;  the paper said in a statement which named Carroll for the first  time.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="15.820512820512821" PS="1.8962264150943395" SM="22">The incident was reported from Baghdad by AFP on Saturday, but  the agency, in common with other foreign and US news outlets, did  not identify Carroll in line with a Monitor request as efforts were  launched to find her.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="17.227272727272727" PS="1.8962264150943395" SM="18">Carroll had reported from the Middle East for Jordanian, Italian  and other news organizations for the last three years, the paper  said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="20.625" PS="1.8962264150943395" SM="8">&quot;In recent months, the Monitor has tapped into her  professionalism, energy, and fair reporting on the Iraqi scene,&quot; the  Monitor statement said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="15.592592592592593" PS="1.8962264150943395" SM="5">&quot;It was her drive to gather direct and accurate views from  political leaders that took her into western Baghdad's Adil  neighborhood on Saturday morning.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="17.818181818181817" PS="1.8962264150943395" SM="37">The paper quoted unidentified relatives of Carroll as pleading  for her release and asking her captors to &quot;consider the work she has  done to reveal the truth about the Iraq war.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="10.764705882352942" PS="1.8962264150943395" SM="44">In a dispatch for the American Journalism Review published last  year, Carroll wrote that she moved to Jordan ahead of the US  invasion of Iraq in 2003 to get a feel for the story.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="14.642857142857142" PS="1.8962264150943395" SM="1">&quot;All I ever wanted to be was a foreign correspondent,&quot; she  wrote.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="10.161290322580646" PS="1.8962264150943395" SM="7">&quot;So when I was laid off from my reporting assistant job at the  Wall Street Journal in August 2002, it seemed the right time to try  to make it happen.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="10.346153846153847" PS="1.2641509433962264" SM="29">&quot;There was bound to be plenty of  parachute journalism once the war started, and I didn't want to be a  part of that.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="20.083333333333332" PS="1.8962264150943395" SM="18">Officials in Baghdad and the Monitor said Carroll was seized as  she was on her way to interview prominent Sunni Arab politician  Adnan al-Dulaimi.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="15.333333333333334" PS="1.8962264150943395" SM="18">The body of her interpreter, Allan Enwiyah, 32, was later found  in the same neighborhood.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="14.3" PS="1.8962264150943395" SM="23">An Iraqi defence ministry official said Enwiyah was able to tell  soldiers that Carroll had been kidnapped before he died.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="18.153846153846153" PS="1.8962264150943395" SM="28">Carroll's driver, quoted in a story posted on the Monitor's  website on Monday, said gunmen jumped in front of her car screaming  &quot;Stop!</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="3.0" PS="1.2641509433962264" SM="0">Stop!</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="23.0" PS="1.2641509433962264" SM="0">Stop!&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="8.666666666666666" PS="1.2641509433962264" SM="15">and others jumped in and surrounded Carroll and  Enwiyah.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="12.0" PS="1.8962264150943395" SM="6">&quot;They didn't give me any time to even put the car in neutral,&quot;  the driver, who requested anonymity, said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="25.555555555555557" PS="1.8962264150943395" SM="0">&quot;It was very obvious this was by design.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="4.333333333333333" PS="1.2641509433962264" SM="14">The whole operation  took no more than a quarter of a minute.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="15.0" PS="1.2641509433962264" SM="0">It was very highly  organized.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="14.375" PS="1.2641509433962264" SM="0">It was a setup, a perfect ambush.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="6.357142857142857" PS="1.8962264150943395" SM="16">A guard outside Dulaimi's office told AFP on Saturday he heard  gunshots fired a short distance away and rushed to find the body of  a slain man.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="5.153846153846154" PS="1.8962264150943395" SM="2">Dulaimi however told AFP he had no appointment to meet a Western  journalist.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="11.666666666666666" PS="1.8962264150943395" SM="14">Several Westerners are currently being held hostage by  insurgents in Iraq, including an American, a Briton and two  Canadians who are members of a Christian peace group.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="13.6875" PS="1.8962264150943395" SM="44">Carroll is the 31st media worker to have been kidnapped in Iraq  since the start of the war in 2003, according to watchdog group  Reporters without Borders (Reporters sans Frontieres, or RSF).</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="12.578947368421053" PS="1.8962264150943395" SM="38">Five of the kidnap victims -- four Iraqis and Enzo Baldoni of  Italy  -- were killed by their abductors.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="21.25" PS="1.2641509433962264" SM="3">The others were released.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="18.526315789473685" PS="1.8962264150943395" SM="17">RSF renewed its call for Carroll's release on Monday, and  bemoaned the dangers faced by reporters in Baghdad.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="14.238095238095237" PS="1.8962264150943395" SM="6">&quot;Journalists working in Iraq have once again been caught in a  deadly ambush,&quot; the group said in a statement.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="15.307692307692308" PS="1.8962264150943395" SM="24">&quot;The interpreters death confirms that the Iraqi press continues  to be the chief victim of the infernal climate for the media in this  country.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="10.483870967741936" PS="2.7594339622641506" SM="29">Iraqi and US investigators were  hunting Tuesday for a US journalist kidnapped in Baghdad as a French  hostage who escaped after five weeks of captivity in Iraq arrived  back in France.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="20.205882352941178" PS="1.8396226415094339" SM="40">Jill Carroll, 28, a freelance reporter working for the Christian  Science Monitor, was seized by gunmen on Saturday after calling by  the office of a prominent Sunni politician, the US newspaper  confirmed on Monday.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="17.333333333333332" PS="1.8396226415094339" SM="5">Her interpreter, Allan Enwiyah, 32, was shot dead and his body  abandoned nearby by the kidnappers, while her driver got away.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="15.675675675675675" PS="1.8396226415094339" SM="21">The incident was reported by AFP on Saturday, but the agency, in  common with other foreign and US news outlets, did not identify  Carroll in line with a Monitor request as efforts were launched to  find her.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="16.666666666666668" PS="1.8396226415094339" SM="16">&quot;We are urgently seeking information about Ms Carroll and are  pursuing every avenue to secure her release,&quot; said Monitor editor  Richard Bergenheim.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="13.305555555555555" PS="1.8396226415094339" SM="30">Carroll's driver, quoted in a story posted on the Monitor's  website, said gunmen jumped in front of the car, pulled him from it,  and drove off with their two captives all within 15 seconds.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="11.666666666666666" PS="1.8396226415094339" SM="14">Several Westerners are currently being held hostage by  insurgents in Iraq, including an American, a Briton and two  Canadians who are members of a Christian peace group.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="16.555555555555557" PS="1.8396226415094339" SM="44">Carroll was the 31st media worker to have been kidnapped in Iraq  since the start of the war in 2003, according to watchdog group  Reporters without Borders.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="12.578947368421053" PS="1.8396226415094339" SM="38">Five of the kidnap victims -- four Iraqis and Enzo Baldoni of  Italy -- were killed by their abductors.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="21.25" PS="1.2264150943396226" SM="3">The others were released.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="7.923076923076923" PS="1.8396226415094339" SM="1">Frenchman Bernard Planche, a 52-year-old engineer, managed to  evade his captors on Saturday.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="8.5" PS="1.8396226415094339" SM="2">He landed at late Monday at a military base in France where he  was met by his daugher and niece, along with Foreign Minister  Philippe Douste-Blazy.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="12.375" PS="1.8396226415094339" SM="18">Blanche, who escaped from a farmhouse west of the capital, said  he was &quot;delighted to return to civilisation and to French soil.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="9.105263157894736" PS="1.8396226415094339" SM="4">The hostage developments followed a twin suicide bombing against  the Iraqi interior ministry that killed at least 28 policemen.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="13.8" PS="1.8396226415094339" SM="33">The Iraqi branch of Al-Qaeda claimed responsibility for the  attack in an Internet message, saying it was to avenge the &quot;torture&quot;  of Sunni Muslims in interior ministry facilities.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="6.5" PS="1.8396226415094339" SM="6">Abuse scandals came to the fore in November and December when US  and Iraqi forces discovered two overcrowded interior ministry  detention centres.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="6.333333333333333" PS="1.2264150943396226" SM="0">Some inmates had reportedly been tortured.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="9.85" PS="1.8396226415094339" SM="10">Meanwhile in Washington, the White House Monday denied that the  US government has been negotiating with insurgents and Saddam  Hussein loyalists in Iraq, but acknowledged that it was reaching out  to those who until now have rejected the political process.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="7.7407407407407405" PS="1.8396226415094339" SM="28">&quot;Part of our strategy, a critical element of our strategy, is to  broaden participation in the political process,&quot; White House  spokesman Scott McClellan told reporters.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="17.2" PS="1.2264150943396226" SM="3">&quot;We have been reaching out  to the rejectionists.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="9.926829268292684" PS="1.8396226415094339" SM="8">The spokesman was reacting to a New York Times report Saturday  that said the United States has stepped up contact with some Iraqi  insurgent groups in a bid to exploit tensions between home-grown  rebels and foreign militant groups such as Al-Qaeda.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="6.861111111111111" PS="1.8396226415094339" SM="46">Washington wants to encourage the Sunni Arab minority to join in  a government of national unity in a bid to undermine Sunni support  for insurgents and allow for the start of withdrawal of US-led  coalition forces.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="9.347826086956522" PS="1.8396226415094339" SM="24">In addition to the human cost of the war, with 2,209 US  servicemen killed and over 16,000 wounded, the Iraq war will likely  cost the United States anywhere between one and two trillion  dollars, according to a new study co-authored by a Nobel Prize  winning economist.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="6.428571428571429" PS="1.8396226415094339" SM="49">The research made public Monday by Joseph Stiglitz of Columbia  University, a 2001 Nobel Prize laureate and former chief economist  at the World Bank, and economy professor Linda Bilmes of Harvard  University, argued that current official assessments of the war cost  fail to consider key expenses likely to dog the US budget for years  to come.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="15.08695652173913" PS="2.292452830188679" SM="27">Sunni Arab Muslims protested  Tuesday a raid by US forces on a Baghdad mosque reportedly linked to  the kidnapping of a US reporter.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="12.67741935483871" PS="1.5283018867924527" SM="38">About 700 people rallied in the gardens of the Umm al-Qura  mosque in the west of the capital to denounce the raid carried out  Saturday night by US and Iraqi forces.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="15.782608695652174" PS="1.5283018867924527" SM="76">&quot;This raid was conducted as a direct result of a tip by an Iraqi  civilian that activities related to the kidnapping were being  carried out inside the mosque,&quot; said Lieutenant-Colonel Barry  Johnson, speaking of the abduction Saturday of Christian Science  Monitor reporter Jill Carroll.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="17.333333333333332" PS="1.5283018867924527" SM="5">Her interpreter, Allan Enwiyah, 32, was shot dead and his body  abandoned nearby by the kidnappers, while her driver got away.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="15.258064516129032" PS="1.5283018867924527" SM="15">&quot;Both Iraqi and coalition Forces raided the mosque in the early  morning hours in order to minimize the impact on worshippers and the  surrounding neighborhood,&quot; the military spokesman said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="11.125" PS="1.5283018867924527" SM="0">Six people were detained for questioning, he added.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="10.689655172413794" PS="1.5283018867924527" SM="32">The Sunni Committee of Muslim Scholars, which is based at the  mosque, confirmed that one of its members, Yunis Aikali, and five  mosque guards were arrested in the raid.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="10.363636363636363" PS="1.5283018867924527" SM="31">In a statement, the committee also accused US soldiers of  desecrating the mosque and carrying away files containing the names  of members.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="16.766666666666666" PS="1.5283018867924527" SM="5">&quot;The attack on the Umm al-Qura mosque is an attack on Muslims  and Islam,&quot; said banners held up by protesters at Tuesday's rally  which followed morning prayers.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="14.813953488372093" PS="1.5283018867924527" SM="38">&quot;We call on the occupiers to withdraw from Iraq because they are  the reason for every crime and the death of every innocent in Iraq,&quot;  Harith al-Aubaidi, a member of the scholars' committee, said in his  sermon at the prayer meeting.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="14.6" PS="1.5283018867924527" SM="0">&quot;There can be no stability as long as Iraq is occupied,&quot; he  added.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="11.833333333333334" PS="1.5283018867924527" SM="5">The UN special representative in Iraq, Ashraf Qazi, also  deplored the raid.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="10.68" PS="1.5283018867924527" SM="42">&quot;This again underlines the importance of all parties respecting  the sanctity of holy sites and places of worship,&quot; he said in a  statement.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="19.4" PS="1.5283018867924527" SM="30">Carroll, 28, a freelance reporter working for the Christian  Science Monitor, was seized by gunmen on Saturday after calling by  the office of a prominent Sunni politician in the neighbourhood.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="16.666666666666668" PS="1.5283018867924527" SM="16">&quot;We are urgently seeking information about Ms Carroll and are  pursuing every avenue to secure her release,&quot; said Monitor editor  Richard Bergenheim.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="13.305555555555555" PS="1.5283018867924527" SM="30">Carroll's driver, quoted in a story posted on the Monitor's  website, said gunmen jumped in front of the car, pulled him from it,  and drove off with their two captives all within 15 seconds.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="11.666666666666666" PS="1.5283018867924527" SM="14">Several Westerners are currently being held hostage by  insurgents in Iraq, including an American, a Briton and two  Canadians who are members of a Christian peace group.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="16.555555555555557" PS="1.5283018867924527" SM="44">Carroll was the 31st media worker to have been kidnapped in Iraq  since the start of the war in 2003, according to watchdog group  Reporters without Borders.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="13.472222222222221" PS="2.3773584905660377" SM="41">Angry Sunni Arabs protested  Tuesday at a raid on a Baghdad mosque by US and Iraqi soldiers  looking for a kidnapped US woman reporter, the latest victim in a  series of abductions of Westerners in Iraq.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="9.3125" PS="1.5849056603773586" SM="6">The demonstration came as Iraqis celebrated the Muslim Eid  Al-Adha holiday a day after a twin suicide bombing at the interior  ministry, claimed by Al-Qaeda, that left at least 28 policemen  dead.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="9.233333333333333" PS="1.5849056603773586" SM="38">Waving banners and chanting anti-US slogans, about 700 people  rallied in the gardens of the Umm al-Qura mosque in the west of the  capital to denounce the Saturday night raid.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="18.041666666666668" PS="1.5849056603773586" SM="21">&quot;The attack on the Umm al-Qura mosque is an attack on Muslims  and Islam,&quot; read one of the banners at the protest.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="23.0" PS="1.5849056603773586" SM="43">The US military said the raid was linked to the hunt for  kidnapped Jill Carroll, a freelance journalist working for the  Christian Science Monitor.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="14.923076923076923" PS="1.5849056603773586" SM="30">Lieutenant Colonel Barry Johnson, a US military spokesman, said  the raid was ordered &quot;as a direct result of a tip by an Iraqi  civilian that activities related to the kidnapping were being  carried out inside the mosque.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="19.09090909090909" PS="1.5849056603773586" SM="19">The 28-year-old reporter was seized by gunmen on Saturday after  calling by the office of a prominent Sunni politician in the  neighbourhood.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="15.333333333333334" PS="1.5849056603773586" SM="3">Her interpreter, Allan Enwiyah, 32, was shot dead and his body  abandoned nearby, while her driver got away.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="14.827586206896552" PS="1.5849056603773586" SM="13">&quot;Both Iraqi and coalition forces raided the mosque in the early  morning hours in order to minimize the impact on worshippers and the  surrounding neighborhood,&quot; Johnson said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="11.125" PS="1.5849056603773586" SM="0">Six people were detained for questioning, he added.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="10.689655172413794" PS="1.5849056603773586" SM="32">The Sunni Committee of Muslim Scholars which is based at the  mosque, confirmed that one of its members, Yunis Aikali, and five  mosque guards were arrested in the raid.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="10.363636363636363" PS="1.5849056603773586" SM="31">In a statement, the committee also accused US soldiers of  desecrating the mosque and carrying away files containing the names  of members.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="15.022222222222222" PS="1.5849056603773586" SM="52">&quot;We call on the occupiers to withdraw from Iraq because they are  the reason for every crime and the death of every innocent in Iraq,&quot;  Harith al-Aubaidi, a member of the committee said in his sermon at  the prayers ahead of the protest.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="11.833333333333334" PS="1.5849056603773586" SM="5">Ashraf Qazi, the UN special representative in Iraq, also  deplored the raid.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="10.68" PS="1.5849056603773586" SM="42">&quot;This again underlines the importance of all parties respecting  the sanctity of holy sites and places of worship,&quot; he said in a  statement.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="15.6875" PS="1.5849056603773586" SM="4">Iraqi security forces, meanwhile, were on alert in western  Baghdad looking for hostages, security sources said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="22.666666666666668" PS="1.5849056603773586" SM="14">The US embassy said it had nothing new to report on Carroll.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="22.157894736842106" PS="1.5849056603773586" SM="3">The Christian Science Monitor said it was urgently seeking  information about its reporter after confirming her abduction on  Monday.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="13.305555555555555" PS="1.5849056603773586" SM="30">Carroll's driver, quoted in a story posted on the Monitor's  website, said gunmen jumped in front of the car, pulled him from it,  and drove off with their two captives all within 15 seconds.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="11.666666666666666" PS="1.5849056603773586" SM="14">Several Westerners are currently being held hostage by  insurgents in Iraq, including an American, a Briton and two  Canadians who are members of a Christian peace group.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="16.555555555555557" PS="1.5849056603773586" SM="44">Carroll was the 31st media worker to have been kidnapped in Iraq  since the start of the war in 2003, according to watchdog group  Reporters without Borders.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="12.65" PS="1.5849056603773586" SM="39">Five of the journalist kidnap victims -- four Iraqis and Enzo  Baldoni of Italy -- were killed by their abductors.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="21.25" PS="1.0566037735849056" SM="3">The others were  released.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="10.275" PS="1.5849056603773586" SM="18">Frenchman Bernard Planche, a 52-year-old engineer, held hostage  for over a month and who managed to evade his captors on Saturday,  was debriefed Tuesday by the DGSE foreign intelligence agency at a  base near the Loire Valley city of Orleans.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="10.257142857142858" PS="1.5849056603773586" SM="28">In other developments, a Polish soldier was wounded and two  rebels killed during a raid carried out by coalition forces near the  town of Hamza, south of Baghdad, Poland's PAP news agency reported  Tuesday.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="6.2" PS="1.5849056603773586" SM="15">Coalition forces captured four suspects wanted over the killing  of a Spanish officer in 2004.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="11.058823529411764" PS="1.5849056603773586" SM="4">In Baghdad, two policemen were killed and two wounded in  separate shooting incidents Tuesday, security officials said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="6.44" PS="1.5849056603773586" SM="16">In Spain itself, police arrested 20 people across the country,  mostly Moroccans, suspected of recruiting radical Islamist  volunteers to fight in Iraq, national radio said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="9.346153846153847" PS="1.5849056603773586" SM="26">In the United States, a new study co-authored by a Nobel Prize  winning economist, claimed that -- in addition to the human cost of  the war, with 2,209 US servicemen killed and over 16,000 wounded --  the Iraq campaign will likely cost the United States anywhere  between one and two trillion dollars.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="10.68" PS="2.3349056603773586" SM="16">The family of an electrical contractor believed killed by a militant group in Iraq is convinced he is dead, and is preparing a memorial service.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="10.81081081081081" PS="1.5566037735849056" SM="34">The Islamic Army of Iraq claimed that it killed Ronald Schulz last month, and a video on a Web site, purportedly posted by the group, showed a blindfolded man being shot in the back of the head.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="15.23076923076923" PS="1.0377358490566038" SM="2">His face was not shown and it was impossible to verify his identity.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="10.375" PS="1.0377358490566038" SM="2">The video also showed Schulz's identity card.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="12.724137931034482" PS="1.5566037735849056" SM="4">While U.S. officials have not confirmed Shulz's death, his sister, Julie Schulz, said Tuesday night that the family identified him from two videos reportedly posted by the group.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="11.8125" PS="1.5566037735849056" SM="4">&quot;Although his face was not visible, there are enough consistencies between the two videos and enough evidence that my family, in our hearts, believe that Ron is dead,&quot; Schulz said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="7.9375" PS="1.0377358490566038" SM="0">&quot;We had hoped his body would be found so that we could bring him home.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="13.5" PS="1.0377358490566038" SM="0">But this has not happened.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="11.7" PS="1.5566037735849056" SM="2">The family is planning a memorial service on Jan. 14.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="17.666666666666668" PS="1.5566037735849056" SM="11">Shulz, 40, was working as an electrical contractor when he was kidnapped.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="9.0625" PS="1.5566037735849056" SM="19">Insurgents have kidnapped more than 250 foreigners in the past two years, aiming to force U.S.-led troops to leave Iraq or prevent Arab nations from strengthening their ties with the Baghdad government.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="15.434782608695652" PS="1.5566037735849056" SM="47">Most recently, Jill Carroll, an American freelance reporter, was kidnapped in Baghdad shortly after she was leading office of a leading Sunni politician.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="9.384615384615385" PS="1.5566037735849056" SM="24">No claim of responsibility has so far been issued in Carroll's case.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="11.051282051282051" PS="2.292452830188679" SM="38">An Arab television network ran a video showing kidnapped journalist Jill Carroll Tuesday with an accompanying message from her unnamed captors that she would be killed unless the United States freed all female prisoners in Iraq within 72 hours.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="19.375" PS="1.5283018867924527" SM="16">The group holding Carroll captive was not identified in the tape that was broadcast over Al-Jazeera.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="16.68421052631579" PS="1.0188679245283019" SM="6">Although the 28-year-old Christian Science Monitor reporter appeared to be talking on the tape, her words were not audible.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="17.083333333333332" PS="1.0188679245283019" SM="26">Carroll was kidnapped Jan. 7 while on assignment and her captors had made no public comment or demand until the tape was shown Tuesday.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="25.09090909090909" PS="1.0188679245283019" SM="2">Her translator was shot dead but her driver was set free.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="12.590909090909092" PS="1.5283018867924527" SM="17">Her family issued a statement Tuesday afternoon pleading for ``the speedy and safe return of our beloved daughter and sister.''</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="14.066666666666666" PS="1.5283018867924527" SM="37">``Jill is an innocent journalist and we respectfully ask that you please show her mercy and allow her to return home to her mother, sister and family,'' read the letter signed by her parents Jim and Mary Beth Carroll and her sister Katie.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="13.923076923076923" PS="1.0188679245283019" SM="34">``Jill is a friend and sister to many Iraqis and has been dedicated to bringing the truth of the Iraq war to the world.''</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="14.590909090909092" PS="1.5283018867924527" SM="20">News organizations withheld details of her abduction for several days to allow time for her newspaper and family to seek her release.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="13.285714285714286" PS="1.0188679245283019" SM="6">David Cook, her newspaper's Washington bureau chief and spokesman, said that the paper has had no contact with the kidnappers.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="11.058823529411764" PS="1.5283018867924527" SM="14">In the 20-second tape, Carroll was shown against a white background and appeared reasonably healthy, although tired.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="17.357142857142858" PS="1.0188679245283019" SM="14">An Al-Jazeera news reader said that the network has appealed for Carroll's release.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="15.428571428571429" PS="1.0188679245283019" SM="16">U.S. State Department spokesman Sean McCormack said the Bush administration was continuing ``to make every effort'' to free Carroll.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="12.096774193548388" PS="2.3773584905660377" SM="20">Arabic television Al-Jazeera said  Tuesday the kidnappers of a US woman journalist abducted in Baghdad  had threatened to kill her if female prisoners in Iraq were not  freed within 72 hours.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="17.774193548387096" PS="1.5849056603773586" SM="43">The station broadcast a brief videotape of the journalist Jill  Carroll, 28, a freelance reporter working for the Christian Science  Monitor who was seized by gunmen in Baghdad on January 7.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="13.666666666666666" PS="1.5849056603773586" SM="16">Carroll, wearing a grey sweatshirt with her long brown hair  loose, was shown alone in the video and speaking but there was no  sound.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="18.75" PS="1.0566037735849056" SM="3">It was the first time she has been since since her  disappearance.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="13.5" PS="1.5849056603773586" SM="30">The Qatar-based station said the kidnappers identified  themselves as members of a previously unknown armed group calling  itself the &quot;Brigades of Vengeance&quot;.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="15.214285714285714" PS="1.5849056603773586" SM="69">&quot;Al-Jazeera reiterates its rejection and condemnation of all  forms of violence targeting journalists, and demands the release of  the US journalist Jill Carroll,&quot; the station said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="17.4" PS="1.5849056603773586" SM="17">Carroll's interpreter, Allan Enwiyah, 32, was shot dead and his  body abandoned nearby by the kidnappers during the abduction, while  her driver got away.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="12.244444444444444" PS="1.5849056603773586" SM="34">US forces have been hunting for the woman, and one day last week  raided a mosque in the west of the capital after a tip that  &quot;activities related to the kidnapping were being carried out  inside,&quot; triggering angry protests from Sunni Muslim clerics.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="15.692307692307692" PS="1.5849056603773586" SM="16">&quot;We are urgently seeking information about Ms Carroll and are  pursuing every avenue to secure her release,&quot; Monitor editor Richard  Bergenheim said last week.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="13.305555555555555" PS="1.5849056603773586" SM="30">Carroll's driver, quoted in a story posted on the Monitor's  website, said gunmen jumped in front of the car, pulled him from it,  and drove off with their two captives all within 15 seconds.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="11.666666666666666" PS="1.5849056603773586" SM="14">Several Westerners are currently being held hostage by  insurgents in Iraq, including an American, a Briton and two  Canadians who are members of a Christian peace group.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="16.555555555555557" PS="1.5849056603773586" SM="44">Carroll was the 31st media worker to have been kidnapped in Iraq  since the start of the war in 2003, according to watchdog group  Reporters without Borders.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="12.578947368421053" PS="1.5849056603773586" SM="38">Five of the kidnap victims -- four Iraqis and Enzo Baldoni of  Italy -- were killed by their abductors.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="21.25" PS="1.0566037735849056" SM="3">The others were released.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="14.38888888888889" PS="1.5849056603773586" SM="14">Frenchman Bernard Planche, a 52-year-old engineer, managed to  evade his captors on the very day Carroll was abducted.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="18.48148148148148" PS="2.8867924528301887" SM="42">The family of Jill  Carroll, a US woman journalist abducted in Iraq, issued an emotional  appeal Monday for her release after her captors threatened her with  execution.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="14.38888888888889" PS="1.9245283018867925" SM="32">&quot;Jill is an innocent journalist and we respectfully ask that you  please show her mercy and allow her to return home to her mother,  sister and family,&quot; Carroll's family said in a statement.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="14.090909090909092" PS="1.9245283018867925" SM="28">Earlier, the Qatar-based Arabic television station Al-Jazeera  showed a videotape of Carroll taken by her kidnappers, who said they  would kill her if female prisoners in Iraq were not freed within 72  hours.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="21.25" PS="1.9245283018867925" SM="15">Carroll, 28, a freelance reporter working for the Christian  Science Monitor, was seized by gunmen in Baghdad on January 7.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="21.46153846153846" PS="1.2830188679245282" SM="4">Her  interpreter was shot dead during the abduction, while her driver got  away.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="18.958333333333332" PS="1.9245283018867925" SM="18">&quot;Jill is a kind person whose love for Iraq and the Iraqi people  are evident in her articles,&quot; the family statement said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="11.8" PS="1.9245283018867925" SM="15">&quot;She has been welcomed into the homes of many Iraqis and shown  every courtesy.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="13.947368421052632" PS="1.2830188679245282" SM="5">From that experience, she understands the hardships  and suffering that the Iraqi people face every day,&quot; it said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="13.923076923076923" PS="1.9245283018867925" SM="34">&quot;Jill is a friend and sister to many Iraqis and has been  dedicated to bringing the truth of the Iraq war to the world.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="16.555555555555557" PS="1.9245283018867925" SM="44">Carroll was the 31st media worker to have been kidnapped in Iraq  since the start of the war in 2003, according to watchdog group  Reporters without Borders.</sentence>
	</Sentences>
</Topic>
