<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<Topic id="D0915C">
	<Sentences>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="25.0" PS="2.2710280373831777" SM="27">At least 30 people were killed in Iraq  as insurgents intensified attacks on Iraqi and US targets, and  election workers backed by troops started distributing ballot boxes  for the vote in just two days' time.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="22.071428571428573" PS="1.514018691588785" SM="28">The latest attacks Thursday came as Iraqi exiles voting in  Australia and New Zealand became the first to vote in their  country's historic national elections early Friday.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="16.74074074074074" PS="1.514018691588785" SM="4">The exiles began casting votes as a British newspaper reported  the United States and Britain have privately agreed on a way of  withdrawing their troops from Iraq.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="19.31578947368421" PS="1.514018691588785" SM="27">Militants have promised an all-out onslaught against the  election, but US President George W. Bush has urged Iraqis to brave  death threats and seize what he termed an &quot;historic opportunity&quot; to  vote in Iraq on Sunday.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="18.81578947368421" PS="1.514018691588785" SM="15">Supporters of Iraq's most wanted man, Abu Musab al-Zarqawi, on  Thursday posted a video on the Internet of their murder of a  candidate in Iraq's elections from the party of US-backed interim  Prime Minister Iyad Allawi.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="14.076923076923077" PS="1.514018691588785" SM="4">The Al-Qaeda Group in the Land of Two Rivers announced Sunday on  a website that it had executed Salem Jaafar al-Kanani, &quot;secretary of  the traitor Iyad Allawi&quot;, and a video would be released at a later  time.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="16.044444444444444" PS="1.514018691588785" SM="4">Allawi's party has had 22 of its members killed in the space of  two months, party official Imad Shbib told AFP on January 11, adding  that as many as 44 had been murdered since the fall of Saddam  Hussein's regime in April 2003.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="21.857142857142858" PS="1.514018691588785" SM="26">An Islamist group linked to Al-Qaeda warned it would attack  Iraqis involved in the general election even after voting was over.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="12.217391304347826" PS="1.514018691588785" SM="4">&quot;We have warned you not to go to the centres of this sordid  comedy, called voting bureaus ... we renew our warning.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="16.11111111111111" PS="1.0093457943925233" SM="2">They will be  the targets of the mujahedeen (Islamist fighters),&quot; Ansar al-Sunna  said in a website statement.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="13.846153846153847" PS="1.514018691588785" SM="13">Meanwhile, Iraqi exiles registered at three centres, in Sydney,  Melbourne and the remote community of Shepparton in Victoria state  on Friday and started casting their ballots.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="17.710526315789473" PS="1.514018691588785" SM="26">In London, The Guardian newspaper reported US Defense Secretary  Donald Rumsfeld and his British counterpart Geoff Hoon have agreed  on a so-called exit-strategy based on doubling the number of Iraqi  police trainees and setting up Iraqi paramilitary units.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="22.34375" PS="1.514018691588785" SM="6">The pair were acting on recommendations from retired US General  Gary Luck, who was sent to Iraq by the Pentagon last month to look  at the failings of Iraq's security force.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="19.714285714285715" PS="1.514018691588785" SM="3">New attacks across Iraq followed the deaths of 31 US military  personnel in a helicopter crash in western Iraq on Wednesday.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="16.934782608695652" PS="1.514018691588785" SM="26">In one deadly attack Thursday, a car driven by a suicide bomber  rammed an Iraqi army patrol in Samarra, a mainly Sunni Arab city  north of Baghdad where US and Iraqi forces launched a massive  operation last October to wrest control from insurgents before the  vote.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="11.208333333333334" PS="1.514018691588785" SM="4">As security forces sealed off the sector to evacuate victims, a  second car burst onto the scene from the direction of a nearby  hospital.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="29.444444444444443" PS="1.0093457943925233" SM="0">Eight soldiers and three civilians were killed, police  said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="20.939393939393938" PS="1.514018691588785" SM="16">In Baquba, north of the capital, a car bomb attack on a  provincial government headquarters killed five people while the  bodies of four executed Iraqi soldiers were found in the city of  Ramadi.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="18.2" PS="1.514018691588785" SM="14">South of Baghdad, in the so-called triangle of death, a homemade  bomb killed five Iraqis and wounded 15 on the road between  Mahmudiyah and Latifiyah.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="24.444444444444443" PS="1.0093457943925233" SM="1">A US marine was killed in the same area.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="21.70967741935484" PS="1.514018691588785" SM="5">With some 40 polling stations already destroyed by insurgent  attack, even the distribution of ballot boxes for Iraq's estimated  14.1 million eligible voters underscored the tension hanging over  the poll.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="17.564102564102566" PS="1.514018691588785" SM="14">In the Shiite holy city of Najaf south of the capital, police,  US and Iraqi forces sealed off a one kilometre (0.6 mile) perimeter  around a school being used as a polling station as ballot papers  were taken in.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="19.05263157894737" PS="1.514018691588785" SM="5">Amid the relentless violence, the electoral commission pressed  on with its mission in the closing hours of the campaign.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="10.82857142857143" PS="1.514018691588785" SM="3">Ballot boxes were distributed to 5,300-odd polling centres  across the country, along with millions of ballot papers and tens of  thousands of bottles of indelible ink which voters will be tagged  with to avoid fraud.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="15.933333333333334" PS="1.514018691588785" SM="4">The total number of electoral staff is expected to swell to  200,000 on polling day.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="21.807692307692307" PS="1.514018691588785" SM="15">The US president said the vote offered an &quot;historic opportunity&quot;  for Iraqis to start building a truly democratic society after  decades of brutal dictatorship.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="21.59259259259259" PS="1.514018691588785" SM="4">&quot;This is a historic opportunity for the people of Iraq to vote  for a government,&quot; Bush said in an interview with Arabic televison  station Al-Arabiya.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="23.93548387096774" PS="1.514018691588785" SM="15">The US military's top commander in Iraq, General George Casey,  told AFP that the more Iraqi security forces come on line, the less  visible America's 150,000 troops will be.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="12.03225806451613" PS="1.514018691588785" SM="0">In Washington, top Democratic Senator Edward Kennedy called for  a withdrawl of at least 12,000 US troops after Sunday's poll with a  goal of a complete pull out next year.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="17.4375" PS="1.514018691588785" SM="25">Sunday's election has been marred not only by growing violence  but also by a boycott by many Sunni politicians concerned that the  election will cede power to the long-oppressed Shiite majority.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="8.058823529411764" PS="1.514018691588785" SM="3">However, a high turnout is expected among Shiites and Kurds  ready to exercise their right to vote.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="21.964285714285715" PS="1.514018691588785" SM="15">Former US president Bill Clinton called Thursday on Iraq's  Shiite majority to reach out to the nation's Sunni minority if they  win this weekend's election.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="18.166666666666668" PS="1.514018691588785" SM="3">Speaking at the World Economic Forum in Davos, Switzerland, he  also said he was &quot;totally against&quot; the notion of setting a timetable  for the withdrawal of US troops.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="27.318181818181817" PS="2.5023364485981308" SM="25">Insurgents killed at least 19  Iraqis and bombed  polling stations on Thursday in a fierce  campaign to wreck Sunday's general elections.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="19.181818181818183" PS="1.6682242990654206" SM="12">With the election only three days away, violence has been  escalating.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="24.916666666666668" PS="1.1121495327102804" SM="5">The flurry of attacks, following a helicopter crash  that killed 31 US troops on Wednesday, were concentrated on the  heartland of Iraq' minority Sunnis.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="22.6" PS="1.6682242990654206" SM="15">In the deadliest attack on Thursday, a car bomb hit an Iraqi  army patrol near a polling station in Samarra, a mainly Sunni  Muslim city.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="33.4" PS="1.1121495327102804" SM="11">Seven Iraqis were killed and five others wounded,  police said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="14.521739130434783" PS="1.6682242990654206" SM="2">In Baquba, 60 km northeast of the capital Baghdad, a suicide  car bomb hit the headquarters of a provincial government, killing  five people.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="17.6" PS="1.6682242990654206" SM="14">South of Baghdad, in the so-called triangle of death, a  homemade bomb killed five Iraqis and injured 15 on the road  between Mahmudiyah and Latifiyah.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="16.59090909090909" PS="1.6682242990654206" SM="1">Gunmen killed a policeman in an attack in Musayyib, south of  Baghdad, and a roadside bomb killed a police officer in Baiji.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="15.56" PS="1.6682242990654206" SM="2">One US Marine was killed in action and four others wounded  while conducting security and stability operations in Babil  Province, according to the US military.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="19.428571428571427" PS="1.6682242990654206" SM="3">Three small bomb blasts occurred at polling stations in Iraq's  southern city of Basra on Thursday, but no one was hurt, according to a British army spokesman.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="20.575757575757574" PS="1.6682242990654206" SM="4">With about 40 polling stations destroyed by insurgents, even  the distribution of ballot boxes for Iraq's 13 million eligible  voters, about half of the country's population, underscored the  grim security situation.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="18.641025641025642" PS="1.6682242990654206" SM="25">In the Shiite holy city of Najaf, Iraqi police, US troops and  Iraqi security forces sealed off an area within a one-kilometer  perimeter around a school to be used as a polling station when  ballot papers were brought in.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="19.08695652173913" PS="1.6682242990654206" SM="4">Several guerrilla groups, including a faction led by Abu Musab  al-Zarqawi, have declared war on the poll, vowing to kill anyone  who votes.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="15.928571428571429" PS="1.6682242990654206" SM="14">The militant group Army of Ansar al-Sunna issued a &quot;final  warning,&quot; saying anyone who votes would be marked for death,  either during or after the election.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="19.434782608695652" PS="1.6682242990654206" SM="4">&quot;Those who don't pay heed will have only themselves to blame,&quot;  the group said in a statement on the Internet.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="14.257142857142858" PS="1.6682242990654206" SM="2">The faction led by al-Qaida ally Abu Musab al-Zarqawi said  Thursday on a website that it had executed a candidate of interim  Prime Minister Iyad Allawi's party and a video would be released  later.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="18.63157894736842" PS="1.6682242990654206" SM="2">In the past two months, 22 members of Allawi's party were  killed, according to party official Imad Shbib.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="31.0625" PS="1.6682242990654206" SM="29">In the countdown to the election, the Iraqi security forces  bore the brunt of the attacks.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="22.785714285714285" PS="1.1121495327102804" SM="26">While US forces worked to quell the insurgency, the US State Department has asserted that Iraqis will  take &quot;paramount&quot; responsibility in providing security for the  election.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="25.741935483870968" PS="1.6682242990654206" SM="37">&quot;I think you will see on Election Day that most of the security is being provided by the Iraqis and the Iraqi forces,&quot; said State  Department spokesman Richard Boucher.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="16.470588235294116" PS="1.6682242990654206" SM="14">Boucher said US President George W. Bush was confident that the world would recognize the legitimacy of the election despite  worries that it would be marred by a boycott by Sunni Muslims and  violence.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="20.27777777777778" PS="1.6682242990654206" SM="12">US military commanders and Iraqi officials predict that  violence will flare up as insurgents attempt spectacular new  attacks.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="20.136363636363637" PS="1.6682242990654206" SM="26">Meanwhile, US President Bush and interim Iraqi President Ghazi  al-Yawar on Thursday discussed efforts to get Iraqis to vote  despite growing violence.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="19.235294117647058" PS="1.1121495327102804" SM="13">This was the seventh conversation that  Bush has had with Iraqi leaders since the beginning of 2003.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="19.71875" PS="1.6682242990654206" SM="26">Despite Bush's confidence in the election, Turkish Prime  Minister Tayyip Erdogan said on Thursday that the election would  not be fully democratic since one major ethnic group is to be  absent.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="15.931034482758621" PS="1.6682242990654206" SM="17">Russia, a major player in the arena of world politics, said on  Thursday that it would not send observers to monitor the election  due to the security situation there.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="26.513513513513512" PS="2.544392523364486" SM="37">Insurgents set off a car bomb and  attacked polling stations and security forces in several Iraqi  cities Friday, killing at least six people as Iraqi exiles across  the globe began voting in their country's landmark election.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="22.0" PS="1.6962616822429908" SM="15">Four people were killed in a suicide car bomb attack at a power  station in the southern Baghdad neighbourhood of Dura, while an  Iraqi soldier and a policeman were killed in separate attacks in  Samarra and Kirkuk</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="19.114285714285714" PS="1.6962616822429908" SM="28">Campaigning by candidates for Sunday's election officially ended  on Friday, as Iraqi expatraites in 14 countries -- from the Middle  East to Australia to the United States -- began voting in a  three-day process.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="19.833333333333332" PS="1.6962616822429908" SM="0">&quot;Yes, we did it!&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="8.583333333333334" PS="1.1308411214953271" SM="1">shouted Ali al-Kabeer, clapping his hands  after casting his ballot in Dubai and breaking into tears as he  hugged his wife who also voted.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="14.035714285714286" PS="1.6962616822429908" SM="1">Kabeer, a commercial director, said he had &quot;been waiting for  this moment for 54 years,&quot; 24 of which he has spent in England and  the UAE.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="16.736842105263158" PS="1.1308411214953271" SM="1">&quot;I'm doing this for my children ... it's the first step in  a thousand-mile journey.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="15.542857142857143" PS="1.6962616822429908" SM="16">However, insurgents, including Al-Qaeda frontman Abu Musab  al-Zarqawi, have vowed to wreck the country's first democratic vote  in decades and there are fears the violence will pursue right  through the election weekend and beyond.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="18.025" PS="1.6962616822429908" SM="6">At least 60 people have been killed in a spate of attacks across  the country over the past two days alone, in additon to the killing  of 31 US military personnel in a helicopter crash in western Iraq on  Wednesday.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="17.583333333333332" PS="1.6962616822429908" SM="14">The Iraqi authorities have ordered tough security measures,  including a curfew, sealing off the borders and the closure of  Baghdad international airport from Saturday.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="15.630434782608695" PS="1.6962616822429908" SM="16">US President George W. Bush has urged Iraqis to brave death  threats and seize what he termed an &quot;historic opportunity&quot; to vote,  while a British newspaper reported the United States and Britain  have privately agreed on a way of withdrawing their troops from  Iraq.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="19.305555555555557" PS="1.6962616822429908" SM="15">Supporters of Zarqawi, Iraq's most wanted man, on Thursday  posted a video on the Internet of their murder of a candidate in  Iraq's elections from the party of US-backed interim Prime Minister  Iyad Allawi.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="14.076923076923077" PS="1.6962616822429908" SM="4">The Al-Qaeda Group in the Land of Two Rivers announced Sunday on  a website that it had executed Salem Jaafar al-Kanani, &quot;secretary of  the traitor Iyad Allawi&quot;, and a video would be released at a later  time.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="16.23913043478261" PS="1.6962616822429908" SM="2">Allawi's party has had at least 22 of its members killed in the  space of two months, party official Imad Shbib said earlier this  month, adding that as many as 44 had been murdered since the fall of  Saddam Hussein's regime in April 2003.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="21.857142857142858" PS="1.6962616822429908" SM="26">An Islamist group linked to Al-Qaeda warned it would attack  Iraqis involved in the general election even after voting was over.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="12.217391304347826" PS="1.6962616822429908" SM="4">&quot;We have warned you not to go to the centres of this sordid  comedy, called voting bureaus ... we renew our warning.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="16.11111111111111" PS="1.1308411214953271" SM="2">They will be  the targets of the mujahedeen (Islamist fighters),&quot; Ansar al-Sunna  said in a website statement.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="17.710526315789473" PS="1.6962616822429908" SM="26">In London, The Guardian newspaper reported US Defence Secretary  Donald Rumsfeld and his British counterpart Geoff Hoon have agreed  on a so-called exit-strategy based on doubling the number of Iraqi  police trainees and setting up Iraqi paramilitary units.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="22.34375" PS="1.6962616822429908" SM="6">The pair were acting on recommendations from retired US General  Gary Luck, who was sent to Iraq by the Pentagon last month to look  at the failings of Iraq's security force.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="20.848484848484848" PS="1.6962616822429908" SM="5">On Thursday, with some 40 polling stations already destroyed by  insurgent attack, even the distribution of ballot boxes for Iraq's  estimated 14.1 million eligible voters underscored the tension  hanging over the poll.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="10.82857142857143" PS="1.6962616822429908" SM="3">Ballot boxes were distributed to 5,300-odd polling centres  across the country, along with millions of ballot papers and tens of  thousands of bottles of indelible ink which voters will be tagged  with to avoid fraud.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="15.933333333333334" PS="1.6962616822429908" SM="4">The total number of electoral staff is expected to swell to  200,000 on polling day.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="19.916666666666668" PS="1.6962616822429908" SM="14">Bush said the vote offered an &quot;historic opportunity&quot; for Iraqis  to start building a truly democratic society after decades of brutal  dictatorship.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="21.59259259259259" PS="1.6962616822429908" SM="4">&quot;This is a historic opportunity for the people of Iraq to vote  for a government,&quot; Bush said in an interview with Arabic televison  station Al-Arabiya.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="23.93548387096774" PS="1.6962616822429908" SM="15">The US military's top commander in Iraq, General George Casey,  told AFP that the more Iraqi security forces come on line, the less  visible America's 150,000 troops will be.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="17.4375" PS="1.6962616822429908" SM="25">Sunday's election has been marred not only by growing violence  but also by a boycott by many Sunni politicians concerned that the  election will cede power to the long-oppressed Shiite majority.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="8.058823529411764" PS="1.6962616822429908" SM="3">However, a high turnout is expected among Shiites and Kurds  ready to exercise their right to vote.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="22.324324324324323" PS="2.5654205607476634" SM="26">Insurgents set off a car bomb and  attacked voting stations and security forces in several Iraqi cities  Friday, killing at least six people as campaigning for the election  wrapped up and voters began casting their ballots abroad.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="22.03846153846154" PS="1.7102803738317756" SM="3">Four people were killed in a suicide car bomb attack at a power  station in the southern Baghdad neighbourhood of Dura, police and  medical sources said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="13.3" PS="1.7102803738317756" SM="3">&quot;At around 9:00 am (0600 GMT), a black GMC approached the  checkpoint at the entrance of the power plant.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="19.38095238095238" PS="1.1401869158878504" SM="3">There was only a  driver inside the car, his face was masked,&quot; a policeman who  witnessed the attack told AFP.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="16.4375" PS="1.7102803738317756" SM="2">&quot;He was stopped at the checkpoint and a few seconds later, the  explosion went off.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="24.235294117647058" PS="1.1401869158878504" SM="2">We lost three comrades and one civilian was also  killed in the blast,&quot; said the policeman.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="17.91176470588235" PS="1.7102803738317756" SM="4">He was speaking from Baghdad's Yarmuk hospital, where medical  sources at the emergency department confirmed the death toll and  added that three others policemen and a civilian were also wounded  in the attack.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="26.130434782608695" PS="1.7102803738317756" SM="25">Campaigning by candidates for Sunday's election officially ended  on Friday morning, as Iraqi exiles in 14 countries across the globe  began voting.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="17.789473684210527" PS="1.7102803738317756" SM="3">Insurgents, including Al-Qaeda frontman Abu Musab al-Zarqawi,  have vowed to wreck the country's first democratic vote in decades.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="17.583333333333332" PS="1.7102803738317756" SM="14">The Iraqi authorities have ordered tough security measures,  including a curfew, sealing off the borders and the closure of  Baghdad international airport from Saturday.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="17.055555555555557" PS="1.7102803738317756" SM="13">But they have also warned that the insurgent violence will  pursue right through the election weekend and beyond.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="22.53125" PS="1.7102803738317756" SM="17">An Iraqi policeman was killed and two civilians wounded in a  host of attacks on buildings to be used as voting stations around  Kirkuk, 250 kilometers (150 miles) north of the capital.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="24.333333333333332" PS="1.7102803738317756" SM="6">The policeman was shot dead by attackers as he stood guard at  one voting station in the east of the city, police told AFP.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="5.65" PS="1.7102803738317756" SM="0">Kirkuk has a divided population of Kurds, Arabs, Turkmans and  other smaller minorities and has seen mounting violence this week.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="20.14814814814815" PS="1.7102803738317756" SM="6">A car bomb attack went off near a school to be used as a polling  station in the same Baghad neighbourhood where the power station was  targeted.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="17.23076923076923" PS="1.7102803738317756" SM="1">A police officer said the blast had caused material damage but  no casualties.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="19.77777777777778" PS="1.7102803738317756" SM="12">An Iraqi soldier was killed and another wounded when their  patrol vehicle went over a mine near Samarra, in the Sunni Triangle  north of Baghdad, police said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="27.714285714285715" PS="1.7102803738317756" SM="2">Other attacks were reported in the triangle.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="26.03125" PS="1.1401869158878504" SM="6">One man was wounded  in an attack on another polling station at Al-Dur and another  civilian was injured in a mortar attack on a voting centre in  Tikrit, Saddam Hussein's hometown.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="23.130434782608695" PS="1.7102803738317756" SM="16">Dozens of voting stations have been attacked by insurgents who  have put up posters and handed out leaflets warning Iraqis not to  vote.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="18.9" PS="1.7102803738317756" SM="0">US soldiers also discovered three makeshift bombs in Baghdad  Friday.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="23.129032258064516" PS="2.5654205607476634" SM="24">Five US soldiers and at least eight  Iraqis were killed Friday in a string of attacks, two days before  Iraq's landmark elections which insurgents have vowed to drench in  blood.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="15.975" PS="1.7102803738317756" SM="5">A US helicopter also crashed in the Baghdad area, two days after  the crash of a transport helicopter left 31 US troops dead,  inflicting on the US military its heaviest loss in a single incident  since the March 2003 invasion.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="14.346153846153847" PS="1.7102803738317756" SM="1">Lieutenant Colonel James Hutton said that three soldiers were  killed and another wounded in the explosion of a makeshift bomb in a  western district of Baghdad.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="16.805555555555557" PS="1.7102803738317756" SM="15">Another two soldiers were killed and three wounded Friday in two  separate incidents in the capital, bringing to 1,412 the total  number of US servicemen who died in Iraqi since the invasion almost  two years ago.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="12.78125" PS="1.7102803738317756" SM="5">An OH-58 Kiowa Warrior, a reconaissance chopper from the same  Baghdad-based division, crashed in a southwestern district of the  capital, but there was no word on the fate of the two-man crew.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="11.703703703703704" PS="1.7102803738317756" SM="1">&quot;At this time, we have no evidence of hostile fire playing a  role in the helicopter going down,&quot; Colonel Keith Walker said in a  statement.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="21.25" PS="1.7102803738317756" SM="3">Earlier Friday, four people were killed in a suicide car bomb  attack at a power station in the southern Baghdad neighbourhood of  Dura, police and medical sources said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="13.3" PS="1.7102803738317756" SM="3">&quot;At around 9:00 am (0600 GMT), a black GMC approached the  checkpoint at the entrance of the power plant.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="19.38095238095238" PS="1.1401869158878504" SM="3">There was only a  driver inside the car, his face was masked,&quot; a policeman who  witnessed the attack told AFP.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="16.4375" PS="1.7102803738317756" SM="2">&quot;He was stopped at the checkpoint and a few seconds later, the  explosion went off.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="24.235294117647058" PS="1.1401869158878504" SM="2">We lost three comrades and one civilian was also  killed in the blast,&quot; said the policeman.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="17.91176470588235" PS="1.7102803738317756" SM="4">He was speaking from Baghdad's Yarmuk hospital, where medical  sources at the emergency department confirmed the death toll and  added that three other policemen and a civilian were also wounded in  the attack.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="20.3125" PS="1.7102803738317756" SM="24">The bullet-riddled bodies of six Iraqi soldiers were found  Friday in the western city of Ramadi, where two more people were  killed and eight wounded in fighting between Iraqi forces and  insurgents.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="18.166666666666668" PS="1.7102803738317756" SM="2">&quot;The bodies of six soldiers, with their dog-tags, were found in  central Ramadi,&quot; a police officer told AFP on condition of  anonymity.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="11.368421052631579" PS="1.7102803738317756" SM="2">It was the latest in a series of finds of bodies of apparently  executed security personnel in the city.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="18.14814814814815" PS="1.7102803738317756" SM="12">Iraqi troops traded fire with the Sunni Muslim insurgents  Friday, in a gunfight in which a soldier and a civilian were killed,  Lieutenant Colonel Mahmud Mohammed said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="17.636363636363637" PS="1.7102803738317756" SM="1">Four women and four children were also wounded by mortar fire  Thursday night, said Doctor Alaa al-Rawi of the city's hospital.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="22.53125" PS="1.7102803738317756" SM="17">An Iraqi policeman was killed and two civilians wounded in a  host of attacks on buildings to be used as voting stations around  Kirkuk, 250 kilometers (150 miles) north of the capital.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="16.848484848484848" PS="1.7102803738317756" SM="5">The policeman was shot dead by attackers as he stood guard at a  voting station in the east of Kirkuk, which has a divided population  of Kurds, Arabs and Turkmen, police told AFP.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="20.14814814814815" PS="1.7102803738317756" SM="6">A car bomb attack went off near a school to be used as a polling  station in the same Baghad neighbourhood where the power station was  targeted.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="17.416666666666668" PS="1.1401869158878504" SM="1">A police officer said the blast caused material damage but  no casualties.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="22.133333333333333" PS="1.7102803738317756" SM="12">But an Iraqi soldier was killed and another wounded when their  patrol vehicle ran over a mine near Samarra, in the &quot;Sunni Triangle&quot;  north of Baghdad, police said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="27.714285714285715" PS="1.7102803738317756" SM="2">Other attacks were reported in the triangle.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="26.03125" PS="1.1401869158878504" SM="6">One man was wounded  in an attack on another polling station at Al-Dur and another  civilian was injured in a mortar attack on a voting centre in  Tikrit, Saddam Hussein's hometown.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="23.130434782608695" PS="1.7102803738317756" SM="16">Dozens of voting stations have been attacked by insurgents who  have put up posters and handed out leaflets warning Iraqis not to  vote.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="17.666666666666668" PS="2.5023364485981308" SM="29">Hours before Iraqis headed to the polls for a momentous vote, a rocket struck the U.S. Embassy compound Saturday inside the heavily fortified Green Zone, killing two people and shattering the relative calm of election eve in the capital.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="17.333333333333332" PS="1.6682242990654206" SM="3">The rocket attack marked a rare direct hit for insurgents, who frequently target the sprawling embassy complex but have never before killed anyone inside.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="15.827586206896552" PS="1.1121495327102804" SM="15">The stunning strike came despite a massive nationwide security clampdown, complete with Iraqi army tanks rumbling through the capital for the first time since the fall of Saddam Hussein.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="26.125" PS="1.6682242990654206" SM="15">Elsewhere in the country, several bombings and attacks on polling places marred the day before elections.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="10.357142857142858" PS="1.1121495327102804" SM="1">But the kind of large-scale insurgent offensive that some had feared did not materialize.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="12.08" PS="1.1121495327102804" SM="4">Authorities expect the violence to worsen Sunday, when voters will be particularly vulnerable as they venture to some of the more than 5,200 polling places.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="14.633333333333333" PS="1.6682242990654206" SM="2">``I think we'll see millions of people across Iraq vote tomorrow,'' said Lt. Gen. Thomas F. Metz, operational chief for the more than 150,000 coalition troops here.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="18.904761904761905" PS="1.6682242990654206" SM="11">During his weekly radio address Saturday, President Bush hailed Iraqi voters, who he said were ``standing firm'' despite threats.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="17.8" PS="1.1121495327102804" SM="1">His remarks were aired shortly before the embassy was struck.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="22.666666666666668" PS="1.6682242990654206" SM="11">``Tomorrow's elections will happen because of their courage and determination,'' Bush said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="18.64" PS="1.1121495327102804" SM="26">``In the face of assassination, brutal violence and calculated intimidation, Iraqis continue to prepare for the elections and to campaign for their candidates.''</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="6.666666666666667" PS="1.6682242990654206" SM="12">Iraqis are scheduled to choose a 275-member transitional national assembly, 18 provincial councils and, in three northern provinces, a Kurdish Parliament.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="18.210526315789473" PS="1.6682242990654206" SM="13">U.S. and Iraqi security forces spent Saturday setting up cordons around polling stations in an effort to protect voters.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="34.333333333333336" PS="1.6682242990654206" SM="2">``We are on the lookout,'' said Brig.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="7.666666666666667" PS="1.1121495327102804" SM="0">Gen. Adil Molan Ghaidan, police chief in Diyala province northeast of Baghdad.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="13.954545454545455" PS="1.6682242990654206" SM="16">More than 14 million Iraqis are eligible to vote, but turnout is unpredictable amid the violence that has swept across large swaths of Iraq and amid the deep fissures among the nation's three major groups -- Shiite Muslims, Sunni Muslims and ethnic Kurds.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="12.033333333333333" PS="1.6682242990654206" SM="11">This tense capital, its streets devoid of most civilian traffic but bristling with edgy U.S. soldiers and Iraqi forces wearing black ski masks, was oddly quiet through most of Saturday.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="16.033333333333335" PS="1.1121495327102804" SM="5">Anxious troops wary of suicide car bombers trained weapons on the few vehicles that were on Baghdad's usually gridlocked streets, ordering many drivers to halt and submit to searches.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="11.733333333333333" PS="1.1121495327102804" SM="12">At one major intersection, an Iraqi armed personnel carrier incongruously offered free rides to children.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="21.714285714285715" PS="1.6682242990654206" SM="3">Security measures included restrictions on driving, a shutdown of Baghdad's international airport and the closure of the country's borders.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="13.095238095238095" PS="1.6682242990654206" SM="2">Repeated reports circulated that insurgents had stolen police trucks or ambulances and were planning to launch suicide attacks from those vehicles.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="16.25" PS="1.6682242990654206" SM="0">A roadside bomb killed a U.S. soldier in western Baghdad, authorities reported.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="16.606060606060606" PS="1.6682242990654206" SM="5">After nightfall, military trucks rolled through Baghdad's streets shining high-power spotlights and warning residents on loudspeakers to stay indoors during the new curfew hours and heed the government's ban on driving.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="6.777777777777778" PS="1.6682242990654206" SM="1">Sporadic bursts of gunfire resounded through the darkened streets.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="9.95" PS="1.6682242990654206" SM="5">The rocket attack that struck the embassy compound occurred shortly before 8 p.m., triggering a wail of sirens from the Green Zone, a sealed-off swath of central Baghdad that is home to Western diplomats, contract workers, U.S. troops and others.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="22.153846153846153" PS="1.1121495327102804" SM="24">The Iraqi Independent Electoral Commission, which runs the elections, is also housed there.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="14.272727272727273" PS="1.6682242990654206" SM="4">According to a U.S. statement, the rocket struck a building connected to the embassy's annex in Saddam's former Republican Palace.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="17.90909090909091" PS="1.1121495327102804" SM="2">The huge palace houses much of the embassy's office space.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="14.405405405405405" PS="1.6682242990654206" SM="16">The Baghdad embassy, one of the largest U.S. missions in the world, is said to be home to some 3,000 employees, including a huge security contingent along with diplomats, representatives of assorted U.S. agencies and Iraqi staff.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="9.947368421052632" PS="1.6682242990654206" SM="3">The facility sits behind two cordons of concrete blast walls and a series of security barriers, checkpoints and body searches -- all testament to its presence in one of the world's most hostile environments for U.S. personnel.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="14.423076923076923" PS="1.6682242990654206" SM="14">The embassy, which opened last June after sovereignty was returned to an Iraqi interim government, is the first U.S. mission here in more than a decade.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="9.25" PS="1.6682242990654206" SM="3">Many embassy workers are housed in nearby prefabricated trailers protected by blast walls and sandbags; the trailers remain vulnerable to mortar and rocket attacks.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="15.0" PS="1.1121495327102804" SM="1">It was not clear precisely where the rocket hit.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="15.38888888888889" PS="1.6682242990654206" SM="7">Outside the capital, a suicide attack earlier in the day in the small Kurdish town of Khanaqin, near the Iranian border, heightened fears that insurgents may try to infiltrate polling stations with bombs or suicide belts.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="19.785714285714285" PS="1.1121495327102804" SM="2">The bomber killed eight people near a police station after detonating an explosives-laden vest.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="10.578947368421053" PS="1.1121495327102804" SM="2">Six others were injured, according to a source at the Patriotic Union of Kurdistan, a leading Kurdish political party.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="15.15" PS="1.6682242990654206" SM="1">Despite the increased security presence, insurgents hit five polling centers around Baqubah, an ethnically divided regional capital northeast of Baghdad.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="9.772727272727273" PS="1.1121495327102804" SM="1">Mortars struck two schools in the city, homemade bombs damaged two others, and gunmen sprayed a fifth with bullets and rocket-propelled grenades.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="18.346153846153847" PS="1.6682242990654206" SM="2">Scores of attacks have targeted polling places across Iraq in recent days, officials said, but mostly the buildings have been empty and casualties have been low.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="16.11111111111111" PS="1.6682242990654206" SM="27">In and around the city of Kirkuk in the north, seven election centers were attacked with small-arms fire or mortars, according to Lt. Col. Yadgar Mohammed, operations room director for the Iraqi national guard in Kirkuk.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="9.794117647058824" PS="1.6682242990654206" SM="16">In southern Basra, U.S. and Iraqi troops sealed off borders with neighboring countries, padlocking gates leading to Iran, blocking roads to Kuwait and closing the Um Qasir sea port leading to the Persian Gulf.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="15.277777777777779" PS="1.6682242990654206" SM="2">In Baghdad, hundreds of young men showed up near the Convention Center for $200-a-day jobs guarding polling stations.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="12.023255813953488" PS="1.6682242990654206" SM="14">``I've been without a job ever since the war, so I signed up for this job because it seems to be honorable and I'd like to a part of it,'' said Abass Mihseen, 42, a former Iraqi Army officer.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="21.727272727272727" PS="1.1121495327102804" SM="0">``Maybe it's a new start for my career.''</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="14.777777777777779" PS="1.6682242990654206" SM="12">At a schoolhouse being used as a polling center in Baghdad's Sadr City neighborhood, election workers pushed aside metal desks and set up cardboard voting booths.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="20.375" PS="1.6682242990654206" SM="2">``Everything is ready for tomorrow,'' said Dhia Fakhir, 38, manager of the voting center.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="23.5" PS="1.1121495327102804" SM="0">``Nobody resigned.''</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="8.421052631578947" PS="1.6682242990654206" SM="3">By late afternoon, Carlos Valenzuela, the top U.N. adviser to the electoral commission, declared that matters were proceeding apace.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="14.73913043478261" PS="1.6682242990654206" SM="0">``So far, things are going ahead of schedule,'' said a cautious Valenzuela, flanked by bodyguards in Baghdad's cavernous convention center.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="17.964285714285715" PS="1.6682242990654206" SM="15">But election preparations were not as smooth in other parts of the country, particularly in Iraq's Sunni Arab heartland to the north and west of the capital.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="12.482758620689655" PS="1.6682242990654206" SM="3">Sunnis have dominated Iraq for decades but have lost power to rival Shiite and Kurdish groups in the new order following the U.S.-led toppling of Saddam, himself a Sunni.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="14.363636363636363" PS="1.1121495327102804" SM="3">Many Sunni clerics and politicians are vowing to boycott the vote, viewing it as another step in their minority community's marginalization.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="19.214285714285715" PS="1.6682242990654206" SM="3">Insurgents, believed to be mostly Sunni Arabs, have vowed to kill anyone who votes.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="7.925925925925926" PS="1.6682242990654206" SM="1">Mohammad Jobouri, head of the electoral commission in largely Sunni Salahuddin province, predicted that only 10 percent of voters would turn out in Tikrit, Saddam's birthplace.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="13.5625" PS="1.1121495327102804" SM="2">It is possible that no one will vote in the restive city of Samarra, he added.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="1.6666666666666667" PS="1.6682242990654206" SM="0">(Optional add end)</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="25.11764705882353" PS="1.6682242990654206" SM="2">``It's all because of the bad security, violence and terrorist attacks recently,'' he said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="11.88888888888889" PS="1.6682242990654206" SM="2">Some Shiite clerics have preached that anyone who does not vote today will face the wrath of God.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="12.925925925925926" PS="1.1121495327102804" SM="14">The Shiite religious and political leadership views the elections as a means of gaining their long-denied place of power in Iraq, where they are in the majority.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="16.2" PS="1.1121495327102804" SM="3">Kurds are also encouraging people to vote despite the threats.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="14.75" PS="1.6682242990654206" SM="1">Throughout Iraq, people vowed not to be intimidated.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="13.38888888888889" PS="1.6682242990654206" SM="1">``This is going to be a free and honest experiment,'' said Amir Moosa, 42, of Basra.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="13.333333333333334" PS="1.1121495327102804" SM="0">``We do not fear threats.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="6.166666666666667" PS="1.1121495327102804" SM="0">Even bombs won't stop us.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="15.8" PS="1.1121495327102804" SM="0">It is our destiny.''</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="5.846153846153846" PS="1.6682242990654206" SM="1">Times staff writers Alissa J. Rubin in Baghdad and Tom Hamburger in Washington and special correspondents in Samarra, Basra, Kirkuk and Baghdad contributed to this report.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="26.9" PS="2.292056074766355" SM="15">A suicide car bomber killed five  people Saturday in an attack on a political party's offices in the  Iraqi town of Khanaqin near the border with Iran, police said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="30.666666666666668" PS="1.52803738317757" SM="16">Six police were killed in other attacks around Baghdad and  strikes against poll stations were reported across Iraq on the eve  of the country's historic election.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="36.36363636363637" PS="1.0186915887850467" SM="1">The US military said at least  one insurgent was also killed.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="16.785714285714285" PS="1.52803738317757" SM="27">A major gunbattle also erupted in central Baghdad as a convoy of  Iraqi soldiers moved from the Green Zone, a high security area that  houses the Iraqi government and the US embassy, towards one of the  main bridges crossing the Tigris river.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="14.366666666666667" PS="1.52803738317757" SM="4">A child and four adults were killed in the early morning attack  in Khanaqin, which lies about 120 kilometers (100 miles) northeast  of Baghdad, close to the frontier with Iran.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="22.84375" PS="1.52803738317757" SM="4">&quot;The suicide bomber's car was packed with explosives when he  drove into the headquarters of the Turkmen of Iraq Front,&quot; said  Colonel Mahmoud Abdallah of the town's police.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="21.696969696969695" PS="1.52803738317757" SM="17">Insurgents have stepped up attacks on political parties,  security forces and civilians in the run-up to Sunday's election,  the first since the fall of former president Saddam Hussein almost  two years ago.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="17.352941176470587" PS="1.52803738317757" SM="4">Four police were shot dead just before midnight Friday as they  drove on the main road between the towns of Baiji and Shorgat, about  200 kilometers (120 miles) north of the capital, police said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="26.555555555555557" PS="1.52803738317757" SM="4">Four other polling stations in Baiji faced bomb attacks on  Saturday and two on Friday night in Shorgat.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="29.55" PS="1.52803738317757" SM="2">Insurgents attacked a police patrol at Salman Pak, just south of  Baghdad, on Saturday killing two security forces, police said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="23.05263157894737" PS="1.52803738317757" SM="3">Gunmen opened fire on a polling station in the Jamia district of  western Baghdad wounding one woman, police said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="34.608695652173914" PS="1.52803738317757" SM="16">The US military said Iraqi forces fought off an attack on a  power station in southwestern Mosul on Friday night, killing one  insurgent.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="27.037037037037038" PS="2.5023364485981308" SM="15">Four hundred Iraqis have been killed so  far this month and dozens of voting stations attacked across Iraq on  Friday, a senior US military officer said Saturday.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="23.151515151515152" PS="1.6682242990654206" SM="25">The commander, speaking on condition of anonymity, said 400  Iraqi civilians, officials and security officers had been killed as  part of a campaign of intimidation ahead of Sunday's election, the  officer said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="27.923076923076923" PS="1.6682242990654206" SM="3">As part of that campaign, insurgents have escalated their  attacks on polling stations.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="35.294117647058826" PS="1.6682242990654206" SM="5">&quot;It was... 45 attacks on polling stations around the country  yesterday,&quot; the officer said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="29.57894736842105" PS="1.6682242990654206" SM="17">Iraq is on high alert for violence on the day of the election,  the first free vote in decades.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="20.756756756756758" PS="2.5023364485981308" SM="15">A suicide bomber wearing an  explosives belt walked up to an Iraqi polling station on Saturday  and set off a blast that killed a child and seven adults, including  three soldiers, said police and the US military.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="27.53125" PS="1.6682242990654206" SM="16">The attack was one of a series by insurgents in which at least  18 people were killed on the eve of Iraq's historic election despite  massive security measures across the country.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="15.045454545454545" PS="1.6682242990654206" SM="4">The suicide bomber approached workers putting up protective  barriers around the voting centre in Khanaqin, a town near the  border with Iran.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="21.80952380952381" PS="1.6682242990654206" SM="5">The blast killed the child, the three soldiers and four of the  workers and wounded seven more workers, the sources said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="15.0" PS="1.6682242990654206" SM="3">The polling centre is close to the headquarters of a Turkmen  political party.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="21.333333333333332" PS="1.6682242990654206" SM="3">In Sulimaniyah, an official with the Kurdistan Patriotic Union  said the attacker had been identified as a Sudanese member of Iraq's  most wanted man Abu Musab al-Zarqawi's network.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="16.857142857142858" PS="1.6682242990654206" SM="1">&quot;It was a Sudanese member of Al-Qaeda,&quot; Molla Bakhtiar, a member  of the party's political bureau, told reporters.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="21.77777777777778" PS="1.6682242990654206" SM="12">Neither US nor Iraqi authorities could confirm the statement.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="13.5" PS="1.6682242990654206" SM="13">Zarqawi, a Jordanian-born fugitive with a 25 million dollar US  price on his head, has taken a high profile role opposing the  elections and threatening &quot;all-out war&quot; against everyone involved.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="18.045454545454547" PS="1.6682242990654206" SM="0">In Samara, 120 kilometres (75 miles) north of Baghdad, a soldier  and a policeman were killed in clashes with insurgents, police said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="20.25" PS="1.1121495327102804" SM="0">Four soldiers and two civilians were also wounded.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="21.696969696969695" PS="1.6682242990654206" SM="17">Insurgents have stepped up attacks on political parties,  security forces and civilians in the run-up to Sunday's election,  the first since the fall of former president Saddam Hussein almost  two years ago.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="29.5" PS="1.6682242990654206" SM="5">As well as the suicide bomber, the US military said an insurgent  was killed trying to attack a power station.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="17.64516129032258" PS="1.6682242990654206" SM="4">Four police were shot dead just before midnight Friday on the  main road between the towns of Baiji and Shorgat, about 200  kilometers (120 miles) north of the capital, police said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="27.352941176470587" PS="1.6682242990654206" SM="4">Four polling stations in Baiji faced bomb attacks on Saturday  and two on Friday night in Shorgat.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="20.041666666666668" PS="1.6682242990654206" SM="1">US forces clashed with insurgents in the Sunni stronghold town  of Ramadi, west of Baghdad, and one civilian was killed, a hospital  doctor said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="21.428571428571427" PS="1.6682242990654206" SM="1">American forces were deployed across the city.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="20.75" PS="1.1121495327102804" SM="3">Three voting  stations were opened and almost immediately came under rebel  attack.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="21.227272727272727" PS="1.6682242990654206" SM="3">One policeman was shot dead in an attack on a polling station  Saturday in Moqdadiya, 105 kilometers (65 miles) north of Baghdad.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="29.55" PS="1.6682242990654206" SM="2">Insurgents attacked a police patrol at Salman Pak, just south of  Baghdad, on Saturday killing two security forces, police said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="23.05263157894737" PS="1.6682242990654206" SM="3">Gunmen opened fire on a polling station in the Jamia district of  western Baghdad wounding one woman, police said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="19.27659574468085" PS="1.6682242990654206" SM="39">US and Iraqi forces fought insurgents in Baghdad and a heavy  bursts of gunfire erupted in the centre of the capital as a convoy  of Iraqi soldiers moved from the Green Zone, the high security area  that houses the Iraqi government and the US and British embassies.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="32.96153846153846" PS="1.6682242990654206" SM="17">The US military said Iraqi forces fought off an attack on a  power station in the northern city of Mosul on Friday night, killing  one insurgent.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="22.4390243902439" PS="2.5023364485981308" SM="29">The group of Al-Qaeda's frontman in Iraq  Abu Musab al-Zarqawi claimed responsibility Saturday for a suicide  attack at an Iraqi polling station and vowed to spill more blood on  election day, according to a statement posted on an Islamist  website.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="16.651162790697676" PS="1.6682242990654206" SM="7">&quot;A lion from the martyrdom-seeking brigade of the Al-Qaeda Group  of Jihad in the Land of Two Rivers carried out an attack against the  Americans and their agents in the Khanaqin region,&quot; said the  statement, whose authenticity could not be verified.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="14.9" PS="1.6682242990654206" SM="1">&quot;This is only (a small) part of what our virtuous sheikh Abu  Musab al-Zarqawi promised,&quot; the statement said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="15.159090909090908" PS="1.6682242990654206" SM="18">&quot;We warn for the last time that tomorrow will be a bloody day  for the Jews, the Christians, their agents, and anyone who agrees to  play the American-Allawi game,&quot; added the statement in a reference  to Iraqi interim Prime Minister Iyad Allawi.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="18.869565217391305" PS="1.6682242990654206" SM="26">Iraqi police and the US military said that a suicide bomber  wearing an explosives belt walked up to an Iraqi polling station in  Khanaqin, a town near the border with Iran, and set off a blast that  killed eight people, including a child and three soldiers.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="27.34375" PS="1.6682242990654206" SM="16">The attack was one of a series by insurgents in which at least  18 people were killed on the eve of Iraq's US-backed election  despite massive security measures across the country.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="16.93103448275862" PS="1.6682242990654206" SM="4">An official from the Patriotic Union of Kurdistan (PUK) in the  Kurdish town of Suleimaniyah said the attacker had been identified  as a Sudanese member of Zarqawi's network.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="16.857142857142858" PS="1.6682242990654206" SM="1">&quot;It was a Sudanese member of Al-Qaeda,&quot; Molla Bakhtiar, a member  of the party's political bureau, told reporters.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="19.59090909090909" PS="1.6682242990654206" SM="3">Zarqawi, a Jordanian-born fugitive with a 25-million-dollar US  price on his head, has threatened to attack anyone involved in  Sunday's polls.</sentence>
	</Sentences>
</Topic>
