<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<Topic id="D0912C">
	<Sentences>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="24.976190476190474" PS="2.53125" SM="26">Two senior White House aides met here on Saturday with the angry mother of a fallen U.S. soldier, but they rejected Cindy Sheehan's demand for a direct accounting from President Bush for the way he has conducted the war in Iraq.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="17.27777777777778" PS="1.6875" SM="14">The surprise meeting, which lasted about 45 minutes, took place on a roadside several miles from the president's ranch, where federal and local law enforcement officials had halted Sheehan's advance toward the 1,600-acre estate.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="23.90909090909091" PS="1.125" SM="2">Bush is spending much of August on vacation at the ranch.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="15.4" PS="1.6875" SM="12">Sheehan, a 48-year-old Vacaville, Calif., woman, was accompanied by more than 50 placard-wielding anti-war activists.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="9.135135135135135" PS="1.125" SM="12">After police and Secret Service agents halted their march on a country lane, Sheehan and a half-dozen die-hard supporters stayed put while others turned back, trudging slowly down Prairie Chapel Road under the hot Central Texas sun.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="20.236842105263158" PS="1.6875" SM="12">In a telephone interview after her conversation with National Security Adviser Stephen J. Hadley and White House deputy chief of staff Joe Hagin, Sheehan said she would remain in Crawford and continue to seek a meeting with Bush.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="37.0" PS="1.6875" SM="0">``I didn't change my mind at all,'' she said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="27.0" PS="1.6875" SM="13">``They said the president really believed that Saddam Hussein had weapons of mass destruction,'' Sheehan added.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="14.5" PS="1.125" SM="0">``And I told them: `I might be a grieving mom, but you men are very intelligent, and I know you don't believe what you're telling me.'''</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="25.8" PS="1.6875" SM="12">Hadley and Hagin said they would relay her sentiments to the president, according to Sheehan.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="22.571428571428573" PS="1.6875" SM="3">Bush has met privately around the country with numerous family members of soldiers killed in Iraq and Afghanistan, but not with relatives who are overtly against the war.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="14.842105263157896" PS="1.6875" SM="3">``We mourn the loss of every life and Americans deeply appreciate those who have made the supreme sacrifice.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="15.310344827586206" PS="1.125" SM="2">The way to honor that sacrifice is to complete the mission so that their lives were not lost in vain,'' said White House deputy press secretary Trent Duffy.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="23.88888888888889" PS="1.6875" SM="13">Sheehan's son, Casey, 24, was killed in the Sadr City section of Baghdad on April 4, 2004.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="22.291666666666668" PS="1.125" SM="2">Afterward, she co-founded Gold Star Families for Peace, an organization of people who have lost loved ones in Iraq or who oppose the war.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="21.928571428571427" PS="1.125" SM="14">Previously, Sheehan was turned away while trying to protest the war at the Pentagon.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="25.29032258064516" PS="1.6875" SM="1">She told reporters here that she not only opposes the war but also strongly objects to Bush's assertions that fallen U.S. soldiers had died ``for a noble cause.''</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="20.1" PS="1.6875" SM="0">``I don't want him to use my son's name, or my name, to justify any more killings.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="27.314285714285713" PS="1.125" SM="14">And I want to tell the president that, and I want to ask the president why my son died,'' Sheehan said, contending that the war was ``based on horrendous lies and deceptions.''</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="23.548387096774192" PS="1.6875" SM="4">Her meeting with two of Bush's top aides came amid a spike in U.S. casualties in Iraq, accompanied by sagging public support for the president's conduct of the war.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="14.0" PS="1.6875" SM="4">A Newsweek poll released on Saturday found that 61 percent of Americans now disapprove of Bush's handling of the war while 34 percent approve.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="23.22222222222222" PS="1.125" SM="3">This is Bush's lowest approval rating on Iraq and the first time that it has dropped below 40 percent in the Newsweek Poll, the magazine said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="16.0" PS="1.6875" SM="4">Half of those polled said the United States is losing ground in its efforts to establish security and democracy in Iraq while 40 percent said the United States is making progress there.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="24.266666666666666" PS="2.53125" SM="5">The mother of an American soldier killed in Iraq led a protest march on President Bush's ranch here on Saturday, prompting the White House to send two senior officials to meet her after she was blocked by the authorities from approaching Bush's home.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="21.15909090909091" PS="1.6875" SM="26">The mother, Cindy Sheehan, who has made regular public appearances in opposition to the war, was accompanied by several dozen chanting anti-war activists, including other parents who had lost children to the war, as she walked down a country road toward Bush's ranch.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="15.75" PS="1.125" SM="2">About five miles from the ranch, they were met by the local police, who barred them from getting any closer.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="33.46666666666667" PS="1.125" SM="11">Sheehan said she would remain as close as possible until Bush agreed to see her.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="17.106382978723403" PS="1.6875" SM="16">Later on Saturday afternoon, the two senior officials -- Stephen J. Hadley, the national security adviser, and Joe Hagin, a deputy White House chief of staff -- went out to meet with Sheehan and several other protesters, said Trent D. Duffy, a spokesman for the White House.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="28.235294117647058" PS="1.6875" SM="12">They met for about 45 minutes, and Sheehan told the two men she appreciated their seeing her.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="41.666666666666664" PS="1.6875" SM="0">Her son, Spc.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="17.055555555555557" PS="1.125" SM="13">Casey A. Sheehan of the Army, a Humvee mechanic, was killed April 24, 2004, in Sadr City, Iraq.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="19.333333333333332" PS="1.125" SM="0">He was 24.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="17.15" PS="1.125" SM="12">As she walked through Crawford on Saturday, Sheehan carried pictures of him as a toddler and in his Army fatigues.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="30.61904761904762" PS="1.6875" SM="1">Before meeting with the officials, she told reporters, &quot;I want to ask George Bush: Why did my son die?&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="24.033333333333335" PS="1.6875" SM="6">She said she was particularly upset by Bush's characterization, in a speech on Wednesday in Grapevine, Texas, of the war and the sacrifice of the families of fallen troops.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="20.22222222222222" PS="1.6875" SM="1">&quot;Our men and women who have lost their lives in Iraq and Afghanistan and in this war on terror have died in a noble cause, in a selfless cause,&quot; Bush said in the speech.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="16.605263157894736" PS="1.6875" SM="6">The confrontation came at the end of a particularly deadly week in Iraq for American troops, and at a time when polls have shown that public approval of Bush's handling of the war has reached new lows.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="19.263157894736842" PS="2.8125" SM="7">The angry mother of a fallen U.S. soldier has met with advisers of President George W. Bush after staging a protest near his ranch to demand an accounting of how the president has conducted the war in Iraq.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="31.785714285714285" PS="1.875" SM="0">Supported by more than 50 demonstrators who chanted, &quot;W. killed her son!&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="28.352941176470587" PS="1.25" SM="23">Cindy Sheehan told reporters: &quot;I want to ask the president, 'Why did you kill my son?</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="34.857142857142854" PS="1.25" SM="0">What did my son die for?'&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="18.583333333333332" PS="1.875" SM="12">Sheehan, 48, didn't get to see Bush, but did talk about 45 minutes with national security adviser Steve Hadley and deputy White House chief of staff Joe Hagin, who went out to hear her concerns.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="23.962962962962962" PS="1.875" SM="12">Appreciative of their attention, yet undaunted, Sheehan said she planned to continue her roadside vigil, except for a few breaks, until she gets to talk to Bush.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="25.357142857142858" PS="1.25" SM="0">Her son, Casey, 24, was killed in Sadr City, Iraq, on April 4, 2004.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="9.875" PS="1.25" SM="0">He was an Army specialist, a Humvee mechanic.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="19.0" PS="1.875" SM="16">&quot;They (the advisers) said we are in Iraq because they believed Saddam Hussein had weapons of mass destruction, that the world's a better place with Saddam gone and that we're making the world a safer place with what we're doing over there,&quot; Sheehan said in a telephone interview after the meeting.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="26.4" PS="1.875" SM="0">&quot;They were very respectful.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="10.75" PS="1.25" SM="0">They were nice men.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="15.65" PS="1.25" SM="1">I told them Iraq was not a threat to the United States and that now people are dead for nothing.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="25.071428571428573" PS="1.25" SM="0">I told them I wouldn't leave until I talked to George Bush.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="33.833333333333336" PS="1.875" SM="0">She said Hagin told her, &quot;I want to assure you that he (Bush) really does care.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="23.473684210526315" PS="1.875" SM="0">&quot;And I said if he does care, why doesn't he come out and talk to me.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="20.0" PS="1.875" SM="12">Sheehan arrived in Crawford aboard a bus painted red, white and blue and emblazoned with the words, &quot;Impeachment Tour.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="18.0" PS="1.25" SM="11">Sheehan, from Vacaville, California, had been attending a Veterans for Peace convention in Dallas.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="17.38095238095238" PS="1.875" SM="3">The bus, trailed by about 20 cars of protesters and reporters, drove at about 15 (24 kph) toward Bush's ranch.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="7.285714285714286" PS="1.25" SM="2">After several miles (kilometers), they parked the vehicles and began to march, in stifling heat, farther down the narrow country road.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="16.9375" PS="1.875" SM="14">Flanked by miles (kilometers) of pasture, Sheehan spoke with reporters while clutching two photographs, one of her son in uniform, and the other, a baby picture, when he was seven months old.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="20.96875" PS="1.875" SM="1">She said she decided to come to Crawford a few days ago after Bush said that fallen U.S. troops had died for a noble cause and that the mission must be completed.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="25.846153846153847" PS="1.875" SM="1">&quot;I want to ask the president, `Why did you kill my son?</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="34.857142857142854" PS="1.25" SM="0">What did my son die for?&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="44.714285714285715" PS="1.25" SM="0">she said, her voice cracking with emotion.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="24.833333333333332" PS="1.25" SM="0">&quot;Last week, you said my son died for a noble cause' and I want to ask him what that noble cause is?&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="17.529411764705884" PS="1.875" SM="1">White House spokesman Trent Duffy said response that Bush also wants the troops to return home safely.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="21.55263157894737" PS="1.875" SM="6">&quot;Many of the hundreds of families the president has met with know their loved one died for a noble cause and that the best way to honor their sacrifice is to complete the mission,&quot; Duffy said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="26.05" PS="1.875" SM="1">&quot;It is a message the president has heard time and again from those he has met with and comforted.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="20.23076923076923" PS="1.25" SM="1">Like all Americans, he wants the troops home as soon as possible.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="16.75" PS="2.25" SM="6">The mother of a fallen U.S. soldier who is holding a roadside peace vigil near President George W. Bush's ranch shares the same grief as relatives mourning the deaths of Ohio Marines, yet their views about the war differ.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="31.75" PS="1.5" SM="0">&quot;I'm angry.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="26.82857142857143" PS="1.0" SM="25">I want the troops home,&quot; Cindy Sheehan, 48, of California, who staged a protest that she vowed on Sunday to continue until she can personally ask Bush: &quot;Why did you kill my son?</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="34.857142857142854" PS="1.0" SM="0">What did my son die for?&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="1.8333333333333333" PS="1.5" SM="1">Jim Boskovitch, father of slain Cpl.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="14.461538461538462" PS="1.0" SM="2">Jeffery Boskovitch, 25, of Ohio, is supporting the U.S. military action in Iraq.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="20.0" PS="1.5" SM="1">&quot;I firmly believe, and I would echo my son's feeling on this, it is very, very important for our country to remain steadfast and complete the mission that they set out to accomplish,&quot; Boskovitch told ABC on Sunday.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="9.615384615384615" PS="1.5" SM="0">Boskovitch is among several families mourning Ohio Marines who suffered heavy losses in three attacks starting July 28, when two were killed in a gun battle.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="10.375" PS="1.0" SM="0">On Monday, five were killed in an ambush.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="13.214285714285714" PS="1.0" SM="0">Nine were killed Wednesday when an armored vehicle was hit by a roadside bomb.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="7.142857142857143" PS="1.5" SM="2">Rosemary Palmer, the mother of Lance Cpl.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="20.153846153846153" PS="1.0" SM="11">Edward Schroeder, 23, another Ohio Marine killed in Iraq, sided more with Sheehan.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="13.555555555555555" PS="1.0" SM="3">If the United States continues its current course in Iraq, the death toll of U.S. troops, now at more than 1,820, will only grow, she told ABC.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="22.035714285714285" PS="1.5" SM="2">&quot;We either have to have more people there to do the job and better equipment, or we have to leave _ one or the other,&quot; she said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="19.47826086956522" PS="1.5" SM="1">Boskovitch said his son, Jeff, &quot;felt extremely, extremely strongly about the Iraqi people and our government deciding to go over there.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="13.2" PS="1.5" SM="0">&quot;His commander in chief needed him to be there, as well as those fellow soldiers, to help those people, help that country to be able to stand on its own and to liberate those people,&quot; Boskovitch told ABC.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="23.36842105263158" PS="1.5" SM="11">Sheehan was among grieving military families who met with Bush in June 2004 at Fort Lewis, near Seattle, Washington.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="23.157894736842106" PS="1.0" SM="0">That was just two months after her son, Casey, was killed in Sadr City, Iraq, on April 4, 2004.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="16.647058823529413" PS="1.5" SM="2">Since then, she said, various government and independent commission reports have disputed the Bush administration's claims that Saddam Hussein had mass-killing chemical and biological weapons _ a main justification for the March 2003 invasion.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="31.928571428571427" PS="1.5" SM="11">&quot;I was still in shock then,&quot; Sheehan said in a telephone interview.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="35.38461538461539" PS="1.5" SM="12">&quot;All of those reports prove my son died needlessly,&quot; said Sheehan.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="25.705882352941178" PS="1.0" SM="0">&quot;This proved that every reason George Bush gave us for going to war was wrong.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="22.692307692307693" PS="1.5" SM="14">Sheehan, who formed a group called Gold Star Families For Peace and has spoken out against the war across the nation, talked for about 45 minutes on Saturday with Steve Hadley, Bush's national security adviser, and Joe Hagin, deputy White House chief of staff, who went out to hear her concerns.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="24.666666666666668" PS="1.5" SM="17">Appreciative of their attention, yet undaunted, Sheehan said she planned to continue her protest along the road during Bush's stay through the end of the month.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="23.272727272727273" PS="1.5" SM="0">&quot;If he doesn't come out and talk to me in Crawford, I'll follow him to D.C.,&quot; she said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="20.766666666666666" PS="1.0" SM="3">&quot;I'll camp on his lawn in D.C. until he has the courtesy and the integrity and the compassion to talk to somebody whose life he has ruined.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="23.419354838709676" PS="2.53125" SM="0">For more than a year, a modest bungalow known as ``Peace House,'' located a few miles from President Bush's ranch, has served as a headquarters for antiwar activists.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="14.823529411764707" PS="1.6875" SM="2">It is lonely work, with little more than a skeleton crew on hand much of the time.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="25.333333333333332" PS="1.6875" SM="22">But then Cindy Sheehan hit town.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="7.857142857142857" PS="1.6875" SM="2">The 48-year old mother of Army Spc.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="17.91304347826087" PS="1.125" SM="14">Casey Sheehan, who was killed in an ambush in Baghdad, Iraq, last year, is consumed by the kind of grief that turns into a furious determination to do something -- in her case, to confront the president and force him to explain why her son died.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="13.136986301369863" PS="1.6875" SM="16">Now, in the space of just a few days, what started out as a seemingly quixotic personal mission has become something of a phenomenon -- with media swarming around Sheehan, leading liberal and antiwar activists parachuting in to try to make her their long-sought voice, and political experts in both parties working to assess what role she may have in galvanizing the public's gathering unhappiness with the increasing American casualties in Iraq.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="15.833333333333334" PS="1.6875" SM="14">Antiwar leaders hope that putting the spotlight on Sheehan will motivate Americans who oppose the war, creating a political force strong enough to compel the Bush administration to change course.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="11.303030303030303" PS="1.6875" SM="1">MoveOn.org and other liberal groups have rushed to provide support, offering media expertise and attempting to assemble a corps of others who have lost relatives in Iraq or have family members serving there.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="16.545454545454547" PS="1.6875" SM="1">Liberal voices have swung into action on the Internet as well.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="15.55" PS="1.125" SM="11">On Wednesday, Democratic media consultant Joe Trippi organized a conference call with Sheehan for bloggers, aiming to garner more publicity.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="26.45" PS="1.125" SM="24">By Wednesday afternoon, ``Cindy Sheehan'' was the top-ranked search term on Technorati.com, the search engine for blog postings.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="26.96153846153846" PS="1.6875" SM="14">The White House, meantime, has sought to cope with Sheehan's vigil without abandoning its strategy for dealing with the families of troops who have died.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="20.285714285714285" PS="1.125" SM="2">On a number of occasions, Bush has met with bereaved relatives -- including some who have challenged him sharply on the war -- but he has done so privately, away from news cameras and reporters.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="22.791666666666668" PS="1.6875" SM="13">Sheehan, a Vacaville resident who opposed the war even before her son's death, was a member of one such group in June 2004.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="16.0" PS="1.125" SM="0">She came away from that meeting dissatisfied and angry.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="16.782608695652176" PS="1.6875" SM="2">``We wanted (the president) to look at pictures of Casey, we wanted him to hear stories about Casey, and he wouldn't.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="29.727272727272727" PS="1.125" SM="12">He changed the subject every time we tried,'' Sheehan said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="16.416666666666668" PS="1.125" SM="0">He wouldn't say Casey's name, called him: `your loved one.'</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="87.0" PS="1.125" SM="0">``</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="24.275862068965516" PS="1.6875" SM="13">Sheehan, a co-founder of the antiwar group Gold Star Families for Peace, has said that she will remain in Crawford until she gets to see Bush face to face.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="16.818181818181817" PS="1.6875" SM="11">Until a sudden cloudburst forced her to move to Peace House early Wednesday morning, Sheehan had been camping in a tent along a road about two miles from Bush's Prairie Chapel Ranch.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="17.365853658536587" PS="1.125" SM="3">On Saturday, the day she arrived in Crawford, two senior White House aides -- national security adviser Stephen Hadley and deputy chief of staff Joe Hagin -- left the ranch to meet with her on a dusty road for 45 minutes.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="38.166666666666664" PS="1.6875" SM="0">That, she said, was not satisfactory.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="18.0" PS="1.6875" SM="11">By Wednesday night, Sheehan had given so many interviews that she was sucking on lozenges to soothe an inflamed throat.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="16.5" PS="1.125" SM="0">Her ears were sore from cradling a telephone.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="23.785714285714285" PS="1.125" SM="11">Her media adviser, newly arrived from San Francisco, said Sheehan had developed a fever.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="17.8" PS="1.6875" SM="1">None of that stopped her.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="15.461538461538462" PS="1.125" SM="0">Whether talking to newspaper reporters, People magazine or radio and television interviewers -- some from as far away as Japan -- she was relentlessly on message.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="26.655172413793103" PS="1.6875" SM="3">''I don't believe his phony excuses for the war,`` she said of Bush in an interview with a CBS reporter for the network's northern California affiliates.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="13.2" PS="1.125" SM="0">''I want him to tell me why my son died.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="18.545454545454547" PS="1.6875" SM="1">``If he gave the real answer, people in this country would be outraged -- if he told people it was to make his buddies rich, that it was about oil ... ''</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="26.46153846153846" PS="1.6875" SM="14">Sheehan is certainly not the first to denounce the president over the war.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="21.181818181818183" PS="1.125" SM="1">From the beginning, activists have been outspoken in criticizing Bush's policy and his stated reasons for sending U.S. troops into Iraq.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="18.355555555555554" PS="1.6875" SM="20">For the moment however, the personal nature of Sheehan's protest -- with its edge of raw emotion -- and the concentration of news media staked out in Crawford, where Bush is spending much of August, have combined to raise her voice above the crowd.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="19.04" PS="1.6875" SM="0">``Anything that focuses media and public attention on Iraq war casualties day after day -- particularly (something) that is a good visual for television, like a weeping Gold Star mother -- is a really bad thing for President Bush and his administration,'' said independent political analyst Charlie Cook.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="20.275862068965516" PS="1.6875" SM="2">``Americans get a little numb by the numbers of war casualties, but when faces, names and families are added, it has a much greater effect,'' he said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="19.951219512195124" PS="1.6875" SM="25">``Cindy Sheehan has tapped into a latent but fervent feeling among some in this country who would prefer that we not engage our troops in Iraq,'' said Republican strategist Kellyanne Conway, president of the Washington-based firm The Polling Company.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="20.714285714285715" PS="1.6875" SM="2">``She can tap into what has been an astonishingly silent minority since the end of last year's presidential contest.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="20.8" PS="1.125" SM="0">It will capture attention.''</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="20.272727272727273" PS="1.6875" SM="12">But other analysts predicted Sheehan would soon fade from the scene.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="29.444444444444443" PS="1.6875" SM="13">``The president has an Iraq problem, but I don't think it's much worsened by Mrs. Sheehan,'' said Stephen Hess of George Washington University.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="20.3125" PS="1.125" SM="0">``One Gold Star mother is a sympathetic figure, but collectively -- as Gold Star Families for Peace -- she is a movement and, as such, can be countered by a counter-movement.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="17.357142857142858" PS="1.6875" SM="2">''I think the president might have defused the situation if he had invited her in instantly,`` Hess said, predicting that GOP strategists would soon mount a counterattack.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="5.571428571428571" PS="1.6875" SM="1">Already, there were signs of just that.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="21.933333333333334" PS="1.6875" SM="13">Some have suggested that Sheehan is disloyal to criticize the president in time of war.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="37.06666666666667" PS="1.125" SM="11">Even in Vacaville, Sheehan said, some people say she is shaming her son's memory.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="19.153846153846153" PS="1.125" SM="12">Conservative blogger Michelle Malkin disdainfully called the activists promoting Sheehan ''grief pimps.``</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="15.935483870967742" PS="1.6875" SM="15">The antiwar activists who have rushed to Sheehan's side are all too well aware of the danger that her moment in the spotlight could become just another partisan shouting match.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="11.0" PS="1.6875" SM="1">Said Tom Matzzie of MoveOn.org: ''Cindy reached out to us.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="9.9375" PS="1.125" SM="0">We're e-mailing our members about her story today, running a print ad in Waco (Texas).</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="17.903225806451612" PS="1.125" SM="13">Cindy is a morally pure voice on the war, so we're trying to keep the focus on her and not jump in and turn it into a political fight.``</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="20.0" PS="1.6875" SM="11">Since Sheehan arrived in Crawford, Peace House has been transformed into a beehive.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="13.0" PS="1.6875" SM="16">On the porch, bottles of water -- and a huge box of collapsible pink umbrellas -- were waiting Wednesday to be ferried out to ''Camp Casey,`` the muddy staging area along Prairie Chapel Road where Sheehan and about 100 of her supporters were gathered.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="6.894736842105263" PS="1.6875" SM="13">On a table in the living room were stacks of white T-shirts that read ''BUSH ... Talk to Cindy!</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="21.75" PS="1.125" SM="1">Moms and Vets Will Stop the War!``</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="5.714285714285714" PS="1.6875" SM="2">In the tiny kitchen, two women busily chopped carrots and celery as they prepared to feed a growing cadre of activists.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="19.75" PS="1.125" SM="1">Other volunteers talked on their cellphones, coordinating with supporters around the country.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="20.103448275862068" PS="1.6875" SM="13">There was much speculation about ``other moms'' and parents of troops serving in the war coming to join Sheehan, although no one seemed to know for certain.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="26.416666666666668" PS="1.125" SM="0">``A busload is coming from Seattle,'' one woman called out.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="32.4" PS="1.6875" SM="11">Stephanie Frizzell, 30, said she drove from Dallas with her son, Julian, 4, ``to provide support for Cindy.''</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="12.583333333333334" PS="1.125" SM="1">They met last weekend at a Dallas convention of veterans for peace.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="15.027027027027026" PS="1.6875" SM="14">According to Ann Wright, who identified herself as a former U.S. diplomat who resigned to protest the war, Sheehan seemed to make a spontaneous decision to come to Crawford when she was while addressing the convention Friday.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="18.545454545454547" PS="1.125" SM="0">Wright said countless hands were raised, offering to join her mission.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="23.428571428571427" PS="1.6875" SM="14">As Sheehan put it Wednesday: ``I just had the right idea in the right place at the right time.''</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="4.75" PS="1.6875" SM="0">Times staff writers Ronald Brownstein, Joel Havemann and Johanna Neuman in Washington contributed to this report.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="23.454545454545453" PS="2.53125" SM="27">Cindy Sheehan, the mother of a soldier killed in Iraq who has been camped outside President Bush's ranch near Crawford, Texas, has taken her antiwar protest to the Internet, joining a conference call with bloggers around the country, along with a stray congresswoman.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="23.289473684210527" PS="1.6875" SM="17">Sheehan, who has been demanding an audience with the president, told the bloggers that she has felt intimidated by the Secret Service, has been awakened in the middle of the night by thunderstorms and has a sore throat.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="33.064516129032256" PS="1.125" SM="13">But, Sheehan said, she has no plans to end her vigil until Bush meets with her to discuss the war, he goes back to the White House or she is arrested.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="20.53846153846154" PS="1.6875" SM="11">``This is going to be a very, very long haul,'' Sheehan said in a call hosted by Democratic strategist and Internet guru Joe Trippi.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="18.5" PS="1.125" SM="2">Trippi, who managed Howard Dean's presidential campaign, urged the bloggers to write about her protest on their individual sites.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="15.64864864864865" PS="1.125" SM="15">The liberal online advocacy group MoveOn.org is also taking up Sheehan's cause, soliciting signatures for a petition in support of her cause and announcing plans to run an ad in the local paper, the Waco Tribune-Herald.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="19.724137931034484" PS="1.6875" SM="15">Many of the bloggers on the call gushed over her protest (``We love you, Cindy'') while Rep. Jan Schakowsky, D-Ill., also chimed in to express her support.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="22.6046511627907" PS="1.6875" SM="16">Sheehan, of Vacaville, Calif., earlier this week described her protest on the popular liberal blog Daily Kos, complaining that the mainstream news media have not paid enough attention to her cause, although she was interviewed Sunday on CNN's ``Late Edition.''</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="27.363636363636363" PS="1.6875" SM="2">``If we didn't have the Internet, none of us would really know what was truly going on,'' she said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="28.7" PS="1.125" SM="0">``This is something that can't be ignored.''</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="19.774193548387096" PS="2.53125" SM="3">The mother of a U.S. soldier killed in Iraq who started a quiet roadside peace vigil near President George Bush's ranch last weekend is drawing supporters from across the nation.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="16.153846153846153" PS="1.6875" SM="1">Dozens of people have joined her and others have sent flowers and food.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="25.0" PS="1.6875" SM="24">Cindy Sheehan, 48, of Vacaville, California, says she was surprised at the response.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="24.967741935483872" PS="1.6875" SM="0">&quot;Before my son was killed, I used to think that one person could not make a difference,&quot; she said Wednesday under a tent where she has slept since Saturday.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="22.41176470588235" PS="1.125" SM="1">&quot;But one person that is surrounded and supported by millions of people can be heard.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="17.692307692307693" PS="1.6875" SM="14">But Kristinn Taylor, co-leader of the Washington, D.C., chapter of FreeRepublic.com, which has held pro-troop rallies, said Sheehan's actions are misguided and hurt troop morale.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="33.26315789473684" PS="1.6875" SM="0">&quot;She has a political agenda that goes way beyond her son's death in combat,&quot; Taylor said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="21.52" PS="1.6875" SM="4">Although a few residents have complained about the protesters, no one has been arrested because the group has been on the public right-of-way, said Capt.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="12.333333333333334" PS="1.125" SM="2">Kenneth Vanek of the McLennan County Sheriff's Office.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="18.92" PS="1.6875" SM="13">On Saturday, two high-level Bush administration officials, the national security adviser and deputy White House chief of staff, talked to Sheehan for about 20 minutes.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="27.5625" PS="1.6875" SM="13">Sheehan called the brief meeting &quot;pointless&quot; and still wants to talk to the president.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="19.157894736842106" PS="1.6875" SM="0">Her 24-year-old son, Casey, was killed in Sadr City, Iraq, in April 2004 just five days after he arrived.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="23.45" PS="1.125" SM="11">Two months later, Sheehan was among grieving military family members who met with Bush at Fort Lewis, near Seattle, Washington.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="16.647058823529413" PS="1.6875" SM="2">Since then, she said, various government and independent commission reports have disputed the Bush administration's claims that Saddam Hussein had mass-killing chemical and biological weapons _ a main justification for the March 2003 invasion.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="21.73076923076923" PS="1.6875" SM="14">On Wednesday, a coalition of anti-war groups in Washington called on Bush to speak with Sheehan, who they say has helped to unify the peace movement.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="34.266666666666666" PS="1.6875" SM="26">&quot;Cindy Sheehan has become the Rosa Parks of the anti-war movement,&quot; said Rev.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="7.636363636363637" PS="1.125" SM="2">Lennox Yearwood, leader of the Hip Hop Caucus, an activist group.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="30.956521739130434" PS="1.125" SM="0">&quot;She's tired, fed up and she's not going to take it anymore, and so now we stand with her.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="12.458333333333334" PS="1.6875" SM="1">Rosa Parks is the iconic civil rights figure who refused to give up her seat on a segregated bus in Montgomery, Alabama, in 1955.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="14.227272727272727" PS="1.125" SM="5">Her arrest triggered one of the movement's earliest landmark events, a 381-day boycott of the bus system organized by the Rev.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="1.0" PS="1.125" SM="0">Martin Luther King Jr.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="15.642857142857142" PS="1.6875" SM="14">At her makeshift camp in muddy ditches off the two-lane, winding road leading to Bush's ranch, Sheehan has spent the past several days talking to reporters, hugging fellow protesters and taking brief breaks to eat sandwiches and fruit brought by supporters.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="20.615384615384617" PS="1.125" SM="1">Her vigil has also become a hot topic on the Internet and blogs.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="24.933333333333334" PS="1.6875" SM="0">Although she doesn't expect Bush to meet with her in Crawford, she says if he did she would ask him whether he has encouraged his twin daughters to enlist.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="32.5" PS="1.6875" SM="0">&quot;I want him to quit using my son's death to justify more killing,&quot; she said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="28.444444444444443" PS="1.125" SM="2">&quot;The only way he can honor my son's death is to bring the troops home.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="16.193548387096776" PS="1.6875" SM="13">Sheehan, a former Roman Catholic youth minister, formed a group called Gold Star Families For Peace earlier this year and has spoken out against the war across the nation and overseas.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="21.923076923076923" PS="2.25" SM="3">As a roadside anti-war vigil initiated by a California woman who lost a son in Iraq continued near his ranch Thursday, President Bush said that he sympathizes with her loss but that agreeing to her demand to immediately withdraw troops ``would be a mistake for the security of this country.''</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="20.875" PS="1.5" SM="28">Speaking to reporters after meeting with members of his national security team, Bush said he has heard the voices of Cindy Sheehan and grieving family members who say the United States should leave Iraq because of the mounting death toll.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="48.111111111111114" PS="1.5" SM="0">``I grieve for every death,'' Bush said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="13.333333333333334" PS="1.0" SM="2">``It breaks my heart to think about a family weeping over the loss of a loved one.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="17.857142857142858" PS="1.0" SM="2">I understand the anguish that some feel about the death that takes place.''</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="18.414634146341463" PS="1.5" SM="3">Nonetheless, Bush added, withdrawing U.S. troops from Iraq before that nation's security forces are able to cope with the ongoing insurgency ``would send a terrible signal to the enemy,'' that the United States is weak and easily intimidated</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="12.8" PS="1.5" SM="8">While Bush met with Vice President Dick Cheney, Secretary of Defense Donald Rumsfeld, and Secretary of State Condoleezza Rice to discuss the war and other foreign policy concerns, a growing clutch of protesters were encamped along the muddy shoulder of the narrow, winding road leading to Bush's 1,600-acre ranch.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="25.464285714285715" PS="1.5" SM="13">Sheehan, who began her vigil Saturday, has been joined by several dozen protesters from across the country, including some others who have had loved ones killed in Iraq.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="27.441176470588236" PS="1.5" SM="14">``The president says he feels compassion for me, but the best way to show that compassion is by meeting with me and the other mothers and families who are here,'' Sheehan said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="19.272727272727273" PS="1.0" SM="1">``Our sons made the ultimate sacrifice and we want answers.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="18.379310344827587" PS="1.0" SM="2">All we're asking is that he sacrifice an hour out of his five-week vacation to talk to us, before the next mother loses her son in Iraq.''</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="26.125" PS="1.5" SM="1">Celeste Zappala of Philadelphia, said her son, Sgt.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="11.714285714285714" PS="1.0" SM="1">Sherwood Baker, was killed in Baghdad while looking for nonexistent weapons of mass destruction.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="40.333333333333336" PS="1.5" SM="0">``This war is a disaster,'' Zappala said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="20.875" PS="1.0" SM="1">``It is a betrayal of our military.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="19.25" PS="1.0" SM="1">It is a betrayal of our democracy.''</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="22.88888888888889" PS="1.5" SM="3">The protesters have strung placards along the roadside saying things such as, ``Who would Jesus bomb?''</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="35.25" PS="1.0" SM="0">and ``Who lied?</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="32.5" PS="1.0" SM="0">Who died?</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="25.5" PS="1.0" SM="0">Who paid?</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="43.0" PS="1.0" SM="0">Who profits?''</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="10.727272727272727" PS="1.0" SM="4">They also drove dozens of small, white wooden crosses into the ground along the road, in honor of those killed in Iraq.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="20.071428571428573" PS="1.5" SM="23">Sheehan's son, Casey Sheehan, 24, a former Eagle Scout and altar boy, was killed in Baghdad on April 4, 2004, within a week of arriving in Iraq.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="18.75" PS="1.0" SM="13">Sheehan met Bush two months later, as part of a group of grieving military family members.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="27.35" PS="1.0" SM="2">She has alleged that Bush treated her callously during their private conversation, and she has demanded a second meeting to air her grievances about the war and to tell Bush about the devastation she has felt since losing her son.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="24.96875" PS="1.5" SM="15">In the wake of her son's death, Sheehan, 48, co-founded Gold Star Families for Peace, an organization of people who have lost loved ones in Iraq or who oppose the war.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="26.52777777777778" PS="1.5" SM="13">Although she met Saturday with two top Bush aides, Sheehan has vowed to maintain her vigil -- both here and, if necessary, outside the White House -- until she is granted another meeting with the president.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="24.033333333333335" PS="1.5" SM="13">Sheehan's protest has created a delicate situation for the White House, which has resisted being drawn into a public battle with a woman who lost a son in Iraq.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="21.78048780487805" PS="1.0" SM="15">While officials would not publicly refute Sheehan's description of her meeting with Bush, they did point out that the president has met with about 900 family members of 272 fallen soldiers -- sessions they describe as often emotional and moving.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="16.70967741935484" PS="2.25" SM="0">U.S. President George W. Bush was meeting with his defense and foreign policy teams Thursday at his Texas ranch, from where he'll look at world hotspots from Baghdad to Pyongyang.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="9.226415094339623" PS="1.5" SM="3">Vice President Dick Cheney and top-rung advisers, including Defense Secretary Donald H. Rumsfeld and Secretary of State Condoleezza Rice, were coming for the serious talks about issues ranging from ongoing violence in Iraq and standoffs with Iran and North Korea over their nuclear programs to anti-American sentiment abroad, especially in the Middle East.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="23.333333333333332" PS="1.5" SM="1">Keeping with tradition, Bush is spending August at the ranch in Crawford.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="8.865384615384615" PS="1.5" SM="6">The unhurried pace of this one-stoplight town stands in sharp contrast to events across the globe: suicide bombings in Iraq; on-again, off-again negotiations with the reclusive North Korea; Iran's decision to restart sensitive nuclear work; next week's pullout of some 9,000 Jewish settlers in the Gaza Strip and West Bank.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="15.090909090909092" PS="1.5" SM="0">Bush's update on defense and foreign policy issues comes at a time when his approval ratings are hovering below 50 percent.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="15.95" PS="1.0" SM="0">An AP-Ipsos poll conducted Aug. 1-3 showed Bush's overall job approval was at 42 percent, with 55 percent disapproving.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="18.571428571428573" PS="1.0" SM="1">That's about where his approval rating has been all summer, but slightly lower than it was when the year began.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="17.454545454545453" PS="1.0" SM="1">His approval on his handling of Iraq stood at 38 percent.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="15.666666666666666" PS="1.5" SM="2">Iraq, where the death toll of U.S. troops has topped 1,840, is likely to take a center stage.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="11.785714285714286" PS="1.5" SM="3">The administration is hoping that progress on the political front will help deflate violence and allow the United States and its partners to begin withdrawing troops next year.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="20.85185185185185" PS="1.5" SM="3">Rumsfeld said success in drafting a new Iraqi constitution is critical toward persuading the majority of Iraqis that the &quot;new Iraq is worth fighting for.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="14.842105263157896" PS="1.0" SM="3">But a deadlock has arisen over the drafting of the charter, which is supposed to be completed by Monday.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="16.36842105263158" PS="1.5" SM="25">Cindy Sheehan, a California mother of a fallen soldier, is holding a roadside protest to bring the troops home.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="10.571428571428571" PS="1.5" SM="4">So far, Rumsfeld has not publicly voiced his thoughts on when U.S. forces may be able to come home in large numbers _ a decision that hinges on the level of violence and the capabilities of Iraqi security forces, which now number 178,000.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="8.478260869565217" PS="1.5" SM="2">A joint U.S.-Iraqi committee that is identifying areas to revert to Iraqi control will submit its final report by the end of September.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="17.125" PS="1.0" SM="5">That is the first step toward what Gen. George W. Casey, the top commander in Iraq, has said could lead to a &quot;fairly substantial&quot; reduction in the 138,000-strong U.S. force by the spring and summer of next year.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="11.777777777777779" PS="1.5" SM="1">Casey has not disclosed numbers, but Pentagon officials have mentioned a reduction figure of 20,000 to 30,000 troops.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="11.615384615384615" PS="1.0" SM="0">That would still leave about 100,000 Americans in Iraq well into next year.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="11.021739130434783" PS="1.5" SM="5">But first the Pentagon will likely have to increase the number of U.S. troops above the current 138,000 to improve security for a planned October referendum and a December election, when a burst of insurgent violence is expected, Rumsfeld spokesman Lawrence Di Rita said this week.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="13.027027027027026" PS="1.5" SM="0">In January, when Iraq held its first elections, troop levels were raised as high as 160,000, mainly by overlapping some units arriving in Iraq to begin a one-year tour with those who were ending their yearlong tours.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="12.0625" PS="1.0" SM="2">Di Rita said that this time commanders could also ask for volunteers to serve extended tours or send some U.S.-based troops to Iraq to augment the force during the fall election period.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="11.791666666666666" PS="1.5" SM="4">The White House says Rumsfeld will brief the president on the Quadrennial Defense Review, a congressionally mandated top-to-bottom review of defense strategy and plans.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="11.61111111111111" PS="1.0" SM="2">The review, begun earlier this year, will be completed around January, in time for the February budget submission.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="27.304347826086957" PS="2.53125" SM="22">Cindy Sheehan's eyes well with tears when she talks about her oldest son, Casey, an easygoing young man with a quiet wit.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="10.166666666666666" PS="1.6875" SM="1">Casey joined the Army in 2000, never imagining he would see combat.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="15.75" PS="1.125" SM="1">Five days after he arrived in Iraq last year, the 24-year-old was killed in Sadr City.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="28.38888888888889" PS="1.6875" SM="11">Sheehan knows nothing can bring back her son, but she wants to talk to President George W. Bush.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="12.961538461538462" PS="1.125" SM="1">The California mother has been camping out along a road near his ranch since Saturday, vowing to remain until his Texas vacation ends later this month.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="24.838709677419356" PS="1.6875" SM="0">&quot;Before my son was killed, I used to think that one person could not make a difference,&quot; she said Wednesday under a tent where she has slept since arriving.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="22.41176470588235" PS="1.125" SM="1">&quot;But one person that is surrounded and supported by millions of people can be heard.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="19.736842105263158" PS="1.6875" SM="12">Bush National Security Adviser Stephen Hadley and a deputy White House chief of staff talked to Sheehan on Saturday.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="37.84615384615385" PS="1.125" SM="1">She said the meeting, which she called &quot;pointless,&quot; lasted 20 minutes.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="24.125" PS="1.125" SM="1">The White House said it lasted 45 minutes.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="10.92" PS="1.6875" SM="1">By Thursday, about 50 people had joined her cause, pitching tents in muddy, shallow ditches and hanging anti-war banners; two dozen others have sent flowers.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="19.384615384615383" PS="1.125" SM="1">Her name was among the most popular search topics Wednesday on Internet blogs.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="21.105263157894736" PS="1.6875" SM="14">The soft-spoken Sheehan, 48, is surprised and touched at the overwhelming response _ most of which is positive, she says.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="28.8" PS="1.6875" SM="0">But not everyone supports her.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="22.523809523809526" PS="1.125" SM="15">Kristinn Taylor, co-leader of the Washington, D.C., chapter of FreeRepublic.com, said Sheehan's protest is misguided and is hurting troop morale.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="20.68421052631579" PS="1.6875" SM="3">&quot;She has a political agenda that goes way beyond her son's death in combat,&quot; said Taylor, whose conservative group has held pro-troop rallies since the Sept. 11, 2001, terror attacks and counter-protests of anti-war demonstrations.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="17.0" PS="1.6875" SM="12">Sheehan, a Catholic youth minister for eight years, never wanted Casey to join the military.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="27.636363636363637" PS="1.125" SM="0">She said he did so after being misled by his recruiter.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="16.153846153846153" PS="1.125" SM="1">Although he also opposed the war, he didn't try to back out.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="33.916666666666664" PS="1.6875" SM="0">&quot;I begged him not to go,&quot; she said through tears.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="25.22222222222222" PS="1.125" SM="0">&quot;I said, 'I'll take you to Canada' ... but he said, 'Mom, I have to go.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="25.5" PS="1.125" SM="0">It's my duty.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="20.8" PS="1.125" SM="0">My buddies are going.'&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="11.966666666666667" PS="1.6875" SM="14">Sheehan has spent the past several days in rainy weather talking to scores of reporters, hugging fellow protesters and taking brief breaks to eat sandwiches and fruit brought by supporters.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="21.285714285714285" PS="1.6875" SM="2">She and her husband are separated, affected by the stress of losing their son.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="25.1875" PS="1.125" SM="0">But her three other children, ages 19 to 24, may join her in Crawford, she said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="29.391304347826086" PS="1.6875" SM="12">Sheehan did meet with Bush in June 2004: She was among grieving military families who met with the president at Fort Lewis, Washington.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="24.3125" PS="1.125" SM="4">She has said her feelings have shifted from shock to anger since then, in part because of various reports that have disputed some of the Bush administration's justifications for the war.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="13.533333333333333" PS="1.6875" SM="12">Many supporters decided to go to Crawford because of rumors that Sheehan would be arrested.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="17.0" PS="1.6875" SM="2">But no protesters will be arrested unless they trespass on private property or block the road, said Capt.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="12.333333333333334" PS="1.125" SM="2">Kenneth Vanek of the McLennan County Sheriff's Office.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="18.25" PS="1.6875" SM="11">Trucker Craig Delaney, 53, was in Georgia on Monday when he heard numerous radio shows discussing Sheehan _ some criticizing her.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="17.529411764705884" PS="1.125" SM="11">He altered his route to California, heading for Texas, and got to Sheehan's site Wednesday morning.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="25.636363636363637" PS="1.6875" SM="0">&quot;I felt compelled to come and tell her I support her,&quot; said Delaney, a self-described hippie from Sly Park, California.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="27.833333333333332" PS="1.125" SM="2">&quot;The way they were bad-mouthing a mother whose son was killed in the war is un-American.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="18.153846153846153" PS="1.6875" SM="1">Nearly 40 Democratic members of Congress have asked Bush to talk to her.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="21.25925925925926" PS="1.125" SM="14">On Wednesday, a coalition of anti-war groups in Washington also called on Bush to speak with Sheehan, who they say has helped to unify the peace movement.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="34.266666666666666" PS="1.6875" SM="26">&quot;Cindy Sheehan has become the Rosa Parks of the anti-war movement,&quot; said Rev.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="7.636363636363637" PS="1.125" SM="2">Lennox Yearwood, leader of the Hip Hop Caucus, an activist group.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="30.956521739130434" PS="1.125" SM="0">&quot;She's tired, fed up and she's not going to take it anymore, and so now we stand with her.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="19.7" PS="1.6875" SM="12">Earlier this year Sheehan formed Gold Star Families for Peace and has spoken to groups across the nation and overseas.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="24.5" PS="1.6875" SM="16">Judith Young, national president of the The American Gold Star Mothers of America Inc., said she is concerned the public will mistake her 76-year-old Washington, D.C., nonprofit organization with Sheehan's group.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="9.36" PS="1.6875" SM="2">In Young's group, commonly known as Gold Star Moms, mothers whose children died in the line of duty volunteer in veterans' hospitals and programs.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="17.0" PS="1.125" SM="0">Members don't do advocacy work, Young said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="1.0" PS="1.6875" SM="0">___</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="12.666666666666666" PS="1.6875" SM="1">On the Net:</sentence>
	</Sentences>
</Topic>
