<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<Topic id="D0911C">
	<Sentences>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="21.714285714285715" PS="2.5655487804878048" SM="27">Chess legend Bobby Fischer, who faces  prison if he returns to the United States, can only avoid  deportation from Japan if Iceland upgrades its granting of residency  to full citizenship, a Japanese lawmaker said Wednesday.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="16.774193548387096" PS="1.7103658536585364" SM="14">Mizuho Fukushima, head of the opposition Social Democratic  Party, told a press conference that Japanese immigration officials  are opting to deport Fischer to the United States unless Iceland  grants him nationality.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="14.428571428571429" PS="1.7103658536585364" SM="14">Fischer, 62, known for his maverick behavior and outspoken  criticism of his country, may face 10 years in prison if convicted  of violating US sanctions imposed on the former Yugoslavia by  playing there in 1992.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="14.117647058823529" PS="1.7103658536585364" SM="2">Fukushima met Masaharu Miura, chief of the justice ministry's  immigration bureau, who had told parliament Tuesday that the chess  genius could only be deported to his country of origin -- the United  States.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="23.85185185185185" PS="1.7103658536585364" SM="14">The socialist leader said of the prospect of Fischer going to  Iceland: &quot;Mr Miura told us that it would be okay if Iceland gives  him citizenship.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="15.642857142857142" PS="1.7103658536585364" SM="1">&quot;The Social Democratic Party will bring up the issue at the  parliament and will work to let the Japanese public know about the  case,&quot; she said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="18.962962962962962" PS="1.7103658536585364" SM="16">Iceland has offered residency to Fischer, who is famous in  Reykjavik for dethroning the Soviet Boris Spassky there in 1972 at  the height of the Cold War.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="20.41176470588235" PS="1.7103658536585364" SM="1">Iceland has sent him a passport which shows residency status but  it has not offered him nationality.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="14.35" PS="1.7103658536585364" SM="2">Socialist leader Fukushima, who is also a well-known human  rights lawyer, is scheduled to meet the Icelandic ambassador on  Thursday.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="21.166666666666668" PS="1.7103658536585364" SM="14">Fischer's supporters accuse the United States of piling pressure  both on Japan and Iceland so it can get ahold of the chess legend.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="14.777777777777779" PS="1.7103658536585364" SM="13">The supporters say Fischer would not receive a fair trial in the  United States due to his controversial past statements, such as  hailing the September 11, 2001 attacks as &quot;wonderful news&quot; and  anti-Jewish remarks.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="34.666666666666664" PS="1.7103658536585364" SM="22">&quot;Mr Fischer would be free if he were not Mr Fischer,&quot; said  Masako Suzuki, his lawyer.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="24.1" PS="1.7103658536585364" SM="13">But even if Iceland offered Fischer citizenship, his case would  still be in legal limbo because of his US nationality.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="14.448275862068966" PS="1.7103658536585364" SM="2">An immigration official at the justice ministry said that a  person with two nationalities is usually deported to the country  whose passport he or she used to enter Japan.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="33.5" PS="1.1402439024390243" SM="12">That would mean the  United States for Fischer.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="21.53125" PS="1.7103658536585364" SM="13">Fischer has been held since July when he attempted to fly out of  Japan on an allegedly invalid US passport, but from detention he has  been unable to renounce his US citizenship.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="8.2" PS="1.7103658536585364" SM="0">A renunciation would make him a man without a country.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="14.48" PS="1.1402439024390243" SM="3">He has  sought political asylum in Japan and applied for a German passport  on account of his German father, but neither route has been  successful.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="17.0625" PS="1.7103658536585364" SM="14">Fukushima said justice ministry officials told her that they had  not discussed Fischer's case with their US nor Icelandic  counterparts, after opposition allegations that Japan was caving in  to US pressure.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="33.5" PS="1.7103658536585364" SM="12">Fischer is little known in Japan.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="13.818181818181818" PS="1.1402439024390243" SM="3">The media has largely ignored  his plight even though in detention he became engaged to the head of  the Japan Chess Association.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="22.77777777777778" PS="2.4420731707317076" SM="28">Chess genius Bobby Fischer, now in a Japanese detention cell awaiting deportation to the United States, will be allowed to leave Japan for Iceland if that country grants him citizenship, an opposition party leader said Wednesday.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="22.35483870967742" PS="1.628048780487805" SM="13">Mizuho Fukushima, head of the Social Democratic Party, said senior immigration officials told her that Fischer could go to Iceland instead of the United States if he is given citizenship there.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="20.923076923076923" PS="1.0853658536585367" SM="14">Fischer is wanted by Washington for violating economic sanctions against the former Yugoslavia when he played a high-profile chess match at a resort there in 1992.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="26.136363636363637" PS="1.628048780487805" SM="0">&quot;They said that if he had citizenship, there would be no problem,&quot; she said after the meeting with immigration officials.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="16.76923076923077" PS="1.0853658536585367" SM="2">Fukushima, a member of Parliament, later met with Iceland's ambassador to Tokyo.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="19.22222222222222" PS="1.628048780487805" SM="13">Iceland recently issued Fischer a special passport and residence permit to help resolve the standoff over his status.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="19.615384615384617" PS="1.0853658536585367" SM="20">Fischer became world chess champion in a 1972 match in Iceland against the Soviet Union's Boris Spassky, and some of his Icelandic supporters have campaigned to help him out of gratitude for putting Iceland in the global spotlight.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="24.444444444444443" PS="1.628048780487805" SM="1">The Iceland passport is one used by foreigners, however.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="24.857142857142858" PS="1.0853658536585367" SM="13">Iceland's parliament voted two weeks ago against granting Fischer citizenship, and it's unclear whether lawmakers plan to reconsider this.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="18.2" PS="1.628048780487805" SM="1">&quot;The decision on citizenship lies with Parliament,&quot; said Illugi Gunnarsson, an advisor to the Foreign Minister David Oddsson.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="19.0" PS="1.628048780487805" SM="15">Since being taken into custody in July for allegedly trying to leave the country on a revoked U.S. passport, Fischer has lived up to his reputation as unpredictable.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="17.137931034482758" PS="1.628048780487805" SM="1">He has repeatedly denounced the U.S. deportation order as politically motivated, demanded refugee status, unilaterally renounced his U.S. citizenship and said he wants to become a German national instead.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="17.238095238095237" PS="1.0853658536585367" SM="2">He has also applied to marry a Japanese woman who heads this country's chess association and is his longtime companion.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="9.222222222222221" PS="1.628048780487805" SM="0">Officials, meanwhile, have taken a hard line with him.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="15.0" PS="1.628048780487805" SM="12">Fischer, 62, is being held in detention just outside Tokyo pending the outcome of a lawsuit challenging the deportation order.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="6.25" PS="1.0853658536585367" SM="0">Officials say they do not know how much longer that could take.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="16.68" PS="1.0853658536585367" SM="14">Most detainees at the center are deported or allowed to leave Japan within about one month, but Fischer has been in custody for eight months.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="23.0" PS="1.628048780487805" SM="11">Fukushima said Fischer, an outspoken critic of the U.S. government, was being treated unfairly.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="22.846153846153847" PS="1.628048780487805" SM="2">&quot;There is no need to keep him in detention,&quot; she said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="14.764705882352942" PS="1.0853658536585367" SM="0">&quot;If this was any other person, I'm sure it would have turned out differently.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="12.0" PS="1.628048780487805" SM="1">Her protest came after a member of Japan's leading opposition party, the Democrats, grilled government officials in Parliament over the case.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="10.714285714285714" PS="1.0853658536585367" SM="2">Fukushima said her party also intended to pursue the issue further in parliamentary debate.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="13.0" PS="1.628048780487805" SM="2">During questioning in Parliament on Tuesday, Foreign Minister Nobutaka Machimura denied allegations Tokyo is trying to please the United States by being tough.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="22.142857142857142" PS="1.628048780487805" SM="12">&quot;I do not recall being asked by the United States to do anything about Fischer,&quot; Machimura told the committee.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="18.523809523809526" PS="1.0853658536585367" SM="1">&quot;So I don't think the Justice Ministry is interpreting the law out of consideration for the United States.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="19.24" PS="2.5792682926829267" SM="27">Lawmakers in Iceland are likely to grant citizenship to mercurial chess genius Bobby Fischer, a member of a parliamentary committee studying the issue said Wednesday.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="12.619047619047619" PS="1.719512195121951" SM="0">Legislator Gudrun Ogmundsdottir told The Associated Press that a citizenship motion would probably be approved by the nine-member committee on Thursday.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="20.153846153846153" PS="1.146341463414634" SM="1">If it passes, it will go before Iceland's 63-member parliament, the Althingi.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="17.791666666666668" PS="1.719512195121951" SM="0">&quot;I think that parliament may approve of the citizenship as early as tomorrow,&quot; said Ogmundsdottir, a member of the opposition Alliance Party.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="14.692307692307692" PS="1.719512195121951" SM="3">&quot;Somebody would then go over to Japan with the passport, which would enable him to travel here or anywhere in the world,&quot; she added.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="20.63888888888889" PS="1.719512195121951" SM="16">Fischer, 62, is in a Japanese detention cell awaiting deportation to the United States, where he is wanted for violating economic sanctions against the former Yugoslavia by playing a highly publicized chess match there in 1992.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="24.483870967741936" PS="1.719512195121951" SM="14">Mizuho Fukushima, leader of Japan's opposition Social Democratic Party, said senior immigration officials told her that Fischer would be allowed to go to Iceland if he is given citizenship there.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="25.25" PS="1.719512195121951" SM="16">There is widespread support for Fischer in Iceland, where he played the Soviet Union's Boris Spassky in a world championship match in 1972.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="26.8" PS="1.719512195121951" SM="12">Iceland's parliament voted last month against granting Fischer citizenship, offering him a special foreigners' passport and residence permit instead.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="20.8" PS="1.146341463414634" SM="12">But Japanese officials have so far declined to release Fischer.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="25.928571428571427" PS="1.719512195121951" SM="13">Several Icelandic politicians indicated Wednesday that parliament was now likely to grant Fischer citizenship.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="20.666666666666668" PS="1.719512195121951" SM="14">&quot;I can't speak for the whole party, but think few if any members of Parliament are opposed to granting Fischer citizenship,&quot; said Drifa Hjartardottir, a lawmaker with the Independence Party, which governs as part of Iceland's coalition government.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="19.058823529411764" PS="1.719512195121951" SM="13">&quot;We will not stand in the way of Fischer getting citizenship and want this issue to be resolved as quickly as possible,&quot; said Ogmundur Jonasson, a lawmaker with the Left-Green opposition party.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="27.05263157894737" PS="1.146341463414634" SM="15">&quot;The worst thing we can do, both for Iceland and for Fischer, is to wait any longer.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="20.77777777777778" PS="1.719512195121951" SM="16">Since being taken into custody in July for allegedly trying to leave Japan on a revoked U.S. passport, Fischer has lived up to his reputation for unpredictability.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="17.137931034482758" PS="1.719512195121951" SM="1">He has repeatedly denounced the U.S. deportation order as politically motivated, demanded refugee status, unilaterally renounced his U.S. citizenship and said he wants to become a German national instead.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="17.238095238095237" PS="1.146341463414634" SM="2">He has also applied to marry a Japanese woman who heads this country's chess association and is his longtime companion.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="25.454545454545453" PS="1.719512195121951" SM="12">Einar S. Einarsson, the former CEO of Visa Iceland who is one of Fischer's most fervent supporters, said he was optimistic.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="15.85" PS="1.719512195121951" SM="1">&quot;We're meeting them at 9:40 tomorrow and we want them to take the final step,&quot; he said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="19.555555555555557" PS="1.146341463414634" SM="1">&quot;It's been like a chess game and there's only one move left before checkmate.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="16.41176470588235" PS="2.5792682926829267" SM="26">A parliamentary committee met here Thursday to discuss granting citizenship to Bobby Fischer, but made no decision, saying it needed more information from Japan, where the mercurial chess genius is being held in custody.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="20.25925925925926" PS="1.719512195121951" SM="1">Legislator Gudrun Ogmundsdottir had said the citizenship motion would probably be passed by the nine-member committee Thursday, then be placed before Iceland's 63-member parliament, the Althingi.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="23.392857142857142" PS="1.719512195121951" SM="3">But during Thursday's meeting the committee said it was awaiting more documents from Japan to be sure he would be let go if given citizenship in Iceland.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="24.57894736842105" PS="1.146341463414634" SM="15">If so, an Icelandic passport would be delivered to Fischer in Japan, enabling him to travel wherever he wanted.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="11.444444444444445" PS="1.719512195121951" SM="1">The parliamentary committee is expected to meet again soon.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="20.63888888888889" PS="1.719512195121951" SM="16">Fischer, 62, is in a Japanese detention cell awaiting deportation to the United States, where he is wanted for violating economic sanctions against the former Yugoslavia by playing a highly publicized chess match there in 1992.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="24.483870967741936" PS="1.719512195121951" SM="14">Mizuho Fukushima, leader of Japan's opposition Social Democratic Party, said senior immigration officials told her that Fischer would be allowed to go to Iceland if he is given citizenship there.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="25.25" PS="1.719512195121951" SM="16">There is widespread support for Fischer in Iceland, where he played the Soviet Union's Boris Spassky in a world championship match in 1972.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="26.8" PS="1.719512195121951" SM="12">Iceland's parliament voted last month against granting Fischer citizenship, offering him a special foreigners' passport and residence permit instead.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="20.8" PS="1.146341463414634" SM="12">But Japanese officials have so far declined to release Fischer.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="25.928571428571427" PS="1.719512195121951" SM="13">Several Icelandic politicians indicated Wednesday that parliament was now likely to grant Fischer citizenship.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="20.666666666666668" PS="1.719512195121951" SM="14">&quot;I can't speak for the whole party, but think few if any members of Parliament are opposed to granting Fischer citizenship,&quot; said Drifa Hjartardottir, a lawmaker with the Independence Party, which governs as part of Iceland's coalition government.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="19.058823529411764" PS="1.719512195121951" SM="13">&quot;We will not stand in the way of Fischer getting citizenship and want this issue to be resolved as quickly as possible,&quot; said Ogmundur Jonasson, a lawmaker with the Left-Green opposition party.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="27.05263157894737" PS="1.146341463414634" SM="15">&quot;The worst thing we can do, both for Iceland and for Fischer, is to wait any longer.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="20.77777777777778" PS="1.719512195121951" SM="16">Since being taken into custody in July for allegedly trying to leave Japan on a revoked U.S. passport, Fischer has lived up to his reputation for unpredictability.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="17.137931034482758" PS="1.719512195121951" SM="1">He has repeatedly denounced the U.S. deportation order as politically motivated, demanded refugee status, unilaterally renounced his U.S. citizenship and said he wants to become a German national instead.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="17.238095238095237" PS="1.146341463414634" SM="2">He has also applied to marry a Japanese woman who heads this country's chess association and is his longtime companion.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="19.04" PS="2.2911585365853657" SM="26">A parliamentary committee voted Friday to grant citizenship to fugitive U.S. chess star Bobby Fischer, putting the issue up for a vote by all legislators.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="20.2" PS="1.5274390243902438" SM="0">&quot;The matter has been finished,&quot; said Gudrun Oegmundsdpttir, a member the General Committee.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="25.0" PS="1.0182926829268293" SM="1">&quot;It will now go before the parliament on Monday for the vote.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="21.685714285714287" PS="1.5274390243902438" SM="16">Fischer, 62, has been detained in Japan awaiting deportation to the United States, where he is wanted for violating economic sanctions against the former Yugoslavia by playing a highly publicized chess match there in 1992.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="25.25" PS="1.5274390243902438" SM="16">There is widespread support for Fischer in Iceland, where he played the Soviet Union's Boris Spassky in a world championship match in 1972.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="26.8" PS="1.5274390243902438" SM="12">Iceland's parliament voted last month against granting Fischer citizenship, offering him a special foreigners' passport and residence permit instead.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="20.8" PS="1.0182926829268293" SM="12">But Japanese officials have so far declined to release Fischer.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="25.533333333333335" PS="1.5274390243902438" SM="13">Several Icelandic politicians indicated this week that parliament was now likely to grant Fischer citizenship.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="21.346153846153847" PS="2.2911585365853657" SM="28">A parliamentary committee in Iceland voted to grant citizenship to fugitive U.S. chess star Bobby Fischer, putting the issue up for a vote by all legislators.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="20.842105263157894" PS="1.5274390243902438" SM="0">&quot;The matter has been finished,&quot; Gudrun Oegmundsdottir, a member the General Committee, said after Friday's vote.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="25.0" PS="1.0182926829268293" SM="1">&quot;It will now go before the parliament on Monday for the vote.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="21.685714285714287" PS="1.5274390243902438" SM="16">Fischer, 62, has been detained in Japan awaiting deportation to the United States, where he is wanted for violating economic sanctions against the former Yugoslavia by playing a highly publicized chess match there in 1992.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="28.44" PS="1.5274390243902438" SM="16">One of Fischer's supporters in Iceland said the Japanese government had confirmed it would allow him to go to Iceland if citizenship was granted.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="34.90909090909091" PS="1.5274390243902438" SM="11">&quot;This is great news,&quot; said Fischer supporter Saemundur Palsson.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="31.7" PS="1.0182926829268293" SM="12">&quot;They had been waiting on confirmation from Japan that Fischer would be let go if he had Icelandic citizenship.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="14.142857142857142" PS="1.0182926829268293" SM="1">This arrived to me this morning.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="25.25" PS="1.5274390243902438" SM="16">There is widespread support for Fischer in Iceland, where he played the Soviet Union's Boris Spassky in a world championship match in 1972.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="26.8" PS="1.5274390243902438" SM="12">Iceland's parliament voted last month against granting Fischer citizenship, offering him a special foreigners' passport and residence permit instead.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="14.714285714285714" PS="1.0182926829268293" SM="1">But Japanese officials declined to release him.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="19.065217391304348" PS="1.5274390243902438" SM="15">Since being taken into custody in July for allegedly trying to leave Japan on a revoked U.S. passport, Fischer has repeatedly denounced the U.S. deportation order as politically motivated, demanded refugee status, renounced his U.S. citizenship and said he wants to become a German national instead.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="13.5" PS="1.5274390243902438" SM="2">He has also applied to marry Mikyoko Watai, head of the Japan Chess Association.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="19.125" PS="1.5274390243902438" SM="14">&quot;We are currently organizing a fundraising for the party that will go out to meet him,&quot; said Einar Einarsson, former CEO of VISA Iceland and one of Fischers strongest supporters.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="16.433333333333334" PS="1.5274390243902438" SM="2">&quot;We might need to bring his girlfriend Miyoko Watai over too, as well as John Bosnitch, his supporter now in Japan, so there are expenses involved,&quot; Einarsson said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="33.23529411764706" PS="1.0182926829268293" SM="11">&quot;Fischer has money, but he can't get at it from where he is now.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="28.324324324324323" PS="2.414634146341464" SM="28">Iceland's parliament voted Monday to grant Icelandic citizenship to the American chess champion Bobby Fischer, laying the groundwork, his supporters said, for his release from the Japanese prison where he has been detained since last summer.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="22.897435897435898" PS="1.6097560975609757" SM="16">&quot;We are most happy,&quot; said Einar S. Einarsson, spokesman for a committee that has been fighting to allow Fischer to leave Japan, where he is being held in prison while he fights deportation to the United States.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="15.020408163265307" PS="1.0731707317073171" SM="18">Einarsson, who called Fischer &quot;part of our modern saga and part of our recent history,&quot; said that the 62-year-old chess champion might be released &quot;in only a few days&quot; and that an Icelandic delegation planned to travel to Tokyo to escort him back to Reykjavik.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="13.18" PS="1.6097560975609757" SM="15">Monday's vote appears to be a resolution -- of sorts -- to the curious legal limbo that Fischer fell into in 1992, when, the U.S. government says, he violated economic sanctions against the former Yugoslavia by accepting a $3.3 million fee to play an exhibition match there that year.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="8.909090909090908" PS="1.6097560975609757" SM="12">After that, the always reclusive, progressively more eccentric Fischer dropped out of sight, living in Budapest and, possibly, the Philippines and Switzerland.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="13.185185185185185" PS="1.0731707317073171" SM="4">Now and then he emerged on radio stations in Iceland, Hungary and the Philippines to rant, in increasingly belligerent terms, against the United States and against Jews.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="11.04" PS="1.6097560975609757" SM="4">He surfaced in earnest in July 2004, when he attempted to board a plane from Japan to Manila and was seized by the Japanese authorities.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="10.538461538461538" PS="1.0731707317073171" SM="1">He was accused of trying to leave the country without a valid passport.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="11.871794871794872" PS="1.0731707317073171" SM="4">Since then he has been held in prison while various governments, as well as a staunch group of supporters from the chess world, have tried to find a resolution to what has proved a vexing and delicate jurisdictional issue.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="20.4" PS="1.6097560975609757" SM="13">But while the United States -- which is also investigating the possibility of charging him with tax evasion -- regards Fischer as a fugitive from justice, in Iceland he is seen as a national hero.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="10.444444444444445" PS="1.0731707317073171" SM="4">It was in Reykjavik in 1972 that he defeated the Russian world champion, Boris Spassky, in an electrifying Cold War chess contest that pitted east against west.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="11.595744680851064" PS="1.6097560975609757" SM="15">Just as the African-American track star Jesse Owens' triumph over Hitler's Aryan athletes did at the 1936 Berlin Olympics, Fischer's victory in Iceland seemed to symbolize nothing less than the triumph of one way of life over another -- in this case, democracy over Communism.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="20.75" PS="1.6097560975609757" SM="14">It is partly for that reason, said Bjarni Benediktsson, chairman of the parliamentary committee, who last week recommended that Fischer be granted Icelandic citizenship, that the full parliament voted in favor of his request on Monday.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="19.0" PS="1.0731707317073171" SM="15">Iceland had already agreed to issue a resident's permit and special passport to Fischer, but these alone did not prove enough for the Japanese authorities.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="28.36" PS="1.6097560975609757" SM="13">Fischer's supporters said they had received assurances from Japan that, with full Icelandic citizenship and passport, he would be free to leave the country.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="22.16" PS="1.6097560975609757" SM="11">&quot;It was very clear from the outset that he had a great influence here,&quot; Benediktsson said of Fischer, speaking by telephone from Reykjavik.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="14.409090909090908" PS="1.0731707317073171" SM="6">&quot;A new generation of international chess players was born here in Iceland after the world championship match in Reykjavik, and it was very clear from the outset of this matter that the authorities in Iceland have very warm feelings toward this memory.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="13.814814814814815" PS="1.6097560975609757" SM="0">Benediktsson emphasized that the granting of citizenship was considered only as a last resort, &quot;after the applicant had exhausted all other possibilities&quot; of gaining freedom.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="28.38095238095238" PS="1.0731707317073171" SM="11">He also said that Fischer's &quot;personal opinions on social issues&quot; had not entered into his government's decision.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="15.347826086956522" PS="1.6097560975609757" SM="12">In a telephone interview, Einarsson played down the significance of Fischer's reputation for misanthropy and his habit of making incendiary public remarks.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="19.41176470588235" PS="1.6097560975609757" SM="1">&quot;Everyone knows his views, and he doesn't need to repeat them again,&quot; Einarsson said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="17.238095238095237" PS="1.0731707317073171" SM="0">&quot;He's like Rembrandt or Mozart, one of these very big people, so his personality is beside the point.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="28.823529411764707" PS="1.6097560975609757" SM="14">Einarsson said that Fischer was likely to make Iceland his home, at least for the time being.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="19.263157894736842" PS="1.0731707317073171" SM="4">&quot;I think he will stay in Iceland a lot, at least for the coming months, and then he will travel freely around the world -- although I don't expect he will be going to America.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="28.37837837837838" PS="2.414634146341464" SM="28">Iceland's Parliament voted Monday to grant Icelandic citizenship to the American chess star Bobby Fischer, laying the groundwork, his supporters said, for his release from the Japanese prison where he has been held since last summer.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="24.944444444444443" PS="1.6097560975609757" SM="14">&quot;We are most happy,&quot; said Einar Einarsson, a spokesman for a committee that has been trying to free Fischer from Japan, where he is being detained while he fights deportation to the United States.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="17.244897959183675" PS="1.6097560975609757" SM="29">Einarsson, who called Fischer &quot;part of our modern saga and part of our recent history,&quot; said Fischer, the 62-year-old chess champion, might be released &quot;in only a few days&quot; and that an Icelandic delegation planned to travel to Tokyo to escort him back to Reykjavik.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="9.242424242424242" PS="1.6097560975609757" SM="2">In Washington, the State Department had no comment on the case, although a spokesman noted that renunciation of American citizenship did not allow citizens to escape prosecution of crimes in the United States.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="14.227272727272727" PS="1.6097560975609757" SM="15">Monday's vote appears to be a resolution of sorts to the curious legal limbo that Fischer fell into in 1992 when, the United States says, he violated economic sanctions against Yugoslavia by accepting a $3.3 million fee to play an exhibition match there.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="10.098039215686274" PS="1.0731707317073171" SM="16">After that, the always reclusive, progressively more difficult Fischer dropped out of sight, living in Budapest -- and possibly the Philippines and Switzerland -- and emerging now and then on radio stations in Iceland, Hungary and the Philippines to rant in increasingly belligerent terms against the United States and against Jews.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="11.297297297297296" PS="1.6097560975609757" SM="4">This latest episode began in July 2004, when he tried to board a plane from Japan to Manila and was seized by the Japanese authorities and accused of trying to leave the country on an invalid passport.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="10.625" PS="1.0731707317073171" SM="5">He has been held in prison since then while the various governments, as well as a staunch group of supporters in the chess world, have tried to find some resolution to what has been a vexing and delicate jurisdictional issue.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="20.4" PS="1.6097560975609757" SM="13">But while the United States -- which is also investigating the possibility of charging him with tax evasion -- regards Fischer as a fugitive from justice, in Iceland he is seen as a national hero.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="10.444444444444445" PS="1.0731707317073171" SM="4">It was in Reykjavik in 1972 that he defeated the Russian world champion, Boris Spassky, in an electrifying Cold War chess contest that pitted East against West.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="11.25" PS="1.0731707317073171" SM="15">As much as the African-American track star Jesse Owens' defeat of Hitler's Aryan athletes did at the 1936 Berlin Olympics, Fischer's victory in Iceland seemed to symbolize nothing less than the triumph of one way of life over another -- in this case, democracy over communism.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="20.970588235294116" PS="1.6097560975609757" SM="14">It is partly for that reason, said Bjarni Benediktsson, chairman of the parliamentary committee that recommended last week that Fischer be granted Icelandic citizenship, that Parliament voted in favor of his request on Monday.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="20.36" PS="1.0731707317073171" SM="15">Iceland had already agreed to issue a resident's permit and special passport to Fischer, but that had not proved enough for the Japanese authorities.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="26.208333333333332" PS="1.6097560975609757" SM="13">His supporters said they had received assurances from Japan that with full Icelandic citizenship and passport, Fischer would be free to leave the country.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="22.16" PS="1.6097560975609757" SM="11">&quot;It was very clear from the outset that he had a great influence here,&quot; Benediktsson said of Fischer, speaking by telephone from Reykjavik.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="14.409090909090908" PS="1.0731707317073171" SM="6">&quot;A new generation of international chess players was born here in Iceland after the world championship match in Reykjavik, and it was very clear from the outset of this matter that the authorities in Iceland have very warm feelings toward this memory.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="14.37037037037037" PS="1.6097560975609757" SM="0">He emphasized that the granting of citizenship was considered only as a last resort, &quot;after the applicant had exhausted all other possibilities&quot; of gaining freedom.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="28.705882352941178" PS="1.0731707317073171" SM="11">He also said Fischer's &quot;personal opinions on social issues&quot; had not been a factor.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="20.285714285714285" PS="1.6097560975609757" SM="25">In Tokyo, the Committee to Free Bobby Fischer praised the Icelandic Parliament, saying it had &quot;made history by standing up to the earth's sole superpower.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="15.522727272727273" PS="1.6097560975609757" SM="4">&quot;This is a historic battle pitting the world's sole superpower-bully against one lone man who had the courage to fight for his own freedom to think and speak as he chooses,&quot; John Bosnitch, chairman of the group, said in a statement.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="15.347826086956522" PS="1.6097560975609757" SM="12">In a telephone interview, Einarsson played down the significance of Fischer's reputation for misanthropy and his habit of making incendiary public remarks.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="22.58823529411765" PS="1.0731707317073171" SM="1">&quot;Everyone knows his views, and he doesn't need to repeat them again,&quot; he said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="17.043478260869566" PS="1.0731707317073171" SM="0">&quot;He's like Rembrandt or Mozart -- one of these very big people -- so his personality is beside the point.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="31.0" PS="1.6097560975609757" SM="14">He said Fischer was likely to make Iceland his home, at least for the time being.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="19.263157894736842" PS="1.0731707317073171" SM="4">&quot;I think he will stay in Iceland a lot, at least for the coming months, and then he will travel feely around the world -- although I don't expect he will be going to America.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="24.075" PS="2.5792682926829267" SM="28">Chess legend Bobby Fischer was on  Monday granted citizenship by the parliament of Iceland, a move  which could allow him to avoid deportation from Japan to the United  States where he is wanted for violating sanctions against the former  Yugoslavia.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="29.5" PS="1.719512195121951" SM="0">&quot;It is done.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="12.705882352941176" PS="1.146341463414634" SM="0">The decision is valid from today,&quot; Atli Gislason, a  deputy from the Left-Green movement, told AFP.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="23.823529411764707" PS="1.719512195121951" SM="14">Fischer, 62, who is in detention in Japan, faces prison if he  returns to the United States.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="11.783783783783784" PS="1.719512195121951" SM="3">The former grandmaster, known for his maverick behavior and  outspoken criticism of the United States, may face 10 years in  prison if convicted of violating US sanctions imposed on the former  Yugoslavia by playing there in 1992.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="18.5" PS="1.719512195121951" SM="13">But last week Mizuho Fukushima, head of the Japanese opposition  Social Democratic Party, told a press conference that Japanese  immigration officials would not deport Fischer to the United States  if Iceland grants him nationality.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="11.851851851851851" PS="1.719512195121951" SM="13">All 40 members of parliament who cast their votes were in favour  of the motion to grant Fischer citizenship, while two deputies  abstained, and 21 were absent.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="17.344827586206897" PS="1.719512195121951" SM="14">Iceland had previously sent Fischer a passport which showed  residency status but not full nationality, a document not deemed  sufficient to save him from deportation to the United States.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="14.795454545454545" PS="1.719512195121951" SM="16">Fischer's link to Iceland dates back to 1972, when he defeated  Russian Boris Spassky in a world championship match, which ended a  long domination of the game by Soviet players and was hailed as a  Cold War victory in his native United States.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="16.1" PS="1.719512195121951" SM="3">He was taken into custody in Japan last July for trying to leave  the country on an invalid US passport.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="31.333333333333332" PS="2.5929878048780486" SM="26">Iceland's parliament voted Monday to grant citizenship to fugitive U.S. chess star Bobby Fischer.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="10.15" PS="1.7286585365853657" SM="0">The legislation, passed with 40 lawmakers voting &quot;aye&quot; and two abstaining following a brief debate, became law immediately.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="22.24" PS="1.7286585365853657" SM="11">&quot;I am very pleased with this, and I think that the dignity of the parliament has increased,&quot; Fischer's supporter Saemundur Palsson said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="20.65909090909091" PS="1.7286585365853657" SM="16">He said Fischer, 62, would be informed of the vote Tuesday morning in Japan, where he has been detained awaiting deportation to the United States on a warrant for violating economic sanctions against the former Yugoslavia by playing a chess match there in 1992.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="17.181818181818183" PS="1.7286585365853657" SM="0">&quot;I hope that he will stop cursing the Americans now.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="20.181818181818183" PS="1.1524390243902438" SM="0">It has gotten him into so much trouble,&quot; Palsson said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="21.789473684210527" PS="1.7286585365853657" SM="13">Einar S. Einarsson, another of Fischer's key supporters, said he spoke to the mercurial chess genius earlier Monday.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="22.0" PS="1.7286585365853657" SM="11">Fischer hoped the vote process would be quick, Einarsson said, and &quot;I don't think it could have been much quicker.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="3.6363636363636362" PS="1.1524390243902438" SM="1">The bill went through the required three readings in 12 minutes.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="24.27777777777778" PS="1.7286585365853657" SM="12">Officials at the Office of Immigration said a passport for Fischer could be ready as early as Tuesday.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="25.25" PS="1.7286585365853657" SM="16">There is widespread support for Fischer in Iceland, where he played the Soviet Union's Boris Spassky in a world championship match in 1972.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="26.8" PS="1.7286585365853657" SM="12">Iceland's parliament voted last month against granting Fischer citizenship, offering him a special foreigners' passport and residence permit instead.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="14.714285714285714" PS="1.1524390243902438" SM="1">But Japanese officials declined to release him.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="19.266666666666666" PS="1.7286585365853657" SM="15">Since being taken into custody in July for allegedly trying to leave Japan on a revoked U.S. passport, Fischer has repeatedly denounced the U.S. deportation order as politically motivated, demanded refugee status, renounced his U.S. citizenship and said he wants to become a German national.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="13.5" PS="1.7286585365853657" SM="2">He has also applied to marry Mikyoko Watai, head of the Japan Chess Association.</sentence>
	</Sentences>
</Topic>
