<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<Topic id="D0919D">
	<Sentences>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="3.25" PS="2.650128865979381" SM="12">So ends years of tabloid and taxicab speculation.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="21.06451612903226" PS="1.7667525773195876" SM="74">In a surprise announcement, Britain's heir to the throne, Prince Charles, declared on Thursday that he will marry his lover, Camilla Parker Bowles, in a spring ceremony at Windsor Castle.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="19.8" PS="1.7667525773195876" SM="97">Parker Bowles will never become Queen Camilla, nor will she take over the title of princess of Wales that was bestowed on her predecessor, Diana, whose marriage to Charles ended in divorce, partly over her.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="10.0" PS="1.1778350515463918" SM="1">Diana died a year later, along with her boyfriend, in a Paris car accident.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="12.428571428571429" PS="1.7667525773195876" SM="51">Instead, in a sort of constitutional compromise, Parker Bowles, 57, will receive the title her royal highness the duchess of Cornwall.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="24.714285714285715" PS="1.1778350515463918" SM="15">If Charles becomes king, she will be called her royal highness the princess consort.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="19.454545454545453" PS="1.1778350515463918" SM="29">``Those are the only royal titles that have been confirmed so far,'' said a spokesperson for the prince of Wales.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="10.517241379310345" PS="1.7667525773195876" SM="57">Britain, which in 1936 forced Charles' great-uncle to abdicate the throne in order to marry an American divorcee, barely batted an eyelash at the consequence of the impending nuptials.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="14.722222222222221" PS="1.7667525773195876" SM="16">Prime Minister Tony Blair wished the couple ``every happiness'' on behalf of himself and his Cabinet.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="18.17142857142857" PS="1.1778350515463918" SM="95">Archbishop of Canterbury Rowan Williams, who serves as spiritual leader of the Anglican Church, said, ``I am pleased that Prince Charles and Mrs. Camilla Parker Bowles have decided to take this important step.''</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="16.775" PS="1.7667525773195876" SM="117">The announcement came in the form of a brief, formal statement from the prince's household, which read, ``It is with great pleasure that the marriage of HRH the prince of Wales and Mrs. Camilla Parker Bowles is announced.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="16.923076923076923" PS="1.1778350515463918" SM="1">It will take place on Friday 8th April, 2005, at Windsor Castle.''</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="21.625" PS="1.7667525773195876" SM="34">Later, Charles issued a statement that said, ``Mrs. Parker Bowles and I are absolutely delighted.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="17.307692307692307" PS="1.1778350515463918" SM="2">It will be a very special day for us and our families.''</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="14.125" PS="1.7667525773195876" SM="4">Queen Elizabeth gave the union her royal blessing.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="17.59090909090909" PS="1.1778350515463918" SM="76">``The duke of Edinburgh and I are very happy that the prince of Wales and Mrs. Parker Bowles are to marry.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="14.538461538461538" PS="1.1778350515463918" SM="1">We have given them our warmest good wishes for their future together.''</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="15.15" PS="1.7667525773195876" SM="73">The 56-year-old prince's two sons, Prince Edward and Prince Harry, announced that they too were delighted at the news of their father's marriage.Although the marriage will cause little political repercussion around Britain, the news dominated the airwaves Thursday.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="18.61904761904762" PS="1.1778350515463918" SM="49">Discussions and surveys showed general acceptance of the marriage but strong reservations about Charles' new wife becoming ``Queen Camilla.''</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="14.2" PS="1.7667525773195876" SM="76">The memory of Diana, mother of his two sons, is still strong among the British public, for whom Parker Bowles is the spoiler of what began as a fairy-tale marriage.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="10.928571428571429" PS="1.7667525773195876" SM="13">Charles and Lady Diana Spencer, a onetime nursery school teacher, were wed in 1981.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="7.833333333333333" PS="1.1778350515463918" SM="12">Their marriage was made in tabloid heaven, their every move scrutinized and documented in pictures by eager paparazzi.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="10.066666666666666" PS="1.1778350515463918" SM="12">But it was also marked by widespread speculation about unhappiness and by questions of infidelity.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="10.8" PS="1.7667525773195876" SM="62">In 1993, the tabloid press published a transcript of a taped call between Charles and Parker Bowles, then the wife of a British brigadier general.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="13.454545454545455" PS="1.1778350515463918" SM="55">Among the lovers' words was a wish by the prince that he become a tampon in order to remain close to Camilla.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="16.454545454545453" PS="1.7667525773195876" SM="38">Charles' relationship with Camilla began about 35 years ago when they met at a polo match on the grounds of Windsor Castle.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="20.20689655172414" PS="1.1778350515463918" SM="81">They continued seeing each other throughout Charles' tumultuous marriage to Diana, and the relationship was said by Diana to be the cause of her eventual breakup with the prince.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="15.333333333333334" PS="1.1778350515463918" SM="22">``There were three of us in this marriage -- so it was a bit crowded,'' she said in a famous TV interview.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="2.3333333333333335" PS="1.7667525773195876" SM="0">(Begin optional trim)</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="22.4" PS="1.7667525773195876" SM="36">From the beginning, it was clear Parker Bowles shared Charles' sporting life more than Diana.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="10.86" PS="1.7667525773195876" SM="94">Since the early days of his marriage to Diana, Charles was clearly more at home on the back of a horse or shooting grouse and fishing for salmon than on a dance floor, listening to pop music or watching ballet, which were among the favorite pastimes of his young bride.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="19.285714285714285" PS="1.7667525773195876" SM="49">Charles and Parker Bowles were often seen fox hunting together or on the polo field, where Charles was a regular player.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="14.0" PS="1.1778350515463918" SM="12">Many of their public outings have been on horseback.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="23.166666666666668" PS="1.7667525773195876" SM="12">Charles and Diana divorced in 1996.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="8.25" PS="1.1778350515463918" SM="25">Diana, as princess of Wales, found her calling as a patron of myriad charities, particularly those supporting sick and disadvantaged children and old people.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="2.875" PS="1.1778350515463918" SM="16">She championed AIDS victims and traveled to war-torn and poverty stricken countries, visiting orphanages and hospitals.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="9.95" PS="1.7667525773195876" SM="64">Her death in a car accident in Paris in August 1997, along with boyfriend Dodi Fayed, provoked an outpouring of grief in Britain and abroad, forcing Charles and Parker Bowles to keep their relationship in the background for some time.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="7.083333333333333" PS="1.7667525773195876" SM="3">Gradually the couple began appearing together in public in carefully choreographed events.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="3.3333333333333335" PS="1.7667525773195876" SM="0">(End optional trim)</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="8.588235294117647" PS="1.7667525773195876" SM="29">The decision to marry comes as what many see as a logical conclusion to a difficult situation.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="13.454545454545455" PS="1.7667525773195876" SM="19">``I don't think the public is hostile to the remarriage,'' says Sarah Richardson , a constitutional historian at Warwick University.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="17.70731707317073" PS="1.1778350515463918" SM="55">``What does surprise me is the recognition of her role as princess consort, which will put her in a spotlight where she will have to deliver and be an active supporter of Charles almost on a par with Diana.''</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="10.214285714285714" PS="1.7667525773195876" SM="0">Relief rather than pleasure was expressed by many Britons interviewed Thursday by TV networks.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="16.772727272727273" PS="1.7667525773195876" SM="1">``I guess it was better that they got married rather than not,'' said Marianne McElwee, 24, a Web site manager.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="24.7" PS="1.7667525773195876" SM="3">``I'm not keen on her,'' McElwee added.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="20.838709677419356" PS="1.1778350515463918" SM="15">``After all, Charles was always in a relationship with her before he met Diana and he went on seeing her after that, which didn't make Diana very happy.''</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="7.352941176470588" PS="1.7667525773195876" SM="68">Although the acceptance of a king-to-be, himself divorced, with a divorcee wife, is indicative of the changing face of Britain, the announcement also forces official recognition of the flawed and human side of royalty.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="14.25" PS="1.7667525773195876" SM="24">Royal marriages must be approved on several levels, so Blair's statement of approval was essential.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="11.238095238095237" PS="1.1778350515463918" SM="37">Charles' marriage will also need an Act of Parliament before the wedding day -- virtually a foregone conclusion in this case.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="3.0" PS="1.7667525773195876" SM="0">(Optional add end)</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="9.88" PS="1.7667525773195876" SM="30">The spring wedding will be a civil service followed by a service of prayer and dedication in the chapel of St. George at Windsor Castle.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="8.294117647058824" PS="1.1778350515463918" SM="19">No details were disclosed Thursday other than that the archbishop had agreed to celebrate the religious ceremony.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="15.413793103448276" PS="1.7667525773195876" SM="46">The couple will spend their honeymoon in Scotland on the royal estate of Birkhall, where Charles is said often to have taken refuge from the public and media glare.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="15.4" PS="1.7667525773195876" SM="50">On Thursday evening, the couple attended a gala dinner at Windsor Castle to support one of Prince Charles's charities.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="15.951219512195122" PS="1.7667525773195876" SM="43">Attention was focused on the prince's bride-to-be wearing her engagement ring for the first time -- a diamond and platinum heirloom reportedly from the prince's grandmother, the queen mother, who was 101 years old when she died in 2002.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="9.310344827586206" PS="1.7667525773195876" SM="56">The smiling Camilla, dressed in a glittering red floor-length dress and a double string of pearls, told waiting crowds that the prince had proposed to her on bended knee.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="19.5" PS="1.1778350515463918" SM="17">``I'm just coming down to earth,'' she said, flashing the ring for photographers.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="14.904761904761905" PS="1.7667525773195876" SM="16">Charles, garbed in a tuxedo with a red collar and cuffs, told the assembled reporters, ``I am very happy.''</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="8.0" PS="1.7667525773195876" SM="21">The couple were applauded by their guests and posed, grinning broadly, in front of the press before joining the party.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="13.285714285714286" PS="2.377577319587629" SM="14">They have been friends for 30 years and lovers for most of that time.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="8.11111111111111" PS="1.5850515463917527" SM="93">They have survived marriages to and divorces from other people; the icy disapproval of relatives; the resentment of the public; and, perhaps most excruciating of all, the publication of intimate details of their risque pillow talk.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="16.64" PS="1.5850515463917527" SM="113">But now Charles, the Prince of Wales, and Camilla Parker Bowles, whose love affair is said to have begun when she cheekily declared, &quot;My great-grandmother was your great-great-grandfather's mistress, so how about it?,&quot; are to take the most radical and surprising step of their long, star-crossed romance.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="20.0" PS="1.056701030927835" SM="0">They are getting married.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="15.3125" PS="1.5850515463917527" SM="63">The wedding is to take place on April 8 in a civil ceremony at Windsor Castle, Charles announced Thursday, but the 57-year-old bride will not become the Princess of Wales -- that position having already been more than filled by the prince's late and much-remembered ex-wife, Diana.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="21.214285714285715" PS="1.056701030927835" SM="37">Instead, Parker Bowles will be known as Her Royal Highness the Duchess of Cornwall.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="24.0" PS="1.5850515463917527" SM="0">Nor will she be crowned queen.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="16.517241379310345" PS="1.056701030927835" SM="68">In a move that addresses one of the thorniest issues surrounding the marriage, Parker Bowles will become the Princess Consort if Charles, 56, succeeds his mother on the throne.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="10.465116279069768" PS="1.056701030927835" SM="50">It will be the first time in the history of the English monarchy that such a title has been used, according to Vernon Bogdanor, professor of politics at Oxford University, and the first time an English king's wife has not been queen.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="18.0" PS="1.056701030927835" SM="11">(Queen Victoria did have Albert as Prince Consort.)</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="13.125" PS="1.5850515463917527" SM="82">The announcement gives official status for the first time to Parker Bowles, who has been living in an uneasy purgatory -- part of the prince's life, but bound by royal custom and social protocol to be an unequal partner.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="8.307692307692308" PS="1.056701030927835" SM="5">Although in recent years the two have appeared more often together in public, their murky status has put her in a difficult and oddly anachronistic position.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="10.434782608695652" PS="1.5850515463917527" SM="25">In earlier eras, of course, royals were not allowed to marry divorced people (never mind, unless they were Henry VIII, being divorced themselves).</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="7.0" PS="1.056701030927835" SM="3">In 1936, Edward VIII renounced the throne rather than give up Wallis Simpson, an American divorcee.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="13.72" PS="1.056701030927835" SM="24">In 1955, Prince Charles' Aunt, Princess Margaret, broke off a relationship with a divorced man rather than relinquish her royal status and all its perks.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="10.774193548387096" PS="1.5850515463917527" SM="58">But in a sign of how much things have changed, this time Queen Elizabeth gave her permission for, and blessing to, the engagement of her divorced son to his divorced lover.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="18.846153846153847" PS="1.056701030927835" SM="16">Saying that she and her husband, Charles' father, were &quot;very happy,&quot; she ordered that the Round Tower at Windsor Castle be lit in celebration.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="18.166666666666668" PS="1.5850515463917527" SM="39">The queen has not always appeared to be Parker Bowles' biggest fan.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="14.529411764705882" PS="1.056701030927835" SM="43">Although Charles has for some time been openly living with Camilla, his mother has very rarely entertained the two of them as a couple and indeed seemed intent on distancing herself from the relationship.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="17.185185185185187" PS="1.056701030927835" SM="9">But the two met in 2000, and on Thursday the Queen said that &quot;we have given them our warmest good wishes for their future together.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="18.81081081081081" PS="1.5850515463917527" SM="59">In their own statement, the prince's two sons, Prince Harry and Prince William, said: &quot;We are both very happy for our father and Camilla and we wish them all the luck in the future.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="11.25" PS="1.5850515463917527" SM="82">While the majority of respondents in several snap public opinion polls in Britain on Thursday said they disapproved of the engagement, crowds of well-wishers cheered Prince Charles during a public appearance in London, and politicians rushed to congratulate the couple.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="13.444444444444445" PS="1.5850515463917527" SM="80">Even officials of the Church of England, which until 2002 did not even allow divorcees to marry in church, have come around to the idea that Charles and Camilla would be better off married than not.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="16.772727272727273" PS="1.056701030927835" SM="31">The question has been complicated by the fact that when he becomes king, Charles will also become supreme governor of the church.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="22.82608695652174" PS="1.5850515463917527" SM="52">The Archbishop of Canterbury, Rowan Williams, said he was pleased at Charles and Camilla's decision &quot;to take this important step.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="12.88" PS="1.056701030927835" SM="30">After the civil wedding ceremony, he has agreed to lead a service &quot;of prayer and dedication&quot; at St. George's Chapel in Windsor.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="10.4" PS="1.5850515463917527" SM="66">In a world of expendable relationships, where middle-aged men trade in middle-aged women for younger, firmer models as easily as they might dispose of a creaky toaster or last year's car, the enduring relationship of Charles and Camilla, as the newspapers call them, carries a sweet poignancy for many.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="8.305555555555555" PS="1.5850515463917527" SM="49">Although in recent years she has had something of an image makeover, appearing more in couture dresses and less in frumpy countrywoman garb, Parker Bowles can hardly be called glamorous and does not appear to care.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="18.529411764705884" PS="1.056701030927835" SM="35">She once called herself &quot;your devoted old bag&quot; in a love letter to Prince Charles.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="10.764705882352942" PS="1.5850515463917527" SM="60">Even those unable to forgive Charles for cheating on the late Princess of Wales can take a certain comfort in knowing that if he had to do it, at least he took the counter-intuitive route, choosing someone older, wrinklier and less svelte than his wife, rather than the other way around.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="14.8" PS="1.5850515463917527" SM="24">It has always been clear that, unlike many couples who are actually married, Charles and Camilla truly like each other.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="7.636363636363637" PS="1.056701030927835" SM="2">They share a passion for hunting, fishing and other outdoor sports.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="8.666666666666666" PS="1.056701030927835" SM="11">They have bawdy senses of humor.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="16.054054054054053" PS="1.056701030927835" SM="59">More than that, it seems, the fun-loving Camilla is relatively uncomplicated (at least compared with Diana) and has been stolidly supportive of Prince Charles over the years, despite all the angst the relationship has put her through.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="14.961538461538462" PS="1.056701030927835" SM="41">The Prince of Wales and Camilla Shand, as she was then, hit it off from the first time they met, at a polo match in 1970.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="15.884615384615385" PS="1.056701030927835" SM="74">But Charles was something of a playboy, and when he dithered and went abroad to join the Navy, Camilla married a longtime suitor, Andrew Parker Bowles.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="20.857142857142858" PS="1.056701030927835" SM="17">The two remained friends with the prince.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="13.121212121212121" PS="1.056701030927835" SM="90">Andrew Parker Bowles even took on the ludicrously named ceremonial post of Silver Stick in Waiting to the prince, while his wife took another traditional role -- that of the prince's mistress.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="14.11111111111111" PS="1.5850515463917527" SM="18">Meanwhile, Charles married Lady Diana Spencer, a coltish 19-year-old who captivated the world -- but not her husband -- with her demure good looks and blue-eyed charisma.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="10.090909090909092" PS="1.056701030927835" SM="21">The two were spectacularly ill-suited for each other and, sunk by rancor and poor behavior on both sides, the marriage fell part.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="19.818181818181817" PS="1.5850515463917527" SM="48">Although Charles later said he took up again with Camilla only when his marriage broke down, Diana claimed that &quot;there were three people in the marriage, so it was quite crowded.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="23.8" PS="1.056701030927835" SM="41">She reportedly called Camilla &quot;the Rottweiler,&quot; while Camilla reportedly referred to her as &quot;that ridiculous creature.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="16.52173913043478" PS="1.5850515463917527" SM="28">It was Camilla Charles loved, and when he and Diana divorced in 1996, it seemed that finally the couple could stop sneaking around.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="9.703703703703704" PS="1.056701030927835" SM="37">But in the national convulsion of grief following Diana's horrific death from a car accident in Paris in 1997, public opinion turned viciously against Parker Bowles.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="7.866666666666666" PS="1.056701030927835" SM="2">At one point, irate shoppers pelted her with bread rolls in her local grocery store.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="12.366666666666667" PS="1.5850515463917527" SM="40">It was not until 1999, at a party in Piccadilly, that the two even appeared publicly together -- an orchestrated event in which Parker Bowles walked well behind the prince.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="11.428571428571429" PS="1.5850515463917527" SM="4">The two were together on Thursday night at a formal dinner in Windsor Palace.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="14.1" PS="1.056701030927835" SM="26">In contrast to his first post-engagement appearance with Diana all those years ago, in which he answered a question about whether he loved her by smirking and saying &quot;whatever love means,&quot; Charles seemed positively ebullient this time around.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="10.333333333333334" PS="1.5850515463917527" SM="44">Dressed in fuschia and flashing her enormous diamond engagement ring, a royal heirloom, Parker Bowles had the glow of a teenager at the prom.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="22.0" PS="1.056701030927835" SM="13">&quot;I'm just coming down to earth,&quot; she said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="34.375" PS="2.5225515463917527" SM="84">Prince Charles is to marry his partner Camilla Parker Bowles, the prince's office said Thursday.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="10.125" PS="1.681701030927835" SM="21">Clarence House didn't immediately announce further details, but Sky News TV reported that the heir to the throne would marry on April 6.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="14.647058823529411" PS="1.681701030927835" SM="24">Charles was previously married to Princess Diana, who died in a car crash in Paris in 1997.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="30.375" PS="1.1211340206185567" SM="11">She was divorced from Charles when she died.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="25.09090909090909" PS="1.681701030927835" SM="23">Charles dated Camilla many years before he married Diana in 1981.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="22.857142857142858" PS="1.1211340206185567" SM="48">They remained friends but Diana blamed Charles' relationship with Parker Bowles, who was also married, for the failure of their union.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="15.652173913043478" PS="1.681701030927835" SM="22">&quot;There were three of us in this marriage, so it was a bit crowded,&quot; Diana said in a 1995 TV interview.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="16.27777777777778" PS="1.681701030927835" SM="50">In 1994, Prince Charles admitted in a TV documentary that he had strayed from his marriage vows, but insisted the infidelity happened only after the marriage was &quot;irretrievably broken down, us both having tried.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="9.0" PS="1.681701030927835" SM="3">The pair divorced in 1996.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="16.27777777777778" PS="1.681701030927835" SM="38">The marriage is a sensitive issue because Parker Bowles is divorced and her former husband is still alive.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="12.96" PS="1.1211340206185567" SM="67">Charles would be the supreme governor of the Church of England if he took the throne, and some Anglicans remain opposed to remarriage of divorcees.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="12.380952380952381" PS="1.681701030927835" SM="34">The church is officially neutral on the issue, but former Archbishop of Canterbury George Carey recently urged the couple to marry.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="21.444444444444443" PS="1.681701030927835" SM="56">Last year, a poll indicated that more Britons support Prince Charles marrying Camilla Parker Bowles than oppose it.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="13.761904761904763" PS="1.1211340206185567" SM="38">Thirty-two percent of respondents to the Populus poll said they would support Charles if he remarried, while 29 percent were opposed.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="9.923076923076923" PS="1.1211340206185567" SM="1">Thirty-eight percent said they didn't care and 2 percent had no opinion.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="20.08" PS="2.5341494845360826" SM="69">Prince Charles and his longtime lover Camilla Parker Bowles _ both divorcees _ will be married in a civil ceremony, not in a Church of England service.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="17.307692307692307" PS="1.6894329896907216" SM="6">&quot;The wedding will be a largely private occasion for family and friends.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="20.352941176470587" PS="1.1262886597938144" SM="12">There will be a civil ceremony in Windsor Castle,&quot; said Clarence House, Charles' residence and office.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="15.2" PS="1.1262886597938144" SM="27">&quot;There will subsequently be a service of prayer and dedication in St. George's Chapel at which the Archbishop of Canterbury will preside.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="21.884615384615383" PS="2.470360824742268" SM="77">Prime Minister Tony Blair on Thursday congratulated Prince Charles and Camilla Parker Bowles after the heir to the throne announced he will marry his long-time partner.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="22.695652173913043" PS="1.6469072164948455" SM="62">&quot;I'm delighted for the Prince of Wales and Camilla Parker Bowles,&quot; Blair said in a statement broadcast on British TV.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="13.53125" PS="1.6469072164948455" SM="24">&quot;It's very happy news and when the Cabinet heard it this morning they sent their congratulations and good wishes on behalf of the whole government,&quot; the prime minister added.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="19.75" PS="1.6469072164948455" SM="1">&quot;We all wish them every happiness for their future together.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="22.047619047619047" PS="2.5225515463917527" SM="88">The Archbishop of Canterbury, Rowan Williams, on Thursday welcomed the news that Prince Charles and Camilla Parker Bowles are to marry.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="20.59375" PS="1.681701030927835" SM="90">&quot;I am pleased that Prince Charles and Mrs. Camilla Parker Bowles have decided to take this important step,&quot; said the archbishop, who is the spiritual leader of the Anglican communion.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="13.4" PS="1.681701030927835" SM="54">The communion includes the Church of England, of which Charles is expected to become Supreme Governor when he succeeds Queen Elizabeth II as British monarch.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="10.838709677419354" PS="1.681701030927835" SM="53">&quot;I hope and pray that it will prove a source of comfort and strength to them and to those who are closest to them,&quot; Williams said in a statement.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="21.8125" PS="1.681701030927835" SM="24">Charles announced he would marry Camilla in a civil ceremony at Windsor Castle on April 8.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="28.0" PS="1.1211340206185567" SM="24">Charles and Camilla are both divorcees.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="18.857142857142858" PS="1.681701030927835" SM="14">Williams said he approved of the proposals.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="12.24390243902439" PS="1.681701030927835" SM="63">&quot;These arrangements have my strong support and are consistent with Church of England guidelines concerning remarriage which the Prince of Wales fully accepts as a committed Anglican and as prospective Supreme Governor of the Church of England,&quot; Williams said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="30.9" PS="2.383376288659794" SM="72">Prince Charles said Thursday he is &quot;very excited&quot; about his engagement to his longtime lover Camilla Parker Bowles.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="15.727272727272727" PS="1.588917525773196" SM="32">After his office surprised Britain by announcing that the couple will be married at Windsor Castle on April 8, the prince was congratulated during a regularly scheduled visit to London's financial district.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="15.0" PS="1.588917525773196" SM="0">&quot;Thank you very much, you're so kind.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="46.5" PS="1.059278350515464" SM="0">he said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="25.833333333333332" PS="1.059278350515464" SM="0">&quot;I am very excited.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="26.2" PS="2.389175257731959" SM="78">Prince Charles' sons William and Harry are &quot;delighted&quot; at news he will marry Camilla Parker Bowles, a spokesman for the heir to the throne's office said Thursday.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="23.0" PS="1.5927835051546393" SM="70">Prince William and Prince Harry, Charles' sons with the late Princess Diana, are said to want the couple to be happy, the spokesman for Clarence House said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="15.1" PS="1.5927835051546393" SM="13">Charles and his future wife will attend a dinner at Windsor Castle later Thursday, a spokeswoman for Clarence House added.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="18.176470588235293" PS="1.5927835051546393" SM="40">Parker Bowles will wear her engagement ring, she added, but she gave no details of the ornament.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="23.533333333333335" PS="2.447164948453608" SM="59">Many Britons welcomed Prince Charles' surprise announcement that he would marry his lover Camilla Parker Bowles, but some said she never will win their hearts the way Princess Diana did.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="15.441176470588236" PS="1.6314432989690721" SM="57">Within minutes of Charles' announcement that the couple will marry at Windsor Castle on April 8, it was hard to find anyone on the streets of central London who hadn't heard the news.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="9.11111111111111" PS="1.6314432989690721" SM="0">&quot;We've all been expecting that sooner or later, said Dina Pine, 73, a retired restaurant owner.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="26.181818181818183" PS="1.0876288659793814" SM="0">&quot;But I don't think she should be queen.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="23.25" PS="1.6314432989690721" SM="1">&quot;I'm fine with him marrying her.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="12.461538461538462" PS="1.0876288659793814" SM="13">They seem to suit each other,&quot; said Bonita Archibald, 39, a hairdresser.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="17.666666666666668" PS="1.6314432989690721" SM="40">Archibald said Prince Charles should be given the benefit of the doubt in such decisions, even though he has been known for occasional gaffes.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="31.916666666666668" PS="1.0876288659793814" SM="25">&quot;Charles seems to have his head screwed on,&quot; she said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="12.151515151515152" PS="1.6314432989690721" SM="63">Sarah Ferguson, the Duchess of York, and other well-known British public figures, said it's time for the public to forget about royal tragedies of the past and welcome Camilla into the fold.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="22.03448275862069" PS="1.6314432989690721" SM="33">Ferguson, who is divorced from Prince Andrew, Charles' brother, said through a spokeswoman in the United States that she &quot;is very happy for&quot; for the engaged couple.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="12.521739130434783" PS="1.6314432989690721" SM="45">Winston Churchill, the grandson of Britain's wartime prime minister of the same name, said the couple are entitled to be happy together.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="15.875" PS="1.6314432989690721" SM="0">&quot;They are clearly very much in love.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="12.153846153846153" PS="1.0876288659793814" SM="45">It must be the end of a series of nightmare years for Camilla, every day reading in the papers about being the mistress this and that.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="12.88888888888889" PS="1.0876288659793814" SM="16">They are entitled to have their own happiness the same as everyone else,&quot; Churchill told Sky News.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="17.08695652173913" PS="1.6314432989690721" SM="38">Asked how he thought the British public would react, veteran broadcaster Sir David Frost said: &quot;I think there will be quite a bit of controversy for 24 hours, but then I think everyone will be happy and feel that Prince Charles deserves his happiness.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="18.375" PS="1.6314432989690721" SM="111">Charles and Camilla _ divorcees and longtime lovers _ will marry in a civil ceremony, not in the Church of England, and that Parker Bowles will be called Her Royal Highness the Duchess of Cornwall after the marriage, and called the princess consort, not the queen, when Charles becomes king.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="16.666666666666668" PS="1.6314432989690721" SM="22">Grocer Phillip Way, 37, said he believes royals such as Prince Charles often earn too much money from their many estates.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="27.6" PS="1.0876288659793814" SM="11">But Way said he doesn't care who Charles marries.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="17.16" PS="1.6314432989690721" SM="40">&quot;We could have Queen Camilla or the Queen of Sheba, and it would make no difference to me,&quot; he said with a laugh.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="18.923076923076923" PS="1.0876288659793814" SM="16">&quot;Who do you think the best man is going to be?&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="18.105263157894736" PS="1.6314432989690721" SM="36">Chris Morris, 54, a building engineer, said that he thought Charles was smart to marry Camilla before becoming king.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="24.0" PS="1.0876288659793814" SM="0">But whatever happens, Morris said, she will never be as popular as Princess Diana was.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="26.307692307692307" PS="1.6314432989690721" SM="1">&quot;Diana is still in so many people's hearts,&quot; he said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="29.11111111111111" PS="1.0876288659793814" SM="12">&quot;Queen Camilla wouldn't be so popular.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="12.424242424242424" PS="1.6314432989690721" SM="32">Charles divorced Diana in 1996, a year before she was killed in a Paris car crash, and some Britons believe the long-standing Charles-Camilla affair was the main reason the Charles-Diana marriage fell apart.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="16.91304347826087" PS="1.6314432989690721" SM="12">Joe Stolerman, 17, a student, said that if Camilla ever becomes queen &quot;I'm sure she won't be well received.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="17.25925925925926" PS="1.6314432989690721" SM="5">Paul Curley, an IT manager, 33, said he doesn't care about the royal family, adding that &quot;they are more for tourists than for us.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="26.470588235294116" PS="1.0876288659793814" SM="28">But he also said, &quot;It's not going to be an easy ride for Camilla.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="22.0" PS="1.6314432989690721" SM="40">Princess Diana's brother Earl Spencer declined to comment on the announcement by Prince Charles.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="12.421052631578947" PS="1.6314432989690721" SM="20">In Diana's home village near the Spencer family's Althorp estate north of London, the reaction was mixed.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="6.3" PS="1.6314432989690721" SM="24">Jacqui Ellard, 33, the landlady of the Brington village pub, the Althorp Coaching Inn Fox and Hounds, welcomed the news.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="16.41176470588235" PS="1.6314432989690721" SM="14">&quot;They should be allowed to do whatever they want and it is as simple as that.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="22.75" PS="1.0876288659793814" SM="1">It is nobody else's business but their own,&quot; she said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="19.696969696969695" PS="1.6314432989690721" SM="29">&quot;Diana was obviously special in many people's hearts for many different reasons, but I don't think there is strong opinion about Charles and Camilla in the village,&quot; Ellard said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="5.0" PS="1.6314432989690721" SM="0">Other villagers disagreed.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="21.11111111111111" PS="1.6314432989690721" SM="50">Retiree Ann Rogers said Prince Charles should abdicate the throne if he wants to marry Camilla, a divorcee.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="28.9" PS="1.6314432989690721" SM="11">&quot;I think that Diana was duped into marrying Charles.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="15.5625" PS="1.0876288659793814" SM="26">He didn't really want to marry her because he already had this relationship with Camilla.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="19.7" PS="1.0876288659793814" SM="0">That is how I see it,&quot; said Rogers, 60.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="17.7" PS="2.452963917525773" SM="46">She may not become queen, but Camilla Parker Bowles will be bona fide royalty because of three key letters: HRH.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="10.75" PS="1.6353092783505154" SM="34">That designation stands for Her Royal Highness and is highly prized because it means the bearer is officially a member of the inner sanctum of the royal family.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="18.1" PS="1.6353092783505154" SM="59">When she weds Charles, Parker Bowles will acquire a slew of titles _ the main one being HRH Duchess of Cornwall.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="18.333333333333332" PS="1.0902061855670102" SM="14">In Scotland, she will be the Duchess of Rothesay.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="15.875" PS="1.6353092783505154" SM="45">However, she will not be known as the Princess of Wales, a title which for many people worldwide still conjures up memories of the prince's popular first wife, the late Diana.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="25.333333333333332" PS="1.6353092783505154" SM="46">If Charles eventually becomes king, Parker Bowles will be known as HRH Princess Consort _ but not Queen Camilla.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="19.73076923076923" PS="1.6353092783505154" SM="51">That decision was made by the couple themselves, Charles's Clarence House office said, and was not imposed on them because of Parker Bowles' divorcee status.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="15.444444444444445" PS="1.6353092783505154" SM="10">Princess Diana lost her HRH status when she was divorced _ a point that rankled greatly with her and was criticized both by the public and the press.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="12.073170731707316" PS="1.6353092783505154" SM="49">In 1936, when King Edward VIII abdicated to marry the American divorcee Wallis Simpson and they became the Duke and Duchess of Windsor, he is said to have been deeply angry and hurt that the HRH was withheld from his wife.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="10.833333333333334" PS="1.6353092783505154" SM="16">As the royal family modernizes, there are likely to be fewer HRHs.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="13.448275862068966" PS="1.6353092783505154" SM="27">Charles' younger brother, Prince Edward, announced in 2003 that his newborn daughter would not receive the HRH, nor would any more children he and his wife, Sophie, might have.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="10.333333333333334" PS="1.6353092783505154" SM="11">Every wife of a reigning king has been known as Queen Consort except Queen Mary II who was joint sovereign with King William III.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="13.066666666666666" PS="1.0902061855670102" SM="15">She was Queen in her own right and together they reigned from 1689 to 1694.</sentence>
	</Sentences>
</Topic>
