<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<Topic id="D0928E">
	<Sentences>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="10.272727272727273" PS="2.4000000000000004" SM="13">A federal judge has allowed Tyco International Ltd. shareholders to go forward with a class action lawsuit against the company and others.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="10.321428571428571" PS="1.6" SM="33">But U.S. District Judge Paul Barbadoro on Thursday struck down a related claim that sought damages on behalf of Tyco stemming from allegations of fraud and corporate looting.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="17.344827586206897" PS="1.6" SM="37">Former top executives L. Dennis Kozlowski and Mark Swartz are awaiting retrial in federal court in New York on charges of stealing $600 million (euro483.33 million) from the company.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="12.25" PS="1.0666666666666667" SM="12">Their first trial resulted in a hung jury.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="20.8" PS="1.0666666666666667" SM="2">They have denied the charges.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="11.791666666666666" PS="1.6" SM="46">Barbadoro dismissed the claim seeking damages on behalf of Tyco against most of its current directors and several of its former directors and officers.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="14.5" PS="1.0666666666666667" SM="0">Barbadoro said it was barred under Bermuda law.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="12.272727272727273" PS="1.0666666666666667" SM="12">Tyco, managed from West Windsor, New Jersey, is registered in Bermuda.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="12.16" PS="1.6" SM="6">&quot;This represents a big shareholder win and a major step forward in the case,&quot; Jay Eisenhofer, the plaintiffs lawyer, said in a statement.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="14.590909090909092" PS="1.6" SM="6">Barbadoro rejected the defendants' attempt to separate the accounting fraud allegations from the looting allegations, finding &quot;both interrelated and interdependent.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="17.125" PS="1.6" SM="27">In the class-action lawsuit, shareholders seek damages against the company, Kozlowski; Swartz; Mark Belnick, former director Frank Walsh; and the company's auditor PricewaterhouseCoopers.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="2.9" PS="1.6" SM="0">According to some estimates, investors lost $60 billion (euro48.33 billion).</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="11.62962962962963" PS="1.6" SM="11">In a prepared statement, Tyco spokesman David Polk said: &quot;We believe we have a very strong case, and we are prepared to defend it vigorously.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="14.68421052631579" PS="2.525" SM="67">A judge refused to combine a retrial of larceny charges against former Tyco International Ltd. chief executive L. Dennis Kozlowski with a trial on charges that he failed to pay sales taxes on $13 million worth of art.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="14.685714285714285" PS="1.6833333333333333" SM="47">In denying the prosecution's consolidation request on Monday, state Supreme Court Justice Michael Obus noted that the larceny trial, set to begin Jan. 18, includes Tyco's former chief financial officer Mark Swartz, 44.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="17.833333333333332" PS="1.1222222222222222" SM="18">The judge said there is not enough evidence that Swartz was involved in the tax scheme to join that trial with the larceny retrial.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="12.61111111111111" PS="1.6833333333333333" SM="29">&quot;There is no evidence that Swartz entered into any agreement, tacit or express, with either Kozlowski or the art vendors to avoid the payment of the sales tax,&quot; Obus wrote in his 11-page ruling.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="14.666666666666666" PS="1.6833333333333333" SM="13">The tax indictment charges Kozlowski, 57, with conspiracy, falsifying business records and tampering with evidence.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="8.826086956521738" PS="1.1222222222222222" SM="11">Obus had earlier noted that nonpayment of sales taxes is not a crime but it is a crime to fail to collect them.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="16.75" PS="1.6833333333333333" SM="19">Obus also said the charges involved different victims _ Tyco and its shareholders in the larceny case, New York state in the tax evasion case.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="15.5" PS="1.6833333333333333" SM="35">In the tax case, Kozlowski was accused of scheming with dealers to avoid paying more than $1 million on $13 million worth of artworks.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="20.88235294117647" PS="1.1222222222222222" SM="35">In the larceny case, Kozlowski and Swartz are accused of looting more than $600 million from Tyco.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="13.91304347826087" PS="1.6833333333333333" SM="14">If convicted on the first-degree grand larceny charge after their retrial, Kozlowski and Swartz each could face up to 25 years in prison.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="7.954545454545454" PS="1.6833333333333333" SM="13">Tyco, based in Bermuda but with U.S. headquarters in West Windsor, New Jersey, makes everything from telecommunications equipment to home alarm systems.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="11.1" PS="2.525" SM="57">The retrial of two top Tyco International executives accused of stealing $600 million (euro458 million) of company money to finance lifestyles of gaudy excess is set to begin next week.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="11.833333333333334" PS="1.6833333333333333" SM="5">Legal experts say prosecutors should, and probably will, focus less on items like the $6,000 (euro4,580) gold-threaded shower curtain bought with company money and concentrate more on the alleged thefts.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="13.074074074074074" PS="1.6833333333333333" SM="46">The first trial of L. Dennis Kozlowski and Mark Swartz was aborted after six months last year by a menacing letter and telephone call to a juror.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="17.633333333333333" PS="1.6833333333333333" SM="38">Prosecutors have told the judge they expected to present a shorter, leaner case against Kozlowski, Tyco's former chairman and chief executive officer, and Mark Swartz, the former finance chief.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="8.909090909090908" PS="1.1222222222222222" SM="0">They expect it to last a little more than four months.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="14.326086956521738" PS="1.6833333333333333" SM="37">In the first trial in Manhattan's State Supreme Court, prosecutors gave jurors a videotaped look at the $2 million (euro1.53 million) birthday party Kozlowski threw for his wife on a Mediterranean island, and a video tour through his $18 million (euro13.75 million) Fifth Avenue apartment _ .</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="13.137931034482758" PS="1.6833333333333333" SM="45">Jurors were told Kozlowski spent some $11 million (euro8.4 million) of Tyco's money to furnish the apartment with amenities such as a $4,050 tablecloth and a $515 toaster.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="3.210526315789474" PS="1.1222222222222222" SM="11">There was also a $2,900 set of hangers, a $4,995 custom-made blue-and-gold bedskirt, and a $2,665 blue velvet pillow.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="9.833333333333334" PS="1.6833333333333333" SM="2">And those were the little things.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="6.105263157894737" PS="1.6833333333333333" SM="24">The jurors also saw a Persian rug that cost $191,250, a George I walnut arabesque clock that set Tyco back $113,750, an Ascherberg grand piano that cost $77,000, and a pair of French antique stools, bought for $125,000.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="13.84375" PS="1.6833333333333333" SM="29">Prosecutors from Manhattan District Attorney Robert Morgenthau's office said at the time that the extravagances demonstrated the defendants' greed and showed where some of the money they allegedly stole ended up.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="12.5" PS="1.6833333333333333" SM="11">Kozlowski, 58, and Swartz, 44, are charged with grand larceny, falsifying business records, conspiracy and business law violations.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="15.214285714285714" PS="1.6833333333333333" SM="38">Prosecutors said the defendants stole $170 million (euro130 million) by hiding unauthorized bonuses and secretly forgiving loans to themselves, and pocketed an additional $430 million (euro328 million) by pumping up Tyco stock by lying about the state of the company's finances.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="20.923076923076923" PS="1.6833333333333333" SM="22">Defense lawyers said Kozlowski and Swartz earned every penny they got from Tyco.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="12.842105263157896" PS="1.6833333333333333" SM="18">The trial judge, Justice Michael Obus, has already thrown out the top charge in the original indictment _ enterprise corruption.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="13.38888888888889" PS="1.1222222222222222" SM="23">That count suggested that Kozlowski and Swartz had conspired with others to turn Tyco into a criminal enterprise.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="10.153846153846153" PS="1.6833333333333333" SM="18">If convicted of the current top charge, first-degree grand larceny, and the other more serious counts, the defendants each face up to 30 years in prison.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="5.2592592592592595" PS="1.6833333333333333" SM="23">Tyco, which has about 270,000 employees and $36 billion (euro27.5 billion) in annual revenue, makes a wide range of products including electronics, medical supplies and security devices.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="14.2" PS="2.5375" SM="24">L. Dennis Kozlowski wants to be clear: The $6,000 shower curtain wasn't his idea.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="13.121212121212121" PS="1.6916666666666667" SM="49">The shower curtain, bought by his decorator on Tyco International's tab for an extravagantly furnished Manhattan apartment, became perhaps the most notable symbol of corporate excess and conspicuous consumption of the 1990s.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="21.7" PS="1.6916666666666667" SM="59">&quot;I understand why a $6,000 shower curtain seems indefensible,&quot; Kozlowski, Tyco's former chief executive, said on the eve of his retrial on charges of looting the company.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="18.0" PS="1.1277777777777778" SM="0">&quot;But I didn't know about it.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="15.222222222222221" PS="1.1277777777777778" SM="11">I just wasn't even aware of it.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="7.0" PS="1.6916666666666667" SM="24">Dressed in a pair of jeans and hiking boots, Kozlowski did not look much like a swashbuckling, custom-suit-wearing chief executive.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="8.0" PS="1.6916666666666667" SM="0">He did not sound like one either.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="13.931818181818182" PS="1.1277777777777778" SM="58">Soft-spoken and uncharacteristically reticent at times, Kozlowski, in his first extensive interview since he was charged more than two years ago with stealing hundreds of millions of dollars from Tyco, said that he was innocent and that the public perception of him was misguided.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="13.761904761904763" PS="1.6916666666666667" SM="1">&quot;People think that I'm a greedy guy; that I was overcompensated,&quot; he said, leaning forward in his chair.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="18.25" PS="1.1277777777777778" SM="2">&quot;Greed, I think, is the key word.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="12.051282051282051" PS="1.1277777777777778" SM="33">But while I did earn enormous sums of money, which for a poor kid from Newark was spectacular, I worked my butt off, and it was all based on my performance in Tyco's long established pay-for-performance culture.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="10.6" PS="1.6916666666666667" SM="59">That image of greed, of course, stems from accusations that he not only awarded himself unauthorized bonuses, but that he had the company also pay $15,000 for an umbrella stand and half the cost of a multimillion-dollar birthday party for his second wife in Sardinia, with a now notorious ice sculpture of Michelangelo's &quot;David&quot; that flowed vodka.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="9.76086956521739" PS="1.6916666666666667" SM="38">But Kozlowski, who faces a second trial on Tuesday in New York state Supreme Court in Manhattan, portrayed himself as a self-made entrepreneur who has become the victim of an overzealous prosecutor interested in sensational headlines and a board trying to protect itself from shareholder lawsuits.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="14.045454545454545" PS="1.1277777777777778" SM="28">While clearly anxious about the retrial and humbled by the enormity of the situation, he remained unapologetic about his conduct at Tyco.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="14.352941176470589" PS="1.6916666666666667" SM="0">&quot;I firmly believe that I never did or intended to do anything wrong,&quot; he said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="7.25" PS="1.1277777777777778" SM="12">&quot;I never thought in my wildest imagination I or any of us did anything wrong my entire time there.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="12.833333333333334" PS="1.1277777777777778" SM="0">I still cannot believe that they say words like larceny.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="9.11111111111111" PS="1.6916666666666667" SM="0">It is a long way down from flying on private jets and being driven everywhere by a chauffer.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="14.571428571428571" PS="1.1277777777777778" SM="11">&quot;I'm given an allowance to pay for food and, you know, basic essentials that I need,&quot; Kozlowski said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="11.875" PS="1.6916666666666667" SM="4">The case against him, he argued, should have been heard in a civil court, not criminal.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="17.23076923076923" PS="1.1277777777777778" SM="11">&quot;I do believe this is a civil case between Tyco and I.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="7.545454545454546" PS="1.1277777777777778" SM="0">After 27 years, there was an unamicable breakup, a faulty divorce.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="7.9523809523809526" PS="1.1277777777777778" SM="3">And I do believe this should be ironed out in a civil manner and certainly not in a criminal manner.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="7.875" PS="2.275" SM="1">Prosecutors have been chasing corporate crooks and piling up big statistics in court for five years.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="12.08695652173913" PS="1.5166666666666666" SM="48">Now get ready for a series of trials featuring many of the biggest executives charged with the most audacious crimes of their era.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="6.55" PS="1.5166666666666666" SM="2">A few big figures, like Martha Stewart and Frank Quattrone, were mixed into the mostly no-name court lineup last year.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="19.285714285714285" PS="1.011111111111111" SM="26">But 2005 will be remembered as the year of the marquee CEO on trial.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="6.166666666666667" PS="1.011111111111111" SM="0">Take a look at this lineup:</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="4.0" PS="1.5166666666666666" SM="0">Bernie Ebbers.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="16.16" PS="1.011111111111111" SM="30">The trial of the former WorldCom Inc. chief executive charged as the front man for an $11 billion fraud begins this week in New York.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="12.294117647058824" PS="1.5166666666666666" SM="6">Ebbers is charged with fraud and conspiracy in the WorldCom collapse, the largest bankruptcy in US history.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="12.368421052631579" PS="1.011111111111111" SM="13">Former chief financial officer Scott Sullivan, who cut his own plea deal, will be the government's star witness.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="12.15" PS="1.5166666666666666" SM="13">This will be an important test of the &quot;idiot CEO&quot; defense (see Richard Scrushy and Ken Lay, below).</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="10.0" PS="1.011111111111111" SM="3">Ebbers is expected to say he left all the numbers to Sullivan, who told prosecutors what they wanted to hear when he got in trouble.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="8.6" PS="1.011111111111111" SM="0">Ebbers was a big-picture guy.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="22.6" PS="1.5166666666666666" SM="24">L. Dennis Kozlowski, the sequel.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="11.7" PS="1.011111111111111" SM="26">The former Tyco International Ltd. chief who became a symbol of material excess began his retrial in New York Tuesday.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="10.486486486486486" PS="1.5166666666666666" SM="62">The first trial of Kozlowski and Tyco chief financial officer Mark Swartz ended in a sensational mistrial after a juror favoring acquittal found herself in the middle of a media frenzy and ultimately received a threatening note.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="14.0" PS="1.5166666666666666" SM="66">Kozlowski and Swartz are charged with stealing hundreds of millions of dollars from Tyco by hiding details of their compensation from directors and selling big blocks of company stock after inflating its value.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="21.5625" PS="1.5166666666666666" SM="23">But it was Kozlowski's outrageous spending on the company tab ($15,000 for an umbrella stand?)</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="9.833333333333334" PS="1.011111111111111" SM="13">that got most of the headlines.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="5.5" PS="1.5166666666666666" SM="0">Richard Scrushy.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="11.181818181818182" PS="1.011111111111111" SM="28">The founder of HealthSouth Corp. is charged as the mastermind behind a $2.7 billion earnings fraud in a trial underway in Alabama.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="13.0" PS="1.011111111111111" SM="0">A jury is being selected.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="15.222222222222221" PS="1.5166666666666666" SM="6">The HealthSouth scam wasn't as big as the WorldCom fraud, and the company continues to operate today.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="10.272727272727273" PS="1.011111111111111" SM="2">But Scrushy takes the cake when it comes to defense stories.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="11.0" PS="1.011111111111111" SM="3">He wasn't just the idiot CEO, he may have been in a coma.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="15.235294117647058" PS="1.5166666666666666" SM="3">Prosecutors will rely on five former chief financial officers who will all implicate Scrushy as the ringleader.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="19.4" PS="1.011111111111111" SM="5">One secretly recorded the former chief executive for the government.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="13.1" PS="1.5166666666666666" SM="10">Scrushy will blame his lieutenants for inflating HealthSouth's profits.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="1.6666666666666667" PS="1.011111111111111" SM="0">See a pattern?</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="4.0" PS="1.5166666666666666" SM="0">Ken Lay.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="17.5" PS="1.011111111111111" SM="13">The former Enron Corp. chairman faces two trials.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="8.68421052631579" PS="1.011111111111111" SM="1">One, in which Lay faces fraud, conspiracy, and bank fraud charges alone, will probably be held later this year.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="13.956521739130435" PS="1.011111111111111" SM="3">The other, in which he is charged along with two other former Enron executives, may not make it to court before spring 2006.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="9.473684210526315" PS="1.5166666666666666" SM="12">Former chief executive Jeff Skilling and ex-chief accounting officer Richard Causey will join Lay at a second fraud trial.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="17.9375" PS="1.5166666666666666" SM="17">The Enron team was on the job during the most infamous corporate fraud of its time.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="6.714285714285714" PS="1.011111111111111" SM="1">More than 5,000 employees lost their jobs when Enron filed for bankruptcy in 2001.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="12.11111111111111" PS="1.011111111111111" SM="3">Lay, as you surely know by now, was just another big-picture guy in the dark about his company.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="9.692307692307692" PS="1.5166666666666666" SM="2">The idiot CEO strategy may sound risky, but it has been successful elsewhere.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="7.0" PS="1.011111111111111" SM="1">A jury in Hartford was unable to reach a verdict against former Cendant Corp. chairman Walter Forbes two weeks ago, despite incriminating testimony from three executives.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="12.15" PS="1.5166666666666666" SM="29">The trials ahead culminate the effort to hold people criminally responsible for the worst excesses of a dangerously excessive time.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="11.0" PS="1.011111111111111" SM="2">But don't count the idiots out yet.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="5.666666666666667" PS="1.5166666666666666" SM="0">Steven Syre is a Globe columnist.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="7.0" PS="1.011111111111111" SM="0">He can be reached at syreglobe.com.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="16.161290322580644" PS="2.8" SM="48">Jury selection began Tuesday for the second trial of two former top Tyco International Ltd. executives charged with looting the company of $600 million (euro459 million) to subsidize their lavish lifestyles.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="14.56" PS="1.8666666666666667" SM="34">Prosecutors promised to present a leaner case this time against former Tyco chairman and CEO L. Dennis Kozlowski and former chief financial officer Mark Swartz.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="14.421052631578947" PS="1.8666666666666667" SM="37">In the first trial, prosecutors played a videotape of the $2 million (euro1.53 million) birthday party Kozlowski threw for his wife on a Mediterranean island, and a video tour through his $18 million (euro14 million) Fifth Avenue apartment.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="15.064516129032258" PS="1.8666666666666667" SM="23">This time around, prosecutors were expected to focus less on items such as Kozlowski's $6,000 (euro4,600) gold-threaded shower curtain and more on how he and Swartz allegedly looted the company.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="13.777777777777779" PS="1.8666666666666667" SM="2">The retrial is expected to last about four months.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="12.5" PS="1.8666666666666667" SM="11">Kozlowski, 58, and Swartz, 44, are charged with grand larceny, falsifying business records, conspiracy and business law violations.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="10.352941176470589" PS="1.8666666666666667" SM="16">The defendants each face up to 30 years in prison if convicted of the most serious charges.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="9.409090909090908" PS="1.8666666666666667" SM="22">Their first trial, which lasted six months, was aborted last year because of a menacing letter and telephone call to a juror.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="14.930232558139535" PS="1.8666666666666667" SM="58">Kozlowski and Swartz are accused of stealing $170 million (euro130 million) by hiding unauthorized bonuses and secretly forgiving loans to themselves, and pocketing $430 million (euro329 million) more by pumping up Tyco stock with lies about the state of the company's finances.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="20.923076923076923" PS="1.8666666666666667" SM="22">Defense lawyers said Kozlowski and Swartz earned every penny they got from Tyco.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="12.933333333333334" PS="1.8666666666666667" SM="7">The judge has already thrown out the top charge in the original indictment _ enterprise corruption.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="13.38888888888889" PS="1.2444444444444445" SM="23">That count suggested that Kozlowski and Swartz had conspired with others to turn Tyco into a criminal enterprise.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="5.2592592592592595" PS="1.8666666666666667" SM="23">Tyco, which has about 270,000 employees and $36 billion (euro27.6 billion) in annual revenue, makes a wide range of products including electronics, medical supplies and security devices.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="17.5" PS="1.2444444444444445" SM="3">The company is based in Bermuda.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="9.11111111111111" PS="1.2444444444444445" SM="1">Its U.S. headquarters is in West Windsor, New Jersey.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="13.045454545454545" PS="2.3875" SM="37">The Triple Crown of corporate scandals reached full stride this week with the spectacle of three former big-money CEOs on trial simultaneously.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="16.27777777777778" PS="1.5916666666666668" SM="54">Cases against Tyco's Dennis Kozlowski and WorldCom's Bernie Ebbers Jr. began last week in New York.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="13.454545454545455" PS="1.0611111111111111" SM="35">The trial of HealthSouth's Richard Scrushy launched Tuesday in Birmingham.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="8.0" PS="1.5916666666666668" SM="16">The coincidental confluence gives Americans a glimpse of corporate theater: Accountants in the limelight.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="14.0" PS="1.0611111111111111" SM="0">CEOs on hot seats.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="14.75" PS="1.0611111111111111" SM="0">Lavish lifestyles on display.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="8.375" PS="1.5916666666666668" SM="5">Legal and business academics say the cases raise questions about big themes, such as the delicate balance between a free market and government regulation.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="13.814814814814815" PS="1.0611111111111111" SM="15">But academics doubt Americans will be as riveted by the trials as they were by less significant courtroom dramas like the California case against wife-murderer Scott Peterson.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="11.083333333333334" PS="1.5916666666666668" SM="21">&quot;It's hard for a lot of people to get outraged.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="6.566666666666666" PS="1.0611111111111111" SM="33">They see them as a bunch of rich people ripping off a bunch of other rich people,&quot; said Robert Thompson, a Syracuse University professor of TV and pop culture.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="7.3076923076923075" PS="1.5916666666666668" SM="0">Actually, corporate scandals hurt workers, clients and stockholders at all levels, Thompson said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="6.923076923076923" PS="1.0611111111111111" SM="22">But plenty of educated Americans find it excruciating to sort through complex financial allegations to keep track of such malfeasance after recent government crackdowns, he said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="15.636363636363637" PS="1.5916666666666668" SM="24">After all, this is just the latest bubble of corporate trials.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="10.217391304347826" PS="1.0611111111111111" SM="58">A similar round in 2003 and 2004 included the first trial of Tyco's Kozlowski -- which ended in a mistrial -- and cases against former Wall Street investment banker Frank Quattrone, former Rite Aid senior executive Franklin C. Brown and corporate chief/home maven Martha Stewart.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="9.758620689655173" PS="1.5916666666666668" SM="26">While corporate cases in recent years have tended to be big, allegations of wrongdoing are far from new in the world of business, said Emory law professor William Carney.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="12.5625" PS="1.0611111111111111" SM="11">&quot;My first reaction to some of these cases is, 'Ho-hum, just another financial fraud case.'</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="45.0" PS="1.0611111111111111" SM="0">&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="12.333333333333334" PS="1.5916666666666668" SM="2">But Columbia University law professor John Coffee said the latest cases highlight how prosecutors are broadening what they consider corporate crimes they will pursue.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="7.541666666666667" PS="1.0611111111111111" SM="12">In past decades, business leaders usually faced only civil penalties for wrongdoing, except in cases of tax fraud, insider trading or price-fixing, Coffee said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="12.392857142857142" PS="1.5916666666666668" SM="25">&quot;Now we are seeing virtually any kind of corporate scandal that involves the interest of investors will be examined and scrutinized by criminal enforcers,&quot; he said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="16.48780487804878" PS="1.5916666666666668" SM="62">The allegations of the Tyco case -- including news of lavish parties and a $6,000 shower curtain -- revolve around whether corporate executives had the permission of the company's board before embarking on &quot;extraordinary conspicuous consumption,&quot; he said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="14.464285714285714" PS="1.5916666666666668" SM="33">HealthSouth's Scrushy is fighting allegations of fraud and stock manipulation for supposedly trying to make the company's financial situation look better than it was, Coffee said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="17.466666666666665" PS="1.0611111111111111" SM="15">Ebbers is charged with fraud after the collapse of the long-distance phone company he founded.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="17.25" PS="1.5916666666666668" SM="2">The cases will focus public attention again on corporate misbehavior, Coffee said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="13.35" PS="1.0611111111111111" SM="11">But Americans' views of what is reprehensible will be determined by &quot;who goes to prison and for what.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="10.857142857142858" PS="1.5916666666666668" SM="2">Matt Kempner writes for The Atlanta Journal-Constitution.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="1.0" PS="1.0611111111111111" SM="0">E-mail: mkempner@ajc.com</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="16.885714285714286" PS="2.3875" SM="61">Prosecutors rewrote their opening script for the retrial of L. Dennis Kozlowski and Mark H. Swartz on Wednesday, purging the most striking accusations of lavish spending that they had concentrated on during the first trial.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="16.0" PS="1.5916666666666668" SM="50">Instead, prosecutors focused on laying out the core theme of their case, saying the two men, former Tyco executives, had illegally awarded themselves millions of dollars in bonuses and concealed them from the company's board and shareholders.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="15.150943396226415" PS="1.5916666666666668" SM="40">&quot;This case is the story of how two men -- the defendants in this case -- stole $150 million from a company named Tyco and that corporation's owners, its shareholders,&quot; said Owen Heimer, an assistant Manhattan district attorney, in his opening statement in New York State Supreme Court in Manhattan.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="22.5" PS="1.0611111111111111" SM="22">&quot;These defendants ran Tyco, but they did not own Tyco.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="16.836734693877553" PS="1.5916666666666668" SM="73">While the case against Kozlowski and Swartz is very similar to the first trial, the prosecution's new strategy -- conceived after hours of interviews with jurors from the previous trial who criticized their approach as unfocused -- may mean this trial could take on a markedly different tone.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="13.125" PS="1.5916666666666668" SM="24">The prosecution needed no reminder of that trial.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="13.962264150943396" PS="1.0611111111111111" SM="42">The lessons it had learned were already on display: Heimer, a veteran, was added to the prosecution's team and took the lead in opening arguments, while Kenneth Chalifoux, an assistant Manhattan district attorney who presented a meandering and often confusing opening during the first trial, looked on from the prosecution's table.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="17.714285714285715" PS="1.5916666666666668" SM="11">Lawyers for Kozlowski and Swartz are scheduled to present their opening arguments on Thursday.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="10.823529411764707" PS="1.5916666666666668" SM="22">Heimer spent much of his presentation arguing that Kozlowski and Swartz had intended to commit a crime.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="16.35483870967742" PS="1.0611111111111111" SM="18">In the last trial, at least one juror said she had been prepared to acquit on all charges because she could not find that the men had the requisite criminal intent.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="16.285714285714285" PS="1.0611111111111111" SM="14">Many other jurors said they, too, had wrestled with the issue of criminal intent.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="12.222222222222221" PS="1.0611111111111111" SM="13">Heimer repeatedly spoke to the jury of a process he described as &quot;instruct, deceive and conceal.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="15.347826086956522" PS="1.5916666666666668" SM="14">He said he would show evidence that the men had instructed their subordinates to forgive loans, deceived the subordinates by telling them the bonuses had been approved by the board and then had concealed the payments from the board and the public by not disclosing them.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="16.64" PS="1.5916666666666668" SM="6">Heimer said the men had also paid their subordinates unapproved bonuses &quot;because they were buying the employees' loyalty and buying the employees' silence.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="14.055555555555555" PS="2.525" SM="29">The two former top executives of Tyco International Ltd. stole $150 million from the industrial conglomerate even though they were among the highest-paid people in corporate America, a prosecutor told jurors as their retrial began Wednesday.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="8.416666666666666" PS="1.6833333333333333" SM="36">In a 3 1/2-hour opening argument, assistant Manhattan district attorney Owen Heimer said L. Dennis Kozlowski and Mark Swartz earned almost $300 million in legitimate pay between 1999 and 2001, but took the additional money to finance sumptuous lifestyles that included purchases of lavish apartments and fancy artwork.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="18.772727272727273" PS="1.6833333333333333" SM="0">``This authorized compensation -- as huge as it was -- was just not enough for these two men,'' Heimer said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="18.307692307692307" PS="1.1222222222222222" SM="0">``They had to have more, so they stole another $150 million.''</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="16.19047619047619" PS="1.6833333333333333" SM="50">The first trial of Kozlowski and Swartz ended in mistrial last April after a juror's actions upstaged the legal proceedings.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="11.04" PS="1.6833333333333333" SM="5">The juror, retired teacher Ruth B. Jordan, made a gesture in court that some observers interpreted as an ``OK'' sign to the defendants.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="6.086956521739131" PS="1.1222222222222222" SM="2">Jordan was identified by several news organizations and subsequently received a threatening letter, prompting the judge to declare a mistrial a week later.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="9.692307692307692" PS="1.6833333333333333" SM="3">On Wednesday, Jordan sat in the back row as Heimer finished his presentation.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="15.0625" PS="1.6833333333333333" SM="11">``I'm interested -- that's all,'' Jordan said afterward in explaining her appearance.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="6.142857142857143" PS="1.1222222222222222" SM="0">She indicated that she may attend further court sessions, but would not come regularly.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="18.666666666666668" PS="1.1222222222222222" SM="0">``I've got a life,'' she said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="14.757575757575758" PS="1.6833333333333333" SM="48">Kozlowski, Tyco's former chief executive, and his one-time chief financial officer Swartz are accused of grand larceny, securities fraud and conspiracy in an alleged plot to loot the company and cheat shareholders.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="9.0" PS="1.6833333333333333" SM="3">The men, who have pleaded not guilty, face up to 30 years in prison if convicted.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="7.8" PS="1.6833333333333333" SM="0">Defense attorneys are scheduled to give their opening statements Thursday.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="16.88" PS="1.1222222222222222" SM="17">In the first trial, defense lawyers said the executives' actions were approved by the board, and that living an extravagant lifestyle is not a crime.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="11.1" PS="1.6833333333333333" SM="26">Heimer argued Wednesday that Kozlowski and Swartz committed a range of illegal acts, including drawing huge loans from the company and then instructing underlings to erase them from the books.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="18.96" PS="1.1222222222222222" SM="28">The men told Tyco employees that the board of directors had ``forgiven'' the loans through bonuses even though they hadn't, Heimer said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="15.666666666666666" PS="1.6833333333333333" SM="25">After the first trial, several jurors criticized the Manhattan District Attorney's office for what they saw as an overly lengthy and ponderous presentation.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="16.545454545454547" PS="1.1222222222222222" SM="14">The trial had gone on six months before ending in mistrial.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="7.04" PS="1.6833333333333333" SM="22">Heimer appeared to be cognizant of that Wednesday as he delivered a crisp and methodical argument that focused on seven specific instances of alleged theft.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="12.357142857142858" PS="2.3875" SM="62">NEW YORK - Defense lawyers took a decidedly new approach in their opening arguments in the retrial of L. Dennis Kozlowski and Mark H. Swartz in state Supreme Court on Thursday, lashing out at the former directors of Tyco and attacking their credibility.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="15.2" PS="1.5916666666666668" SM="26">Prosecutors are saying the two men had illegally awarded themselves millions of dollars in bonuses and concealed them from the company's board and shareholders.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="14.472727272727273" PS="1.5916666666666668" SM="56">Lawyers for both defendants, who had appeared to soft-peddle that issue in the first trial, told the jury that the directors' accusations that the two men stole more than $150 million -- the entire basis of the prosecution's case -- is part of a self-serving strategy by directors to protect themselves from shareholder lawsuits.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="19.02857142857143" PS="1.5916666666666668" SM="47">&quot;The directors are concerned about their pocketbook,&quot; Kozlowski's lawyer, Stephen Kaufman, said, calling their contention that they had never approved millions of dollars of bonuses for the men &quot;revisionist history.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="11.533333333333333" PS="1.0611111111111111" SM="11">Raising his voice, Kaufman added: &quot;If Dennis can be blamed, that helps them.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="15.869565217391305" PS="1.5916666666666668" SM="14">Swartz's lawyer, Charles Stillman, applied the same theme, telling jurors, &quot;You need to decide who is telling you the truth.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="8.238095238095237" PS="1.0611111111111111" SM="12">But in a revealing moment, Stillman also appeared to divulge a strategy shift, one that could ultimately pit Swartz against Kozlowski.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="16.047619047619047" PS="1.0611111111111111" SM="17">At the end of his presentation, Stillman told the jury, &quot;You must consider the evidence for each man separately.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="12.9" PS="1.5916666666666668" SM="19">That statement is a departure from the strategy that defense teams used in the first trial in which both appeared to approach the case with an all-for-one and one-for-all policy.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="17.035714285714285" PS="1.0611111111111111" SM="33">Indeed, throughout Stillman's presentation Thursday, he constantly referred to Swartz individually and rarely mentioned Kozlowski's unless he was making the case that Swartz was his subordinate.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="21.05" PS="1.5916666666666668" SM="21">Before the first trial and the retrial, Swartz had sought to separate the cases, but the judge refused the requests.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="16.0" PS="1.0611111111111111" SM="27">Still, Stillman's remarks were the first time he seemed to try to distance Swartz from Kozlowski, despite the fact that both men are charged with nearly all the same crimes.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="19.942857142857143" PS="1.0611111111111111" SM="53">The shift may be the result of interviews with jurors from the first trial, who said that they liked Swartz, who testified in the first trial, better than they liked Kozlowski, who did not testify.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="10.727272727272727" PS="1.5916666666666668" SM="25">One issue that both defense teams did agree on was to make the issue of criminal intent a part of their presentations.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="14.78125" PS="1.0611111111111111" SM="19">In the first trial, which ended in a mistrial, at least one juror said she was planning to acquit the men because she could not find that the defendants had criminal intent.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="12.909090909090908" PS="1.5916666666666668" SM="34">Kozlowski's lawyer, Kaufman, spoke in front of a projection screen that said &quot;Good Faith Belief Equals No Criminal Intent.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="19.12" PS="1.5916666666666668" SM="17">&quot;The facts are that every penny that my client earned was on the books and records of the company he headed,&quot; he said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="13.444444444444445" PS="1.0611111111111111" SM="22">&quot;Dennis never committed any act of concealment.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="20.0" PS="1.5916666666666668" SM="3">&quot;Criminals act in criminal ways,&quot; Kaufman said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="12.928571428571429" PS="1.0611111111111111" SM="3">&quot;Does this strike you as a criminal acting in a criminal way?&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="11.655172413793103" PS="1.5916666666666668" SM="4">Stillman, who stood next to a placard with a similar message about criminal intent, also told the jury, &quot;Mark had no criminal intent because his intentions were honest.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="12.571428571428571" PS="1.0611111111111111" SM="1">No criminal intent means no crime.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="14.095238095238095" PS="1.5916666666666668" SM="5">Jurors in the retrial, which is expected to last about four months, are expected to hear the first testimony on Monday.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="13.925" PS="1.5916666666666668" SM="64">Rebutting each of the accusations the prosecution made on Wednesday during its opening argument, Stillman also sought to dissuade the jury from putting any stock in one of the prosecution's main pieces of evidence, the company's board minutes.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="15.04" PS="1.0611111111111111" SM="31">The prosecution said it plans to show that the board approved none of the bonuses paid to Kozlowski and Swartz and documented in the minutes.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="18.61111111111111" PS="1.0611111111111111" SM="2">Stillman said the minutes &quot;cannot be relied on to prove anything&quot; because they are incomplete.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="13.478260869565217" PS="1.0611111111111111" SM="13">He went on to say that he planned to prove that &quot;the directors kept no minutes for half of their meetings.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="9.222222222222221" PS="1.0611111111111111" SM="12">He added, &quot;You will hear of meeting in which important decisions were made and no minutes.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="13.85" PS="1.5916666666666668" SM="4">As he closed, Stillman told the jury to pay attention to what the directors actually did, not what they said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="14.23076923076923" PS="1.0611111111111111" SM="0">&quot;My mother taught me actions speak louder than words,&quot; he said.</sentence>
	</Sentences>
</Topic>
