<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<Topic id="D0926E">
	<Sentences>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="7.714285714285714" PS="2.25" SM="1">Kansas town basks in glow og GlobalFlyer</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="2.6666666666666665" PS="1.5" SM="0">By LAURA BAUER</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="15.24" PS="1.5" SM="5">The Kansas City Star SALINA, Kan. -- Anytime Jeff Palmer hears a plane overhead, he peers out the front window of Mr. G's Market.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="28.387096774193548" PS="1.5" SM="17">&quot;I look to see if it's the GlobalFlyer,&quot; says Palmer, who from behind the store counter demonstrates how he bends down and tilts his head toward the sky.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="20.714285714285715" PS="1.5" SM="16">For more than two weeks the store cashier has been peering out this window, hoping to get a glimpse of the cutting-edge plane designed to break yet another aviation record for millionaire adventurer Steve Fossett.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="19.310344827586206" PS="1.5" SM="29">Having already shattered records in a hot-air balloon and a glider, Fossett hopes to soon become the first to make a solo, nonstop flight around the world without refueling.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="22.023809523809526" PS="1.5" SM="32">As early as next Sunday, the first window of opportunity, Palmer should get a pretty good look at the plane as Fossett and the Virgin Atlantic team attempt the feat from the Salina airport, less than a mile from Mr. G's.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="21.952380952380953" PS="1.5" SM="26">The team was attracted to the central Kansas town and its airport for the extra-long runway and newly renovated hangar 703.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="19.59375" PS="1.5" SM="23">It's inside hangar 703 where the GlobalFlyer, with its 114-feet wing span and 13 gas tanks, has been housed and worked on since it arrived from Mojave, Calif., on Jan. 6.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="21.64864864864865" PS="1.5" SM="19">While the team waits for good weather around the world, constantly measuring barometric pressures and monitoring jet streams, residents are preparing for what they say is their town's best bet to get into the history books.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="13.703703703703704" PS="1.5" SM="24">Employees at the Holiday Inn are ready to roll out their red carpet -- literally -- for the hordes of international and national reporters and television crews.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="16.785714285714285" PS="1.0" SM="2">The hotel bar is concocting a special GlobalFlyer drink, with ingredients not yet revealed.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="22.78787878787879" PS="1.5" SM="9">&quot;It'll be like the flight,&quot; says smiling Holiday Inn sales manager Gala Bloyd, referring to how the details of the mission are kept under wraps until closer to the departure.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="32.75" PS="1.0" SM="2">&quot;We'll announce that (the ingredients) when they take off.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="16.071428571428573" PS="1.5" SM="13">The welcome parties are planned for people like Virgin Atlantic's chairman, Sir Richard Branson, and town leaders have scheduled tours to introduce Salina to an international audience.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="7.769230769230769" PS="1.0" SM="0">Hundreds of volunteers are lined up to make sure guests are treated right.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="16.837209302325583" PS="1.5" SM="15">&quot;This gives us the opportunity to introduce our visitors here to what this community is all about,&quot; says Gerald Cook, president of the Salina Area Chamber of Commerce, who has already fielded questions from reporters in New York, London and Italy.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="35.81818181818182" PS="1.0" SM="11">&quot;It's a show and tell, if you will.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="22.772727272727273" PS="1.5" SM="24">But before all that, and before Fossett hits the sky for what could be up to an 80-hour flight, some preparations remain.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="20.225" PS="1.0" SM="50">For Fossett, the crews from Virgin Atlantic and Scaled Composites (which designed and built the plane) and the Kansas State University Airway Science students who've become an integral part of the mission, there's a lot of unfinished business.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="17.423076923076923" PS="1.5" SM="13">When officials with Virgin Atlantic came to look at the Salina airport facilities and runway, which measures 12,300 feet long, they visited Salina's K-State campus.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="24.416666666666668" PS="1.0" SM="13">The location's main focus is its College of Technology and Aviation.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="24.956521739130434" PS="1.5" SM="18">By that time Salina officials knew there was a good probability the town would be the location for the launch and the landing.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="21.40909090909091" PS="1.0" SM="4">But they had no idea where the flight would be controlled from, or in more technical terms, where Mission Control would be.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="23.19047619047619" PS="1.5" SM="3">&quot;It could have been in London, Hong Kong, anywhere,&quot; says Tim Rogers, executive director of the Salina Airport Authority.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="30.47826086956522" PS="1.0" SM="4">But &quot;when they saw the campus facility, immediately the light came on for Virgin Atlantic staffers, 'This is ideal for Mission Control.'</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="125.0" PS="1.0" SM="0">&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="14.90625" PS="1.5" SM="16">Shortly after the announcement was made that the entire mission would take place in Salina, school officials got in touch with several Airway Science students -- aspiring professional pilots and airplane mechanics.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="20.0" PS="1.0" SM="2">From there, 12 students were hand-picked to help on the mission.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="8.666666666666666" PS="1.5" SM="10">They thought they would run a few errands, do minor research and, if they were lucky, pick up valuable knowledge from seasoned aviation professionals.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="15.947368421052632" PS="1.5" SM="27">Monica Chester, a senior from Phillipsburg in the professional pilot program, laughs now as she and three other students describe how they are instead helping map the mission's flight plan by researching weather patterns and jet streams.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="15.333333333333334" PS="1.5" SM="24">And the eight aviation mechanics students are helping improve and repair the plane to ensure a successful mission.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="28.615384615384617" PS="1.5" SM="1">&quot;It's definitely not a stand-back-and-see-how-it's-done kind of job,&quot; Chester says.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="42.7" PS="1.0" SM="11">&quot;It's step up and get it done.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="20.82608695652174" PS="1.5" SM="8">Under the supervision of Philip Grassa, the crew chief from Scaled Composites, the aviation mechanics students work nearly every day on the plane.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="19.0" PS="1.0" SM="3">After a test flight, the students helped repair a valve that was causing trouble with cabin pressure.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="32.333333333333336" PS="1.5" SM="7">Earlier last week the students installed the flight tires on the plane.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="21.928571428571427" PS="1.0" SM="4">The tires were new, but the tread was shaved down to save on weight.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="29.642857142857142" PS="1.5" SM="2">&quot;They didn't think they'd get to work on the airplane as an actual mechanic,&quot; says Grassa, who has worked on GlobalFlyer for two years.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="38.09090909090909" PS="1.0" SM="0">&quot;They thought they'd be running errands for me.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="35.888888888888886" PS="1.5" SM="0">Grassa hollers, &quot;How we doing over there?&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="19.4" PS="1.0" SM="8">to a small group working on a shield to go over the flight controls in the back of the cabin.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="12.5" PS="1.5" SM="13">After offering a suggestion of where to put glue, Grassa was back to talking about the students and how they have been integral in helping get GlobalFlyer ready.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="40.8125" PS="1.5" SM="2">&quot;This is basically my adopted crew for the preparation for this mission,&quot; Grassa says.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="18.22222222222222" PS="1.5" SM="24">Some of the students get wide eyes as they talk about working with Scaled Composites employees and with Fossett -- whom senior Seth Short from Burrton describes as &quot;your grandpa in real good physical shape.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="41.375" PS="1.0" SM="1">He's as nice as can be.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="22.875" PS="1.5" SM="0">As Chester puts it: &quot;We hoped we'd get to meet him, but now we're on a first-name basis with him.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="22.38095238095238" PS="1.5" SM="11">For the students in the professional pilot program, their work is in front of the computer calculating fluctuations in the weather.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="19.84" PS="1.0" SM="6">They balance the benefits of flying at high altitudes where the jet engine is more efficient versus lower where a plane gets the best winds.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="15.6" PS="1.5" SM="2">Short explains how the weather needs to be just right.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="27.176470588235293" PS="1.5" SM="10">&quot;We're looking for cold weather, high barometric pressure and favorable jet stream,&quot; says Short.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="26.153846153846153" PS="1.0" SM="1">&quot;He can't take off in any precipitation that would freeze.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="3.727272727272727" PS="1.5" SM="1">Another pilot student, Nancy Milleret of Tonganoxie, jumps in to interpret.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="27.93103448275862" PS="1.5" SM="9">&quot;You don't want ice on the plane,&quot; says the junior who is used to breaking down aviation talk to the students she guides in the air.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="63.0" PS="1.0" SM="0">&quot;Ice is bad.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="27.818181818181817" PS="1.5" SM="3">That's because the plane is not equipped with de-icing gear.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="17.857142857142858" PS="1.0" SM="2">That would add weight to the plane.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="24.428571428571427" PS="1.0" SM="14">And for a trip around the world without refueling, extra weight is also bad.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="17.142857142857142" PS="1.5" SM="4">Student Pat Rinearson of Olathe explains why the plane needs the favorable jet stream.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="41.0" PS="1.5" SM="2">&quot;He wants the tail winds,&quot; Rinearson says.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="34.857142857142854" PS="1.0" SM="2">&quot;The jet stream moves every minute.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="28.44" PS="1.0" SM="15">What we're trying to do is figure out where it is and average what the tail wind component will be through the flight.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="22.142857142857142" PS="1.5" SM="2">The plane will travel east to west.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="15.588235294117647" PS="1.0" SM="4">It doesn't have enough gas to make the 20,000-nautical-mile trip without the benefit of tail winds.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="27.333333333333332" PS="1.0" SM="0">As Milleret explains: &quot;West to east, he wouldn't make it.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="34.25" PS="1.0" SM="2">He'd be going against the wind.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="17.75" PS="1.5" SM="24">Whatever the students come up with in their research and calculations, they often show to Fossett.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="32.357142857142854" PS="1.5" SM="3">&quot;What we put into the computer, Steve looks at that,&quot; Short says.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="27.904761904761905" PS="1.0" SM="12">&quot;When we come up with a flight plan, we show it to Steve and he says, 'Explain it to me.'</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="125.0" PS="1.0" SM="0">&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="17.9" PS="1.5" SM="14">As the students work, the town and nearby residents wait.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="32.0" PS="1.5" SM="2">The No.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="30.153846153846153" PS="1.0" SM="2">1 question airport director Rogers gets: &quot;Can we see the airplane?&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="19.25" PS="1.5" SM="4">Looks like Palmer isn't the only one disappointed that there has been no general public viewing of the plane.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="25.225806451612904" PS="1.5" SM="7">&quot;It's the question everyone has,&quot; says Rogers, who has watched the airport's Web site go from 500 hits a day to 20,000 because of interest in GlobalFlyer.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="26.296296296296298" PS="1.5" SM="18">Rogers says that &quot;time is the most critical part of the process&quot; and taking time out to show the airplane would hurt the preparation phase.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="24.58823529411765" PS="1.5" SM="2">&quot;Once I've had the opportunity to explain that, individuals seem to understand,&quot; Rogers says.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="16.75" PS="1.5" SM="14">On the day of departure and landing, the airport can accommodate as many as 30,000 spectators.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="22.55" PS="1.0" SM="14">Two areas have been set up, one on the north side and one at the south, for people to watch.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="9.444444444444445" PS="1.5" SM="2">Some still think the residents deserve a special viewing.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="21.387096774193548" PS="1.5" SM="12">&quot;You'd think they should just fly over the town someday,&quot; says Dustin Forsberg, 23, as he sat outside Cozy Inn Hamburgers with his brother Derek and a friend.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="31.0" PS="1.0" SM="0">&quot;Just as a 'Thanks for letting us be here.'</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="125.0" PS="1.0" SM="0">&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="27.37037037037037" PS="1.5" SM="19">Others say that while having the flight take off and land in Salina is exciting, it's what the mission does for the town that beats all.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="22.555555555555557" PS="1.5" SM="18">Cook, the chamber president, estimates the town has already benefited from &quot;millions of dollars&quot; in advertising -- and the plane still sits in hangar 703.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="30.607142857142858" PS="1.5" SM="6">&quot;It's going to put Salina on the map,&quot; says aviation student Samuel Butler, originally from Cleveland, as he stands outside the town's municipal airport.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="40.5" PS="1.0" SM="1">&quot;That's what I like about it.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="1.0" PS="1.0" SM="0">...</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="51.5" PS="1.0" SM="1">It's history.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="2.375" PS="1.5" SM="0">To reach Laura Bauer, send e-mail to lbauerkcstar.com.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="43.857142857142854" PS="2.433673469387755" SM="14">Steve Fossett is waiting on the wind.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="23.514285714285716" PS="1.6224489795918369" SM="12">With all preparations complete for a solo, non-stop flight  around the globe, the only thing standing in the way of the  legendary adventurers next attempt to set a world record is an  uncooperative jet stream.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="34.92307692307692" PS="1.6224489795918369" SM="1">&quot;It's never been an exact science,&quot; said spokeswoman Anna  Burdsall.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="30.61111111111111" PS="1.0816326530612246" SM="34">&quot;There are two different weather systems we're dealing  with -- the ground weather in Salinas, that's one consideration, and  the other is the weather and the jet stream going around the  world.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="19.956521739130434" PS="1.6224489795918369" SM="5">The launch of the Virgin Atlantic GlobalFlyer has been delayed a  number of times since it arrived in Salinas, Kansas, on January 7.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="23.5" PS="1.6224489795918369" SM="4">The light-bodied aircraft relies on prevailing winds, or the jet  stream, to help push it along its journey.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="23.17391304347826" PS="1.0816326530612246" SM="2">But it needs to avoid the  jet stream until it reaches its cruising altitude or else it could  be damaged by heavy turbulence.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="22.16216216216216" PS="1.6224489795918369" SM="21">A February 2 launch was cancelled because the jet stream moved  too far north, which meant Fossett would lose too much fuel catching  up to it to make it the rest of the way around the world.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="9.851851851851851" PS="1.6224489795918369" SM="34">The February 6 and February 8 launches were cancelled because  the jet stream moved too close to Kansas and created a situation of  heavy wind and turbulence.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="26.0" PS="1.6224489795918369" SM="23">So Fossett and his crew have remained on high alert, waiting for  the perfect weather conditions.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="19.11111111111111" PS="1.0816326530612246" SM="2">The next potential launch date is  late next week.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="24.28125" PS="1.6224489795918369" SM="8">&quot;Everyone within the project team understands how these type of  projects work,&quot; said Burdsall, who described the mood of the 30-plus  people working on the project as one of anticipation.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="13.3" PS="1.6224489795918369" SM="12">The project brings together three giants of aviation and  adventure.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="22.1" PS="1.6224489795918369" SM="43">Fossett has set dozens of world records and world firsts with  jet airplanes and gliders, hot air balloons and sailing.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="16.375" PS="1.0816326530612246" SM="9">The  American millionaire became famous in the mid 1990s when he made a  number of attempts with British entrepreneur Sir Richard Branson to  fly around the globe in a hot air balloon.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="27.5" PS="1.6224489795918369" SM="4">Branson, whose company Virgin Atlantic Airways is funding the  GlobalFlyer, is acting as the reserve pilot.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="16.90909090909091" PS="1.6224489795918369" SM="15">The British businessman has also set a number of sailing and  aviation records in his own right while promoting the Virgin brand.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="30.90909090909091" PS="1.0816326530612246" SM="13">He will monitor Fossett's progress from mission control in Salinas.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="27.40625" PS="1.6224489795918369" SM="5">The GlobalFlyer was designed by Burt Rutan, who recently made  headlines when his SpaceShipOne won the 10-million-dollar &quot;X Prize&quot;  for sending a privately-designed craft into space twice in two  weeks.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="22.87878787878788" PS="1.6224489795918369" SM="18">Rutan also designed the Voyager, which was used by his brother  Dick Rutan and Jeanne Yeager in 1986 to set a record of nine days  for a non-stop, non-refueled flight around the world.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="27.0" PS="1.6224489795918369" SM="22">Fossett hopes to beat that record by making it in less than 80  hours, and by doing it on his own.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="38.0" PS="1.6224489795918369" SM="16">&quot;The first solo non-stop is a grand endeavour,&quot; Fossett said in  an interview on the GlobalFlyer Web site.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="21.975" PS="1.6224489795918369" SM="24">&quot;This will require all of my abilities as a pilot, it will test  my endurance, and it will demonstrate the finest in lightweight  aircraft construction and improvements in jet engine fuel efficiency  that have never before been achieved.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="18.17391304347826" PS="1.6224489795918369" SM="5">The 3,350-pound (1,522-kilogram) single engine aircraft will  carry nearly 19,000 pounds (8,636 kilograms) of fuel in 13 tanks for  the 23,000-mile (37,260-kilometer) journey.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="11.928571428571429" PS="1.6224489795918369" SM="25">Some of the major cities Fossett expects to pass along the way  are Chicago, Toronto, London, Paris, Rome, Cairo, Bahrain, Karachi,  Calcutta, Shanghai, Tokyo, Honolulu and Los Angeles.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="20.6" PS="1.6224489795918369" SM="22">Virgin is looking for people with high powered telescopes to  operate as spotters and take pictures and video of the plane as it  flies overhead at 45,000 feet (13,636 meters).</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="26.884615384615383" PS="2.25" SM="26">Facts and figures about the Virgin  Atlantic GlobalFlyer, which is scheduled to take off from Salina,  Kansas, on Monday with American Steve Fossett at the controls:</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="31.0" PS="1.5" SM="2">The goal:</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="29.75" PS="1.5" SM="5">- a solo, non-stop, non-refueled flight around the world.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="37.5" PS="1.5" SM="2">The journey:</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="9.75" PS="1.5" SM="10">- estimated travel time: between 70 and 80 hours.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="10.55" PS="1.5" SM="4">- distance traveled: must be more than 36,787.559 kilometers  (equal in length to the Tropic of Cancer) or around 23,000 miles</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="13.346153846153847" PS="1.5" SM="25">- some of the major cities Fossett will pass along the way:  Chicago, Toronto, London, Paris, Rome, Cairo, Bahrain, Karachi,  Calcutta, Shanghai, Tokyo, Honolulu and Los Angeles.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="7.909090909090909" PS="1.5" SM="0">- estimated speed: 250 knots (285 miles per hour/460 kilometers  per hour)</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="21.058823529411764" PS="1.5" SM="1">- flying altitude: 45,000 feet or 13,000 meters (typical  altitude for commercial flights is 33,000 to 37,000 feet)</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="39.0" PS="1.5" SM="2">The aircraft:</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="22.64516129032258" PS="1.5" SM="4">- designed by Burt Rutan's California-based Scaled Composites,  which recently won the 10 million dollar &quot;X Prize&quot; for sending a  privately-designed three-person craft into space twice in two  weeks.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="17.483870967741936" PS="1.5" SM="24">- the seven-foot-long (2.1-meter-long) pressurized cabin is  equipped with a reclining carbon fiber seat so low that Fossett will  need to sit on pillows in order to see for takeoff and landing.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="1.0" PS="1.5" SM="0">Specifications:</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="7.666666666666667" PS="1.5" SM="0">- Wing Span: 114 feet (35 meters)</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="8.0" PS="1.5" SM="0">- Length: 44.1 feet (13.41 meters)</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="7.8" PS="1.5" SM="0">- Height: 13.3 feet (4.0 meters)</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="4.666666666666667" PS="1.5" SM="0">- Gross Weight: 22,000 pounds (10,000 kilograms)</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="4.833333333333333" PS="1.5" SM="0">- Empty Weight: 3,350 pounds (1,522 kilograms)</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="11.6" PS="1.5" SM="0">- Number of fuel tanks: 13</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="15.8" PS="1.5" SM="0">- Percentage of weight at take-off that is fuel: 83 percent</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="17.8" PS="1.5" SM="6">- Engine: Williams FJ44-3 ATW, located above the aft fuselage on  the top of the wing</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="14.947368421052632" PS="1.5" SM="22">- Flight controls: all flight controls are mechanically actuated  using cables, push pull tubes and bellcranks and are fully  reversible.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="21.387096774193548" PS="2.25" SM="22">One hundred one years after the Wright brothers ushered in the age of powered flight, Steve Fossett is ready to tackle what may be the last great challenge in world aviation.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="10.2" PS="1.5" SM="0">From Kansas, not Kitty Hawk.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="12.048780487804878" PS="1.5" SM="24">Weather permitting, the 60-year-old millionaire will take off from the Salina, Kan., municipal airport today and be back three days later, by way of Montreal; London; Paris; Rome; Cairo, Egypt; Bahrain; Karachi, Pakistan; Calcutta, India; Shanghai; Tokyo; Honolulu; and Los Angeles.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="25.0" PS="1.5" SM="0">There will be no stops.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="7.0" PS="1.0" SM="0">No refueling.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="26.72222222222222" PS="1.0" SM="31">And not much sleep for Fossett, who will be wedged in the 7 foot cockpit of a veritable flying fuel tank as he attempts the first solo flight around the world on one tank of gas.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="16.82758620689655" PS="1.5" SM="19">If he's successful, Fossett will earn a place in history alongside aviator Wiley Post, who circled the globe alone in 1933 in a single-engine airplane, the Winnie Mae.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="6.8" PS="1.0" SM="10">Post made 11 stops and took just under eight8 days.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="42.57142857142857" PS="1.5" SM="15">&quot;Flying around the world has always been a great adventure,&quot; Fossett says.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="33.0" PS="1.0" SM="11">&quot;I hope to make it with no stops and in under 80 hours.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="30.625" PS="1.5" SM="1">It won't be his first around-the-world flight.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="13.416666666666666" PS="1.0" SM="16">In 2002, he became the first person to solo the globe in a balloon -- a 14-day odyssey, which began and ended in Australia.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="33.6" PS="1.0" SM="0">It was his sixth attempt.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="33.5" PS="1.5" SM="15">The solo aspect of the record is important to Fossett.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="32.0" PS="1.5" SM="2">&quot;Ninety-one people flew across the Atlantic before (Charles) LIndbergh did,&quot; he says.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="26.62962962962963" PS="1.0" SM="18">&quot;The hallmarks of aviation are that solo flights are ranked higher than crew flights just because of the difficulty and the level of self-reliance required.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="29.97142857142857" PS="1.5" SM="12">He may be flying solo, but he will be supported by more than 40 engineers, meteorologists and pilots at Salina &quot;mission control&quot; who will advise him by radio as he circles the globe.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="36.42857142857143" PS="1.0" SM="11">A network of amateur spotters will report &quot;Fossett sightings&quot; as he travels.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="21.928571428571427" PS="1.0" SM="13">And a chase plane will rendezvous with him several times during the three-day flight.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="24.806451612903224" PS="1.5" SM="17">Fossett, who made his fortune as a trader on the Chicago Board Options Exchange, is the most visible of three aviation giants who have pooled their talents for the record attempt.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="24.38095238095238" PS="1.5" SM="29">Virgin Atlantic Airways founder and chairman Richard Branson, himself an avid balloonist, is funding the $2.5 million project, which he calls &quot;the last great aviation record inside the Earth's atmosphere and the first great aviation achievement of this century.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="6.888888888888889" PS="1.5" SM="0">Branson, whose $2.2 billion net worth makes him No.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="24.0" PS="1.0" SM="6">247 on Forbes' list of the world's richest people, isn't fretting about the cost.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="28.454545454545453" PS="1.0" SM="3">Besides, he says the flight will demonstrate technology that will help develop &quot;a new generation of more fuel-efficient commercial aircraft.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="20.170731707317074" PS="1.5" SM="14">The airplane is decked out in the red-and-white livery of Branson's airline, but the craft is the brainchild of aviation design genius Burt Rutan, whose SpaceShipOne last year became the first privately built craft to reach the edge of space.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="19.785714285714285" PS="1.0" SM="4">Rutan won the $10 million Ansari X Prize for the advancement of space tourism.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="19.17142857142857" PS="1.5" SM="31">The Virgin Atlantic Global Flyer -- first sketched by Rutan on the back of a napkin in 1999 -- is undoubtedly one of the strangest-looking flying machines ever to take wing over the Kansas heartland.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="15.272727272727273" PS="1.5" SM="3">Built by Rutan's Scaled Composites of Mojave, Calif., it consists of two 44-foot lightweight carbon fiber torpedoes joined at the hip.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="13.642857142857142" PS="1.0" SM="13">A cigar-shaped cockpit is suspended between, with a single jet engine -- a modified turbofan like those used in corporate jets -- mounted above and behind the cockpit.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="18.857142857142858" PS="1.0" SM="13">Fossett has to sit on padded cushions to see out of the bubble-like canopy.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="21.954545454545453" PS="1.5" SM="4">The design is so aerodynamically perfect that the plane has to deploy two drogue parachutes to help it descend for a landing.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="20.4" PS="1.0" SM="4">With a 114-foot wing span that makes it 2 1/2 times wider than it is long, however, the contraption looks like it might have trouble just getting off the ground.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="15.272727272727273" PS="1.5" SM="3">Taking off may, in fact, be one of the toughest challenges.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="18.066666666666666" PS="1.0" SM="2">Fully loaded, the plane carries 3,000 gallons of jet fuel, six times its own weight.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="9.5" PS="1.0" SM="1">Commercial airliners carry less than half their weight in fuel.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="16.0" PS="1.5" SM="6">At takeoff, because so much fuel is stored in the plane's hollow wings, they will droop to within 3 feet of the runway -- meaning any sudden gust of wind could become an adventure-ending disaster.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="32.2" PS="1.5" SM="13">&quot;It's an experimental aircraft with such lightweight construction there's a risk of structural failure,&quot; Fossett says.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="34.476190476190474" PS="1.0" SM="4">&quot;The first time it flies with a full load of fuel will be when I take off on the mission.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="30.727272727272727" PS="1.0" SM="2">If I miscalculate, I will run right into the cornfields.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="27.5" PS="1.5" SM="17">The dicey aspects of the takeoff are one reason Fossett chose the Salina airport.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="16.70967741935484" PS="1.0" SM="34">Its 12,300-foot runway and a 1,300-foot overrun -- built when it was Schilling Air Force Base -- provide plenty of room for the Global Flyer to get up to takeoff speed.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="20.95" PS="1.5" SM="14">Once he is airborne, Fossett intends to climb to around 50,000 feet, well above the altitude flown by commercial traffic.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="28.181818181818183" PS="1.0" SM="10">The plane will be so heavy early in the flights that he'll have to avoid the turbulence of the jet stream.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="25.652173913043477" PS="1.5" SM="17">As the plane's fuel load lightens, however, the jet stream will play a major role in whether Fossett will make it home.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="16.90909090909091" PS="1.0" SM="26">As he crosses Europe, the Middle East, Asia and the Pacific Ocean, he hopes to use the tailwind to add an average of 70 miles to his ground speed and increase his range.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="15.595238095238095" PS="1.5" SM="34">The Global Flyer carries only enough fuel to cover 20,000 miles in still air -- a good 3,000 miles short of the 36,787.559-kilometer minimum distance required for the arbiter of world aviation records, the Paris-based Federation Aeronautique Internationale, to recognize the feat.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="27.666666666666668" PS="1.5" SM="21">But Fossett has another reason for using a midcontinent location for his takeoff and return.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="19.636363636363637" PS="1.0" SM="2">In the final hours, he'll be running close to empty.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="22.852941176470587" PS="1.5" SM="6">&quot;If I run out of fuel in the last thousand miles, I will be able to glide to a safe landing at almost any airport in the western United States,&quot; he says.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="26.941176470588236" PS="1.0" SM="3">&quot;If I had chosen a West Coast airport, I would risk ditching in the Pacific.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="19.923076923076923" PS="1.5" SM="28">So critical is the jet stream to Fossett's ambitions -- both as an early obstacle and a late-in-the-game friend -- that the flight has already been delayed more than two weeks in hopes of a more favorable alignment.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="18.58823529411765" PS="1.5" SM="4">Although the plane has been ready to fly since Feb. 2, the weather has prompted several delays.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="23.454545454545453" PS="1.0" SM="38">A meteorological &quot;go&quot; requires the proper speed and course of winds aloft, the right local weather (cold and calm) for the absence of any major storms along Fossett's planned route.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="24.045454545454547" PS="1.5" SM="13">&quot;Looking at the behavior of the jet stream over the last five5 or 10 years, things only line up the way we need them about 50 percent of the time,&quot; says David Dehenauw, a Belgian meteorologist doing long-range forecasting for the flight.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="24.333333333333332" PS="1.5" SM="29">The Global Flyer won't be the first airplane to circle the world without refueling.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="12.15" PS="1.0" SM="15">Voyager, an earlier Rutan creation that now hangs in the Smithsonian's Air and Space Museum, did that in 1986.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="16.0" PS="1.5" SM="11">But Voyager had two pilots, Burt Rutan's older brother Richard Rutan and pilot Jeana Yeager.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="12.588235294117647" PS="1.0" SM="10">It also had two engines and a speed that averaged a little over 100 miles an hour.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="21.146341463414632" PS="1.0" SM="18">Because it couldn't fly high enough to make use of the jet stream, the flight took nine days -- and nearly failed when it had to be rerouted due to Libya's refusal to let the plane enter its airspace.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="25.68421052631579" PS="1.5" SM="14">Unlike his marathon balloon flights, which have allowed time for napping, Fossett -- cruising at nearly 300 miles an hour -- will have to stay awake for most, if not all, of the 80 hours he is airborne.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="21.681818181818183" PS="1.5" SM="18">But as a precaution, the plane also carries a control system that would maintain the course in the event Fossett nods off.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="27.666666666666668" PS="1.5" SM="12">Fossett hasn't said publicly what he'll do if he doesn't make it, but his earlier balloon flights have made it clear that he doesn't quit easily.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="17.641025641025642" PS="1.5" SM="17">His successful around-the-world flight in 2002 was his sixth attempt in eight years -- including one flight that ended in a near disaster when a thunderstorm shredded his balloon and he had to ditch off the coast of Australia.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="20.666666666666668" PS="1.0" SM="10">He was picked up by a passing yacht -- and promptly began making preparations for his next attempt.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="20.857142857142858" PS="1.5" SM="2">Mike Toner writes for The Atlanta Journal-Constitution.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="1.3333333333333333" PS="1.0" SM="0">E-mail: mtoner@ajc.com</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="32.55882352941177" PS="2.3418367346938775" SM="24">The early stages of American  adventurer Steve Fossett's bid to make the first solo non-stop  flight around the world without refueling aboard the GlobalFlyer  have gone &quot;exactly as planned&quot;, organizers said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="23.305555555555557" PS="1.5612244897959184" SM="21">&quot;Mission control has spoken with Steve and he reports that  everything is working well and that he is extremely pleased with  progress so far,&quot; project manager Paul Moore told a press briefing  late Monday.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="14.666666666666666" PS="1.5612244897959184" SM="12">After weeks of weather delays, the GlobalFlyer took off at 6:47  pm (0047 GMT Tuesday) from Salina Municipal Airport on a journey  expected to last between 60 and 80 hours.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="17.076923076923077" PS="1.5612244897959184" SM="28">Hundreds of spectators lined the tarmac and cheered as the  aircraft, heavily laden down by fuel, trundled down the runway and  rose into the darkening sky.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="15.74074074074074" PS="1.5612244897959184" SM="14">There was a brief moment of anxiety when the craft appeared to  lose altitude seconds after taking off, before it regained height  and climbed into the skies.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="18.545454545454547" PS="1.5612244897959184" SM="13">Fossett spoke briefly to reporters before climbing into the  cramped cockpit.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="37.0" PS="1.5612244897959184" SM="0">&quot;I'm feeling good.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="12.75" PS="1.0408163265306123" SM="0">I'm feeling healthy.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="23.77777777777778" PS="1.0408163265306123" SM="11">It's going to be a long  night tonight and a long night tomorrow night,&quot; he said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="27.0" PS="1.5612244897959184" SM="23">The three-day journey will test Fossetts endurance and his  abilities as a pilot.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="19.833333333333332" PS="1.5612244897959184" SM="27">The delicate, light-bodied airplane has been built with very  little margin for complications like turbulence and Fossett will  need to keep a close eye on the fuel distribution to ensure that the  plane remains properly balanced.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="27.814814814814813" PS="1.5612244897959184" SM="32">The greatest potential for structural problems came during the  first two hours of the flight when Fossett maneuvered the plane  through the ground winds and potential turbulence.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="19.205882352941178" PS="1.5612244897959184" SM="5">At takeoff, the 3,350-pound (1,522-kilogram) single engine  aircraft was carrying nearly 19,000 pounds (8,636 kilograms) of fuel  in 13 tanks for the 23,000-mile (37,260-kilometer) journey at  altitudes as high as 52,000 feet (15,850 meters).</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="15.444444444444445" PS="1.5612244897959184" SM="22">Fossett is wearing a chest pack with a parachute and should be  able to bail out in less than two minutes if he encounters any  critical failures.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="15.777777777777779" PS="1.0408163265306123" SM="0">Once he reaches his cruising altitude of about  45,000 feet (13,000 meters) he can expect a smoother ride.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="13.291666666666666" PS="1.5612244897959184" SM="31">By 10:00pm (0400 GMT, Tuesday) Fossett had traveled 1,400  kilometers (869 miles) and was approaching Canadian airspace after  having passed over Chicago and Detroit.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="16.59090909090909" PS="1.0408163265306123" SM="0">He was flying at an altitude  of 38,000 feet (11,580 meters) at an approximate speed of 310 knots  (357 miles per hour).</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="20.210526315789473" PS="1.5612244897959184" SM="15">While in the air, Fossett will be in near-constant contact with  mission control here via a NASA-designed communication system.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="35.05882352941177" PS="1.5612244897959184" SM="14">&quot;It was obviously an emotional moment in that I was standing  with Steve Fossett's wife.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="22.91176470588235" PS="1.0408163265306123" SM="24">It was a dangerous moment and an enormous  relief when it got off the ground and left Salina,&quot; said British  entrepreneur Sir Richard Branson, whose Virgin Atlantic Airways is  funding the daring venture.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="33.76470588235294" PS="1.5612244897959184" SM="0">&quot;Something I never thought I would get to say was 'next stop  Salina,'&quot;  Branson said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="23.03846153846154" PS="1.5612244897959184" SM="27">A chase plane is following Fossett along the route in order to  document the flight and provide support should he be forced into an  early landing.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="20.529411764705884" PS="1.0408163265306123" SM="11">Fossett has been equipped with an emergency beacon  which would alert search-and-rescue teams to his exact position.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="17.555555555555557" PS="1.5612244897959184" SM="24">Fossett has little room to stretch in the 7.7-foot-long  (2.3-meter-long) cabin and will sustain himself with diet  milkshakes.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="32.666666666666664" PS="1.5612244897959184" SM="15">Despite the dangers, Fossett said he is determined to try to  capture the &quot;most important aviation records that have been left  undone.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="57.44444444444444" PS="1.0408163265306123" SM="3">&quot;It's worth the risk,&quot; he said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="13.3" PS="1.5612244897959184" SM="12">The project brings together three giants of aviation and  adventure.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="22.1" PS="1.5612244897959184" SM="43">Fossett has set dozens of world records and world firsts with  jet airplanes and gliders, hot air balloons and sailing.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="16.962962962962962" PS="1.5612244897959184" SM="8">The former stock options trader became famous in the mid 1990s  when he made an attempt with Branson to circumnavigate the globe in  a hot air balloon.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="21.428571428571427" PS="1.0408163265306123" SM="5">He managed the trip solo on his sixth attempt in  the summer of 2002.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="16.36842105263158" PS="1.5612244897959184" SM="13">Branson has set a number of sailing and aviation records in his  own right while promoting the Virgin brand.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="30.90909090909091" PS="1.0408163265306123" SM="13">He will monitor  Fossett's progress from mission control in Salina.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="25.77777777777778" PS="1.5612244897959184" SM="5">The GlobalFlyer was designed by aviation legend Burt Rutan, who  recently made headlines when his SpaceShipOne won the 10 million  dollar &quot;X Prize&quot; for sending a privately-designed craft into space  twice in two weeks.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="22.87878787878788" PS="1.5612244897959184" SM="18">Rutan also designed the Voyager, which was used by his brother  Dick Rutan and Jeanne Yeager in 1986 to set a record of nine days  for a non-stop, non-refueled flight around the world.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="27.0" PS="1.5612244897959184" SM="22">Fossett hopes to beat that record by making it in less than 80  hours, and by doing it on his own.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="22.058823529411764" PS="1.5612244897959184" SM="15">Once he clears the Canadian province of Newfoundland, Fossett  will head across the Atlantic Ocean to Africa.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="9.045454545454545" PS="1.5612244897959184" SM="10">He hopes pass above Casablanca before he continuing on towards  Libya, Egypt, Saudi Arabia, Pakistan, India, Bangladesh, China,  South Korea and Japan.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="21.193548387096776" PS="2.9846938775510203" SM="19">Millionaire adventurer Steve Fossett has taken off on his attempt to become the first person to complete a solo trip around the world in an airplane without making a single stop.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="17.63888888888889" PS="1.9897959183673468" SM="18">Fossett, the first person to circle the globe solo in a balloon, launched his GlobalFlyer from the Salina Municipal Airport shortly before 7 p.m. Monday, beginning a 66-hour journey by climbing northeast into a darkening sky.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="10.333333333333334" PS="1.9897959183673468" SM="4">Hundreds of spectators, braving a bitterly cold wind, gathered along the two-mile (three-kilometer) runway to watch the takeoff.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="21.333333333333332" PS="1.3265306122448979" SM="11">Fossett hoped to return to Salina on Thursday morning.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="19.80952380952381" PS="1.9897959183673468" SM="5">The 23,000-mile (37,000-kilometer) flight had already been postponed several times because of shifting jet stream patterns or weather at the airport.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="30.318181818181817" PS="1.9897959183673468" SM="14">&quot;I'm a bit nervous about takeoff,&quot; said Fossett, 60, who has logged about 30 hours in the jet-powered aircraft.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="42.25" PS="1.3265306122448979" SM="2">&quot;I will be the ultimate test pilot.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="12.714285714285714" PS="1.3265306122448979" SM="0">I have a lot to worry about.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="34.833333333333336" PS="1.3265306122448979" SM="1">It's a major endeavor.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="27.045454545454547" PS="1.9897959183673468" SM="7">Financed by Virgin Atlantic founder Sir Richard Branson, it would be the first solo flight around the world without stopping to refuel.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="33.42857142857143" PS="1.9897959183673468" SM="18">Branson watched the takeoff from the side of the runway with Fossett's wife.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="36.111111111111114" PS="1.3265306122448979" SM="14">&quot;It was obviously an emotional moment and the most dangerous part of the journey,&quot; he said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="39.214285714285715" PS="1.3265306122448979" SM="2">&quot;It was an enormous relief when it actually came off the ground.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="23.555555555555557" PS="1.9897959183673468" SM="11">By late Monday night, Fossett was soaring over Canada.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="29.095238095238095" PS="1.9897959183673468" SM="2">&quot;He was pretty determined to get away,&quot; project manager Paul Moore said at a briefing hours after the takeoff.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="13.875" PS="1.9897959183673468" SM="15">Aviation pioneer Wiley Post made the first solo around-the-world trip in 1933, taking more than seven days and stopping numerous times along the way.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="20.392857142857142" PS="1.3265306122448979" SM="27">The first nonstop global flight without refueling by a duo was made in 1986 by Jeana Yeager and Dick Rutan, brother of Burt Rutan, designer of the GlobalFlyer.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="26.0" PS="1.9897959183673468" SM="16">Besides the nonstop record, Fossett will attempt to break seven other aviation records, including the longest flight by a jet aircraft.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="16.176470588235293" PS="1.3265306122448979" SM="3">The current record is more than 12,000 miles (19,300 kilometers), set by a B-52 bomber in 1962.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="18.454545454545453" PS="1.9897959183673468" SM="23">Mission control director Kevin Stass said Fossett would fly over Chicago, Detroit and Canada before heading across the Atlantic late Monday night.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="16.0" PS="1.3265306122448979" SM="16">The route would then take him over Africa, the Middle East, India, China and the Pacific Ocean.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="19.304347826086957" PS="1.9897959183673468" SM="3">The flight plan was adjusted once more later Monday after Algeria closed a portion of its airspace, mission control director Kevin Stass said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="22.464285714285715" PS="1.3265306122448979" SM="21">The change, he said, would slightly reduce the overall length of the flight and save some of the 18,000 pounds ( 8,100 kilograms) of fuel aboard the single-engine jet.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="20.26086956521739" PS="1.9897959183673468" SM="23">Fossett planned to fly at an average speed of 287.5 mph (462.6 kph) and rely on the jet stream to stretch his fuel.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="26.896551724137932" PS="1.3265306122448979" SM="8">The GlobalFlyer will have about 15 percent extra fuel to allow for weather conditions or other changes to the flight plan, said Jon Karkow, chief engineer for the flight.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="20.72" PS="1.9897959183673468" SM="5">There was a risk the fuel could freeze from flying in the cold at altitudes of 52,000 feet (15,600 meters) for such a long time.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="32.833333333333336" PS="1.9897959183673468" SM="11">Fossett will survive on diet milkshakes.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="35.1764705882353" PS="1.3265306122448979" SM="4">&quot;I just picked a bunch of flavors off the shelf at the store,&quot; he said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="29.047619047619047" PS="1.9897959183673468" SM="29">Branson planned to follow Fossett in a chase plane for the first day of the flight and on the last leg.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="29.666666666666668" PS="1.3265306122448979" SM="14">He gave Fossett his wristwatch, complete with emergency beacon device, to wear for the flight.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="27.529411764705884" PS="1.9897959183673468" SM="15">&quot;We want you and (the watch) back in one piece at the end,&quot; Branson quipped.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="21.28" PS="1.9897959183673468" SM="21">Fossett became the first to fly a balloon solo around the world in 2002 after nearly dying twice in six attempts to set the record.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="17.692307692307693" PS="1.3265306122448979" SM="6">He has also tried to break the world gliding altitude record for the past four years in New Zealand but has failed because of poor conditions.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="1.0" PS="1.9897959183673468" SM="0">___</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="21.666666666666668" PS="1.9897959183673468" SM="2">On the Net:</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="21.37142857142857" PS="2.295918367346939" SM="22">American adventurer Steve  Fossett flew over Africa on Tuesday after battling a series of  equipment problems in the early stages of his bid to make the first  solo non-stop flight around the world without refueling.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="29.195652173913043" PS="1.5306122448979593" SM="28">Fossett, who took off from here in the Virgin Atlantic  GlobalFlyer on Monday for a flight expected to last between 60 and  80 hours, said he had to deal with a number of &quot;dramas,&quot;  particularly during takeoff, but the flight was going well overall.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="21.91304347826087" PS="1.5306122448979593" SM="34">At 1607 GMT, Fossett was at approximately 45,000 feet (13,000  meters) and had been in the air for 15 hours and 20 minutes.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="16.38095238095238" PS="1.0204081632653061" SM="3">The  GlobalFlyer was over Morocco heading east at a speed of around 340  knots (390 miles per hour/630 kilometers per hour)</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="31.17391304347826" PS="1.5306122448979593" SM="13">&quot;At this time everything is going very well,&quot; Fossett said in a  radio hook-up with reporters at Mission Control in Salina.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="27.944444444444443" PS="1.0204081632653061" SM="12">&quot;I'm very  happy with the situation and I think we've got a good chance.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="24.48148148148148" PS="1.5306122448979593" SM="6">He said the takeoff of the GlobalFlyer, which is essentially a  flying gas tank -- 83 percent of the total weight is fuel -- had  been difficult.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="29.818181818181817" PS="1.0204081632653061" SM="14">&quot;It had a lot of dramas in the launch, dramas with  equipment failures that had to be solved,&quot; Fossett said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="32.34615384615385" PS="1.5306122448979593" SM="14">&quot;The plane was much slower than I expected but fortunately the  plane picked up speed and I didn't have to abort,&quot; he said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="22.31578947368421" PS="1.5306122448979593" SM="27">Among the problems was a temporary failure of the Global  Positioning System, or GPS, Fossett's primary navigation aid.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="31.193548387096776" PS="1.5306122448979593" SM="3">&quot;This was my sole source of navigation so this was very  serious,&quot; he said, adding that the GPS had not functioned for about  half of his flight over Canada.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="55.72727272727273" PS="1.0204081632653061" SM="11">&quot;I believe it was an antenna  problem,&quot; Fossett said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="17.894736842105264" PS="1.5306122448979593" SM="13">He cautioned that other problems could arise during the flight  and there was still a long way to go.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="37.793103448275865" PS="1.0204081632653061" SM="3">&quot;There may be new things that  come up so there's no real basis for confidence,&quot; he said, &quot;but I'm  happy with the situation.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="32.583333333333336" PS="1.5306122448979593" SM="14">Fossett said he had consumed three chocolate milkshakes since  the flight began.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="38.31578947368421" PS="1.0204081632653061" SM="4">&quot;It's not exactly my favorite diet but it will  certainly serve the purpose for this flight.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="21.6" PS="1.5306122448979593" SM="1">At Mission Control, flight controllers were carefully monitoring  fuel consumption.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="33.0" PS="1.5306122448979593" SM="4">&quot;One of the critical factors we are monitoring is the amount of  fuel he has left,&quot; said project manager Paul Moore.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="34.5" PS="1.0204081632653061" SM="2">&quot;He's eaten  quite substantially into his fuel (so far)  but that's as we  expected.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="23.3" PS="1.5306122448979593" SM="2">Moore said the GPS problem had been potentially very serious.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="45.5" PS="1.0204081632653061" SM="0">&quot;This could have been a showstopper,&quot; he said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="19.5" PS="1.0204081632653061" SM="0">&quot;This was really a  big worry as we are unable to fly without GPS especially when were  out of radio range.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="48.111111111111114" PS="1.5306122448979593" SM="1">&quot;Steve was essentially flying blind,&quot; Moore said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="26.0" PS="1.0204081632653061" SM="2">&quot;Happily,  after a couple of hours of malfunction the GPS system did  reengage.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="20.02857142857143" PS="1.5306122448979593" SM="57">The three-day journey will test the endurance and piloting  abilities of Fossett, a 60-year-old millionaire who has set dozens  of world records and world firsts with jet airplanes and gliders,  hot air balloons and sailing.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="19.205882352941178" PS="1.5306122448979593" SM="5">At takeoff, the 3,350-pound (1,522-kilogram) single engine  aircraft was carrying nearly 19,000 pounds (8,636 kilograms) of fuel  in 13 tanks for the 23,000-mile (37,260-kilometer) journey at  altitudes as high as 52,000 feet (15,850 meters).</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="27.952380952380953" PS="1.5306122448979593" SM="18">Virgin Atlantic Airways of Sir Richard Branson is funding the  GlobalFlyer and the British entrepreneur is in Salina monitoring the  flight.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="25.77777777777778" PS="1.5306122448979593" SM="5">The GlobalFlyer was designed by aviation legend Burt Rutan, who  recently made headlines when his SpaceShipOne won the 10 million  dollar &quot;X Prize&quot; for sending a privately-designed craft into space  twice in two weeks.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="22.87878787878788" PS="1.5306122448979593" SM="18">Rutan also designed the Voyager, which was used by his brother  Dick Rutan and Jeanne Yeager in 1986 to set a record of nine days  for a non-stop, non-refueled flight around the world.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="27.0" PS="1.5306122448979593" SM="22">Fossett hopes to beat that record by making it in less than 80  hours, and by doing it on his own.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="27.96" PS="2.8010204081632653" SM="16">American adventurer Steve  Fossett likes to joke that his attempt to fly around the world  without stopping or refueling has no &quot;practical&quot; purpose.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="16.91891891891892" PS="1.8673469387755102" SM="26">But the research that went into developing the super-light and  aerodynamic aircraft could one day lead to more fuel-efficient and  environmentally friendly commercial planes, said Sir Richard  Branson, chairman of Virgin Atlantic, which is funding the project.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="23.060606060606062" PS="1.8673469387755102" SM="10">&quot;As an airline, we hope that Virgin Atlantic airplanes will (one  day) be made of composite materials and that metal will be thrown  away,&quot; Branson said at a press conference Monday.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="16.782608695652176" PS="1.8673469387755102" SM="3">The single engine turbofan aircraft designed by Burt Rutans  Scale Composites is constructed with lightweight, composite  materials in order to maximize fuel efficiency.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="16.833333333333332" PS="1.2448979591836735" SM="0">It is so  aerodynamically perfect that it needs drag parachutes to land.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="22.515151515151516" PS="1.8673469387755102" SM="26">While he admits that his taste for adventure and publicity also  drove his interest in the GlobalFlyer, Branson said he also hopes  that the project will spur further interest in aviation and  adventure.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="27.8" PS="1.8673469387755102" SM="0">&quot;A lot of benefits to mankind come from projects like this,&quot;  Branson said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="21.84" PS="1.2448979591836735" SM="29">&quot;Kids around the world can log in and participate in a  great adventure and perhaps aspire to something like it in the  future.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="17.23076923076923" PS="1.8673469387755102" SM="14">The aircraft will also allow the National Aeronautics and Space  Administration to test a new state-of-the-art communications system  that will one day be used on spacecraft.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="24.580645161290324" PS="1.8673469387755102" SM="29">NASA said that the equipment has the potential to &quot;reduce the  cost and infrastructure of the current ground-based communications  systems&quot; by using satellites to relay tracking and flight data.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="27.357142857142858" PS="1.8673469387755102" SM="2">The GlobalFlyer is also being used as a platform for research  into cosmic radiation.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="24.785714285714285" PS="1.8673469387755102" SM="17">The experimental aircraft took off from Salina Municipal Airport  here on Monday for a flight around the world that is expected to  last between 60 and 80 hours.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="33.2" PS="1.2448979591836735" SM="23">Fossett crossed the Atlantic and was  over Africa on Tuesday.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="21.314285714285713" PS="2.8010204081632653" SM="21">American adventurer Steve  Fossett flew over the Middle East on Tuesday after overcoming a  navigation equipment problem that threatened to derail his historic  bid to make the first non-stop flight around the world without  refueling.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="25.896551724137932" PS="1.8673469387755102" SM="25">Fossett, who took off from here in the Virgin Atlantic  GlobalFlyer on Monday for a flight expected to last between 60 and  80 hours, said he hae navigation aid.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="31.193548387096776" PS="1.8673469387755102" SM="3">&quot;This was my sole source of navigation so this was very  serious,&quot; he said, adding that the GPS had not functioned for about  half of his flight over Canada.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="55.72727272727273" PS="1.2448979591836735" SM="11">&quot;I believe it was an antenna  problem,&quot; Fossett said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="12.5" PS="1.8673469387755102" SM="10">He cautioned that other problems could arise and there was still  a long way to go.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="37.793103448275865" PS="1.2448979591836735" SM="3">&quot;There may be new things that come up so there's  no real basis for confidence,&quot; he said, &quot;but I'm happy with the  situation.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="21.6" PS="1.8673469387755102" SM="1">At Mission Control, flight controllers were carefully monitoring  fuel consumption.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="33.0" PS="1.8673469387755102" SM="4">&quot;One of the critical factors we are monitoring is the amount of  fuel he has left,&quot; said project manager Paul Moore.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="34.5" PS="1.2448979591836735" SM="2">&quot;He's eaten  quite substantially into his fuel (so far)  but that's as we  expected.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="29.75" PS="1.8673469387755102" SM="5">Moore said the GPS problem had been potentially fatal to the  flight.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="45.5" PS="1.2448979591836735" SM="0">&quot;This could have been a showstopper,&quot; he said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="19.5" PS="1.2448979591836735" SM="0">&quot;This was  really a big worry as we are unable to fly without GPS especially  when were out of radio range.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="48.111111111111114" PS="1.8673469387755102" SM="1">&quot;Steve was essentially flying blind,&quot; Moore said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="26.0" PS="1.2448979591836735" SM="2">&quot;Happily,  after a couple of hours of malfunction the GPS system did  reengage.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="18.85" PS="1.8673469387755102" SM="15">Moore said cabin pressure was good and the temperature in the  cramped cockpit was 65 degrees Fahrenheit (18 degrees Celsius).</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="41.7" PS="1.2448979591836735" SM="0">&quot;His  feet are a bit chilly,&quot; said Moore.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="20.02857142857143" PS="1.8673469387755102" SM="57">The three-day journey will test the endurance and piloting  abilities of Fossett, a 60-year-old millionaire who has set dozens  of world records and world firsts with jet airplanes and gliders,  hot air balloons and sailing.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="19.205882352941178" PS="1.8673469387755102" SM="5">At takeoff, the 3,350-pound (1,522-kilogram) single engine  aircraft was carrying nearly 19,000 pounds (8,636 kilograms) of fuel  in 13 tanks for the 23,000-mile (37,260-kilometer) journey at  altitudes as high as 52,000 feet (15,850 meters).</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="27.952380952380953" PS="1.8673469387755102" SM="18">Virgin Atlantic Airways of Sir Richard Branson is funding the  GlobalFlyer and the British entrepreneur is in Salina monitoring the  flight.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="25.77777777777778" PS="1.8673469387755102" SM="5">The GlobalFlyer was designed by aviation legend Burt Rutan, who  recently made headlines when his SpaceShipOne won the 10 million  dollar &quot;X Prize&quot; for sending a privately-designed craft into space  twice in two weeks.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="22.87878787878788" PS="1.8673469387755102" SM="18">Rutan also designed the Voyager, which was used by his brother  Dick Rutan and Jeanne Yeager in 1986 to set a record of nine days  for a non-stop, non-refueled flight around the world.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="27.0" PS="1.8673469387755102" SM="22">Fossett hopes to beat that record by making it in less than 80  hours, and by doing it on his own.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="20.63888888888889" PS="2.3418367346938775" SM="21">US adventurer Steve Fossett was  approaching the coast of Pakistan late Tuesday after overcoming a  navigation equipment problem that threatened to derail his historic  bid to make the first non-stop flight around the world without  refueling.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="29.822222222222223" PS="1.5612244897959184" SM="28">Fossett, who took off from here in the Virgin Atlantic  GlobalFlyer on Monday for a flight expected to last between 60 and  80 hours, said he had to deal with a number of &quot;dramas&quot; during  takeoff but the flight was going well overall.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="24.9" PS="1.5612244897959184" SM="24">At 03:30 GMT, Fossett was at 48,197 feet (14,700 meters) and had  been in the air for nearly 27 hours.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="16.68" PS="1.5612244897959184" SM="5">The GlobalFlyer was over the Arabian sea heading east towards  Karachi, Pakistan at speeds of around 340 knots (390 miles per  hour/630 kilometers per hour).</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="30.689655172413794" PS="1.5612244897959184" SM="19">Earlier in the day, in a radio hook-up with reporters at Mission  Control in Salina, Fossett said he had a &quot;good chance&quot; of completing  the record-breaking flight.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="24.0" PS="1.5612244897959184" SM="10">&quot;I have picked up a 100 mile per hour (160 kilometers) jet  stream just behind mew and I am covering territory fast, which is  very encouraging,&quot; he said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="24.5" PS="1.0408163265306123" SM="11">&quot;It's interesting to watch things go by  and I am looking forward to another good day tomorrow.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="21.75" PS="1.5612244897959184" SM="27">The most serious problem was a temporary failure of the Global  Positioning System, or GPS, Fossett's satellite navigation aid.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="31.193548387096776" PS="1.5612244897959184" SM="3">&quot;This was my sole source of navigation so this was very  serious,&quot; he said, adding that the GPS had not functioned for about  half of his flight over Canada.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="55.72727272727273" PS="1.0408163265306123" SM="11">&quot;I believe it was an antenna  problem,&quot; Fossett said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="12.5" PS="1.5612244897959184" SM="10">He cautioned that other problems could arise and there was still  a long way to go.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="37.793103448275865" PS="1.0408163265306123" SM="3">&quot;There may be new things that come up so there's  no real basis for confidence,&quot; he said, &quot;but I'm happy with the  situation.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="21.6" PS="1.5612244897959184" SM="1">At Mission Control, flight controllers were carefully monitoring  fuel consumption.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="33.0" PS="1.5612244897959184" SM="4">&quot;One of the critical factors we are monitoring is the amount of  fuel he has left,&quot; said project manager Paul Moore.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="34.5" PS="1.0408163265306123" SM="2">&quot;He's eaten  quite substantially into his fuel (so far) but that's as we  expected.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="29.75" PS="1.5612244897959184" SM="5">Moore said the GPS problem had been potentially fatal to the  flight.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="45.5" PS="1.0408163265306123" SM="0">&quot;This could have been a showstopper,&quot; he said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="19.5" PS="1.0408163265306123" SM="0">&quot;This was  really a big worry as we are unable to fly without GPS especially  when were out of radio range.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="48.111111111111114" PS="1.5612244897959184" SM="1">&quot;Steve was essentially flying blind,&quot; Moore said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="26.0" PS="1.0408163265306123" SM="2">&quot;Happily,  after a couple of hours of malfunction the GPS system did  reengage.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="6.0" PS="1.5612244897959184" SM="0">Moore s Celsius).</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="41.7" PS="1.0408163265306123" SM="0">&quot;His  feet are a bit chilly,&quot; said Moore.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="30.375" PS="1.5612244897959184" SM="14">Fossett nonetheless reported being &quot;comfortable enough&quot; in the  7.7 foot (2.3 meter) long cockpit.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="31.055555555555557" PS="1.5612244897959184" SM="0">&quot;I have got elbow room, I can get to everything, I'm not  complaining,&quot; he said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="34.333333333333336" PS="1.0408163265306123" SM="2">&quot;It is a long trip - especially the nights.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="20.333333333333332" PS="1.0408163265306123" SM="10">I  feel a little bit tired but I have been through this before and I am  going to be okay.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="20.02857142857143" PS="1.5612244897959184" SM="57">The three-day journey will test the endurance and piloting  abilities of Fossett, a 60-year-old millionaire who has set dozens  of world records and world firsts with jet airplanes and gliders,  hot air balloons and sailing.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="19.205882352941178" PS="1.5612244897959184" SM="5">At takeoff, the 3,350-pound (1,522-kilogram) single engine  aircraft was carrying nearly 19,000 pounds (8,636 kilograms) of fuel  in 13 tanks for the 23,000-mile (37,260-kilometer) journey at  altitudes as high as 52,000 feet (15,850 meters).</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="27.952380952380953" PS="1.5612244897959184" SM="18">Virgin Atlantic Airways of Sir Richard Branson is funding the  GlobalFlyer and the British entrepreneur is in Salina monitoring the  flight.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="25.77777777777778" PS="1.5612244897959184" SM="5">The GlobalFlyer was designed by aviation legend Burt Rutan, who  recently made headlines when his SpaceShipOne won the 10 million  dollar &quot;X Prize&quot; for sending a privately-designed craft into space  twice in two weeks.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="22.87878787878788" PS="1.5612244897959184" SM="18">Rutan also designed the Voyager, which was used by his brother  Dick Rutan and Jeanne Yeager in 1986 to set a record of nine days  for a non-stop, non-refueled flight around the world.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="27.0" PS="1.5612244897959184" SM="22">Fossett hopes to beat that record by making it in less than 80  hours, and by doing it on his own.</sentence>
	</Sentences>
</Topic>
