<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<Topic id="D0935G">
	<Sentences>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="15.275862068965518" PS="2.25" SM="48">Still without approval from baseball club owners or the city they plan to call home, the Washington Nationals were born Monday in a sea of red, white and blue.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="18.227272727272727" PS="1.5" SM="27">These are not your grandfather's Washington Nationals, because those Nationals played in the American League and were alternately called the Senators.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="22.964285714285715" PS="1.5" SM="25">The new National League Nationals were named not only before they have approval to play in the nation's capital, but also before they have a new owner.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="15.83673469387755" PS="1.5" SM="95">Major League Baseball, the owner of record, has moved so slowly on the transfer and the sale of the team that a new owner isn't guaranteed to be in place in time to make marketing plans for next season or to have a say in off-season player decisions.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="16.954545454545453" PS="1.5" SM="33">For what some people expect to be $400 million to $500 million, the new guy doesn't get to name his team.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="20.764705882352942" PS="1.5" SM="10">&quot;We need a name for marketing,&quot; Bob DuPuy, baseball's chief operating officer, said Monday.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="21.0" PS="1.0" SM="10">&quot;We're not going to have an owner for some time.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="15.933333333333334" PS="1.0" SM="13">What if we don't have an owner by the start of spring training?&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="10.285714285714286" PS="1.5" SM="15">Nearly 30 individuals or groups have submitted expressions of interest in buying the team.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="10.789473684210526" PS="1.0" SM="43">Baseball expects about half of that number to bid seriously when the time comes to put up their money.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="15.619047619047619" PS="1.5" SM="7">One owner said Monday that he believed the leading contender for the team was Mark Broxmeyer, a Long Island builder, but another hopeful said there was no way anyone could be a leading contender because the first dollar hasn't been bid.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="17.5" PS="1.5" SM="31">If there is a leader in the bidding, having nothing to do with finances, it could be the group headed by Stan Kasten, who for many years was the president of the Atlanta Braves.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="15.703703703703704" PS="1.0" SM="13">Kasten has been exploring multiple opportunities in multiple sports, but if he decides to reach for the Nationals, he would have an advantage over other prospective buyers.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="2.0" PS="1.5" SM="0">Why?</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="16.75" PS="1.0" SM="10">Study recent baseball history.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="17.451612903225808" PS="1.0" SM="14">The winning bidder for the Boston Red Sox three years ago was John Henry's group, which was loaded with baseball people who had a close relationship with Commissioner Bud Selig.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="13.9" PS="1.0" SM="3">He might not have known it at the time, but Cablevision's Charles F. Dolan never really had a chance.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="9.555555555555555" PS="1.0" SM="0">Kasten has had a good, long relationship with Selig.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="17.555555555555557" PS="1.5" SM="13">The Washington bidding will be a show worth watching.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="16.97142857142857" PS="1.0" SM="57">Not long after Major League Baseball took control of the Expos, baseball people talked about an eventual sale bringing in $400 million, giving the other 29 teams a rewarding payday for their $120 million purchase.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="13.647058823529411" PS="1.5" SM="23">Then the economy turned south, and some people felt baseball would be fortunate to get $200 million.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="15.1875" PS="1.0" SM="23">Maybe that's why baseball officials dragged their feet in deciding where to put the Expos.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="10.625" PS="1.0" SM="12">They were trying to wait out the economy.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="15.695652173913043" PS="1.5" SM="23">Time hasn't done much for the economy, but it did give baseball time to find a knight on a big white horse.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="16.65714285714286" PS="1.0" SM="33">The Washington mayor, Anthony Williams, came riding in and pledged that the District of Columbia would build a new ballpark for the new team, whatever the cost, which some estimates say could exceed $600 million.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="24.14814814814815" PS="1.5" SM="7">The new owner, whose team will play at Robert F. Kennedy Stadium for the first three seasons, will have what might be the best stadium deal ever.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="16.70967741935484" PS="1.0" SM="19">The Nationals will pay nothing for the construction of the park, pay $3.5 million a year for rent and receive all stadium-related revenue from tickets, concessions, parking, signs and naming-rights fees.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="11.666666666666666" PS="1.5" SM="28">The prospect of getting that combined revenue and money from a regional sports network to be shared with the Baltimore Orioles will drive up the sale price.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="13.288461538461538" PS="1.5" SM="30">A financial investment adviser said Monday that he would never advise a client to pay $400 million for the Nats, although maybe $300 million, but he acknowledged the possibility that some bidder might make a $400 million bid if he really wanted the team and wanted to break away from the crowd.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="18.095238095238095" PS="1.5" SM="17">Just like the old Nationals, who became the Senators in 1957, these Nationals will have the right to change their name.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="22.652173913043477" PS="1.0" SM="28">&quot;When they move into the new stadium, the owner will have the right to petition to change the name,&quot; DuPuy said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="19.925" PS="1.5" SM="27">Club owners are expected to approve the team's move within the next two weeks, whether or not baseball officials have concluded an agreement with Peter Angelos, the Orioles' owner, on compensation for intruding on what he considers his turf.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="24.454545454545453" PS="1.0" SM="13">The Washington city council will vote on stadium financing next month.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="9.235294117647058" PS="1.5" SM="21">Meanwhile, even though no owner is in place to decide which players he might want or how much he would spend on them, Jim Bowden continues to do his job as interim general manager.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="11.153846153846153" PS="1.5" SM="14">Bowden has already demonstrated his acumen in running a low-budget operation, having served as general manager of the economically deprived Cincinnati Reds for 10 1/2 years.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="8.097560975609756" PS="1.0" SM="29">And in the space of a few days last week, Bowden signed half an infield's worth of free agents -- third baseman Vinny Castilla and shortstop Cristian Guzman -- and traded for a productive, if volatile, outfielder in Jose Guillen.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="17.714285714285715" PS="1.5" SM="20">Bowden hasn't been told if he can exceed the $41 million payroll with which the Expos opened last season, but baseball officials have estimated that the Nationals will take in at least $100 million more in revenue than the Expos did.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="8.3" PS="1.0" SM="10">That should give Bowden a little more to play with.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="19.583333333333332" PS="1.5" SM="2">Even if he doesn't know who the new owner will be.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="24.157894736842106" PS="2.808" SM="68">Major League Baseball owners Friday conditionally approved the relocation of the Montreal Expos to Washington for the upcoming season.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="20.28" PS="1.8719999999999999" SM="39">The approval was &quot;subject to all conditions set forth in the Baseball Stadium Agreement,&quot; signed by the Expos and Washington Mayor Anthony Williams.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="18.526315789473685" PS="1.248" SM="25">The agreement calls for the District of Columbia government to enact funding for a new ballpark by December 31.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="18.043478260869566" PS="1.8719999999999999" SM="47">&quot;This is another important step in finalizing the relocation of the Montreal Expos to Washington DC,&quot; baseball commissioner Bud Selig said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="18.928571428571427" PS="1.248" SM="56">&quot;We are looking forward to finishing the last few steps, including the sale of the ballclub, and the rebirth of the club as the Washington Nationals.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="20.045454545454547" PS="1.8719999999999999" SM="39">The last time a major league club moved cities was after the 1971 season, when the Washington Senators became the Texas Rangers.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="19.5" PS="1.8719999999999999" SM="11">Until a new ballpark is built, Washington will play at RFK Stadium.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="1.0" PS="1.8719999999999999" SM="0">bb/nr04</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="20.073170731707318" PS="2.6279999999999997" SM="59">Major League Baseball on Wednesday rejected as &quot;wholly unacceptable&quot; a stadium financing plan approved the day before by the Washington City Council, throwing into grave doubt the city's plans to bring the former Montreal Expos here next season.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="14.872727272727273" PS="1.7519999999999998" SM="70">Baseball's statement came in response to legislation the Council approved late Tuesday night requiring that half of the riverfront stadium's projected $280 million construction costs be paid for privately, delivering a stinging rejection of a deal struck by Mayor Anthony Williams and baseball officials to finance the ballpark almost entirely with tax dollars.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="8.384615384615385" PS="1.7519999999999998" SM="0">On Wednesday, a grim Williams expressed pessimism that his plan could be salvaged.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="24.454545454545453" PS="1.168" SM="11">&quot;I do think baseball is in jeopardy,&quot; he said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="16.166666666666668" PS="1.168" SM="23">&quot;The dream of 33 years is now close to dying.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="22.333333333333332" PS="1.7519999999999998" SM="58">Critics of Williams' plan said he was exaggerating the threat that Major League Baseball would take the team, renamed the Nationals, to another city.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="17.24137931034483" PS="1.168" SM="35">They said baseball had few alternatives, since the Nationals are scheduled to play next season in Robert F. Kennedy Memorial Stadium in Washington while their new home is built.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="23.9375" PS="1.168" SM="17">Once the team is in Washington, the city's negotiating position will be strengthened, they argued.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="14.833333333333334" PS="1.7519999999999998" SM="61">But in a statement, Bob DuPuy, president of Major League Baseball, called the legislation &quot;wholly unacceptable&quot; and gave the city until Dec. 31, the previously agreed upon deadline, to approve the original financing deal.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="16.818181818181817" PS="1.168" SM="11">After that date, baseball said, it will begin considering other sites.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="19.708333333333332" PS="1.7519999999999998" SM="19">&quot;The legislation approved by the District of Columbia City Council last night does not reflect the agreement we signed,&quot; the statement said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="25.705882352941178" PS="1.7519999999999998" SM="13">DuPuy said baseball had stopped promotional activities for the Nationals and would refund deposits for season tickets.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="17.81081081081081" PS="1.7519999999999998" SM="61">Under the deal Williams reached with baseball owners to bring the Expos to Washington next spring, less than 20 percent of the stadium would have been financed by private funds, specifically through rent payments from the team.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="13.466666666666667" PS="1.7519999999999998" SM="22">Amid the uncertainty, the one clear thing on Wednesday was the stark and surprisingly forceful message the Council sent about growing public resentment toward the high cost of sports stadiums.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="13.055555555555555" PS="1.7519999999999998" SM="3">With land acquisition and service improvements, Williams had projected that the total stadium package would cost $440 million.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="15.285714285714286" PS="1.168" SM="15">But the city's chief financial officer has put the cost closer to $535 million, and other estimates have gone higher.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="17.5625" PS="2.808" SM="71">The White House said Thursday it hoped that the city of Washington and Major League Baseball could still reach an agreement that would bring a professional team to the US capital city.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="15.266666666666667" PS="1.8719999999999999" SM="34">US President George W. Bush, an avid fan and former team owner, &quot;thought it was great that baseball would be coming to Washington,&quot; spokesman Scott McClellan told reporters.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="13.727272727272727" PS="1.248" SM="10">&quot;Hopefully, they'll be able to work things out.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="17.48936170212766" PS="1.8719999999999999" SM="51">The District of Columbia Council has voted to require private financing for at least half the construction costs of a new ballpark for the Nationals -- the former Montreal Expos, who are due to kick off next season in their new city against Arizona on April 14.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="15.0" PS="1.8719999999999999" SM="46">&quot;The legislation is inconsistent with our carefully negotiated agreement and is wholly unacceptable to Major League Baseball,&quot; MLB president and CEO Bob DuPuy said in a statement a day after Tuesday's vote.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="19.9" PS="1.8719999999999999" SM="43">In the initial agreement between the team and Washington Mayor Anthony A. Williams, the city was to be responsible for 531 million dollars in bonds to finance the stadium plan.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="20.08" PS="1.8719999999999999" SM="21">But under the legislation approved by the council, 50 percent of the costs must come from private financing, or the approval for the plan expires.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="18.625" PS="1.8719999999999999" SM="15">With the new provision in place, the Nationals may have to reopen bidding for a permanent home if private financial obligations are not met.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="16.058823529411764" PS="1.8719999999999999" SM="0">Asked whether Bush supported public financing for sports stadiums, McClellan replied: &quot;Those are local decisions.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="20.11904761904762" PS="2.4480000000000004" SM="82">The city's top two political leaders cleared the way Monday night for Major League Baseball in the nation's capital, after daylong negotiations to guarantee the construction of a stadium that baseball officials demanded to relocate the former Montreal Expos here.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="18.738095238095237" PS="1.6320000000000001" SM="61">The city's mayor, Anthony A. Williams, and the City Council chairman, Linda W. Cropp, agreed, together with baseball officials, to alterations in the deal the mayor made with Major League Baseball in September that used mostly taxpayer dollars for stadium construction.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="9.5" PS="1.6320000000000001" SM="43">Cropp wanted to minimize the use of public money to build a stadium, which has been estimated to cost as much as $585 million.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="19.31578947368421" PS="1.6320000000000001" SM="18">The compromise will be voted on Tuesday by the full 13-member council at its last meeting of the year.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="20.884615384615383" PS="1.6320000000000001" SM="26">Cropp persuaded fellow council members last week to adopt an amendment requiring private financing for the new stadium, where the renamed Washington Nationals team would play.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="17.304347826086957" PS="1.6320000000000001" SM="17">The compromise reached late Monday assures that 50 percent of the stadium will be privately financed, said the mayor's spokesman Chris Bender.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="14.870967741935484" PS="1.6320000000000001" SM="13">Several private financing possibilities already have been investigated by city officials, Bender said, including a parking meter plan that is expected to generate $100 million in upfront revenue for the city.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="13.166666666666666" PS="1.088" SM="16">If no other private deals are found, Bender said, the city expects to sign onto the parking arrangement offered by the Cleveland-based Gates Group.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="13.958333333333334" PS="1.6320000000000001" SM="59">In return for assurances that private financing is viable, Cropp said she would drop her legislative language requiring a specific amount of private financing, a demand which had aroused the ire of baseball supporters since they feared that it would torpedo the team's chances of moving here.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="17.457142857142856" PS="1.6320000000000001" SM="51">Baseball officials also agreed to reduce the $19 million in damages the city would incur if the new stadium, to be built by the Anacostia River in Southeast Washington, did not open by March 2008.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="15.764705882352942" PS="1.088" SM="18">Instead, the city would forfeit a $5 million yearly rental payment it would earn when the Nationals team plays at Robert F. Kennedy Memorial Stadium, which it is set to do beginning in 2005.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="16.15" PS="1.6320000000000001" SM="45">Baseball officials also agreed to split the cost of construction insurance with the city to limit taxpayer liability, Bender said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="15.555555555555555" PS="1.6320000000000001" SM="26">Williams said that having a team was not just about baseball, but also &quot;about revitalizing the Anacostia River, creating new jobs, bringing in new tax revenues and creating a new source of civil pride.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="18.105263157894736" PS="2.43" SM="14">Baseball fans in the nation's capital can start dreaming again about their first opening day in 33 years.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="17.892857142857142" PS="1.62" SM="40">The District of Columbia Council voted 7-6 Tuesday to approve legislation clearing the way for the Montreal Expos to move here next season and be renamed the Nationals.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="15.636363636363637" PS="1.08" SM="63">The measure allows the city to sell up to $584 million (euro436 million) in bonds for construction of a 41,000-seat stadium about a 1.6 kilometers (one mile) south of the Capitol, and for renovations to RFK Stadium, where the team will play next year.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="8.444444444444445" PS="1.62" SM="12">Ticket and team merchandise sales were to resume Wednesday.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="20.083333333333332" PS="1.08" SM="19">They were suspended for a week because of uncertainty caused by changes the council had made in the city's agreement with the team.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="23.307692307692307" PS="1.62" SM="35">&quot;The Nationals are finally rounding third and heading for home,&quot; said Mayor Anthony A. Williams, who negotiated the move with major league baseball officials.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="18.78125" PS="1.62" SM="38">Williams said he will sign the bill as soon as it reaches his desk, leaving only baseball commissioner Bud Selig's approval of the RFK renovations for the move to become final.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="20.34375" PS="1.62" SM="43">The Nationals' home opener on April 14 would be the first regular season major league game in the city since the Senators left to become the Texas Rangers after the 1971 season.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="16.96875" PS="1.62" SM="27">The city almost struck out a week earlier when the council amended Williams' deal with baseball officials to require that half the construction costs be paid privately, or it would be voided.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="17.608695652173914" PS="1.62" SM="28">Baseball officials balked at the provision and threatened to take the team elsewhere if the original deal wasn't approved by Dec. 31.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="13.1" PS="1.62" SM="24">But Williams won the necessary votes after he, Cropp and baseball officials compromised during a day of intense negotiations Monday.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="20.642857142857142" PS="1.62" SM="40">The final bill calls for the city and baseball to split the cost of insurance that would limit the city's liability on cost overruns or construction delays.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="19.210526315789473" PS="1.08" SM="4">That amendment, introduced by Cropp, also reduces compensatory damages for the first year if the stadium is finished late.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="21.303030303030305" PS="1.08" SM="42">Instead, the Washington Nationals would not have to pay $5.3 million (euro3.96 million) in rent if the ballpark is not ready for the 2008 season and the team has to remain at RFK.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="11.80952380952381" PS="1.62" SM="2">A second amendment, approved 10-3, deletes a sunset provision that would have canceled the deal if there was no private financing.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="22.55" PS="1.62" SM="17">Baseball officials were pleased with the vote and the guarantees that the stadium would be built as planned, Selig said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="16.0625" PS="1.62" SM="28">&quot;We are also pleased that our discussions with Washington's elected leaders over the last several days have helped each side better understand the concerns of the other,&quot; Selig said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="13.357142857142858" PS="1.08" SM="36">&quot;We are now more confident than ever of a long and productive relationship with the city of Washington as we move forward with this great project.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="10.470588235294118" PS="1.62" SM="13">Williams sent Cropp a letter Tuesday, noting his commitment to include private financing in the stadium package.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="14.757575757575758" PS="1.08" SM="15">If there is no better proposal, Williams wrote, he will use a proposal from the Cleveland-based Gates Group that would provide $100 million (euro74.66 million) in return for parking revenues near the stadium.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="12.903225806451612" PS="1.62" SM="27">Supporters of the measure also made some parliamentary maneuvers to ensure the bill could not be reconsidered next year, when three new members who oppose the stadium project begin their terms.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="22.82758620689655" PS="2.6279999999999997" SM="49">The Washington Nationals will make  their debut in the nation's capital when they host the New York Mets  in a major league baseball exhibition game on April 3.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="23.863636363636363" PS="1.7519999999999998" SM="4">The game will be played at RFK Stadium, which will serve as the  Nationals' temporary home before their new stadium is constructed.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="20.923076923076923" PS="1.7519999999999998" SM="25">Formerly the Montreal Expos, the Nationals were officially  relocated to Washington last month.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="15.775" PS="1.7519999999999998" SM="31">After the move was approved the team's future in the District of  Columbia briefly seemed in jeopardy when stadium funding hit a snag,  but local officials have since approved a plan for public funding of  a 400 million-dollar stadium.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="16.083333333333332" PS="2.25" SM="38">The Montreal Expos can move to Washington, change their name and never play the Canadian national anthem again, but they cannot seem to go anywhere without the New York Mets following along for a photo-op.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="10.933333333333334" PS="1.5" SM="3">Despite everything that has changed with this vagabond franchise, its trusty sidekick remains the same.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="13.911764705882353" PS="1.0" SM="39">More than 35 years after the Mets welcomed the Expos to the major leagues and more than five months after they ushered them out, the Mets once again rode shotgun into history on Wednesday.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="8.7" PS="1.5" SM="13">The spring training schedule-makers have quite a sense of symmetry.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="20.695652173913043" PS="1.0" SM="37">The Expos played their first regular-season game against the Mets in 1969 and their last game against the Mets on Oct. 3, so it was only fitting that the Washington Nationals would play their first game against the Mets on opening day in the Grapefruit League.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="21.75" PS="1.5" SM="40">If anyone missed the nostalgic significance of the event, the Mets will travel to Washington for the Nationals' first game at RFK Stadium, an exhibition on April 3.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="17.166666666666668" PS="1.0" SM="25">By the end of the regular season, these two National League East companions will have met 26 times.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="19.583333333333332" PS="1.0" SM="11">&quot;It's getting really weird,&quot; Washington outfielder Brad Wilkerson said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="19.0" PS="1.0" SM="1">&quot;It's always us and them.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="16.73076923076923" PS="1.5" SM="17">In the first regular-season game between thesefranchises, Tom Seaver started for the Mets at Shea Stadium and Coco Laboy powered the Expos to an 11-10 victory.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="15.478260869565217" PS="1.0" SM="15">In their last meeting, Tom Glavine started for the Mets at Shea and Todd Zeile homered to deal the Expos an 8-1 defeat.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="21.238095238095237" PS="1.0" SM="5">On Wednesday at Space Coast Stadium, Glavine started again for the Mets and the Nationals came back for a 5-3 victory.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="23.95" PS="1.5" SM="5">&quot;To start the last game and start the first game,&quot; Glavine said, &quot;that's pretty cool.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="13.1" PS="1.5" SM="16">The Mets can take solace in lessons of the past.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="11.777777777777779" PS="1.0" SM="25">When they dropped the opener to this franchise in 1969, they went on to win the World Series.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="20.695652173913043" PS="1.0" SM="3">&quot;Maybe that's an omen for our team,&quot; said Mets outfielder Ron Calloway, who came over from the Expos this winter.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="19.77777777777778" PS="1.0" SM="1">&quot;Or maybe it's just a reach.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="14.647058823529411" PS="1.5" SM="13">To celebrate their first game, the Nationals wore their regular-season home uniforms instead of their batting-practice jerseys.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="9.714285714285714" PS="1.0" SM="1">They got their first hit from shortstop Christian Guzman and their first home run from outfielder Jose Guillen, both off-season acquisitions.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="12.454545454545455" PS="1.0" SM="26">The Nationals have sold 20,000 season-ticket packages in Washington, but they drew a more modest sellout of 7,558 in Viera on Wednesday.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="13.173913043478262" PS="1.0" SM="16">After the third inning, there was still a traffic jam outside the stadium, with ticket-holders trying to get into the grass parking lot.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="15.466666666666667" PS="1.5" SM="23">&quot;There is a lot of enthusiasm and anticipation,&quot; Washington manager Frank Robinson said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="13.733333333333333" PS="1.0" SM="1">&quot;There is interest in this ball club that hasn't been there before.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="26.545454545454547" PS="1.5" SM="5">The Nationals were not the only players on a new team.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="17.142857142857142" PS="1.0" SM="3">Doug Mientkiewicz started his first game for the Mets at first base and made a nifty scoop on a double play.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="9.285714285714286" PS="1.0" SM="4">Kazuo Matsui started his first spring-training game at second base and successfully charged two grounders, bare-handing one and short-hopping the other.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="20.65" PS="1.0" SM="6">Carlos Beltran was in the Mets' lineup for the first time and went 1 for 3 with a searing single.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="19.22222222222222" PS="1.0" SM="0">&quot;I was a little nervous,&quot; Beltran said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="24.142857142857142" PS="1.0" SM="0">&quot;But that's just me.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="8.482758620689655" PS="1.5" SM="15">With Mike Piazza and Cliff Floyd back in Port St. Lucie, and Mike Cameron rehabilitating from wrist surgery, Beltran was the second-most popular reason to watch Wednesday's game.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="9.923076923076923" PS="1.0" SM="10">&quot;Whenever I throw my last warm-up pitch, I always turn around to make sure everybody is ready,&quot; Glavine said after working two shutout innings.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="12.304347826086957" PS="1.0" SM="15">&quot;To see the new guys we had out there, and to see Carlos in center field, it was a good feeling.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="12.0" PS="1.5" SM="27">Even the Mets' rookie manager, Willie Randolph, was bouncing out of the dugout to greet players coming off the field.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="15.0" PS="1.0" SM="16">After the Mets hired Randolph in November, one of the first congratulatory calls he received was from Robinson.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="17.681818181818183" PS="1.0" SM="24">And after Randolph put on a Mets' uniform for the first time last month, one of his first calls was to Robinson.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="19.88888888888889" PS="1.5" SM="23">This game will undoubtedly be remembered as the Nationals' introduction to baseball, but it also included two African-American managers who have relied on each other for support.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="15.153846153846153" PS="1.5" SM="10">&quot;I think Willie is going to do really well,&quot; Robinson said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="15.307692307692308" PS="1.5" SM="2">Randolph seemed much more comfortable than Omar Minaya, the Mets' general manager, who could be forgiven for forgetting for a day which organization signs his paycheck.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="16.95" PS="1.0" SM="9">Minaya, the Expos' general manager the past three years, helped make the Nationals a competitor and the Mets a contender.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="14.772727272727273" PS="1.0" SM="16">In the first of many reunions with his former team, Minaya wore a blue hat with a white M on the front.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="20.90909090909091" PS="1.0" SM="4">The hat was not a new style released by the Mets.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="22.357142857142858" PS="1.0" SM="13">It was worn by the Montreal Royals, Jackie Robinson's first professional baseball team.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="11.625" PS="1.5" SM="1">&quot;I'm happy today, and I'm also a little bit sad,&quot; Minaya said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="27.083333333333332" PS="1.0" SM="11">&quot;I'm happy for Washington, but I'm sad for Montreal.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="7.833333333333333" PS="1.0" SM="11">It can be sort of emotional.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="14.666666666666666" PS="1.0" SM="11">There is a lot of newness here today.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="9.727272727272727" PS="1.5" SM="16">As a sign that not everything had changed, the former first-round draft choice Aaron Heilman allowed three runs in two innings for the Mets, wasting a pair of run-scoring hits from Jason Phillips.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="11.0" PS="1.0" SM="5">Felix Heredia, who frustrated Yankees' fans last season, gave up the winning run in the sixth.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="7.6923076923076925" PS="1.5" SM="12">Heredia did not get any help from his former Yankees' teammate, infielder Miguel Cairo, who booted a ground ball at third base to score the run.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="16.24137931034483" PS="1.5" SM="13">The Mets and the Yankees have had many players go back and forth across town over the years, but the Mets and the Nationals share a more common history.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="15.31578947368421" PS="1.0" SM="17">The two franchises always seem to be starting over at the same time, and often on the same field.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="16.8" PS="2.25" SM="52">Cox News Service WASHINGTON On the day when Washington's new baseball team won its first exhibition game, President Bush honored Jackie Robinson in a congressional ceremony on Wednesday and welcomed the champion Boston Red Sox to the White House.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="12.0" PS="1.5" SM="4">The ceremony marking the Red Sox first World Series win since 1918 was an upbeat event despite political overtones.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="18.0625" PS="1.5" SM="3">Pitcher Curt Schilling, who presented Bush with a team jersey, campaigned for the president last year.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="10.5" PS="1.5" SM="1">But team executives backed Massachusetts Sen. John Kerry.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="15.588235294117647" PS="1.5" SM="7">John Henry, a Kerry backer and the team's principal owner, was ill and skipped the event.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="12.170212765957446" PS="1.5" SM="29">Red Sox General Manager Theo Epstein also endorsed Kerry, saying last year, &quot;It's been four days and I'm finally starting to believe the Red Sox won the World Series and I still can't believe George Bush is president of the United States.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="14.590909090909092" PS="1.5" SM="19">Epstein attended the White House south lawn event, but sat with the audience instead of joining the team and Bush on stage.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="1.5" PS="1.5" SM="0">Massachusetts Sens.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="13.192307692307692" PS="1.5" SM="19">Kerry and Ted Kennedy, two of Bush's harshest critics, attended the event, though Kerry was late in arriving from the Robinson ceremony at the Capitol.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="11.666666666666666" PS="1.5" SM="0">Bush spotted Kerry as he arrived.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="13.090909090909092" PS="1.5" SM="10">&quot;Good to see you,&quot; Bush told his former foe.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="7.142857142857143" PS="1.5" SM="20">&quot;I like to see Senator Kerry, except when we're fixing to debate.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="10.714285714285714" PS="1.5" SM="0">If you know what I mean.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="13.25" PS="1.5" SM="19">Bush, former managing partner of the Texas Rangers, greeted the Red Sox with a jab aimed at the fact that they had not won the championship since 1918.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="12.11111111111111" PS="1.5" SM="0">&quot;So, like, what took you so long?&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="15.444444444444445" PS="1.5" SM="6">he joked, noting that Woodrow Wilson was president the last time the Red Sox won the World Series.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="17.0" PS="1.5" SM="17">Bush praised the Red Sox for their hustling style of play and touted their organization for its long-standing charitable programs, including The Jimmy Fund.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="17.466666666666665" PS="1.5" SM="61">Just before welcoming the team to the White House, Bush participated in a Congressional Gold Medal ceremony for the late Robinson, the first black to play in Major League Baseball.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="12.795454545454545" PS="1.5" SM="44">&quot;This is a guy who inspired little 7-year-olds to dream of wearing 42 and dashing for home in Brooklyn,&quot; Bush said, &quot;and a 7-year-old like me hoping to get his Topps baseball card, even though I was a Giants fan.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="16.833333333333332" PS="1.5" SM="0">&quot;He was an amazing guy.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="16.214285714285715" PS="1.5" SM="3">And his story was powerful then and it is powerful today,&quot; Bush said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="20.870967741935484" PS="1.5" SM="43">The baseball events came as the Washington Nationals, who moved to the city from Montreal during the off-season, defeated the New York Mets 5-3 in their first exhibition game in Florida.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="19.181818181818183" PS="1.5" SM="14">Bush is expected to throw the ceremonial first pitch when the Nationals play their first regular season home game on April 14.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="14.538461538461538" PS="1.5" SM="13">The name of a prominent Democrat will also be associated with that game.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="19.0" PS="1.5" SM="6">The Nationals will play in Robert F. Kennedy Memorial Stadium, named for the late Democratic senator and attorney general.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="13.142857142857142" PS="1.5" SM="0">Ken Herman's e-mail address is khermancoxnews.com</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="16.444444444444443" PS="2.25" SM="14">The following editorial appeared in Tuesday's Washington Post:</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="19.142857142857142" PS="1.5" SM="50">It is time for Major League Baseball to stand up to Peter G. Angelos.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="16.17142857142857" PS="1.5" SM="82">Mr. Angelos, majority owner of the Baltimore Orioles, has used the threat of litigation and a flair for brinkmanship to cast a pall over the start of Washington baseball's first season in 34 years.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="20.166666666666668" PS="1.0" SM="18">The city's new team, the Nationals, begins regular season play Monday, with a home opener set for April 14, and it remains without a deal to televise its games.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="15.682926829268293" PS="1.0" SM="44">Whatever the local enthusiasm for the Nationals -- and it appears to be enormous -- the absence of a television broadcasting outlet is an impediment that will undercut early attempts to market the new team and give it a running start.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="15.916666666666666" PS="1.0" SM="15">This is unacceptable, and it is largely the doing of Mr. Angelos.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="16.70967741935484" PS="1.5" SM="40">Mr. Angelos opposed bringing baseball to Washington on the grounds that it might further damage his Orioles franchise, whose fortunes have nose-dived in the 12 years since he purchased the team.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="11.875" PS="1.0" SM="2">In that he may have a point; last week, the Orioles reported that ticket sales were running 12 percent behind last year's level.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="22.954545454545453" PS="1.0" SM="36">He has insisted that Major League Baseball should compensate him for the revenue he believes the Nationals will leech from the Orioles.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="11.32" PS="1.0" SM="43">According to published reports, he has already received from baseball officials a guaranteed minimum price of $365 million should he decide to sell the Orioles.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="18.642857142857142" PS="1.0" SM="6">That's more than twice the amount Mr. Angelos paid for the franchise in 1993 -- not bad for a team whose attendance has plummeted on his watch.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="19.892857142857142" PS="1.5" SM="24">If baseball officials want to indemnify Mr. Angelos for his anticipated financial losses, that's fine -- but not if the compensation would come at the Nationals' expense.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="12.806451612903226" PS="1.0" SM="17">Yet with negotiations in the eleventh hour, the Orioles' owner has insisted on a prejudicial television broadcasting arrangement that would hold the Nationals' financial fortunes hostage to his own whims indefinitely.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="14.301587301587302" PS="1.0" SM="62">Claiming a highly dubious exclusive right to broadcast all baseball in this region, Mr. Angelos says Nationals games could be shown on his own Orioles regional network; in return for airing its games, he says he would offer the Washington team a ``fair and appropriate fee'' -- but not an equity stake in the network or a percentage of broadcast profits.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="16.925" PS="1.0" SM="42">In fact, such a deal is a rip-off that would deflate the Nationals' value and imperil the task of finding a buyer for the franchise -- an orphan that is now the collective property of baseball's 29 team owners.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="8.32" PS="1.0" SM="42">What prospective Nationals' owner would cede control of broadcasting rights to a rival -- to say nothing of a rival as truculent as Mr. Angelos?</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="13.538461538461538" PS="1.0" SM="4">Might as well trade away the team's best sluggers and star pitchers.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="9.727272727272727" PS="1.5" SM="10">Mr. Angelos has threatened to sue unless he gets his way.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="17.736842105263158" PS="1.0" SM="22">Evidently hoping to avoid the drawn-out, bare-knuckled litigation for which he is notorious, baseball officials have kept negotiations alive.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="23.307692307692307" PS="1.0" SM="3">But the talks have gone on for six months, and time's up.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="14.5" PS="1.0" SM="25">The season starts next week, and Washington's baseball-starved fans want to tune in.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="13.444444444444445" PS="1.0" SM="0">Lawyers say Mr. Angelos's legal position is weak.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="23.36" PS="1.0" SM="42">It's time for Major League Baseball to fix a sensible broadcasting deal for the Nationals -- whether or not Mr. Angelos will play ball.</sentence>
	</Sentences>
</Topic>
