<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<Topic id="D0932F">
	<Sentences>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="16.20689655172414" PS="2.513297872340426" SM="31">The Rwandan government has launched a national war against plastic bags as an attempt to maintain the environment and clean up the country, President Paul Kagame told reporters Monday.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="16.84375" PS="1.6755319148936172" SM="32">Kagame who participated in the clean-up of the Kigali city said that his government had endorsed the ban on all plastic bags and anyone who still owns them ought to face penalties.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="15.88888888888889" PS="1.6755319148936172" SM="4">&quot;We want people to use traditional baskets and give the land a breathing space,&quot; Kagame said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="14.96875" PS="1.6755319148936172" SM="19">&quot;We have a real problem with plastic and we are linking this with our efforts to protect our rivers and lakes,&quot; Mugorewera Drocella, minister of lands and environment told reporters.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="10.9375" PS="1.6755319148936172" SM="5">However, shop owners feel the government's decision was to hostile and too heavy for them.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="21.103448275862068" PS="1.1170212765957448" SM="22">&quot;We have now resorted to using newspapers as packing bags until the government shows us what to be used,&quot; one businessman in the capital city Kigali said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="25.0" PS="2.4055851063829783" SM="49">City officials are considering charging grocery stores 17 cents each for grocery bags to discourage use of plastic sacks.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="17.92" PS="1.603723404255319" SM="27">More than 90 percent of consumers choose plastic bags, which are blamed for everything from clogging recycling machines to killing marine life and suffocating infants.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="20.285714285714285" PS="1.0691489361702127" SM="17">But the fee would also apply to paper bags to help reduce overall waste.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="12.515151515151516" PS="1.603723404255319" SM="3">Promoting a healthy environment &quot;means we need to help change people's patterns, and that even means their shopping patterns,&quot; said incoming city Supervisor Ross Mirkarimi, who takes office in January.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="28.125" PS="1.0691489361702127" SM="0">&quot;This is a sensible user fee.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="21.333333333333332" PS="1.603723404255319" SM="6">The city's Commission on the Environment will consider the proposal Tuesday.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="12.857142857142858" PS="1.0691489361702127" SM="2">Mayor Gavin Newsom is reviewing the idea.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="22.0" PS="1.603723404255319" SM="16">The city's Department of the Environment estimates San Francisco customers bring home about 50 million bags each year.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="11.526315789473685" PS="1.0691489361702127" SM="2">That accounts for about 2 percent of waste, at an annual cleanup cost of about $8.4 million (euro6.45 million).</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="20.375" PS="1.603723404255319" SM="17">Grocers and the plastics industry oppose the measure.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="22.047619047619047" PS="1.603723404255319" SM="13">&quot;We think essentially it's an unnecessary and misguided approach,&quot; said Tim Shestek, spokesman for the American Plastics Council.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="21.428571428571427" PS="1.0691489361702127" SM="2">&quot;This tax is going to hurt those who can least afford it.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="18.5" PS="1.603723404255319" SM="11">State legislators defeated a bill last year that would have charged 2 cents on each non-recyclable disposable bag.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="18.423076923076923" PS="1.603723404255319" SM="26">The San Francisco proposal parallels efforts in Ireland, South Africa, Bangladesh, Australia, Shanghai and Taiwan, which ban plastic bags or charge a fee to use them.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="18.0" PS="2.513297872340426" SM="29">In San Francisco, the free grocery bag soon might go the way of the full-service gas station.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="18.81578947368421" PS="1.6755319148936172" SM="44">City officials are considering charging grocery stores 17 cents apiece for the bags, 90 percent of which are plastic -- and are blamed by environmentalists for everything from clogging recycling machines to killing marine life and suffocating infants.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="18.516129032258064" PS="1.6755319148936172" SM="26">Although the environmentalists are not as concerned about the effect of recyclable paper bags on the environment, the proposal would include them, too, with the idea of reducing waste in general.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="16.727272727272727" PS="1.6755319148936172" SM="6">In turn, the fee would be passed on to the consumer.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="8.666666666666666" PS="1.1170212765957448" SM="10">Proponents of the surcharge hope this will persuade shoppers to give up the convenience of the disposable sack.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="15.5" PS="1.6755319148936172" SM="8">&quot;Yes, it's going to be a pain the ass, but that's part of the point,&quot; said Mark Murray, executive director of Californians Against Waste.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="10.8" PS="1.1170212765957448" SM="6">&quot;One thing we've learned is that sending a financial signal to the marketplace tends to modify behavior much better than voluntary approaches.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="15.933333333333334" PS="1.6755319148936172" SM="17">Trade groups representing grocers and the plastics industry predictably aren't crazy about the idea.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="22.047619047619047" PS="1.6755319148936172" SM="13">&quot;We think essentially it's an unnecessary and misguided approach,&quot; said Tim Shestek, spokesman for the American Plastics Council.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="21.428571428571427" PS="1.1170212765957448" SM="2">&quot;This tax is going to hurt those who can least afford it.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="22.942857142857143" PS="1.6755319148936172" SM="37">The proposal, set to be considered by the Commission on the Environment on Tuesday, imitates efforts around the world to stem the use of plastic bags -- known in China as &quot;white pollution.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="16.666666666666668" PS="1.1170212765957448" SM="32">Ireland, South Africa, Bangladesh, Australia, Shanghai and Taiwan are just a few of the places where the government either bans plastic bags outright or charges a fee to use them.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="7.909090909090909" PS="1.6755319148936172" SM="5">Trade groups contend that the results of those efforts are mixed.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="20.62162162162162" PS="1.1170212765957448" SM="38">In Ireland, for example, there is anecdotal evidence of increased shoplifting as people bring in their own bags and higher sales of boxes of plastic bags, which consumers use for everything from pet waste to trash cans.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="16.48148148148148" PS="1.6755319148936172" SM="17">Murray said the local effort is the first in California after an Assembly bill to levy a statewide 2-cents charge on nonrecyclable disposable bags failed last year.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="17.166666666666668" PS="1.6755319148936172" SM="8">&quot;We've attempted to pursue this at a state level, but the lobbyists for the retail industry are too strong,&quot; he said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="11.96" PS="1.6755319148936172" SM="12">After being considered by the commission, the proposal would move to the mayor's office or the Board of Supervisors in search of legislative sponsors.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="17.916666666666668" PS="1.1170212765957448" SM="2">A spokesman for Mayor Gavin Newsom said the mayor is reviewing it.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="15.552631578947368" PS="1.1170212765957448" SM="16">Meanwhile, the proposal has at least one potential champion on the Board of Supervisors, the newly elected Ross Mirkarimi, who helped found the city's Department of the Environment, which is overseen by the Commission on the Environment.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="12.55813953488372" PS="1.6755319148936172" SM="5">&quot;We all have a responsibility to promote a healthy and sustainable environment, and by doing that, it means we need to help change people's patterns, and that even means their shopping patterns,&quot; said Mirkarimi, who will take office in January.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="28.125" PS="1.1170212765957448" SM="0">&quot;This is a sensible user fee.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="6.864864864864865" PS="1.6755319148936172" SM="17">The proposal, which takes the form of a resolution urging the mayor and board to take action, also suggests expanding the surcharge in the future beyond grocers to include drug stores, dry cleaners, newspapers and other retailers.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="18.857142857142858" PS="1.6755319148936172" SM="29">According to the Department of the Environment, consumers lug home about 50 million bags from San Francisco grocery stores each year.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="21.285714285714285" PS="1.1170212765957448" SM="13">Of those, 90 percent are nonrecyclable plastic.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="14.79245283018868" PS="1.6755319148936172" SM="30">A report prepared in support of the proposal by Robert Haley, recycling program manager for the environment department, says plastic bags gum up recycling and composting machines at Norcal -- San Francisco's waste management provider -- resulting in $1 million in extra costs and lost revenue from the sale of recyclable materials.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="23.65625" PS="1.6755319148936172" SM="31">The bags account for 2 percent of the city's total &quot;waste stream,&quot; and picking up and disposing littered bags cost an additional $7.4 million annually, according to the report.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="15.964285714285714" PS="1.6755319148936172" SM="30">It notes that an estimated 12 million barrels of oil go into the production of plastic bags, while 14 million trees are felled to make their paper counterparts.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="13.631578947368421" PS="1.6755319148936172" SM="7">Paul Smith, vice president of the California Grocers Association, said the proposal is strongly opposed by the industry group.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="16.842105263157894" PS="1.6755319148936172" SM="4">&quot;We're not sure where it came from or ... where the 17 cents is going to go.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="16.09090909090909" PS="1.1170212765957448" SM="1">There's not really a lot of accountability,&quot; Smith said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="16.2" PS="1.6755319148936172" SM="22">According to the proposal, grocers would be able to keep half of the fee and would be expected to spend it on city-approved programs, such as discounted reusable shopping bags.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="23.025" PS="1.6755319148936172" SM="64">Shestek, the American Plastics Council spokesman, said some of the costs attributed to plastic bags could be recouped by sending plastic bag waste to companies that can use it as a raw material, such as decking and composite lumber producers.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="10.172413793103448" PS="1.6755319148936172" SM="10">Heidi Melander, president of the Northern California Recycling Association, a supporter of the proposal, said the fee was a tangible way the public can participate in helping reduce waste.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="32.63636363636363" PS="1.6755319148936172" SM="13">&quot;We've been trained to want bags,&quot; she said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="17.413793103448278" PS="1.1170212765957448" SM="13">&quot;It's gotten out of hand -- everywhere you go, they force them on you, and they think you're weird if you don't take a bag.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="9.933333333333334" PS="1.1170212765957448" SM="4">We might not have control over the blister packaging around the electronic equipment we buy.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="32.111111111111114" PS="1.1170212765957448" SM="12">But we have control over taking that bag.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="15.666666666666666" PS="2.3816489361702127" SM="16">The Ugandan government is considering a total ban on polythene bags after a 50 percent excise duty has failed to reduce their production and usage, reported local press on Tuesday.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="11.0" PS="1.5877659574468086" SM="19">Minister of State for Trade Richard Nduhura was quoted as saying that the rampant use of polythene bags has led to environmental disasters like blockage of drainages, suffocation of children and animals and soil degradation.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="17.714285714285715" PS="1.5877659574468086" SM="12">&quot;An excise duty of 50 percent was imposed on plastics in June 2002.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="16.595238095238095" PS="1.0585106382978724" SM="42">It has not deterred indiscriminate use of the plastics, prompting us to take drastic measures,&quot; Nduhura said at a meeting on plastics waste management and development of environmentally- degradable plastics in Kampala which was attended by delegates from eight African countries.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="13.047619047619047" PS="1.5877659574468086" SM="17">He added that the government was still looking at optional measures like controlling importation, production, usage and disposal of polythene bags.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="14.804878048780488" PS="2.3816489361702127" SM="26">I've gotten more than 70 e-mails responding to my Tuesday column about the San Francisco Commission on the Environment's resolution urging the Board of Supervisors to force supermarkets in the city to charge shoppers 17 cents apiece for bags.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="11.352941176470589" PS="1.5877659574468086" SM="3">Roughly one-third of these readers love the idea, saying it will cut down on waste and trash.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="16.77777777777778" PS="1.0585106382978724" SM="15">Some say the proposal doesn't go far enough, that fees should apply to other stores and bags.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="9.571428571428571" PS="1.5877659574468086" SM="5">Roughly one-third hate the idea, saying it's a government plot to raise taxes.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="9.5" PS="1.5877659574468086" SM="6">The remaining third might warm to the idea, but have some questions and reservations.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="17.833333333333332" PS="1.5877659574468086" SM="12">Today, I'll share some of these comments, but after this, please, no more feedback on bag fees.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="15.875" PS="1.5877659574468086" SM="13">-- The European scene: More than a dozen e-mails came from people who live or have lived in Germany, Switzerland, Ireland, Norway or South Africa, where charging for shopping bags is common.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="12.3125" PS="1.0585106382978724" SM="1">Virtually all of them said it's a minor expense or inconvenience, but well worth it.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="25.555555555555557" PS="1.5877659574468086" SM="26">&quot;My native Germany charges a fee for these bags, and people respond in the best way for the environment -- they bring their own tote bags!</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="17.708333333333332" PS="1.0585106382978724" SM="18">When I came to the U.S. seven years ago, I was astonished (and disgusted) by the practice of using new bags on each trip.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="12.755555555555556" PS="1.0585106382978724" SM="18">And while I have to admit that I easily fell into this behavior myself, the proposed legislation reminded me that bringing my own tote bag is an easy way to be a good citizen of our one and only planet Earth,&quot; says Franziska Marks.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="12.333333333333334" PS="1.5877659574468086" SM="0">&quot;I am an Irish citizen living in S.F.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="9.0" PS="1.0585106382978724" SM="2">I remember the same excuses being trotted out when this was first introduced in Ireland (in 2002).</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="8.675" PS="1.0585106382978724" SM="21">The key difference is that the retailers embraced this change as a way to tout their 'green' credentials by offering a free, sturdy shopping tote to each club member for a limited time to carry their groceries (enabling free advertising).</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="23.105263157894736" PS="1.0585106382978724" SM="27">It really has dramatically reduced the level of plastic bag waste all over the country,&quot; writes Ray Walsh.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="18.866666666666667" PS="1.5877659574468086" SM="13">-- Pooper scoopers: Many readers told me they put their old bags to good use.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="17.6875" PS="1.0585106382978724" SM="25">One even sent me a photo of her kitchen recycling center, rigged to hold plastic bags.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="51.45454545454545" PS="1.5877659574468086" SM="44">&quot;Everybody I know uses plastic grocery bags for garbage bags.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="9.444444444444445" PS="1.0585106382978724" SM="8">They use them to go to the dog park, empty the kitty litter, and a dozen other things.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="33.888888888888886" PS="1.0585106382978724" SM="58">If you don't get plastic bags with your groceries, then you would have to buy plastic bags.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="10.307692307692308" PS="1.0585106382978724" SM="4">So it sort of defeats the purpose,&quot; writes Jim Knowles of Alameda.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="13.38888888888889" PS="1.5877659574468086" SM="17">&quot;Considering the estimated 85,000 dogs in San Francisco, has anyone factored the additional citywide expense in cleaning up poo that people will refuse to pick up in a 17-cent bag three times a day?&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="1.3333333333333333" PS="1.0585106382978724" SM="0">asks Melinda Graves.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="24.142857142857142" PS="1.5877659574468086" SM="13">&quot;For about eight years, I have reused bags many times because I want to do my part for our environment.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="16.58823529411765" PS="1.0585106382978724" SM="12">In fact, for one month, I kept count of how many times I reused a single bag.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="18.3125" PS="1.0585106382978724" SM="15">Seventeen times in one month meant that 17 bags were not sent to the dump!&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="3.3333333333333335" PS="1.0585106382978724" SM="0">writes Charlotte Pederson.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="34.0" PS="1.5877659574468086" SM="11">I feel a book coming on: &quot;101 Uses for Old Bags.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="7.333333333333333" PS="1.5877659574468086" SM="0">-- Fuzzy math?</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="19.425531914893618" PS="1.0585106382978724" SM="58">My column explained that the San Francisco Department of the Environment came up with the 17 cents by dividing the environmental cost of used grocery bags ($8.5 million annually) by the estimated number of plastic and paper bags distributed in San Francisco supermarkets each year (50 million).</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="21.054054054054053" PS="1.5877659574468086" SM="49">The $8.5 million is the departments' estimate of what it costs the city to sweep up and dispose of bags, plus what it costs Norcal Waste Systems to remove plastic bags from its recycling and composting system.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="9.882352941176471" PS="1.5877659574468086" SM="0">Some readers point out that city residents already pay for these costs through taxes and garbage-collection fees.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="15.653846153846153" PS="1.5877659574468086" SM="4">&quot;Shouldn't the amount that is presently being paid for garbage service be taken into consideration when determining how much it really costs the city?</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="15.416666666666666" PS="1.0585106382978724" SM="6">Or are residents supposed to pay twice for the same service?&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="1.3333333333333333" PS="1.0585106382978724" SM="0">asks David Schnapf.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="17.386363636363637" PS="1.5877659574468086" SM="31">Engineer Neil Lillemark says the city's calculation ignores two facts: Some of the 50 million bags distributed each year get reused and don't go immediately into the waste stream, and a fee would cut bag consumption (and thus the city's costs).</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="18.5" PS="1.5877659574468086" SM="16">Using certain assumptions, he suggests that &quot;10 cents a bag would be a more fair estimate of the charge which should be applied if they were to go this route.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="16.580645161290324" PS="1.5877659574468086" SM="19">Some readers suggested it would be more economically efficient to ban free bags, but to allow grocers to sell them for those who forget or choose not to use their own.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="7.625" PS="1.0585106382978724" SM="7">That would eliminate the cost of creating a system to collect, track and distribute the fees.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="19.41025641025641" PS="1.5877659574468086" SM="17">Mark Westlund, spokesman for the environment department, said the 17-cent fee is not set in stone, and if a bag fee went into effect, a reduction in taxes and/or garbage fees &quot;certainly could be on the table.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="15.777777777777779" PS="1.0585106382978724" SM="6">He adds that the department &quot;would be open to any ideas that would address the issue.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="11.095238095238095" PS="1.5877659574468086" SM="2">-- Bad bagger behavior: Several readers said grocers could reduce waste if they simply instructed their baggers to use fewer sacks.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="27.14814814814815" PS="1.5877659574468086" SM="33">&quot;Baggers can be careless, often double bagging for no reason, or putting one or two items in a bag that could have fit into another bag.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="18.405405405405407" PS="1.0585106382978724" SM="34">It's probably faster to use a lot of bags instead of trying to figure out how to make the best use of each bag, but it's so wasteful,&quot; says Sarah Stockton of Daly City.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="10.75" PS="1.5877659574468086" SM="7">Paul Smith, a vice president of the California Grocers Association, explains: &quot;We try to minimize breakage to product.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="14.1875" PS="1.0585106382978724" SM="20">If a bag breaks when a customer is moving it from store to car or car to kitchen, most stores that are members of his association will replace the contents for free.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="21.0" PS="1.5877659574468086" SM="2">&quot;There are marketing reasons why we do this,&quot; he says.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="19.952380952380953" PS="1.0585106382978724" SM="18">However, &quot;There are retailers who are right now evaluating their clerk and bagger training to (encourage) reduction of bags.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="14.323529411764707" PS="1.5877659574468086" SM="17">-- Good question: Ford Kanzler of El Granada writes: &quot;I've often wondered why food markets don't sell reusable cloth bags at the check stand (along with) all the impulse-purchase junk.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="27.5" PS="1.5877659574468086" SM="11">-- Who knows where that bag has been?</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="24.25" PS="1.0585106382978724" SM="11">Mike McHugh fears reusing bags may be unhealthful.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="45.5" PS="1.5877659574468086" SM="11">&quot;A new bag is clean!</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="9.5" PS="1.0585106382978724" SM="1">Customers can return home with their items confident that their purchases have been protected from dirt and germs.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="19.7" PS="1.0585106382978724" SM="11">An old reused bag cannot guarantee such a situation.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="9.733333333333333" PS="1.0585106382978724" SM="3">It may be dirty, even if you can't see the dirt with your eyes.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="15.473684210526315" PS="1.0585106382978724" SM="16">It might have held raw meat that may have bled ever so little onto the sides of the bag.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="25.153846153846153" PS="1.0585106382978724" SM="15">The bag might even have previously been used to carry poisonous substances!&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="9.0" PS="1.0585106382978724" SM="0">he writes.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="19.392857142857142" PS="1.5877659574468086" SM="35">Point of interest: When Ireland imposed a 15-cent charge on all plastic shopping bags in 2002, it exempted a number of bags, including those that hold raw meat.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="8.25" PS="1.5877659574468086" SM="0">-- Why just supermarkets?</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="8.8" PS="1.0585106382978724" SM="4">Some readers wonder why the proposal applies only to grocers.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="18.785714285714285" PS="1.5877659574468086" SM="2">&quot;Saving the environment can be done in many ways,&quot; writes Catherine Ying.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="21.564102564102566" PS="1.0585106382978724" SM="36">&quot;Instead of making our life more complicated by charging for shopping bags, why don't we start with something that is more of a luxury, such as Diaper Genie,&quot; which wraps dirty disposable diapers in plastic bags.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="14.714285714285714" PS="1.5877659574468086" SM="19">&quot;What about stores like Walgreens that try to put every little item in a bag -- even if the customer is a woman with a large handbag,&quot; writes Beth Wells of San Francisco.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="16.545454545454547" PS="1.0585106382978724" SM="13">And how about restaurants that put food &quot;in those toxic Styrofoam boxes and then put the box in a bag.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="26.5" PS="1.5877659574468086" SM="24">&quot;What bugs me is that my Chronicle is delivered every day in a plastic bag.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="13.03125" PS="1.0585106382978724" SM="2">They are limited in their re-use -- I don't have a dog and don't travel that often, as they make excellent wrappers for shoes or slippers,&quot; writes Doug Stewart.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="20.75" PS="1.5877659574468086" SM="26">Chris Blaser, The Chronicle's circulation vice president responds: &quot;Our policy is to only deliver newspapers in plastic bags on rainy/heavy fog days.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="24.833333333333332" PS="1.0585106382978724" SM="15">Our other general rule is to bag when the forecast is mixed.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="17.37037037037037" PS="1.5877659574468086" SM="16">&quot;We do, however, have some carriers who bag more frequently (of their own initiative) in an effort to assure that the paper is in good condition.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="13.181818181818182" PS="1.0585106382978724" SM="14">We do notify any of these carriers to stop bagging (except on rainy days) whenever we receive a call from a customer.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="28.066666666666666" PS="1.0585106382978724" SM="24">We also make sure the plastic bags we buy come primarily from recycled materials.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="18.210526315789473" PS="1.5877659574468086" SM="15">Westlund says the city might consider extending bag fees &quot;to other areas like fast foods, drug stores, etc.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="20.285714285714285" PS="1.0585106382978724" SM="0">Right now (it's) strictly supermarkets.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="26.0" PS="2.5372340425531914" SM="11">LOS ANGELES - Paper or plastic?</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="8.0" PS="1.6914893617021276" SM="0">It might not matter soon.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="13.055555555555555" PS="1.6914893617021276" SM="19">Supermarket shoppers could end up paying for selecting either bag if Los Angeles politicians follow a San Francisco proposal -- and the advice of some environmentalists -- to recoup the cost of cleaning up grocery-sack litter.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="13.4" PS="1.6914893617021276" SM="18">San Francisco officials are considering a fee of 17 cents per bag in a bid to encourage Bay Area shoppers to bring their own sacks.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="5.75" PS="1.6914893617021276" SM="3">Los Angeles city leaders also want to get rid of grocery-bag blight.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="14.555555555555555" PS="1.127659574468085" SM="41">Hoping to avoid drastic measures, Councilman Ed Reyes wants manufacturers of plastics and officials in grocery chains to partner with him on bag cleanups and recycling programs.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="15.7" PS="1.6914893617021276" SM="4">&quot;San Francisco has the wherewithal to charge that much.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="16.9" PS="1.127659574468085" SM="0">San Francisco has a different income group,&quot; Reyes said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="16.0" PS="1.127659574468085" SM="3">&quot;Here in Los Angeles, I would rather work with the industry before we get into that.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="17.5" PS="1.6914893617021276" SM="30">Reyes' proposal to create a task force on plastic bags will likely go to the full City Council next week after being approved Wednesday by the council's Environmental Quality and Waste Management Committee.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="6.888888888888889" PS="1.127659574468085" SM="2">Reyes hopes the task force will hold its first meeting in March and produce recommendations 60 days later.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="11.0" PS="1.6914893617021276" SM="3">So far, plastics-industry representatives have said they will participate in Reyes' task force -- particularly in light of the proposed fee in San Francisco, which they oppose.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="23.366666666666667" PS="1.6914893617021276" SM="29">&quot;The bag manufacturers in the last few years have gotten together and realize there is an issue,&quot; said Donna Dempsey, executive director of the Film and Bag Federation.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="17.3" PS="1.127659574468085" SM="2">&quot;We're willing to work toward that goal.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="14.628571428571428" PS="1.6914893617021276" SM="31">All sides agree that plastic bags are a blight on the Los Angeles River, where hundreds of white sacks float on the shallow water, stick to rocks and dangle like Spanish moss from tree branches.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="10.8" PS="1.6914893617021276" SM="7">City officials were spurred to action by a new mandate to cut trash from the river and from Ballona Creek by 10 percent each year, starting this year, at an estimated cost of $120 million.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="19.6" PS="1.6914893617021276" SM="41">Plastics make up more than half of all the trash in the river, and plastic bags alone constitute slightly more than one-third of the litter.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="15.0" PS="1.6914893617021276" SM="11">Unlike paper or wood or other organic garbage, plastics don't biodegrade.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="9.8125" PS="1.127659574468085" SM="2">They cause environmental damage by breaking into smaller pieces that are eaten by fish and wildlife.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="23.6" PS="1.127659574468085" SM="24">Plastic bags also clog the screens installed on storm drains that filter trash from runoff.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="24.363636363636363" PS="1.6914893617021276" SM="16">&quot;Plastic is the single most important component of the litter.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="15.055555555555555" PS="1.127659574468085" SM="6">It's also the most environmentally damaging,&quot; said Kosta Kaporis, an engineer with the Bureau of Sanitation.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="28.714285714285715" PS="1.127659574468085" SM="2">&quot;It's aesthetically the worst.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="6.9411764705882355" PS="1.6914893617021276" SM="9">Los Angeles River ad hoc committee staffer Lupe Vela is in charge of task force preparation and hopes to bring industry representatives to the table first to see if they can develop voluntary programs.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="27.733333333333334" PS="1.6914893617021276" SM="36">Right now only about 5 percent of the plastic used in grocery bags is recycled.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="21.413793103448278" PS="1.127659574468085" SM="35">Some grocery stores have bins in which to deposit used bags, and some offer a discount -- 5 cents or less -- for shoppers who bring their own bags.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="27.333333333333332" PS="1.6914893617021276" SM="12">And bags can't be mixed with curbside recyclables.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="7.545454545454546" PS="1.127659574468085" SM="2">They stick to bottles and cans, and they clog sorting equipment.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="21.82608695652174" PS="1.127659574468085" SM="26">Yet there is a demand for the raw material by companies that use old sacks to make more bags or plastic building materials.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="19.615384615384617" PS="1.6914893617021276" SM="15">The task force will likely talk about ways to collect and recycle bags.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="11.1" PS="1.127659574468085" SM="23">Members are virtually certain to consider public-education campaigns to get people to stop littering, to bring their own reusable bags when they shop, and to participate in neighborhood cleanup programs.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="12.533333333333333" PS="1.6914893617021276" SM="19">But some question whether voluntary, public-private programs will deliver the kind of dramatic cut in plastic litter that is needed for the city of Los Angeles to meet trash regulations.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="17.274509803921568" PS="1.6914893617021276" SM="43">&quot;I'm skeptical that the plastics industry is going to be capable of coming up with a solution that involves fewer numbers of plastic bags being sold,&quot; said Mark Murray, executive director of Californians Against Waste, which has pushed San Francisco and Los Angeles authorities to consider fee-per-bag systems.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="21.448275862068964" PS="1.6914893617021276" SM="41">He points to the success in Ireland, where use of plastic bags dropped by 90 percent a year after the nation imposed a fee of 15 cents per bag.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="15.178571428571429" PS="1.6914893617021276" SM="23">Though Reyes champions the partnership with industry and the community now, he said he is open to tougher means to get bags out of the Los Angeles River.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="25.264705882352942" PS="1.6914893617021276" SM="40">&quot;Maybe we'll come up with a fine or a tax for the plastic bags, and give the bag some value, so people will think twice before throwing it on the streets.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="3.0" PS="1.6914893617021276" SM="0">X X X</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="14.285714285714286" PS="2.5372340425531914" SM="34">Kenya is being swamped with a flood of  discarded plastic shopping bags that pose a growing public health  risk and should take steps to ban the popular lould be banned and a hefty levy  slapped on thicker ones to rid Kenya of an increasing environmental  and health menace,&quot;  the United Nations Environment Programme (UNEP)  said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="9.947368421052632" PS="1.6914893617021276" SM="9">The call came in a study of Kenya's solid waste management  presented to UNEP governors who are currently meeting at the  agency's headquarters here and was backed by Wangari Maathai, last  year's Nobel Peace Prize.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="16.43243243243243" PS="1.6914893617021276" SM="30">Discarded plastic bags &quot;provide several million habitats for  mosquitoes to breed that increase the risk of malaria,&quot; she said,  noting that the disease was a leading cause of infant mortality in  Kenya and throughout Africa.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="18.64" PS="1.6914893617021276" SM="36">Maathai, who serves as Kenya's deputy environment minister,  pledged to push the Kenyan government to adopt measures to reduce  the use of plastic bags.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="14.428571428571429" PS="1.6914893617021276" SM="17">Earlier this week, Kenyan President Mwai Kibaki told UNEP  officials that his government would address the problem posed by the  bags but Maathai said she wanted action now.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="16.5" PS="1.6914893617021276" SM="0">&quot;If I had my way, we would have started that immediately&quot; she  told reporters.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="12.263157894736842" PS="1.6914893617021276" SM="34">In addition to exacerbating the mosquito problem, plastic bags  block gutters and drains, choke farm animals and marine wildlife,  pollute the soil, can ruin Kenya's dramatic natural vistas and can  take 20 to 1,000 years to decompose.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="19.791666666666668" PS="1.6914893617021276" SM="27">In Europe, Ireland introduced a similar bid to cut down the use  of plastic bags in March 2002, then dubbed a &quot;plastax&quot;.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="22.85" PS="1.127659574468085" SM="27">By August  that year, shoppers had already cut the use of plastic bags by 90  percent, the environment ministry announced.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="20.02857142857143" PS="1.6914893617021276" SM="30">The government announced that the funds raised from a tax on  plastic bags would be used for an office for environment  enforcement, implementing a national waste prevention programme and  the disposal of fridges and freezers.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="5.857142857142857" PS="1.6914893617021276" SM="4">Rwanda and South Africa are moving towards a similar policy,  according to UNEP officials.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="14.095238095238095" PS="1.6914893617021276" SM="28">The state-run Kenya Institute for Public Policy Research and  Analysis (KIPPRA) and National Environmental Management Authority  (NEMA) said at least two million plastic bags a year were being  distributed to shoppers in Nairobi alone, many of which were not  disposed of properly.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="10.172413793103448" PS="1.6914893617021276" SM="16">More than 48 million thin plastic bagsng at a rate of 10 percent per year to  feed massive consumer demand at home and in neighboring countries,  the study said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="20.916666666666668" PS="2.549202127659574" SM="25">Uganda will soon ban the  manufacture and importation of plastic bags and impose a hefty  levy on thicker ones, an environment official has said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="9.303030303030303" PS="1.6994680851063828" SM="8">Dr. Aryamanya Mugisha, head of Uganda National Environment  Management Authority (NEMA), was quoted on Monday by local press  as saying that the measure would get rid of the increasing  environmental and health menace.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="20.848484848484848" PS="1.6994680851063828" SM="16">&quot;We are banning polythene bags and it is a matter of time for  them to become history,&quot; Mugisha said on Sunday in Nairobi, Kenya  where he is heading a NEMA delegation.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="21.3" PS="1.6994680851063828" SM="32">He said that the NEMA had made recommendations to the cabinet  to ban the plastic bags about five years ago.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="24.155555555555555" PS="1.6994680851063828" SM="51">Mugisha said a ban on plastic bags is among proposals aimed at  reducing the use of polythene, adding that but the tax imposed on  the plastic bags about two years ago has not helped in restricting their use because their price is still very low.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="31.0" PS="1.6994680851063828" SM="26">He said he expected the ban on plastic bags to be effected  later this year.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="20.864864864864863" PS="1.6994680851063828" SM="44">Rwanda imposed a ban on the manufacture and importation of  polythene bags last year, while the United Nations Environment  Program is working with the Kenyan government to ban plastic bags  there in a new waste management strategy.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="23.555555555555557" PS="1.6994680851063828" SM="29">Uganda is one of the few countries in the Great Lakes region  where plastic bags are not regulated.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="23.545454545454547" PS="1.1329787234042552" SM="54">Sources blamed the delay in  effecting the decision on ban the manufacture and importation of  plastic bags on the lack of political will and protecting those  who have invested heavily in plastic bags.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="10.86111111111111" PS="2.5252659574468086" SM="22">Parts of Eritrea once littered by a sea  of flimsy shopping bags are being cleaned up thanks to a new law  that entered into force in January to help the Horn of Africa  country protect nature.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="13.714285714285714" PS="1.6835106382978724" SM="21">In the capital Asmara and other outlying regions, the bags have  been replaced by the cotton and nylon and Eritreans have no choice  but to adapt to instead.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="20.612903225806452" PS="1.6835106382978724" SM="30">Since January, &quot;those who import, produce, distribute or sell  plastic bags are fined,&quot; said Wolde Yohannes, the head of  environment wing in the ministry of land, water and environment.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="6.9523809523809526" PS="1.6835106382978724" SM="6">Wolde did not give the amount of the fine, but several sources  estimated that offenders can pay several thousands of nakfa.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="7.571428571428571" PS="1.6835106382978724" SM="6">Since a dollar here is worth 15 nakfa, such fines are hefty in  the country where, according to an International Monetary Fund  report, annual Gross Domestic Product (GDP) per capita is 130  dollars (100 euros).</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="8.444444444444445" PS="1.6835106382978724" SM="7">Authorities here are indeed determined to stem the problem.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="31.416666666666668" PS="1.6835106382978724" SM="27">Individuals are not fined if they are caught with a plastic bag.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="21.333333333333332" PS="1.122340425531915" SM="17">They simply have to tell the authorities where they got the bag  from, explained Wolde.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="16.666666666666668" PS="1.6835106382978724" SM="2">&quot;If we find that individuals don't cooperate, they could also be  fined,&quot; said Kibrom Asmarom, an official in the environment  department.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="16.0" PS="1.6835106382978724" SM="2">Kibrom expressed satisfaction on people's respect on the law,  nevertheless.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="10.75" PS="1.6835106382978724" SM="21">Authorities had a raft of reasons for declaring war on the  flimsy bags that not only block gutters and drains, choke farm  animals and marine wildlife, pollute the soil, but also ruin  dramatic natural vistas and can take 20 to 1,000 years to  decompose.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="36.53846153846154" PS="1.6835106382978724" SM="26">&quot;The animals were eating the plastic bags and dying,&quot; Wolde  said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="6.823529411764706" PS="1.122340425531915" SM="2">Loss of livestock can be depressing in this poor country that  regulary suffers from bouts of drought.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="33.888888888888886" PS="1.6835106382978724" SM="17">&quot;The bags used to clog the drainage pipes.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="10.294117647058824" PS="1.122340425531915" SM="4">And they were thrown  everywhere, got stuck in the trees, and spoiled the landscape,&quot; he  added.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="15.689655172413794" PS="1.6835106382978724" SM="27">As animals were dying and drainage getting choked before the law  came into force, some areas around Asmara used to be covered by a  sea of coloured plastic bags.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="10.666666666666666" PS="1.122340425531915" SM="2">Unwittingly, goats and sheep chewed  them, the officials said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="12.375" PS="1.6835106382978724" SM="2">Authorities had better plans for the outlawed papers.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="25.555555555555557" PS="1.6835106382978724" SM="11">&quot;We don't burn them, factories which make plastic use them for  other purposes,&quot; said Wolde.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="19.53846153846154" PS="1.6835106382978724" SM="0">&quot;Only a few people have complained about this ban,&quot; he added.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="8.363636363636363" PS="1.6835106382978724" SM="7">With a threat of fine, Eritrean in the streets of Asmara have  no choice but to abide by this environmentally friendly law.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="18.105263157894736" PS="1.6835106382978724" SM="22">Others have even forgotten that plastic bags did exist and  littered their streets and trash-dumbing zones, just before  January.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="28.263157894736842" PS="1.6835106382978724" SM="24">&quot;People have already forgotten about plastic bags, they've moved  on to other things,&quot; quipped one Eritrean.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="8.794871794871796" PS="1.6835106382978724" SM="16">While Eritrea has kicked out plastics, a much needed backing  from  anti-plastic campaign rang at UN Environment Programme  governor's meeting in Kenya last week, with Nobel Peace Laureate  Wangari Maathai leading a league to ban the flimsy types.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="16.43243243243243" PS="1.6835106382978724" SM="30">Discarded plastic bags &quot;provide several million habitats for  mosquitoes to breed that increase the risk of malaria,&quot; she said,  noting that the disease was a leading cause of infant mortality in  Kenya and throughout Africa.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="18.92" PS="1.6835106382978724" SM="27">While in Europe, Ireland introduced a similar bid to cut down  the use of plastic bags in March 2002, then dubbed a &quot;plastax&quot;.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="22.85" PS="1.122340425531915" SM="27">By  August that year, shoppers had already cut the use of plastic bags  by 90 percent, the environment ministry announced.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="14.25925925925926" PS="2.4055851063829783" SM="21">Tanzania is on the way to  handle the increasing plastic waste through establishing a  recycling plant believed to be the first one in east and central  Africa.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="10.195652173913043" PS="1.603723404255319" SM="12">Minister for Industry and Trade Juma Ngasongwa was quoted by  local newspaper Daily News on Thursday as saying that the  Tanzanian government has set aside 1.5 million US dollars to  operate the recycling plant as the first phase of the country's  multi-million-dollar anti-plastic litter project.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="16.71875" PS="1.603723404255319" SM="31">The plant is expected to start operating in May this year, with the capacity of recycling every day about 10 tons of plastic bags, bottles and other industrial waste from collection centers.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="12.521739130434783" PS="1.603723404255319" SM="16">Plastic litter has become an environmental hazard in the east  African country where the public have not been made aware of  disposal methods.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="20.736842105263158" PS="1.0691489361702127" SM="24">The abandoned plastic bags and containers can be spotted in many towns, blamed for clogging sewage and drainage  systems.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="10.818181818181818" PS="1.0691489361702127" SM="0">It is also reported that cows died after eating this  material.</sentence>
	</Sentences>
</Topic>
