<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<Topic id="D0933F">
	<Sentences>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="11.476190476190476" PS="3.1071428571428568" SM="35">Children of older fathers face an enhanced risk of developing schizophrenia when they grow older, according to research published on Friday.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="7.64" PS="2.071428571428571" SM="19">Doctors in Sweden and Britain spotted the statistical risk after sifting through the medical records of 712,000 people born in Sweden between 1973 and 1980.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="15.882352941176471" PS="2.071428571428571" SM="12">They identified 639 people who had been hospitalised with schizophrenia at some point between 1989 and 2001.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="5.833333333333333" PS="1.380952380952381" SM="11">Only four of these were siblings.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="10.973684210526315" PS="2.071428571428571" SM="35">After taking into account the patients' socioeconomic background, family history of psychosis, early parental death and other factors that could affect the outcome, the researchers found a strong statistical link between schizophrenics and the age of their father.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="16.448275862068964" PS="2.071428571428571" SM="18">More than 15 percent of cases may have been due to the fact that the patient had a father who was aged over 30 years at birth, they believe.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="18.63157894736842" PS="2.071428571428571" SM="41">The risk of schizophrenia was statistically small but rose steadily the greater the age of the father at birth.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="12.029411764705882" PS="2.071428571428571" SM="24">The authors say this statistical evidence adds to previous research that points to an inherited source for schizophrenia and that mutations in sperm, which accumulate as a man gets older, contribute to the risk.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="13.1" PS="2.071428571428571" SM="40">Schizophrenia is a severe disease of the brain, characterised by hallucinations and delusions that give a distorted view of reality.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="19.53846153846154" PS="1.380952380952381" SM="13">It is not, as is popularly thought, a Jekyll-and-Hyde condition of split personality.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="19.214285714285715" PS="2.071428571428571" SM="15">The study is published by BMJ Online First, of the British Medical Journal (BMJ).</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="17.176470588235293" PS="1.380952380952381" SM="14">Its lead author is Finn Rasmussen, an associate professor of epidemiology at the Karolinska Institute in Stockholm.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="11.764705882352942" PS="2.071428571428571" SM="8">The doctors say that their findings are important, given the trend in developed countries towards delaying parenthood.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="14.115384615384615" PS="2.071428571428571" SM="42">In the case of England and Wales, they note that the average age of fathers at the birth of their child was 29.2 years in 1980.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="11.875" PS="1.380952380952381" SM="1">In 2002, this had risen to 32.1 years.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="14.454545454545455" PS="2.071428571428571" SM="27">If the model is correct, this increase in paternal age could have led to an additional 720 cases of schizophrenia in 2002.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="1.0" PS="2.071428571428571" SM="0">Health-disease-schizophrenia-X%</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="12.043478260869565" PS="2.2857142857142856" SM="8">Researchers in Iceland have discovered a region in the human genome that, among Europeans, appears to promote fertility, and maybe longevity as well.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="18.945945945945947" PS="1.5238095238095237" SM="32">Though the region, a stretch of DNA on the 17th chromosome, occurs in people of all countries, it is much more common in Europeans, as if its effect is set off by something in the European environment.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="18.150943396226417" PS="1.0158730158730158" SM="38">A further unusual property is that the genetic region has a much more ancient lineage than most human genes, and the researchers suggest, as one possible explanation, that it could have entered the human genome through interbreeding with one of the archaic human lineages that developed in parallel with that of modern humans.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="16.4" PS="1.5238095238095237" SM="23">The genetic region was discovered by scientists at DeCode Genetics, a biotechnology company in Reykjavik, Iceland, which has made the Icelandic population, with its comprehensive genealogy and medical records, a prime hunting ground for the genetic roots of common diseases.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="12.76" PS="1.0158730158730158" SM="16">Their finding is published in Monday's issue of Nature Genetics in a report by Kari Stefansson, Augustine Kong, Hreinn Stefansson and other DeCode scientists.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="16.944444444444443" PS="1.5238095238095237" SM="4">The report seems likely to receive considerable attention, even though it raises as many questions as it answers.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="20.155555555555555" PS="1.0158730158730158" SM="22">&quot;I thought it was one of the most interesting papers in population genetics I have ever read,&quot; said Nick Patterson, a mathematician at the Broad Institute in Cambridge, Mass., who advised DeCode on the article but has no other connection with the company.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="15.9" PS="1.5238095238095237" SM="10">The DNA region came to light during the search for a schizophrenia-causing gene, which turned out not to be there.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="16.8125" PS="1.0158730158730158" SM="10">But the DeCode researchers noticed that the DNA sequences they had examined did not seem to agree with those in the standard human genome sequence, said Kari Stefansson, DeCode's chief executive.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="14.956521739130435" PS="1.5238095238095237" SM="35">The lack of agreement turned out to be caused by the fact that the region exists in two forms in the Icelandic population.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="12.482758620689655" PS="1.0158730158730158" SM="44">The region is not a single gene but a vast section of DNA, some 900,000 units in length, situated in the 17th of the 23 pairs of human chromosomes.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="19.7" PS="1.0158730158730158" SM="9">In some Icelanders, the DeCode team found, the section runs in the standard direction, but in others it is flipped.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="15.619047619047619" PS="1.0158730158730158" SM="8">Looking for any physical consequence, the DeCode researchers found that women carrying the inverted section tended to have slightly more children.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="15.875" PS="1.5238095238095237" SM="14">The section carries several known genes, not one of which has any obvious connection with fertility.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="21.263157894736842" PS="1.0158730158730158" SM="16">It is not clear why inverting the section should have any effect on the number of children, Stefansson said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="14.173913043478262" PS="1.0158730158730158" SM="41">But the inversion does increase the rate of recombination, the shuffling of genes between generations that is a major source of genetic novelty.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="14.6" PS="1.0158730158730158" SM="16">That could account for some of the increase in fertility.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="15.064516129032258" PS="1.5238095238095237" SM="24">The DeCode scientists found that the chromosome-17 inversion is rare in Africans and almost absent in Asians, but is present in 20 percent of Europeans, the same frequency as in Iceland.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="13.238095238095237" PS="1.0158730158730158" SM="6">The inversion seems to have been favored by natural selection among Europeans in fairly recent times, perhaps the past 10,000 years.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="20.666666666666668" PS="1.0158730158730158" SM="6">&quot;Maybe something switched it on in the European environment, such as an interaction with diet,&quot; said David Reich, a population geneticist at the Broad Institute.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="3.0" PS="1.5238095238095237" SM="0">(BEGIN OPTIONAL TRIM.)</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="18.814814814814813" PS="1.5238095238095237" SM="6">Fertility is without doubt affected by different genes in different populations, and DeCode found a genetic element special to Europeans because that is where it was looking.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="13.1" PS="1.0158730158730158" SM="50">The increased frequency of the inversion in Europeans is one of a growing number of examples of recent human evolution.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="19.571428571428573" PS="1.5238095238095237" SM="2">The inversion itself, however, is surprisingly ancient.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="22.866666666666667" PS="1.0158730158730158" SM="13">Its age is revealed by its counterpart, the standard or noninverted section of chromosome 17.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="10.947368421052632" PS="1.0158730158730158" SM="5">The standard and inverted regions cannot exchange genetic elements during recombination because their DNA sequences do not match.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="11.958333333333334" PS="1.0158730158730158" SM="29">Hence, unlike most of the rest of the genome, which gets shuffled in each generation, the two forms have existed separately since their creation.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="12.380952380952381" PS="1.0158730158730158" SM="6">This event presumably happened when the region came adrift from its parent chromosome and got knitted back in the opposite way.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="12.862068965517242" PS="1.5238095238095237" SM="19">When all the known versions of a human gene are compared, in most cases they turn out to have had a single common ancestor about a million years ago.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="10.4" PS="1.0158730158730158" SM="17">But the standard and flipped versions of the chromosome 17 region last shared a common ancestor 3 million years ago.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="13.814814814814815" PS="1.0158730158730158" SM="27">It is highly unusual for two versions of a gene to endure for so long, because one will usually get lost by a natural process of elimination.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="20.0" PS="1.5238095238095237" SM="2">The DeCode researchers propose two explanations.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="18.17241379310345" PS="1.0158730158730158" SM="20">One is that the standard and flipped versions confer different advantages, so that it is beneficial for a person to have inherited a copy of each from different parents.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="7.466666666666667" PS="1.0158730158730158" SM="14">This balancing selection can keep two versions of a gene around in a population indefinitely.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="16.216216216216218" PS="1.5238095238095237" SM="34">DeCode's alternative proposal is that the flipped version was carried for many years in a different human lineage, one of the archaic populations that preceded the emergence of anatomically modern humans in Africa 150,000 years ago.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="9.148148148148149" PS="1.0158730158730158" SM="28">Then, in some episode of interbreeding, a single copy of the flipped version entered the modern human lineage some time before humans left Africa 60,000 years ago.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="14.2" PS="1.5238095238095237" SM="16">In support of this view, the flipped version carries far fewer mutations than does the standard version, as if it had been accumulating them from a much more recent date.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="12.205882352941176" PS="1.0158730158730158" SM="29">There have been other recent hints of modern human interaction with archaic hominids, notably the finding in October that a lineage of body lice seems to have been inherited from a different human species.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="2.3333333333333335" PS="1.5238095238095237" SM="0">(END OPTIONAL TRIM.)</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="20.52173913043478" PS="1.5238095238095237" SM="17">Stefansson said that another property of the inversion, though one not described in Monday's article, was that it is associated with longevity.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="16.31578947368421" PS="1.0158730158730158" SM="1">DeCode scientists have located two sites on Icelanders' genomes where there is some genetic variant that promotes longer lifespan.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="17.153846153846153" PS="1.0158730158730158" SM="13">The chromosome 17 inversion, it turns out, lies at one of these sites.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="9.6" PS="1.0158730158730158" SM="6">It occurs at much higher frequency in women over 95 and in men over 90 than in the normal population.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="17.61111111111111" PS="1.0158730158730158" SM="5">&quot;It seems to confer on people the ability to live to extreme old age,&quot; Stefansson said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="10.052631578947368" PS="1.5238095238095237" SM="30">It is particularly surprising that the same genetic element should promote fertility and longevity, because most organisms are obliged to follow a strategy either of breeding fast during short lives or of living longer and having fewer children.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="13.384615384615385" PS="1.0158730158730158" SM="13">&quot;Usually people think of there being a tradeoff between fertility and longevity.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="14.523809523809524" PS="1.0158730158730158" SM="16">So we are getting a free lunch here,&quot; said Dr. Alan Rogers, a population geneticist at the University of Utah.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="16.133333333333333" PS="1.5238095238095237" SM="2">Stefansson said his findings were empirical observations for which functional explanations have yet to emerge.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="18.666666666666668" PS="1.0158730158730158" SM="15">Despite the loose ends, other researchers seem impressed with the solidity of DeCode's findings.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="20.416666666666668" PS="1.0158730158730158" SM="6">&quot;It's a startling and amazing claim, and it's actually pretty convincing and compelling evidence at the same time,&quot; Reich said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="11.771428571428572" PS="2.25" SM="31">Alarmed by the rising consumption of  cannabis among French teenagers, the government on Wednesday  launched a 10-million euro (13 million dollar) campaign to warn of  the drug's harmful effects on physical and mental health.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="11.612244897959183" PS="1.5" SM="21">With more than one in five 18 year-old boys claiming to be  regular users -- and more than half of all 17 year-olds having  smoked cannabis at least once -- France has the highest consumption  rate in Europe along with Britain and the Czech Republic, according  to official figures.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="13.804347826086957" PS="1.5" SM="72">The media campaign -- including a series of radio and television  advertisements and the distribution of hundreds of thousands of  leaflets -- is to &quot;set the myth of cannabis against the reality in  order to debunk notions about its alleged harmlessness,&quot; the  ministry said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="10.44" PS="1.5" SM="9">Nearly 250 consultation centres are also to be established  across the country, and a telephone hotline set up to advise those  tempted by the drug.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="15.4375" PS="1.0" SM="17">From the start of the next academic year, the  campaign will be extended inside secondary schools.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="10.357142857142858" PS="1.5" SM="30">According to the French Observatory on Drugs and Addiction  (OFDT), there are 850,000 regular consumers of cannabis in the  country -- of whom 450,000 smoke cannabis every day.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="19.444444444444443" PS="1.0" SM="16">The number of  17 year-olds who have experimented with it has doubled in ten years,  the OFDT calcalates.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="14.142857142857142" PS="1.5" SM="15">Toxicologists have established that the cannabis widely consumed  today is far stronger than the drug that became current in  university campuses in the 1960s and 70s, and warn that the  psychological damage is greatly underestimated.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="10.217391304347826" PS="1.5" SM="9">Among the harmful effects to be highlighted in the campaign are  memory loss, concentration lapses, altered perception and alienation  from friends and family.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="10.333333333333334" PS="1.5" SM="28">&quot;There is a syndrome of demotivation which results in a lack of  interest in school work and a gradual desocialisation.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="12.741935483870968" PS="1.0" SM="28">At the same  time we now have proof of the link between cannabis abuse and  certain acute or chronic psychotic conditions,&quot; said Dr Michel  Reynaud, author of Cannabis and Health.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="14.214285714285714" PS="1.5" SM="26">Recent studies have established that cannabis can be a  contributory cause in triggering schizophrenia.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="13.814814814814815" PS="1.5" SM="30">Concern over cannabis use has grown in recent years after a  series of fatal road accidents in which it was shown that the drug  was a cause.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="9.608695652173912" PS="1.0" SM="18">In 2003 a law was passed that makes driving under the  influence of cannabis a criminal offence, and urine tests are being  extended.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="17.0" PS="1.5" SM="50">&quot;Cannabis has been shown to be responsible for 20 percent of  accidents caused by people under 30 years of age,&quot; said Patrick  Mura, president of the French Society for Analytical Toxicology.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="19.655172413793103" PS="1.5" SM="23">The government is also alarmed by the power of the drug economy  in the country's high-immigration city suburbs, to where much the  cannabis is initially smuggled from Morocco.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="11.214285714285714" PS="2.642857142857143" SM="27">At 76, Dr. James Watson has been recognized repeatedly for his brilliance and his life-altering discovery 50 years ago, along with a colleague, of the structure of DNA.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="16.470588235294116" PS="1.7619047619047619" SM="4">Remember that winding double-staircase known as the double helix that's recognized worldwide as DNA's model?</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="16.0" PS="1.7619047619047619" SM="1">That was his discovery.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="7.714285714285714" PS="1.7619047619047619" SM="4">And that finding at age 25 led him to become a Nobel Prize winner.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="21.625" PS="1.7619047619047619" SM="16">This day, when we meet, he is being honored by the National Alliance for Research on Schizophrenia and Depression at a Palm Beach dinner.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="14.513513513513514" PS="1.1746031746031746" SM="31">He sits with members of NARSAD -- the president has a daughter with schizophrenia -- and we begin talking about his research into devastating mental illness and his quest to find the genes that produce these disorders.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="13.61111111111111" PS="1.7619047619047619" SM="4">He has already found genes implicated in attention deficit disorder and Tourette's syndrome in children with autism.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="11.642857142857142" PS="1.7619047619047619" SM="3">And we begin to talk about diagnostic testing -- when these genes are isolated.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="21.105263157894736" PS="1.1746031746031746" SM="15">He thinks it's possible we could soon have a test, like that done for Down syndrome, for schizophrenia.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="20.933333333333334" PS="1.1746031746031746" SM="3">Parents could find out when the child is still in utero if it was afflicted.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="16.770833333333332" PS="1.7619047619047619" SM="29">(The same test, known as a DNA biopsy, might also be used in adults and children with schizophrenia to find genes that are damaged and then select the best therapy for them, similar to the way Herceptin is used in breast cancer and Gleevec is used for leukemia.)</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="17.08108108108108" PS="1.7619047619047619" SM="9">&quot;We just have to spend the money ... if you were at war, you'd work 24 hours a day, seven days a week, but that's not the way science is done,&quot; he says.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="24.857142857142858" PS="1.1746031746031746" SM="2">&quot;We don't have the money.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="16.11111111111111" PS="1.1746031746031746" SM="12">We have no grants in support of this.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="16.0" PS="1.7619047619047619" SM="1">He rambles on about famous families who have genetic defects -- bipolar, dyslexia, for example.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="16.53846153846154" PS="1.1746031746031746" SM="2">And how fortunate it would be if they donated money to his research.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="22.047619047619047" PS="1.7619047619047619" SM="18">&quot;If you found the gene that caused it, you could finally rid this curse from the family,&quot; he says.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="16.666666666666668" PS="1.7619047619047619" SM="12">I ask him why he has chosen to concentrate now on schizophrenia.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="28.428571428571427" PS="1.7619047619047619" SM="1">&quot;We have a son who's been hospitalized with it,&quot; he answers.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="21.4" PS="1.1746031746031746" SM="1">There is a shocked silence.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="7.666666666666667" PS="1.1746031746031746" SM="0">No one knew.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="11.363636363636363" PS="1.7619047619047619" SM="1">His son, now 35, hasn't responded to medication, he says.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="13.848484848484848" PS="1.7619047619047619" SM="22">I ask him about what seems the cosmic injustice: A man whose genius makes it possible for him to search out genetic causes for disorders to be a father to such a son.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="19.142857142857142" PS="1.7619047619047619" SM="15">&quot;I just look at it as DNA can't be copied perfectly, and this has always been true, and it leads to a lot of inequality.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="7.2" PS="1.7619047619047619" SM="1">A speech given a few years ago enhances his views.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="9.714285714285714" PS="1.7619047619047619" SM="32">&quot;Random throws of the genetic dice during the formation of sperm and egg take away from too many infants the opportunity to participate in a meaningful life.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="3.8666666666666667" PS="1.1746031746031746" SM="1">Those unfortunate individuals genetically programmed ... represent unambiguous tragedies lacking in any compensatory side advantages.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="16.791666666666668" PS="1.1746031746031746" SM="15">Common sense tells me that no one is seriously harmed by steps taken to prevent the birth of such children,&quot; he has said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="12.88" PS="1.7619047619047619" SM="14">So he, a Nobel Prize winner, hasn't been spared the pain of dealing with what his own research may someday spare others from suffering.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="4.714285714285714" PS="1.1746031746031746" SM="2">And that drives him, hard, every day.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="13.0" PS="1.7619047619047619" SM="3">Carolyn Susman writes for The Palm Beach Post.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="4.4" PS="1.1746031746031746" SM="0">E-mail: carolyn--susman@pbpost.com</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="15.9" PS="3.071428571428571" SM="50">Australian researchers announced a  breakthrough Thursday in the search for the cause of schizophrenia,  linking the impaired thought processes involved with the disorder to  thinning grey matter in the brain.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="12.03125" PS="2.0476190476190474" SM="79">Vaughan Carr of the Neuroscience Institute of Schizophrenia and  Allied Disorders said the discovery could provide a better  understanding of the genetic causes of the illness and eventually  lead to improved treatments.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="21.2" PS="2.0476190476190474" SM="35">&quot;The importance of this research is that it links together for  the first time abnormal brain structure and function in the one  image and ties that with abnormal thinking in schizophrenia,&quot; Carr  said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="27.875" PS="2.0476190476190474" SM="1">&quot;Now this is a remarkable achievement.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="17.772727272727273" PS="2.0476190476190474" SM="28">The researchers used advanced computing technology to give them  a &quot;new window&quot; into the brains of schizophrenia sufferers, Carr  said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="9.323529411764707" PS="2.0476190476190474" SM="32">They examined the thickness and function of the brain in 10  Australian patients with early onset schizophrenia while they  performed a planning task involving attention and memory in a  magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) scanner.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="16.736842105263158" PS="2.0476190476190474" SM="18">They compared the results with a healthy control group and found  those with schizophrenia had difficulty completing the task.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="10.5" PS="2.0476190476190474" SM="47">The computer analysis showed impaired thought processes and  inability to problem solve among those with the debilitating mental  illness were directly related to the thinning outer layer of grey  matter and reduced activity of the affected part of the brain.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="12.366666666666667" PS="2.0476190476190474" SM="42">Carr said the find, to be published in the international journal  Neuroimage, would open new areas of research examining post-mortem  tissue samples of the affected grey matter in schizophrenia  sufferers.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="15.63888888888889" PS="2.0476190476190474" SM="43">&quot;It means we can now focus on the genetics of a very specific  area of the brain and delve deeper and deeper into why the tissue  located there deteriorates in schizophrenia sufferers,&quot; he said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="12.5" PS="2.0476190476190474" SM="15">Researchers hope to pinpoint genes that may be turned on or off  in schizophrenia sufferers, leading to possible new treatments.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="11.206896551724139" PS="2.0476190476190474" SM="22">The mental disorder, which usually strikes people aged between  15 to 25, alters the way the brain functions and causes symptoms  including hallucinations, hearing voices, delusions and impaired  thinking.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="17.642857142857142" PS="2.0476190476190474" SM="7">The research was done in collaboration with scientists in the  United States and Germany.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="14.083333333333334" PS="2.321428571428571" SM="30">In Dr. Huda Y. Zoghbi's laboratory at the Baylor College of Medicine in Houston, her research team has found the genetic roots of at least two crippling neurological diseases -- Rett syndrome and spinocerebellar ataxias.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="5.5" PS="1.5476190476190474" SM="29">Recently, she and her colleagues identified a gene that regulates the growth of tiny inner ear hair cells, essential elements of hearing and balance in mammals.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="10.633333333333333" PS="1.5476190476190474" SM="32">For her findings, Zoghbi, a 50-year-old pediatrician who was born in Lebanon, has won major honors in the world of science, including her election to the National Academy of Sciences.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="13.419354838709678" PS="1.5476190476190474" SM="7">&quot;To me, women don't have to give up relationships to dedicate themselves to science,&quot; Zoghbi said over coffee at the Regency Hotel in Manhattan on a recent Saturday.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="27.5" PS="1.0317460317460316" SM="0">She is married with two children.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="22.923076923076923" PS="1.0317460317460316" SM="4">&quot;My life is two things: the people I love and my work.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="20.545454545454547" PS="1.0317460317460316" SM="12">With a little bit of organization, it can be done.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="7.0" PS="1.5476190476190474" SM="0">Q.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="13.0" PS="1.0317460317460316" SM="1">You started out as a neurological pediatrician.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="23.875" PS="1.0317460317460316" SM="5">Why quit the clinic for the research bench?</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="18.75" PS="1.5476190476190474" SM="1">A. I got into research for emotional reasons.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="18.956521739130434" PS="1.0317460317460316" SM="1">In 1985 when I was about to finish my neurology training, I was pregnant with my first child, Roula, who is now 20.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="12.526315789473685" PS="1.0317460317460316" SM="3">It was very hard on me to be an expectant mother and meet parents whose children had neurodegenerative diseases.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="16.454545454545453" PS="1.0317460317460316" SM="3">It devastated me to say, &quot;Well, your child has a genetic disorder, and we can't do anything about it.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="17.933333333333334" PS="1.5476190476190474" SM="5">I was fortunate that around that time I ran into Professor Arthur Beaudet, a genetics researcher, who said, &quot;I'll be happy to train you in molecular genetics.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="10.666666666666666" PS="1.0317460317460316" SM="15">So I started over because I wanted to find a way to solve some of these terrible diseases.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="14.916666666666666" PS="1.0317460317460316" SM="5">At the beginning, I knew less than the technicians in his laboratory.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="7.0" PS="1.5476190476190474" SM="0">Q.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="12.863636363636363" PS="1.0317460317460316" SM="5">How did you come to study the neurodegenerative disease known as Rett syndrome, which, I believe, strikes about 1 girl in 10,000?</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="12.0" PS="1.5476190476190474" SM="0">A.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="12.727272727272727" PS="1.0317460317460316" SM="2">While I was still a resident, I met Ashley, a 5-year-old.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="12.5" PS="1.0317460317460316" SM="2">She couldn't communicate, was having seizures and balance problems and was constantly wringing her hands.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="10.833333333333334" PS="1.0317460317460316" SM="12">These are signs of Rett syndrome.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="12.6" PS="1.5476190476190474" SM="26">Her parents said she had started life as a perfectly normal girl and then at the age of 18 months, all of this became manifest.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="12.555555555555555" PS="1.0317460317460316" SM="3">Knowing that Ashley started out as a healthy child, it was hard to get her off my mind.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="10.538461538461538" PS="1.0317460317460316" SM="1">A week later, another little girl was brought to me with similar symptoms.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="17.25" PS="1.0317460317460316" SM="1">This can't be that rare, I thought.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="12.695652173913043" PS="1.5476190476190474" SM="30">So I went to medical records and found the charts of five more girls with symptoms that fit the diagnosis of Rett syndrome.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="17.0625" PS="1.0317460317460316" SM="0">If I could identify about seven patients, I knew this was much more common than believed.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="18.0" PS="1.0317460317460316" SM="0">Moreover, I was intrigued by Rett syndrome, intellectually.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="13.0" PS="1.0317460317460316" SM="16">I wondered what goes on with the brain of a child who starts out normally and then loses her communication and motor skills.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="7.0" PS="1.5476190476190474" SM="0">Q.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="15.0" PS="1.0317460317460316" SM="13">Have you unraveled the puzzle of Rett syndrome yet?</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="12.0" PS="1.5476190476190474" SM="0">A.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="15.583333333333334" PS="1.0317460317460316" SM="16">Well, we've found the gene that, when mutated, causes Rett syndrome.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="20.428571428571427" PS="1.0317460317460316" SM="3">That's the methyl-CpG-binding protein 2 gene.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="15.555555555555555" PS="1.0317460317460316" SM="1">Six years ago, we were able to clone it.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="15.8" PS="1.5476190476190474" SM="14">It turns out that this gene's mutations cause a lot more than Rett syndrome.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="20.76923076923077" PS="1.0317460317460316" SM="2">There are patients with it who get seizures and others who get autism.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="12.272727272727273" PS="1.0317460317460316" SM="2">In rare cases, you even have bipolar disease and mental retardation.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="18.454545454545453" PS="1.5476190476190474" SM="22">A couple of patients with juvenile-onset schizophrenia also have this mutation.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="16.55" PS="1.0317460317460316" SM="6">So we think that the gene that's mutated in Rett syndrome is probably affecting many processes and neuronal activities.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="18.80952380952381" PS="1.5476190476190474" SM="5">It's the same for another neurological disease we study in my lab, spinocerebellar ataxia Type 1, which is also inherited.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="15.25" PS="1.0317460317460316" SM="2">That's even rarer because only 1 in 100,000 people get it.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="18.575757575757574" PS="1.0317460317460316" SM="13">Yet, by studying it, we've learned that what happens to mutant proteins in the cell is the same as what happens to the proteins mutated in Huntington's and Parkinson's diseases.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="10.428571428571429" PS="1.0317460317460316" SM="5">In all cases, the mutant proteins accumulate within neurons and are not cleared properly.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="14.0" PS="1.5476190476190474" SM="6">So, if we can figure out how to deal with the proteins mutated in ataxia, similar approaches could be taken in Parkinson's and Alzheimer's.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="10.1875" PS="1.0317460317460316" SM="4">By researching diseases that affect only a few people, we might solve others that affect many.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="7.0" PS="1.5476190476190474" SM="0">Q.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="19.105263157894736" PS="1.0317460317460316" SM="5">Why is it such a big breakthrough when you discover a gene that's associated with a specific disease?</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="12.0" PS="1.5476190476190474" SM="0">A.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="21.333333333333332" PS="1.0317460317460316" SM="14">With Rett syndrome, it's helpful to the parents of these kids.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="13.6" PS="1.0317460317460316" SM="2">Some thought they'd done something wrong and that's why their child was sick.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="23.76923076923077" PS="1.0317460317460316" SM="3">Once we had the gene, they could see it was not their fault.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="13.875" PS="1.5476190476190474" SM="28">In terms of research, finding the gene permitted us to make animal models of the disease.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="8.11111111111111" PS="1.0317460317460316" SM="1">We can now engineer mice to carry this mutation.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="18.0" PS="1.0317460317460316" SM="9">It is possible to finally study the disease in the mouse, and to spare humans.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="20.3" PS="1.5476190476190474" SM="4">Also, once you have the gene, drugs are a possibility.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="7.0" PS="1.5476190476190474" SM="0">Q.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="9.291666666666666" PS="1.0317460317460316" SM="29">The president of Harvard, Lawrence Summers, suggested that biological differences might explain why women had not advanced so much in the world of science.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="13.75" PS="1.0317460317460316" SM="0">What was your reaction?</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="17.1" PS="1.5476190476190474" SM="0">A. I was disappointed by how he phrased his comments.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="10.714285714285714" PS="1.0317460317460316" SM="1">When I read them, I worried about how a female graduate student would feel.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="17.041666666666668" PS="1.0317460317460316" SM="3">My biggest concern was that these words might be taken by young female scientists to go, &quot;Oww, I might not make it.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="4.8" PS="1.0317460317460316" SM="2">And that really upset me.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="13.37037037037037" PS="1.5476190476190474" SM="14">In my own case, I've succeeded, in part, because I had a very supportive husband -- William Zoghbi, who is a professor of cardiology at Baylor.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="8.727272727272727" PS="1.0317460317460316" SM="1">We've been together since we were medical students in Beirut.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="11.066666666666666" PS="1.0317460317460316" SM="2">He's always respected my need to go late at night to do my experiments.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="11.375" PS="1.0317460317460316" SM="1">I also had fantastic mentors, male and female.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="15.0" PS="1.5476190476190474" SM="7">Dawna Armstrong, a Baylor pathologist, when my baby was 2 months old, she could see my guilt about being away from the baby and say, &quot;Huda, babies, they sleep all the time when they are this age.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="7.0" PS="1.5476190476190474" SM="0">Q.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="11.933333333333334" PS="1.0317460317460316" SM="14">Do you think there's such a thing as a female style of doing science?</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="9.6" PS="1.5476190476190474" SM="5">A. I think females communicate quite a bit, and that's important in a lab.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="17.333333333333332" PS="1.0317460317460316" SM="1">Also, there are times when I follow my intuition.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="17.736842105263158" PS="1.0317460317460316" SM="3">You think, &quot;I'm going to follow this, even though the data doesn't say I should.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="15.615384615384615" PS="1.0317460317460316" SM="1">I do wonder if that intuitive approach is more prevalent among women scientists.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="6.666666666666667" PS="1.0317460317460316" SM="12">Lawrence Summers didn't talk about any of that.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="7.0" PS="1.5476190476190474" SM="0">Q.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="9.222222222222221" PS="1.0317460317460316" SM="4">What drew you to medicine in the first place?</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="8.5" PS="1.5476190476190474" SM="1">A. I grew up in an educated, cultured Beirut family.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="3.0" PS="1.0317460317460316" SM="2">My mother urged me to become a pediatrician.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="14.75" PS="1.0317460317460316" SM="14">I started medical school at the American University of Beirut in 1975.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="17.1" PS="1.0317460317460316" SM="6">That was the year the civil war in Lebanon began.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="17.375" PS="1.5476190476190474" SM="15">Bombs fell on the neighborhood of the university.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="12.461538461538462" PS="1.0317460317460316" SM="6">My class was so determined to study that we attended lectures in the basement and we slept there at night because you couldn't go home.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="16.875" PS="1.0317460317460316" SM="29">I found a corner of the ladies' room where I lived for most of the semester.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="9.727272727272727" PS="1.5476190476190474" SM="17">At the end of that year, my parents sent me and my brothers to visit our sister, who was living in Texas.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="20.2" PS="1.0317460317460316" SM="1">They were afraid for us.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="12.166666666666666" PS="1.0317460317460316" SM="6">While we were in the United States, the borders to Lebanon closed.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="18.0" PS="1.0317460317460316" SM="0">There was no returning.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="5.7368421052631575" PS="1.0317460317460316" SM="2">So Meharry Medical College in Nashville, Tenn., a traditionally African-American institution, accepted me two months after their term began.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="13.5" PS="1.5476190476190474" SM="5">But as kind as they were, there I was, 21, alone in a new country, always worried about people back home: 150,000 people would die in the Lebanese civil war.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="15.0" PS="1.0317460317460316" SM="0">Somehow I managed.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="11.0" PS="1.0317460317460316" SM="1">That year shaped me.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="16.0" PS="2.25" SM="5">Medical marijuana is now legal in 11 states, and bills to legalize it are pending in at least seven more.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="22.058823529411764" PS="1.5" SM="18">The drug is also at the heart of a case being considered by the U.S. Supreme Court.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="10.333333333333334" PS="1.5" SM="1">Yet there remains much confusion over whether marijuana in fact has any significant medical effect.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="15.906976744186046" PS="1.5" SM="30">&quot;People subjectively report benefits,&quot; said Dr. Joseph I. Sirven, an epilepsy specialist and associate professor of neurology at the Mayo Clinic College of Medicine in Scottsdale, Ariz. &quot;There's a whole Internet literature suggesting what a wonderful thing it is.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="27.333333333333332" PS="1.0" SM="2">But the reality is, we don't know.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="16.055555555555557" PS="1.5" SM="28">In an editorial last year in the journal Neurology, Sirven said the best studies of marijuana's effects on humans so far have shown little objective evidence of benefit in patients with epilepsy or multiple sclerosis.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="10.655172413793103" PS="1.0" SM="53">And a growing body of research indicates that, at least in teenagers, heavy marijuana use over a period of years significantly increases the risk of developing psychosis and schizophrenia.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="9.155555555555555" PS="1.5" SM="31">In the Supreme Court case, two California residents, Angel McClary Raich and Diane Monson, brought a suit against federal officials in October 2002 to defend their use of marijuana after six of Monson's marijuana plants were seized and destroyed by the Drug Enforcement Administration.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="10.5" PS="1.5" SM="22">The federal government, which considers marijuana illegal under the Controlled Substances Act, asked the Supreme Court to overturn a Court of Appeals ruling that supported the two women.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="5.857142857142857" PS="1.0" SM="2">Oral arguments were heard just after Thanksgiving and a ruling could come any day.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="9.156862745098039" PS="1.5" SM="31">Raich's physician, Dr. Frank Henry Lucido of Berkeley, Calif., asserted in an affidavit that Raich risked death if she was denied the marijuana to treat nausea, anorexia, severe chronic pain and other disorders brought on by a variety of illnesses, including post-traumatic stress disorder, asthma and an inoperable brain tumor.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="10.826086956521738" PS="1.0" SM="5">On a Web site created on her behalf, www.angeljustice.org, Raich says she joined the lawsuit &quot;in order to save my life.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="8.833333333333334" PS="1.5" SM="16">While little scientific evidence supports such a lifesaving role for marijuana, many studies have found modest benefits in patients' subjective measures of pain, sleep, nausea, appetite, tremors and muscle spasms.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="12.456521739130435" PS="1.5" SM="28">&quot;There's nothing better for nerve pain than marijuana,&quot; said Phillip Alden, 41, a writer in Redwood City, Calif. Twice a month, he spends about $200 to buy a half ounce of high-potency marijuana from one of San Francisco's medical marijuana buyers' clubs.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="13.457142857142857" PS="1.5" SM="10">He smokes it three or more times a day to treat pain from a back injury and to improve his appetite and reduce nausea associated with AIDS and the antiviral drugs he takes for it.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="15.916666666666666" PS="1.0" SM="14">It has even checked the progression of his peripheral neuropathy, he said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="11.136363636363637" PS="1.5" SM="15">Two recent surveys published in Neurology have documented widespread use of marijuana among Canadian patients and a widespread belief in its benefits.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="15.848484848484848" PS="1.0" SM="33">The first survey, of 220 patients with multiple sclerosis, found that 36 percent had used marijuana to treat their symptoms and that 14 percent were using it at the time of the survey.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="13.391304347826088" PS="1.5" SM="31">The second, of 136 patients attending the University of Alberta Epilepsy Clinic, found that 21 percent had used marijuana in the previous year.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="12.653846153846153" PS="1.0" SM="40">Just over two-thirds of the active users said it decreased the severity of their seizures and slightly more than half reported a decreased frequency of seizures.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="17.896551724137932" PS="1.5" SM="19">But the lead author of the epilepsy study said it proved only that some patients believed in marijuana, not that it or its active ingredients, called cannabinoids, actually worked.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="15.609756097560975" PS="1.0" SM="29">&quot;There's not been a randomized, controlled trial demonstrating that marijuana or any cannabinoid is any more effective in controlled seizures than a placebo,&quot; said Dr. Donald W. Gross, director of the University of Alberta's adult epilepsy program.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="12.5" PS="1.5" SM="3">Although doctors may now prescribe marijuana in Canada for certain disorders, including epilepsy, Gross said he had never done so.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="21.125" PS="1.0" SM="2">&quot;It's terribly complicated from a physician's standpoint, and somewhat frustrating,&quot; he said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="15.866666666666667" PS="1.0" SM="13">&quot;We have a product that has been legitimized without any evidence of efficacy.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="10.11111111111111" PS="1.5" SM="16">A large body of research in test tubes and animals supports the view that cannabinoids have anticonvulsive properties.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="10.694444444444445" PS="1.0" SM="31">But while a 2003 study of 657 patients with MS published in the journal Lancet found significant improvements in subjective reports of muscle spasms and pain, it found no improvement by objective measures after 15 weeks.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="15.216216216216216" PS="1.5" SM="21">A follow-up report on the same group of patients did show modest benefit after 12 months, but the researchers said the results should be interpreted cautiously because the study had been intended to test only short-term benefits.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="10.551724137931034" PS="1.5" SM="39">Dr. David Baker, a professor at the Institute of Neurology in London, has found beneficial effects of cannabinoids in mice who have an artificially induced type of multiple sclerosis.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="21.133333333333333" PS="1.0" SM="1">But, he said, &quot;Showing clinical benefit in humans has been an elusive beast.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="20.772727272727273" PS="1.5" SM="4">&quot;At best there is a narrow therapeutic effect before the side effects become unacceptable for many people,&quot; he said. &quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="25.846153846153847" PS="1.0" SM="1">What is clear is that there have been no dramatic improvements overall.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="11.636363636363637" PS="1.5" SM="30">Dr. Kenneth P. Mackie, a professor of anesthesiology at the University of Washington, has devoted 15 years to studying the brain's response to cannabinoids through specialized brain receptors called CB1 and CB2.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="15.433333333333334" PS="1.5" SM="28">&quot;There's a whole bunch of theoretical reasons suggesting there would be a benefit for marijuana on a variety of conditions relating to pain and neuroinflammation,&quot; Mackie said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="26.9" PS="1.0" SM="3">&quot;But the clinical studies just aren't there.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="12.833333333333334" PS="1.5" SM="15">Far stronger evidence exists for a harmful effect of marijuana in teenagers who use it early and often.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="15.951219512195122" PS="1.0" SM="68">&quot;We know that cannabis is a contributory cause of schizophrenia,&quot; said Dr. Robin M. Murray, a professor at the Institute of Psychiatry in London and the co-editor of a new book, &quot;Marijuana and Madness: Psychiatry and Neurobiology.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="11.08" PS="1.5" SM="33">In a 2002 study published in the British medical journal BMJ, Murray reported that New Zealand teenagers who started smoking marijuana before age 15 and continued doing so on a daily basis raised their risk of developing psychosis and schizophrenia from about 2 percent to as much as 10 percent.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="19.870967741935484" PS="1.5" SM="23">The study, he said, ruled out the possibility that the teenagers who used marijuana were also those who were more likely to develop schizophrenia, whether or not they used the drug.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="18.153846153846153" PS="1.5" SM="3">&quot;You have to take a lot to go psychotic,&quot; Murray said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="16.925925925925927" PS="1.0" SM="26">&quot;But with five joints a day for five years, an amount that is increasingly common in Europe, you're seriously increasing your risk of schizophrenia.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="14.733333333333333" PS="1.5" SM="6">But he added, the risk dropped sharply as people aged, so that most chronically ill people who used marijuana for medical purposes were unlikely to experience psychosis as a result.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="15.25" PS="1.5" SM="3">Research in the United States has been greatly hampered by legal restrictions.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="12.708333333333334" PS="1.5" SM="45">In 1997, Dr. Donald Abrams, an oncologist and assistant director of the Positive Health Program at the University of California at San Francisco, became the first doctor authorized by the National Institute of Drug Abuse to receive marijuana to conduct research to determine if it provided medical benefits.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="20.166666666666668" PS="1.5" SM="29">Now more than a dozen California researchers are studying it under the auspices of the University of California's Center for Medicinal Cannabis Research.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="20.083333333333332" PS="1.5" SM="12">&quot;Cannabis has a 5,000-year history of medical use,&quot; Abrams said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="15.90625" PS="1.0" SM="17">He said he had completed three studies in patients with HIV that showed no negative effects on their immune systems or on the functioning of the protease inhibitor drugs they were taking.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="18.235294117647058" PS="1.0" SM="3">He is now trying to show that marijuana has a beneficial effect on immune functioning, he said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="14.333333333333334" PS="2.2857142857142856" SM="5">About 1.47 million Ugandans are  suffering from sever mental illness, local media said on Friday  quoting a report dubbed &quot;Progress Report 2004-2005.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="15.482758620689655" PS="1.5238095238095237" SM="33">This figure also accounts for the two percent of the population that suffers from epilepsy, one percent suffer from schizophrenia  and three percent maniac depression, according to the report.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="9.285714285714286" PS="1.5238095238095237" SM="15">Uganda has a population of 26.8 million, according to the 2002  national population census.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="12.571428571428571" PS="1.5238095238095237" SM="19">The report quotes World Health Organization statistics showing  that mental illness accounts for about 12.3 percent of the global  disease burden.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="13.481481481481481" PS="1.5238095238095237" SM="4">&quot;This will rise to 15 percent by the year 2020 by which time,  depression will disable more than AIDS heart disorders, traffic  accidents and wars combined.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="16.263157894736842" PS="1.0158730158730158" SM="21">The impact, both social and economic, on the lives of mentally ill people, their families and  communities is phenomenal,&quot; said the report which was carried out  by an international non-governmental organization, Basic needs UK  in Uganda (BUU).</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="14.885714285714286" PS="1.5238095238095237" SM="21">According to Dr. Margaret Mungerera, a senior psychiatrist at  Butabika National Psychiatrist Hospital, the number of people with mental disorders is likely to be high because the BUU study did  not cover the whole country</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="10.666666666666666" PS="1.5238095238095237" SM="16">The study covered the districts of Kampala, Masaka, Hoima  Sembabule and Masindi.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="6.0" PS="1.0158730158730158" SM="12">Uganda has a total of 56 districts.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="15.722222222222221" PS="1.5238095238095237" SM="14">&quot;Basing on what we see, the country might even be having a  bigger number of psychiatric victims.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="14.73076923076923" PS="1.0158730158730158" SM="30">Take example of poverty  gibbering among the people, the northern Uganda war and the  changed lifestyle, all these can cause mental disorders,&quot; said Dr. Mungerera.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="9.7" PS="1.5238095238095237" SM="16">At least 115 mentally ill people in Kampala and Sembabule were  cured of mental disorders and discharged during the study.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="10.272727272727273" PS="1.5238095238095237" SM="8">The BUU study was started in 2002 to determine whether Uganda  would be eligible to initiate a mental health and development  program.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="18.166666666666668" PS="2.2857142857142856" SM="18">IBM said on Monday that it is  teaming with a European institute in a research initiative to  uncover the secrets of human cognitive intelligence.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="12.2" PS="1.5238095238095237" SM="50">Scientists from IBM and the Ecole Polytechnique Federale de  Lausanne (EPFL) of Switzerland will work together over the next  two years to create a detailed model of the circuitry in the  neocortex -- the largest and most complex part of the human brain, IBM said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="13.875" PS="1.5238095238095237" SM="34">The scientists hope that by expanding the project, nicknamed  the Blue Brain Project, to model other areas of the brain, they  will eventually build an accurate, computer-based model of the  entire brain.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="16.13888888888889" PS="1.5238095238095237" SM="18">Using the digital model created with IBM's Blue Gene  supercomputer, scientists will run computer-based simulations of  the brain at the molecular level, shedding light on internal  processes such as thought, perception and memory, IBM said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="13.40625" PS="1.5238095238095237" SM="45">The scientists also hope to understand more about how and why  certain microcircuits in the brain malfunction -- thought to be  the cause of psychiatric disorders such as autism, schizophrenia  and depression.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="16.92105263157895" PS="1.5238095238095237" SM="46">&quot;Modeling the brain at the cellular level is a massive  undertaking because of the hundreds of thousands of parameters  that need to be taken into account,&quot; said Henry Markram, the EPFL  professor heading up the project.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="12.571428571428571" PS="1.5238095238095237" SM="15">Under the initiative, IBM will install a Blue Gene  supercomputer at EPFL, with a peak processing speed of at least 22.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="10.842105263157896" PS="1.0158730158730158" SM="16">8 trillion floating-point operations per second (22.8 teraflops),  making it one of the most powerful supercomputers in the world.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="17.105263157894736" PS="1.5238095238095237" SM="54">Markram is the founder of EPFL's Brain and Mind Institute,  where more than 10 years of research and wet-lab experiments have  produced the world's most comprehensive set of empirical data on  the micro-architecture of the neocortex.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="10.93939393939394" PS="1.5238095238095237" SM="18">Researchers from IBM will use their experience in simulating  complex biological systems to help turn this data into a working 3- dimensional model re-creating the high-speed electro-chemical  interactions of the brain's interior.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="12.222222222222221" PS="2.25" SM="13">Identical twins possess exactly the same set of genes.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="12.75" PS="1.5" SM="1">Yet as they grow older, they may begin to display subtle differences.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="12.642857142857142" PS="1.5" SM="3">They may start to look different, develop different diseases or slide into different personalities.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="16.105263157894736" PS="1.0" SM="5">Women who are identical twins may differ in their fertility or in the age at which they reach menopause.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="7.5" PS="1.5" SM="3">These discrepancies are usually attributed to ill-defined differences in environment.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="14.59375" PS="1.5" SM="15">But a whole new level of explanation has been opened up by a genetic survey showing that identical twins, as they grow older, differ increasingly in what is known as their epigenome.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="11.08108108108108" PS="1.0" SM="12">The term refers to natural chemical modifications that occur in a person's genome shortly after conception and that act on a gene like a gas pedal or a brake, marking it for higher or lower activity.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="19.375" PS="1.5" SM="16">Identical twins have the same set of epigenetic marks on the genome when they are born.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="12.756756756756756" PS="1.0" SM="34">But differences in the epigenome emerge as the twins grow older and become greater the longer they live apart, say a team of researchers led by Dr. Manel Esteller of the Spanish National Cancer Center in Madrid.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="12.3125" PS="1.5" SM="39">Their report appears in Tuesday's issue of The Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="21.214285714285715" PS="1.5" SM="30">&quot;This is one of the most fascinating things I have read,&quot; said Dr. Nancy Segal, a psychologist who studies twins at California State University at Fullerton and the author of &quot;Indivisible by Two,&quot; a forthcoming book on twins.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="15.208333333333334" PS="1.0" SM="14">&quot;By giving us a handle on something specific it opens up many new avenues of inquiry as to why twins are different.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="23.666666666666668" PS="1.5" SM="2">There are two possible explanations for Esteller's findings.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="17.8125" PS="1.0" SM="4">One is simply the well- known fact that epigenetic marks are lost as people get older.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="11.65" PS="1.0" SM="17">Because the marks are removed randomly, they would be expected to occur differently in two members of a twin pair.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="12.212121212121213" PS="1.5" SM="21">A second possible explanation is that personal experiences and elements in the environment -- including toxic agents like tobacco smoke -- feed back onto the genome by changing the pattern of epigenetic marks.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="20.11111111111111" PS="1.5" SM="0">Esteller believes he is seeing both processes at work.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="21.642857142857142" PS="1.0" SM="13">The evidence for the second process, he said, is that twins who reported that they had lived apart the longest also had the greatest differences in their epigenome.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="25.45945945945946" PS="1.5" SM="17">&quot;This is a way for the genome to be responsive to the environment,&quot; he said, noting that it is easier for chemical marks on the genome to change than for the genome itself to mutate.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="12.916666666666666" PS="1.5" SM="18">His study suggests that the epigenome may be involved in many diseases that can affect identical twins differently, like schizophrenia, bipolar disorder and cancer.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="15.764705882352942" PS="1.0" SM="17">Although schizophrenia evidently has a genetic component, the epigenome may hold the clue to its nongenetic aspects.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="11.4" PS="1.5" SM="4">Differences between identical twins could also help pinpoint the epigenetic differences that contribute to cancer.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="15.676470588235293" PS="1.0" SM="32">&quot;We think that epigenetic changes are very common in cancer,&quot; said Dr. Peter A. Jones, president of the American Association for Cancer Research and a professor at the University of Southern California.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="21.083333333333332" PS="1.5" SM="19">Jones said Esteller's finding &quot;is exceptionally interesting in that it underlines the importance of epigenetic changes in human development and disease.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="6.769230769230769" PS="1.5" SM="2">Jones recently convened a workshop to discuss starting an international human epigenome project.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="18.906976744186046" PS="1.0" SM="39">The proposal could rival the Human Genome Project in complexity because the human genome is the same in every cell of a person's body, while the epigenome is expected to be different for each of the 250 or so human cell types.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="12.76923076923077" PS="1.5" SM="31">Among the most important components of the epigenome are small chemical handles known as methyl groups, which are added directly to the chemical units of DNA.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="11.571428571428571" PS="1.5" SM="28">A wave of demethylation occurs in a sperm's genome shortly after an egg is fertilized, followed by the extensive readdition of methyl groups in early embryonic development.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="13.380952380952381" PS="1.5" SM="17">These methyl groups, which generally inhibit the activity of the genes in which they occur, tend to be lost during aging.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="13.69047619047619" PS="1.0" SM="48">Esteller's team studied the total amount of methylation in the twins' genomes, as well as another kind of epigenetic modification, the addition of acetyl groups to the histone proteins that act as a scaffolding and as a control system for DNA.</sentence>
	</Sentences>
</Topic>
