<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<Topic id="D0936G">
	<Sentences>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="24.3125" PS="2.5580912863070537" SM="61">Sandra Day O'Connor, the first  woman ever appointed to the US Supreme Court, said Friday that she is retiring, giving US president George W. Bush his first  opportunity to appoint a justice.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="20.558139534883722" PS="1.7053941908713692" SM="41">&quot;This is to inform you of my decision to retire from my  position as an associate justice of the Supreme Court of the  United States, effective upon the nomination and confirmation of  my successor,&quot; she said in a letter to Bush.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="14.222222222222221" PS="1.7053941908713692" SM="12">O'Connor, 75, did not explain why she was resigning.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="23.210526315789473" PS="1.1369294605809128" SM="45">A Supreme  Court spokeswoman said O'Connor needs to spend time with her  husband who suffered from Alzheimer's disease.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="19.83783783783784" PS="1.7053941908713692" SM="44">Her resignation, which will result in the first opening on the  US Supreme Court in 11 years, will allow Bush to make his first  appointment to the nine-member court which makes many vital  decisions concerning US society.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="17.0625" PS="1.1369294605809128" SM="7">Experts said the appointment is  set to trigger fierce political battle between the Republicans and Democrats.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="20.484848484848484" PS="1.7053941908713692" SM="51">In a statement confirming O'Connor's resignation, Bush said he  will pick her successor in a timely manner so her vacancy can be  filled by the time the court resumes work in October.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="20.8" PS="1.7053941908713692" SM="8">He also promised to &quot;be deliberate and thorough&quot; in making the  choice and will consult with the Senate which will confirm his  nominee.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="23.576923076923077" PS="2.567427385892116" SM="74">Sandra Day O'Connor, the first woman  appointed to the US Supreme Court and a frequent swing vote, has  announced her retirement, a court source said Friday.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="22.564102564102566" PS="1.7116182572614107" SM="39">Her retirement, which sets up a long-awaited political battle  for a successor and gives President George W. Bush his first chance  to select a justice for the high court, was confirmed by a Supreme  Court official who requested anonymity.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="14.666666666666666" PS="1.7116182572614107" SM="3">As rival groups geared up for what is likely to be a bitter  nomination battle, Bush scheduled a news conference for 11:15 am  (1515 GMT) in the White House Rose Garden, his spokesman Scott  McClellan said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="20.333333333333332" PS="1.7116182572614107" SM="37">O'Connor, 75, who is considered a moderate conservative, was  appointed to the court by president Ronald Reagan and took her seat  in September 1981.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="15.022222222222222" PS="1.7116182572614107" SM="33">Her retirement gives Bush the chance to shape the ideological  balance of the court, a fact that could spark a prolonged  confirmation battle in the US Senate for a successor, touching on  lightning bolt questions such as abortion and the separation of  church and state.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="22.5" PS="2.4553941908713695" SM="23">President George W. Bush on Friday  said he would nominate a new Supreme Court Justice in a timely  manner, and called for a dignified confirmation battle, as rival  political camps geared up for battle.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="18.57894736842105" PS="1.6369294605809128" SM="37">Bush made a statement in the White House Rose Garden, shortly  after Justice Sandra Day O'Connor announced her retirement.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="28.357142857142858" PS="1.6369294605809128" SM="14">&quot;Under the Constitution, I am responsible for nominating a  sucessor for Justice O'Connor.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="8.6" PS="1.0912863070539418" SM="0">I take this responsibility seriously.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="28.333333333333332" PS="1.0912863070539418" SM="1">I will be deliberate and thorough in this process,&quot; Bush said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="32.80952380952381" PS="1.6369294605809128" SM="29">&quot;The nation deserves and I will select a Supreme Court Justice  that Americans can be proud of,&quot; Bush said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="13.692307692307692" PS="1.6369294605809128" SM="9">&quot;The nation also deserves a dignified process of confirmation in  the United States Senate, characterised by fair treatment, a fair  hearing and a fair vote.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="22.666666666666668" PS="1.6369294605809128" SM="32">&quot;I will chose a nominee in a timely manner so the hearing and  the vote can be compelted before the new Supreme Court term  begins.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="24.0" PS="1.6369294605809128" SM="28">Bush also paid tribute to O'Connor, the first woman to serve on  the top US court.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="27.3" PS="1.6369294605809128" SM="25">&quot;America is proud of Justice O'Connor's distinguished service  and I am proud to know her,&quot; he said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="15.294117647058824" PS="1.6369294605809128" SM="4">&quot;She has been a discerning and conscientious judge and a public  servant of complete integrity.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="18.633333333333333" PS="2.567427385892116" SM="74">Sandra Day O'Connor, the first woman  appointed to the US Supreme Court and a frequent swing vote,  announced her retirement Friday, setting up a fierce political  showdown for her seat.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="18.394736842105264" PS="1.7116182572614107" SM="44">The move handed President George W. Bush his first chance to  reshape the ideological balance of the court, which has immense  influence over the lives of Americans, interprets the constitution  and acts as a court of last resort.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="19.84" PS="1.7116182572614107" SM="49">Minutes after O'Connor's announcement, political leaders and  lobby groups fired the first shots in a long brewing battle for the  court's political soul.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="18.125" PS="1.7116182572614107" SM="3">Liberals warned Bush not to name an &quot;extremist&quot; while  Republicans urged him to pick someone who would apply rather than  interpret the constitution -- in other words a strict conservative.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="32.80952380952381" PS="1.7116182572614107" SM="29">&quot;The nation deserves and I will select a Supreme Court justice  that Americans can be proud of,&quot; Bush said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="17.0" PS="1.7116182572614107" SM="12">&quot;The nation also deserves a dignified process of confirmation in  the United States Senate, characterised by fair treatment, a fair  hearing and a fair vote,&quot; Bush said in a statement delivered in the  White House Rose Garden.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="24.057142857142857" PS="1.7116182572614107" SM="14">Bush said he would pick a new justice in a &quot;timely manner&quot; but  the White House said there would be no announcement before he  returns from next week's G8 summit in Scotland.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="18.625" PS="1.7116182572614107" SM="30">The president was set to pore over profiles of potential Supreme  Court picks during the long flight to Europe, his spokesman Scott  McClellan said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="20.26923076923077" PS="1.7116182572614107" SM="17">Justices are not term limited, so presidents have a chance to  mould the country for years after they leave the political scene,  through their court choices.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="18.424242424242426" PS="1.7116182572614107" SM="29">Bush's chance to remake the court is all the more important  because key cases on abortion, assisted suicide and gay rights are  looming when justices return from their summer break in October.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="17.307692307692307" PS="1.7116182572614107" SM="15">Democratic activists fear that Bush will replace O'Connor, who  cast the key votes in two key abortion rights test cases in 2000,  with a 'pro-life' justice.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="13.045454545454545" PS="1.7116182572614107" SM="18">O'Connor, a snowy haired 75-year-old judge and former prosecutor  told Bush her retirement would become effective upon the  confirmation of a successor.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="20.642857142857142" PS="1.7116182572614107" SM="16">&quot;It has been a great privilege indeed to have served as a member  of the Court for 24 terms,&quot; she wrote in a letter to Bush.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="20.842105263157894" PS="1.7116182572614107" SM="37">&quot;I will leave it with enormous respect for the integrity of the  Court and its role under our constitutional structure,&quot; wrote  O'Connor, who was born in Texas and practiced law in the  southwestern state of Arizona.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="30.466666666666665" PS="1.7116182572614107" SM="12">Bush and O'Connor spoke in what aides said was an &quot;emotional&quot;  phone call.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="20.6" PS="1.1410788381742738" SM="0">With a nod to their shared Texas heritage, Bush said:  &quot;for an old ranching girl, you turned out pretty good,&quot; according to  McClellan.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="16.571428571428573" PS="1.7116182572614107" SM="23">O'Connor was appointed by president Ronald Reagan and took her  seat in September 1981.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="18.194444444444443" PS="1.7116182572614107" SM="23">She often sided with more radical conservatives on the court, as  when she voted with the majority to stop recounts in Florida after  the 2000 election, effectively handing the White House to Bush over  Al Gore.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="17.84" PS="1.7116182572614107" SM="3">Cancer-stricken Chief Justice William Rehnquist had been seen as  the most likely justice to retire, but has so far made no  announcement on his future.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="28.5" PS="1.7116182572614107" SM="49">O'Connor's retirement opens the first vacancy on the Supreme  Court in 11 years.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="22.04" PS="1.1410788381742738" SM="17">The last justice appointed was the liberal  Justice Stephen Breyer, who was named by president Bill Clinton and  he took his seat in August 1994.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="26.0" PS="1.7116182572614107" SM="28">It leaves Justice Ruth Bader Ginsburg as the sole woman on the  nine justice Supreme Court bench.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="20.666666666666668" PS="1.7116182572614107" SM="37">Senator Edward Kennedy, who famously scuppered the confirmation  of Ronald Reagan's Supreme Court nominee Robert Bork, called on Bush  to appoint someone who could be embraced by all Americans.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="36.64705882352941" PS="1.7116182572614107" SM="14">&quot;Justice O'Connor was a mainstream conservative who was  confirmed unanimously by the Senate,&quot; Kennedy said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="27.133333333333333" PS="1.7116182572614107" SM="1">&quot;President Bush is faced with a decision that affects each and  every American.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="22.12" PS="1.7116182572614107" SM="4">Republican Senate Majority Leader Bill Frist said: &quot;America  needs judges who are fair, independent, unbiased and committed to  equal justice under the law.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="8.076923076923077" PS="1.7116182572614107" SM="3">The liberal political action committee MoveOn.org swiftly rolled  out a television advertising campaign.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="17.071428571428573" PS="1.7116182572614107" SM="18">&quot;The message: Don't nominate an extremist who will undermine the  rights of individuals and families as the President did in the Terri  Schiavo case several months ago,&quot; MoveOn.org said in a statement,  referring to the recent Florida right-to-die controversy.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="21.074074074074073" PS="2.4647302904564317" SM="57">US Republicans and Democrats geared  up Saturday for a major political battle over a successor to Supreme  Court Justice Sandra Day O'Connor, who has announced her  retirement.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="18.05" PS="1.6431535269709545" SM="42">Her decision, announced Friday, handed President George W. Bush  his first chance to reshape the ideological balance of the court,  which has immense influence over the lives of Americans, interprets  the constitution and acts as a court of last resort.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="19.84" PS="1.6431535269709545" SM="49">Minutes after O'Connor's announcement, political leaders and  lobby groups fired the first shots in a long brewing battle for the  court's political soul.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="18.125" PS="1.6431535269709545" SM="3">Liberals warned Bush not to name an &quot;extremist&quot; while  Republicans urged him to pick someone who would apply rather than  interpret the constitution -- in other words a strict conservative.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="32.80952380952381" PS="1.6431535269709545" SM="29">&quot;The nation deserves and I will select a Supreme Court justice  that Americans can be proud of,&quot; Bush said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="17.0" PS="1.6431535269709545" SM="12">&quot;The nation also deserves a dignified process of confirmation in  the United States Senate, characterised by fair treatment, a fair  hearing and a fair vote,&quot; Bush said in a statement delivered in the  White House Rose Garden.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="24.057142857142857" PS="1.6431535269709545" SM="14">Bush said he would pick a new justice in a &quot;timely manner&quot; but  the White House said there would be no announcement before he  returns from next week's G8 summit in Scotland.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="18.625" PS="1.6431535269709545" SM="30">The president was set to pore over profiles of potential Supreme  Court picks during the long flight to Europe, his spokesman Scott  McClellan said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="11.0" PS="1.6431535269709545" SM="0">No official announcement has been made.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="10.466666666666667" PS="1.095435684647303" SM="15">But the most frequently  mentioned names include Attorney General Alberto Gonzales as well as  federal appeals court judges Michael Luttig, Harvie Wilkinson, John  Roberts and former solicitor general Theodore Olson.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="20.26923076923077" PS="1.6431535269709545" SM="17">Justices are not term limited, so presidents have a chance to  mould the country for years after they leave the political scene,  through their court choices.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="18.424242424242426" PS="1.6431535269709545" SM="29">Bush's chance to remake the court is all the more important  because key cases on abortion, assisted suicide and gay rights are  looming when justices return from their summer break in October.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="17.307692307692307" PS="1.6431535269709545" SM="15">Democratic activists fear that Bush will replace O'Connor, who  cast the key votes in two key abortion rights test cases in 2000,  with a 'pro-life' justice.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="13.045454545454545" PS="1.6431535269709545" SM="18">O'Connor, a snowy haired 75-year-old judge and former  prosecutor, told Bush her retirement would become effective upon the  confirmation of a successor.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="20.642857142857142" PS="1.6431535269709545" SM="16">&quot;It has been a great privilege indeed to have served as a member  of the Court for 24 terms,&quot; she wrote in a letter to Bush.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="20.842105263157894" PS="1.6431535269709545" SM="37">&quot;I will leave it with enormous respect for the integrity of the  Court and its role under our constitutional structure,&quot; wrote  O'Connor, who was born in Texas and practiced law in the  southwestern state of Arizona.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="30.466666666666665" PS="1.6431535269709545" SM="12">Bush and O'Connor spoke in what aides said was an &quot;emotional&quot;  phone call.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="20.6" PS="1.095435684647303" SM="0">With a nod to their shared Texas heritage, Bush said:  &quot;for an old ranching girl, you turned out pretty good,&quot; according to  McClellan.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="16.571428571428573" PS="1.6431535269709545" SM="23">O'Connor was appointed by president Ronald Reagan and took her  seat in September 1981.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="18.194444444444443" PS="1.6431535269709545" SM="23">She often sided with more radical conservatives on the court, as  when she voted with the majority to stop recounts in Florida after  the 2000 election, effectively handing the White House to Bush over  Al Gore.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="17.84" PS="1.6431535269709545" SM="3">Cancer-stricken Chief Justice William Rehnquist had been seen as  the most likely justice to retire, but has so far made no  announcement on his future.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="28.5" PS="1.6431535269709545" SM="49">O'Connor's retirement opens the first vacancy on the Supreme  Court in 11 years.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="22.04" PS="1.095435684647303" SM="17">The last justice appointed was the liberal  Justice Stephen Breyer, who was named by president Bill Clinton and  he took his seat in August 1994.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="26.0" PS="1.6431535269709545" SM="28">It leaves Justice Ruth Bader Ginsburg as the sole woman on the  nine justice Supreme Court bench.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="19.625" PS="1.6431535269709545" SM="0">Senator Edward Kennedy called on Bush to appoint someone who  could be embraced by all Americans.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="24.210526315789473" PS="1.6431535269709545" SM="4">&quot;President Bush is faced with a decision that affects each and  every American,&quot; warned the Massachusetts Democrat.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="22.12" PS="1.6431535269709545" SM="4">Republican Senate Majority Leader Bill Frist said: &quot;America  needs judges who are fair, independent, unbiased and committed to  equal justice under the law.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="19.57894736842105" PS="2.25" SM="27">WASHINGTON - President Dwight D. Eisenhower figured Earl Warren would make an ideal chief justice of the U.S. Supreme Court.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="8.470588235294118" PS="1.5" SM="10">Warren, the Republican governor of California, had been a loyal supporter of Eisenhower in the 1952 election.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="22.31578947368421" PS="1.0" SM="6">Eisenhower said he chose Warren the next year because of his deliberate style and his &quot;middle-of-the-road&quot; philosophy.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="15.689655172413794" PS="1.5" SM="26">Warren turned out to be one of the most liberal justices in history, leading the court to landmark rulings on civil rights and the separation of church and state.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="24.9375" PS="1.0" SM="3">Eisenhower later said appointing Warren was &quot;the biggest damn fool mistake I ever made.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="22.24390243902439" PS="1.5" SM="69">As President Bush searches for someone to succeed Justice Sandra Day O'Connor, who announced her resignation Friday, the experiences with Warren and many other members of the Supreme Court provide reminders that justices often don't vote the way presidents expect.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="15.25925925925926" PS="1.5" SM="3">Justice Byron White, an appointee of President John Kennedy in 1962, was expected to be a liberal, but often voted conservatively on personal liberty and law-and-order cases.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="23.678571428571427" PS="1.0" SM="50">O'Connor, named to the court in 1981 by President Ronald Reagan, was more conservative in her early years but gradually sided more often with the court's liberals.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="26.125" PS="1.5" SM="29">Justice David Souter, an appointee of the first President Bush in 1990, has angered conservative Republicans by often voting with the court's liberals.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="25.0" PS="1.5" SM="0">&quot;We thought Justice Souter would vote differently than he turned out to vote,&quot; said Boyden Gray, White House counsel under former President Bush.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="23.9" PS="1.5" SM="0">He said many presidents have been unhappy with their appointees.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="34.63636363636363" PS="1.5" SM="3">&quot;The landscape is littered with crushed expectations,&quot; Gray said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="15.727272727272727" PS="1.0" SM="0">&quot;You can never predict or control (how they'll vote).</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="16.666666666666668" PS="1.0" SM="10">That's just absolutely a fact a life.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="6.666666666666667" PS="1.5" SM="0">Not enough homework</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="16.666666666666668" PS="1.5" SM="3">Some justices defy expectations because the presidents who chose them didn't do enough homework.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="18.85185185185185" PS="1.5" SM="28">That was the case with Souter, a state judge in New Hampshire who served briefly as a federal appeals judge before his nomination to the Supreme Court.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="23.263157894736842" PS="1.0" SM="6">Researchers who looked into his record found so little that the press dubbed him &quot;the stealth justice.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="19.424242424242426" PS="1.5" SM="17">White House aides &quot;really didn't know much about him,&quot; said Eddie Lazarus, a former clerk for Justice Harry Blackmun and author of Closed Chambers, an inside look at the court.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="35.285714285714285" PS="1.0" SM="0">&quot;That was their own fault.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="12.277777777777779" PS="1.5" SM="0">It was difficult to assess Souter because he had been a federal judge for less than a year.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="19.952380952380953" PS="1.5" SM="5">&quot;Nobody knew what he stood for,&quot; said Paul Finkelman, a law professor at the University of Tulsa in Oklahoma.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="23.071428571428573" PS="1.5" SM="3">The experience has prompted a refrain by many conservatives: &quot;No more Souters.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="22.818181818181817" PS="1.5" SM="15">For other vacancies on the court, presidents have nominated former politicians like Warren and White who have little or no judicial experience.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="18.0" PS="1.0" SM="19">The presidents assumed the nominees would follow their party's ideology, but it turned out the nominees had different ideas.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="17.357142857142858" PS="1.5" SM="3">Mary Cheh, a law professor at George Washington University, said White was a New Deal Democrat who was in favor of &quot;big government and federal programs.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="27.25" PS="1.0" SM="14">But he surprised many people by often voting conservatively on the court.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="26.666666666666668" PS="1.5" SM="24">&quot;He was consistent that he thought the court should stay out of the way of the legislature,&quot; Cheh said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="3.0" PS="1.5" SM="0">Transformations</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="30.9" PS="1.5" SM="14">Other justices have changed after they got on the court.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="25.571428571428573" PS="1.5" SM="41">In her first few years as a justice, O'Connor was known as the &quot;Arizona Twin&quot; because she voted so often with Chief Justice William Rehnquist, one of the court's most conservative members.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="20.92" PS="1.5" SM="39">Cheh says O'Connor's opinions in the early days were &quot;very mechanical&quot; and the only issue she was passionate about was states' rights.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="31.263157894736842" PS="1.5" SM="17">But the longer she was on the court, &quot;she became more sensitive to individual rights,&quot; Cheh said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="14.5" PS="1.5" SM="2">There was a similar transformation for Blackmun, an appointee of President Nixon in 1970.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="20.1" PS="1.5" SM="15">Blackmun was a longtime Republican, so Nixon and his aides figured he would be a dependable conservative on the court.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="19.53846153846154" PS="1.0" SM="0">In his early years, he frequently voted with conservative Chief Justice Warren Burger.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="17.076923076923077" PS="1.5" SM="10">But Blackmun increasingly sided with liberals and authored the 1973 opinion that is the flashpoint for many conservatives: the Roe vs. Wade decision on abortion rights.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="13.333333333333334" PS="1.5" SM="3">Why the transformations?</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="14.40625" PS="1.5" SM="29">Finkelman, the University of Tulsa professor, said getting a lifetime appointment to the nation's highest court leaves people free to make their own judgments without being bound by a rigid ideology.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="38.44444444444444" PS="1.5" SM="0">&quot;Their vantage point is altered,&quot; he said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="17.272727272727273" PS="1.0" SM="11">&quot;Having gotten to the pinnacle, the top of the highest mountain, they suddenly discover there is no place to strive for.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="23.142857142857142" PS="1.0" SM="3">They look at the world differently.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="16.458333333333332" PS="1.5" SM="10">U.S. Rep. Tom Feeney, R-Oviedo, said it's more common for Republican appointees to morph into liberals than for Democratic nominees to become conservative.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="15.375" PS="1.0" SM="5">He blames it on the culture of Washington.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="13.257142857142858" PS="1.5" SM="7">&quot;When you surround yourself by other rich lawyers and liberal policymakers, you tend to grow out of touch with Joe Six Pack and Brenda Babysitter out there in the real world,&quot; Feeney said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="18.607142857142858" PS="1.5" SM="6">Lazarus, the former Blackmun clerk, said he agrees there is a seduction, but said it affects nominees who don't come to the job with a strict ideology.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="21.916666666666668" PS="1.5" SM="35">&quot;Once they get on the court, people who are not ideological get swept up in the majesty of interpreting the Constitution's beautiful but vague promises of due process and equal protection,&quot; he said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="22.6" PS="1.0" SM="3">&quot;That tends to draw them to the left.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="7.0" PS="1.5" SM="0">Ideologues don't morph</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="23.23076923076923" PS="1.5" SM="25">The court's most consistent conservatives are Justices Antonin Scalia and Clarence Thomas.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="14.1" PS="1.5" SM="18">They are the darlings of the right and the foes of the left because they rarely stray from conservative orthodoxy.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="11.68421052631579" PS="1.5" SM="0">Legal analysts say they haven't morphed because they are strict ideologues who apply their principles to every decision.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="18.842105263157894" PS="1.0" SM="22">Many conservative groups are urging President Bush to nominate someone like Thomas and Scalia to be O'Connor's successor.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="17.55" PS="1.5" SM="6">Liberal groups such as People for the American Way are saying just the opposite, urging Bush to pick a moderate.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="8.8" PS="1.5" SM="0">But how can either side know what they're getting?</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="11.357142857142858" PS="1.0" SM="0">How can they be sure they won't get another Warren - or another White?</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="9.68" PS="1.5" SM="6">Both sides are scouring the records of possible nominees to look for clues about how they might vote: judicial opinions, speeches and law review articles.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="19.952380952380953" PS="1.5" SM="20">Ralph Neas, president of People for the America Way, said Bush's nominee &quot;is probably going to be either a judge or an academic with a lengthy record that is faithful to the record of a Thomas or a Scalia.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="17.1875" PS="1.5" SM="9">Gray, the former White House counsel, said Republicans have learned lessons from the nomination of Souter.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="23.88235294117647" PS="1.5" SM="3">&quot;The most important indicator is their track record - what have they said, what have they written.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="21.263157894736842" PS="1.0" SM="3">I think if you have a candidate who has a known record, that is the best,&quot; Gray said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="14.724137931034482" PS="1.5" SM="6">Cheh, the George Washington University law professor, said Bush and his aides have learned from history and will thoroughly research possible nominees to make sure they get an ideologue.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="39.642857142857146" PS="1.5" SM="3">&quot;The Republicans,&quot; she said, &quot;have made this a high art.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="19.085714285714285" PS="2.474066390041494" SM="59">The perennial battle over abortion  rights in the United States is galvanizing conservative and liberal  activists, who are hoping to influence President George W. Bush's  choice to fill a newly-vacated US Supreme Court seat.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="9.73076923076923" PS="1.649377593360996" SM="11">For decades, a deep ideological rift over a woman's right to end  an unwanted pregnancy has cleaved this country into two powerful,  and equally-impassioned camps.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="16.03448275862069" PS="1.649377593360996" SM="84">Conservatives, who turned out in record numbers to cast votes  last November for the Republican president, see in the retirement of  moderate Justice Sandra Day O'Connor a historic chance to reshape  the nine-member high court, and fulfill a fervent wish to overturn  the watershed Roe v. Wade Supreme Court case which guaranteed women  the right to an abortion.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="19.46875" PS="1.649377593360996" SM="18">Liberals, meanwhile, have sternly warned Bush not to name an  &quot;extremist&quot; to the court and have vowed to put up a fierce fight to  safeguard the right to legal abortion.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="16.066666666666666" PS="1.649377593360996" SM="45">With a Supreme Court seat now open for the first time in more  than a decade, groups on both sides of the bitter abortion divide  have said they are planning to spend millions to lobby Congress and  the White House, and to rally their supporters.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="10.541666666666666" PS="1.649377593360996" SM="17">Political observers predicted Armaggedon once the fight to  replace O'Connor is joined in earnest, with dozens of political  groups expected to play a role.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="21.609756097560975" PS="1.649377593360996" SM="38">&quot;I think we're in for a pretty partisan battle,&quot; said Orrin  Hatch, a conservative US senator and longserving member of the  powerful Senate Judiciary committee that will vet US President  George W. Bush's eventual Supreme Court nominee.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="18.17391304347826" PS="1.649377593360996" SM="16">The debate also is expect to further polarize an already-divided  US Senate which will be called upon to confirm the president's  pick.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="17.033333333333335" PS="1.649377593360996" SM="21">&quot;He said he's going to pick a strong conservative, and I think  that's going to cause a battle no matter what,&quot; Hatch told ABC  television Tuesday.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="16.591836734693878" PS="1.649377593360996" SM="40">Even before O'Connor announced her departure, the conservative  Progress for America group last month launched a 700,000-dollar  fundraising effort, hoping to beat back &quot;liberal attack groups ...  hungry to smear almost any potential candidate for the Supreme Court  who doesn't meet their left-wing, extemist litmus test.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="21.15" PS="1.649377593360996" SM="10">Likewise, the Family Research Council said on its website that  it is &quot;primed for the fight it will take to confirm a nominee,&quot; and  vowed to mobilize 20,000 churches across the nation to lobby for a  conservative justice.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="12.473684210526315" PS="1.649377593360996" SM="20">Liberal groups were equally motivated: The pro-choice Feminist  Majority sounded the alarm within hours of O'Connor announcing her  retirement.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="43.5" PS="1.649377593360996" SM="0">&quot;This is it!</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="25.666666666666668" PS="1.099585062240664" SM="34">The worst has happened with the resignation of  Sandra Day OConnor,&quot; the group said on its website.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="19.6875" PS="1.649377593360996" SM="28">&quot;Let there be no mistake about it: Sandra Day OConnor was the  fifth vote that was saving Roe vs. Wade,&quot; the group said in a dire  warning to its supporters.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="31.545454545454547" PS="1.649377593360996" SM="4">&quot;Abortion rights and womens rights are on the line.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="12.545454545454545" PS="1.649377593360996" SM="6">Another liberal group, MoveOn.org said on its website that it  aimed to deliver 300,000 petition signatures by Tuesday to the US  Senate, asking lawmakers to help preserve the right to end a  pregnancy.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="20.0" PS="1.649377593360996" SM="36">And the left-leaning &quot;Ms.&quot; magazine this month warned its  readers that &quot;rolling back reproductive rights is only the first act  in a nightmare scenario that could come to pass if right-wing judges  take over the federal courts and the nations highest court.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="19.28125" PS="1.649377593360996" SM="6">Bush said in a newspaper interview published Tuesday that he  expected to have a new justice on the bench by October, and already  had identified &quot;a good-sized&quot; number of prospects.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="14.037037037037036" PS="1.649377593360996" SM="9">The US president called on partisan groups to tone down the  heated rhetoric, insisting in an interview USA Today that he is  immune to the high-intensity lobbying.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="20.425531914893618" PS="1.649377593360996" SM="31">&quot;I feel no pressure, except the pressure to put somebody on the  bench who will bring dignity to the office, somebody who's got the  intellect necessary to do the job, somebody of great integrity and  somebody who will faithfully interpret the Constitution,&quot; Bush  said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="20.23076923076923" PS="2.474066390041494" SM="40">US President George W. Bush on  Wednesday chastised critics of Attorney General Alberto Gonzales as  a potential candidate for the recently-vacated seat in the Supreme  Court.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="17.181818181818183" PS="1.649377593360996" SM="0">&quot;I don't like it when a friend gets criticized.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="13.464285714285714" PS="1.099585062240664" SM="8">I'm loyal to my  friends,&quot; the US leader said of Gonzales during a brief stop in  Denmark on Wednesday before attending the G8 summit in Scotland.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="20.59259259259259" PS="1.649377593360996" SM="57">Republicans and Democrats are geared up for a major political  fight over a successor to Supreme Court Justice Sandra Day O'Connor,  who announced her retirement last Friday.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="18.387096774193548" PS="1.649377593360996" SM="30">The vacancy handed Bush his first chance to reshape the  ideological balance of the nine-member high court, which has immense  influence over the lives of Americans as it interprets the  constitution.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="21.8" PS="1.649377593360996" SM="10">Liberals warned Bush not to name an &quot;extremist&quot; who could  undermine women's right to have an abortion, while Republicans have  urged him to pick a strict conservative.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="12.571428571428571" PS="1.649377593360996" SM="4">Speculation has circled around Gonzales, who has been criticized  by both liberals and conservatives, especially for his role in the  controversial US policy towards terrorist suspects in captivity.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="12.26086956521739" PS="1.649377593360996" SM="3">&quot;(A)ll of a sudden this fellow, who is a good public servant and  a really fine person, is under fire...</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="12.538461538461538" PS="1.099585062240664" SM="12">I don't like it at all,&quot; Bush  told reporters gathered outside Danish Prime Minister Anders Fogh  Rasmussen's country residence, just north of Copenhagen.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="23.17241379310345" PS="1.649377593360996" SM="28">The US leader also reiterated that there would be &quot;no litmus  test&quot; on controversial issues like abortion or gay marriage for  nominees to the Supreme Court position.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="19.1875" PS="1.649377593360996" SM="2">&quot;(A)s I said during both of my campaigns, there will be no  litmus test.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="20.727272727272727" PS="1.099585062240664" SM="8">I'll pick people who... will strictly interpret the  Constitution and not use the bench to legislate from,&quot; he said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="12.977777777777778" PS="1.649377593360996" SM="18">Bush's visit, his first to Denmark but his fifth meeting with  Rasmussen since 2002, was seen by commentators as a symbolic gesture  thanking Denmark for supporting the war in Iraq, where it has  deployed more than 500 troops near the southern city of Basra.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="17.736842105263158" PS="2.4553941908713695" SM="43">The new Supreme Court justice must be a strong advocate for civil rights, and NAACP members are pressuring lawmakers to make that a priority in the selection process, NAACP officials said at the group's annual convention Saturday.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="17.242424242424242" PS="1.6369294605809128" SM="16">&quot;We very badly want to support a nominee committed to justice and fair play,&quot; said Julian Bond, chairman of the board of the National Association for the Advancement of Colored People.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="15.882352941176471" PS="1.0912863070539418" SM="0">&quot;We don't want to have to oppose a nominee who is opposed to those things.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="15.11111111111111" PS="1.0912863070539418" SM="6">... We hope to support someone who brings the country together rather than drives the country apart.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="12.902439024390244" PS="1.6369294605809128" SM="48">Bond's comments came on the opening day of the group's 96th annual convention, where more than 8,000 people are expected to discuss issues such as reparations for slavery, renewal of the voting rights act and ways of increasing membership.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="10.1" PS="1.6369294605809128" SM="12">The gathering comes as the group works to overcome budget shortfalls and recover from allegations that its former president, Kweisi Mfume, played favorites among employees and mismanaged the national staff.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="14.714285714285714" PS="1.0912863070539418" SM="21">It is also fighting an investigation by the Internal Revenue Service, which claims that NAACP officials' strong criticisms of the Bush administration violated the group's nonprofit status.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="12.2" PS="1.6369294605809128" SM="7">Last month, the Baltimore-based nonprofit selected a new president, Bruce S. Gordon, who will start in the job Aug. 1.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="24.0" PS="1.6369294605809128" SM="79">On Sunday, a seminar will focus on who will fill the Supreme Court seat that will be vacated by Justice Sandra Day O'Connor, who announced her retirement July 1.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="14.3" PS="1.0912863070539418" SM="25">NAACP members are being urged to contact the White House and their senators to influence selection of the nominee, said Hilary Shelton, head of the NAACP's Washington, D.C., branch.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="31.0" PS="1.6369294605809128" SM="0">&quot;We've educated our members on this,&quot; Shelton said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="19.31578947368421" PS="1.0912863070539418" SM="3">&quot;We've been doing this ever since we knew the chief justice (William Rehnquist) had thyroid cancer.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="9.076923076923077" PS="1.6369294605809128" SM="20">The convention also will highlight the persistent health disparities between blacks and other groups, with panel discussions, free health screenings and fitness sessions planned each day.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="18.0" PS="1.6369294605809128" SM="5">&quot;African Americans have the worst health outcomes of all groups,&quot; said Evelyn Lewis, a physician with Pfizer Inc., a pharmaceutical company, who spoke on a panel Saturday.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="33.375" PS="1.0912863070539418" SM="0">&quot;This is a civil rights issue.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="12.923076923076923" PS="1.6369294605809128" SM="31">The NAACP's health committee is investigating how well hospitals address racial gaps _ particularly by having black physicians on staff _ and it will grade hospitals in a report card to be released next year, said Rupert Richardson, an NAACP board member from Louisiana and chairwoman of the group's national health committee.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="34.77777777777778" PS="1.6369294605809128" SM="0">&quot;This is a problem everywhere,&quot; Richardson said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="11.21875" PS="1.6369294605809128" SM="12">NAACP officials also announced that Howard Dean, chair of the Democratic National Committee, and Ken Mehlman, chair of the Republican National Committee, will participate in a discussion on political issues on Thursday.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="1.0" PS="1.6369294605809128" SM="0">___</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="12.666666666666666" PS="1.6369294605809128" SM="3">On the Net:</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="20.40740740740741" PS="2.483402489626556" SM="71">Just when we thought there was no new speculation about President Bush's pending replacement of Sandra Day O'Connor on the Supreme Court, along comes a surprise.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="16.36111111111111" PS="1.6556016597510375" SM="21">During the president's politically correct consultation with the bipartisan Senate leadership this week, several senators urged that someone be considered who is not already on a lower federal bench, the customary source of previous appointments.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="4.5" PS="1.103734439834025" SM="0">A non-judge!</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="3.3333333333333335" PS="1.103734439834025" SM="0">What a concept.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="11.88" PS="1.6556016597510375" SM="12">The president apparently welcomed the suggestion, although the names being circulated so far in public all wear black robes or did so in the past.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="22.0" PS="1.103734439834025" SM="0">&quot;Would I be willing to consider people who had never been a judge?</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="27.666666666666668" PS="1.103734439834025" SM="3">The answer is: You bet,&quot; Bush told reporters.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="14.857142857142858" PS="1.103734439834025" SM="0">He indicated he was already doing so.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="20.0" PS="1.103734439834025" SM="2">&quot;We're considering all kinds of people -- judges, non-judges.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="14.527777777777779" PS="1.6556016597510375" SM="34">The idea is that a little hands-on political experience, such as O'Connor had in the Arizona state legislature before becoming a state court judge, might help the nominee reach sensible judicial judgments the country can support.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="18.060606060606062" PS="1.6556016597510375" SM="7">Sen. Arlen Specter, R-Pa., chairman of the Senate Judiciary Committee, noted that career lawyers spend too much time with &quot;footnotes and semicolons&quot; and have &quot;very little contact with people.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="17.0" PS="1.103734439834025" SM="5">Sen. Patrick Leahy, D-Vt., added that he approved of going &quot;outside the judicial monastery.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="17.923076923076923" PS="1.6556016597510375" SM="0">This is not as shocking an idea as it seems at first blush.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="18.176470588235293" PS="1.103734439834025" SM="0">Chief Justice William Rehnquist, for example, was tapped by President Richard Nixon while an assistant attorney general.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="18.77777777777778" PS="1.6556016597510375" SM="36">Legal historians point out that of the 108 justices who have served on the Supreme Court, only 48 were actually drawn from the ranks of sitting judges.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="10.619047619047619" PS="1.103734439834025" SM="9">The others have been practicing lawyers, attorneys general, Cabinet officers, senators, members of the House, governors, solicitors general and law professors.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="18.2" PS="1.6556016597510375" SM="14">Indeed, the Constitution does not even require high court justices to have a law degree.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="20.047619047619047" PS="1.103734439834025" SM="28">It merely says that judges, &quot;both of the supreme and inferior courts, shall hold their offices during good behavior.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="19.2" PS="1.6556016597510375" SM="21">The court under Chief Justice Earl Warren is an example of judicial diversity that has stood the test of time.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="10.466666666666667" PS="1.103734439834025" SM="16">That court handed down the landmark Brown vs. Board of Education ruling outlawing school segregation.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="11.947368421052632" PS="1.6556016597510375" SM="15">Although the Brown decision temporarily caused widespread social turmoil and President Dwight D. Eisenhower later complained that his decision to nominate Warren was his biggest mistake, the unanimous ruling was gradually accepted as the law of the land.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="13.444444444444445" PS="1.103734439834025" SM="16">Warren was a former governor and unsuccessful vice presidential candidate and the court included three former U.S. senators.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="18.916666666666668" PS="1.103734439834025" SM="0">Their background meant &quot;you had a broader experience,&quot; Specter observed.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="13.0" PS="1.6556016597510375" SM="35">Rehnquist's bout with thyroid cancer and sudden, short hospital stay this week for a fever have created a spike in speculation that Bush may have two vacancies to fill before the new court term begins in October.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="8.727272727272727" PS="1.103734439834025" SM="6">That would give him an opportunity to name simultaneously both a judge and a non-judge, broadening the public appeal of his choices.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="16.84375" PS="1.6556016597510375" SM="4">This adds a new dimension to the partisan argument about whether any new justice should reveal his or her ideological leanings or be judged only on that vague category, &quot;character.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="5.709677419354839" PS="1.6556016597510375" SM="6">A non-judge would have a different sort of record than a legal scholar, reflecting political choices made in real life with real consequences, instead of writings full of abstract philosophical theory.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="6.666666666666667" PS="1.6556016597510375" SM="3">So whose name might join the gossip circus now?</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="14.764705882352942" PS="1.103734439834025" SM="26">Sen. Orrin Hatch, R-Utah, former chairman of the Judiciary Committee, has openly lusted for a court seat.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="15.363636363636363" PS="1.103734439834025" SM="1">Although an ultraconservative, he is fair-minded and could be easily confirmed.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="14.375" PS="1.103734439834025" SM="15">Alas, he is 71 years old, a tad ancient for a lifetime seat the president sees as an important part of his historical legacy.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="14.882352941176471" PS="1.6556016597510375" SM="1">There are other sitting senators as well who are not extremists and could serve honorably with dignity.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="11.45945945945946" PS="1.6556016597510375" SM="11">Sen. Ben Nelson, D-Neb., a moderate and a leader of the bi-partisan &quot;gang of 14&quot; that derailed a GOP Senate move to kill the right to filibuster judicial nominations, might be an acceptable bipartisan compromise.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="7.625" PS="1.103734439834025" SM="10">That would also open up a Democratic seat in a red state that Republicans might recapture.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="15.153846153846153" PS="1.6556016597510375" SM="17">First Lady Laura Bush is publicly plumping for a woman to replace O'Connor, but gender is not foremost in the minds of most legal interest groups.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="10.625" PS="1.103734439834025" SM="0">Bush says he will consider picking a female, but he seems more interested in naming a Hispanic male -- perhaps Attorney General Alberto Gonzales.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="28.857142857142858" PS="1.103734439834025" SM="26">Bush is also getting advice from an unusual quarter, the current Supreme Court justices.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="24.261904761904763" PS="1.103734439834025" SM="20">Senate Minority Leader Harry Reid, D-Nev., said that at a recent luncheon, some of the justices said they would prefer &quot;somebody new on the court&quot; rather than more appellate judges who &quot;sit in their offices and read briefs.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="8.8125" PS="1.6556016597510375" SM="8">Despite the importance of the work, it can obviously get boring within those marble judicial halls.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="9.333333333333334" PS="1.103734439834025" SM="3">Not much dancing in the aisles.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="6.583333333333333" PS="1.103734439834025" SM="2">But a lot of people would figuratively kill to get there anyway.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="9.090909090909092" PS="1.6556016597510375" SM="3">(Marianne Means can be reached at the e-mail address means@hearstdc.com)</sentence>
	</Sentences>
</Topic>
