<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<Topic id="D0940H">
	<Sentences>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="17.322580645161292" PS="2.508710801393728" SM="68">Commissioner for Tourism Eva  Cheng Wednesday said the opening of Hong Kong Disneyland will be  divided into three phases from early August in order to ensure a  smooth and well-coordinated start.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="12.774193548387096" PS="1.6724738675958188" SM="26">&quot;The idea of a phased opening is to give the theme park, public transport operators and relevant departments a familiarization  period to adjust their operation and services,&quot; Cheng said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="13.75" PS="1.6724738675958188" SM="24">From early August to mid-August, the Disneyland Resort Line is  scheduled to run between Sunny Bay and Disneyland Resort Stations.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="16.923076923076923" PS="1.1149825783972125" SM="26">A section of the Park Promenade linked to the line will be opened.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="16.674418604651162" PS="1.6724738675958188" SM="43">From August to Sept. 11, all public facilities at Penny's Bay,  including public roads, the Park Promenade, the Inspiration Lake  Recreation Center, the Disneyland Resort Public Transport  Interchange, the Disneyland car and coach parks and the Disneyland Resort Pier will begin operation.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="8.25" PS="1.1149825783972125" SM="0">Franchised buses and taxis will  also start service.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="21.0" PS="1.6724738675958188" SM="15">From Sept. 12, the theme park and hotels will be open to the  public.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="9.08" PS="1.6724738675958188" SM="15">To ensure both the public and visitors are well informed of the operation sequence, communication channels have been set up by  relevant departments and operators.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="20.541666666666668" PS="1.6724738675958188" SM="37">Visitors can obtain information for planning their trips by  visiting a designated website, the Transport Department's website, and the Hong Kong Disneyland website.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="27.142857142857142" PS="1.6724738675958188" SM="35">Inquiry telephone lines will also be provided by the department and Hong Kong Disneyland.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="7.0" PS="1.1149825783972125" SM="11">Information booklets, TV and radio  commercials will be launched in August.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="16.583333333333332" PS="1.6724738675958188" SM="2">Cheng said the familiarization period will last for more than  one month.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="1" FQ="6.185185185185185" PS="1.1149825783972125" SM="24">She urged people to plan their visit, and make good use of communication channels to gather important information, such as the new transport services and opening hours.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="16.153846153846153" PS="2.508710801393728" SM="59">Disney officials consulted Chinese feng shui experts before building Hong Kong Disneyland, making changes such as tilting the site of the park several degrees and setting up &quot;no fire zones&quot; in kitchens, a company spokeswoman said Sunday.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="8.92" PS="1.6724738675958188" SM="15">Feng shui is the Chinese belief that harmonious energy and therefore better fortune can be achieved by the correct positioning of furniture and other objects.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="23.954545454545453" PS="1.6724738675958188" SM="36">Other feng shui influences include the park's orientation to face water with mountains behind, Hong Kong Disneyland spokeswoman Esther Wong said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="15.380952380952381" PS="1.6724738675958188" SM="25">The park's groundbreaking date and opening date of Sept. 12 were picked after conferring with feng shui specialists, she said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="7.068965517241379" PS="1.6724738675958188" SM="37">Feng shui experts also designated &quot;no fire zones&quot; in the kitchens, to try to keep the five elements of metal, water, wood, fire and earth in balance.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="9.052631578947368" PS="1.6724738675958188" SM="0">Wong said U.S.-based Walt Disney Co. decided to observe feng shui because it wanted to defer to local custom.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="13.161290322580646" PS="1.6724738675958188" SM="29">&quot;It's cultural considerations,&quot; Wong said, noting, &quot;all the food and language in the park must follow the habits and tastes of our consumers and future guests.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="24.047619047619047" PS="1.6724738675958188" SM="55">Hong Kongers tend to be Westernized, but Hong Kong Disneyland is expected to draw droves of guests from neighboring mainland China.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="10.11111111111111" PS="1.6724738675958188" SM="0">However, Disney's cultural sensitivity drew a backlash recently.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="11.96551724137931" PS="1.1149825783972125" SM="17">The park had planned to serve shark's fin soup, a Chinese delicacy, but dropped the dish after protests from environmentalists who expressed fears about the extinction of sharks.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="21.444444444444443" PS="1.6724738675958188" SM="85">Hong Kong Disneyland _ built on reclaimed land in the outlying Lantau island _ is a joint venture between The Walt Disney Co. and the Hong Kong government, but local taxpayers are footing most of the construction bill.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="8.1" PS="1.6724738675958188" SM="2">Critics have questioned whether the government got a good deal.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="2" FQ="20.6" PS="1.1149825783972125" SM="2">Officials have said the park will boost employment and tourism.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="22.25" PS="2.508710801393728" SM="35">Hong Kong Disneyland started its  on-line tickets selling Friday and its spokesperson said the  process had been smooth so far.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="30.90909090909091" PS="1.6724738675958188" SM="33">Hong Kong Disneyland announced its on-line ticketing plan on  June 22.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="18.541666666666668" PS="1.1149825783972125" SM="48">People who want to visit the theme park need to use their credit card to book tickets through the website of Hong Kong  Disneyland.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="6.888888888888889" PS="1.1149825783972125" SM="0">Each credit card can buy at most 10 tickets.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="19.357142857142858" PS="1.6724738675958188" SM="26">The theme park said that starting from Friday, guests can buy  tickets for its grand opening day on Sept. 12 and the first 90  days after its opening.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="27.22222222222222" PS="1.6724738675958188" SM="33">Hong Kong Disneyland will begin its rehearsal on Aug. 16 and it will last for approximately four weeks.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="14.096774193548388" PS="1.6724738675958188" SM="11">Rehearsal days have been a long-standing tradition at Disney  theme parks and present an opportunity for cast members --  Disneyland's term for employees -- to practice and adjust their  performance.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="8.037037037037036" PS="1.6724738675958188" SM="24">Specially invited guests include business affiliates, travel  trade associates, contractors, consultants, alliance partners,  government officers who have been involved in the disneyland  project, and certain charitable organizations.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="22.047619047619047" PS="1.6724738675958188" SM="37">Among the first guests to be received during the rehearsal days will be Hong Kong Disneyland cast members and their families.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="3" FQ="8.866666666666667" PS="1.6724738675958188" SM="0">Invitations to guests will range from several thousand to 30, 000 on a daily basis.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="27.5" PS="2.4224738675958193" SM="59">Hong Kong Disneyland will stage  its rehearsal from Aug. 16 to the theme park's opening on Sept.  12, the park said in a press release on Friday.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="13.264705882352942" PS="1.6149825783972127" SM="2">Rehearsal days have been a long-standing tradition at Disney  theme parks and resorts around the world and present an  opportunity for cast members, Disney's term for employees, to  practice and adjust their performance.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="17.352941176470587" PS="1.6149825783972127" SM="26">The rehearsal period at HK Disneyland will last for  approximately four weeks prior to the grand opening.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="12.64864864864865" PS="1.6149825783972127" SM="57">Specially invited guests including business affiliates, travel  trade associates, contractors, consultants, alliance partners,  government officers who have been involved in the Hong Kong  Disneyland project, and certain charitable organizations can enjoy a full day of Disney magic.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="20.73913043478261" PS="1.6149825783972127" SM="35">Among the first guests to be received during rehearsal days  will be Hong Kong Disneyland cast members and their families on  August 16.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="13.176470588235293" PS="1.6149825783972127" SM="2">Invitations to guests to experience the park will range from  thousands to 30,000 on a daily basis.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="4" FQ="25.954545454545453" PS="1.6149825783972127" SM="57">Meanwhile, tickets for Hong Kong Disneyland's grand opening day and the first 90 days after its opening went on sale Friday.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="24.11111111111111" PS="2.336236933797909" SM="83">The ticket sale of the Hong Kong Disneyland has been proceeding well, although there are still  tickets left for all the days available for booking online, Hong  Kong Disneyland Group Managing Director Don Robinson said Monday.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="11.272727272727273" PS="1.5574912891986061" SM="0">&quot;We started ticket sales last week, they are very popular.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="19.0" PS="1.038327526132404" SM="15">The  opening day and the weekend is most popular.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="22.46153846153846" PS="1.038327526132404" SM="23">Robinson said after  a signing ceremony with Standard Chartered Bank (Hong Kong)  Limited.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="17.285714285714285" PS="1.5574912891986061" SM="7">Although the tickets for all the days are not sold out,  Robinson said he is satisfied with the sale so far.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="15.3" PS="1.038327526132404" SM="2">He said the  company is looking into other sale outlets.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="5" FQ="17.61111111111111" PS="1.5574912891986061" SM="72">The Disneyland and Standard Chartered have signed an agreement  Monday for Standard Chartered to take a leading role in providing  various banking services for Hong Kong Disneyland, including the  exclusive provision of ATMs throughout the park.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="13.606060606060606" PS="2.508710801393728" SM="59">Hong Kong is banking on Mickey Mouse, Donald Duck and Buzz Lightyear to turn the city of skyscrapers and designer boutiques into one of the best places in Asia for a family holiday.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="24.318181818181817" PS="1.6724738675958188" SM="46">But critics say Hong Kong Disneyland, which opens Sept. 12, won't be the magic kingdom its supporters say it will be.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="13.826086956521738" PS="1.1149825783972125" SM="4">They question whether the park is the best way to create jobs, and they're also doubtful that it will attract big-spending tourists.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="16.714285714285715" PS="1.6724738675958188" SM="56">A fantasy land with a Sleeping Beauty Castle set against lush mountains on an outlying island, Hong Kong Disneyland predicts it will draw about 3.6 million tourists to Hong Kong within a year and up to 7.4 million annually after 15 years.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="16.216216216216218" PS="1.6724738675958188" SM="30">The park is expected to create 18,400 jobs _ 5,000 on site and the rest indirectly _ a number predicted to grow to 35,800 over two decades, according to the park and its prime investor, the Hong Kong government.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="11.69767441860465" PS="1.6724738675958188" SM="46">Authorities have bold ambitions: They hope Mickey Mouse will bring in a total of 148 billion Hong Kong dollars (US$19 billion; euro15 billion) over 40 years and transform the center for shopping and gourmet food into a tourist destination for all ages.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="12.05" PS="1.6724738675958188" SM="15">These potential benefits came at a hefty price for the government, which has a 57 percent stake in the park.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="12.352941176470589" PS="1.6724738675958188" SM="22">Hong Kong taxpayers are shelling out HK$16.5 billion (US$2.1 billion; euro1.7 billion), including costs for reclaiming land and supporting infrastructure, and extending a HK$6.1 billion (US$782 million; euro631 million) loan.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="13.0" PS="1.6724738675958188" SM="11">Disney's tab comes in much smaller.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="8.166666666666666" PS="1.1149825783972125" SM="11">It's paying HK$2.45 billion (US$314 million; euro253 million) and HK$120 million (US$15.4 million; euro12.4 million) in rent per year.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="24.894736842105264" PS="1.6724738675958188" SM="27">But even Hong Kong's political opposition, frequently at odds with the government, thinks it's the right move.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="25.454545454545453" PS="1.6724738675958188" SM="28">Democratic Party lawmaker Sin Chung-kai, the opposition's point man on the project, said the park will boost Hong Kong's economy.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="13.176470588235293" PS="1.6724738675958188" SM="2">&quot;Looking at jobs creation ... tourism, we approved the project from this perspective,&quot; Sin said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="40.25" PS="1.6724738675958188" SM="33">But critics say Hong Kong Disneyland is overrated.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="10.333333333333334" PS="1.6724738675958188" SM="6">Without the theme park, the territory's economy would still be able to generate just as many jobs _ and without the hefty investment from taxpayers, argues Credit Suisse First Boston economist Tao Dong.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="12.833333333333334" PS="1.6724738675958188" SM="0">&quot;It has more news value than economic value,&quot; he said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="17.263157894736842" PS="1.6724738675958188" SM="46">Tao questioned whether Hong Kong offered enough flights and hotel rooms to handle the expected influx of Disneyland visitors.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="19.727272727272727" PS="1.1149825783972125" SM="41">The Hong Kong Hotels Association has said the territory aims to add 14,000 extra hotel rooms by the end of the year.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="13.148148148148149" PS="1.6724738675958188" SM="24">Disneyland officials have said they expect about 40 percent of the visitors will eventually come from mainland China, just a short ride away by bus or train.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="12.833333333333334" PS="1.1149825783972125" SM="55">China relaxed rules on travel to Hong Kong in 2003, allowing its citizens to go as individuals instead of part of a tour group.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="10.710526315789474" PS="1.6724738675958188" SM="35">Tony Latter, a senior research fellow at the Hong Kong Institute of Economics and Business Strategy, expressed worries that low-spending tourists _ an apparent reference to visitors from China, where wages are low _ may create more problems than benefits.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="12.4" PS="1.6724738675958188" SM="0">&quot;High spenders are fine.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="9.205128205128204" PS="1.1149825783972125" SM="50">But the low spenders probably incur more hidden costs in terms of inconvenience, and pressure on infrastructure, than they generate added value for the economy,&quot; Latter said in a recent op-ed piece in the South China Morning Post.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="9.836363636363636" PS="1.6724738675958188" SM="91">Chinese traveling to Hong Kong on their own instead of with a tour group spent an average of HK$7,429 (US$952; euro768) in 2005, down from HK$10,440 in 2004, according to a study by Market Insights Group, which also found that more than 10 percent of the visitors in 2005 were just window-shoppers.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="9.130434782608695" PS="1.6724738675958188" SM="48">They spent an average of about four days in the city in 2005, compared to about a week in 2004, the survey said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="15.466666666666667" PS="1.6724738675958188" SM="38">The government should enrich the tourist experience beyond shopping by developing more tourist sites and activities unique to Hong Kong, not just Disneyland, Market Insights Group Director Roland Leung said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="14.05" PS="1.6724738675958188" SM="23">&quot;In terms of developing tourism facilities, we are focusing too much on one new site _ Disneyland,&quot; he said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="6" FQ="13.666666666666666" PS="1.6724738675958188" SM="44">&quot;We worry that even though people will spend an extra few hundred (Hong Kong) dollars (US$20-30) on tickets and some extra money on food, drinks and souvenirs because of Disneyland, overall it may not necessarily have a significant economic effect,&quot; he said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="16.953488372093023" PS="2.4303135888501743" SM="49">Mickey Mouse, Sleeping Beauty's castle and the Lion King are all here at Disney's new theme park in Hong Kong, along with classic rides familiar to fans of other Disney theme parks _ Space Mountain, the Mad Hatter Tea Cups and Dumbo.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="8.44" PS="1.6202090592334495" SM="24">But in creating the Disney experience for a mostly Chinese audience, this thoroughly American _ and notoriously detail-obsessed _ company has incorporated many elements of local culture.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="8.878787878787879" PS="1.6202090592334495" SM="41">Experts in the Chinese tradition of feng shui _ the belief that harmonious energy and good fortune can be achieved by the correct positioning of furniture and other objects _ were put on the payroll.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="6.0" PS="1.6202090592334495" SM="0">And while Coke and hamburgers can easily be found, guests can also dine on dim sum and sweet and sour pork.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="9.428571428571429" PS="1.0801393728222997" SM="11">Signage is in both Chinese and English.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="15.235294117647058" PS="1.6202090592334495" SM="31">On the advice of feng shui masters, the park faces the water with mountains in the back.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="16.714285714285715" PS="1.0801393728222997" SM="28">The feng shui experts even picked the opening date of the park _ Sept. 12.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="14.0" PS="1.6202090592334495" SM="3">Park officials also tweaked the layout to conform with feng shui principles.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="7.0" PS="1.0801393728222997" SM="36">They recommended &quot;no fire&quot; zones in restaurant kitchens _ with an eye to keeping the five elements of metal, water, wood, fire and earth in balance _ and water fountains.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="10.25" PS="1.0801393728222997" SM="13">A giant fountain near the park entrance features Mickey Mouse surfing on a stream of water spouting from a whale.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="3.111111111111111" PS="1.0801393728222997" SM="11">Statues of Donald Duck and Minnie Mouse stand nearby.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="13.842105263157896" PS="1.6202090592334495" SM="16">Visitors can navigate the park with signs written in their native Chinese, but the rides also include bilingual explanations.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="6.0" PS="1.0801393728222997" SM="13">Inside the Buzz Lightyear Astro Blasters ride, a talking animated Buzz Lightyear figure speaks in English while Chinese subtitles are flashed on a display board nearby.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="10.2" PS="1.6202090592334495" SM="3">Disney has delved deepest into local culture with the menu, which encompasses several Asian cuisines.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="8.533333333333333" PS="1.0801393728222997" SM="0">Apart from Chinese staples, there's also Kashmiri chicken curry and shrimp and vegetable tempura.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="6.555555555555555" PS="1.6202090592334495" SM="14">The Asian culinary delights are served in restaurants with decidedly un-Chinese architecture, providing a sometimes bizarre East-meets-West contrast.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="4.75" PS="1.6202090592334495" SM="2">The Tahitian Terrace restaurant serves roasted duck and curry laksa noodle soup.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="10.25" PS="1.0801393728222997" SM="25">The Viennese-influenced Market House Bakery in Main Street, U.S.A, uses European decor but juxtaposes Western pastries with Hong Kong-style delicacies.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="3.3125" PS="1.0801393728222997" SM="0">Chocolate croissants and cinnamon rolls are displayed alongside barbecued pork puffs, egg tarts and pineapple buns.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="18.0" PS="1.6202090592334495" SM="15">The rest of the park _ and even supporting infrastructure _ is vintage Disney.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="15.314285714285715" PS="1.0801393728222997" SM="27">Hong Kong's subway operator has launched a Mickey-themed train carriage _ with windows and hanging straps shaped like the character's head _ to ferry visitors from a suburban rail line to the park and back.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="25.75" PS="1.6202090592334495" SM="44">Hong Kong Disneyland also includes a variety of Disney attractions found elsewhere.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="7.897435897435898" PS="1.0801393728222997" SM="19">In addition to Space Mountain, Mad Hatter Tea Cups, Dumbo the Flying Elephant, and Buzz Lightyear Astro Blasters, there is a Jungle River Cruise and the &quot;Festival of the Lion King&quot; show, inspired by the animated movie.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="16.85185185185185" PS="1.6202090592334495" SM="50">Anchoring the park's skyline is a replica of the original Sleeping Beauty Castle from Disneyland in Anaheim, Calif., the flagship park that opened 50 years ago.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="17.142857142857142" PS="1.6202090592334495" SM="36">And &quot;The Golden Mickeys,&quot; a Broadway-style show that until now has been seen only on Disney cruises, has come ashore with its debut in Hong Kong.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="15.352941176470589" PS="1.6202090592334495" SM="47">One standout in Hong Kong is Mickey's PhilharMagic in Fantasyland, a 3-D show with appearances from Mickey, Donald Duck, Ariel from &quot;The Little Mermaid,&quot; Aladdin, Peter Pan, Tinker Bell and Simba.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="10.85" PS="1.6202090592334495" SM="40">With the help of 3-D glasses, the Disney characters appear as if they're right in front of the viewer.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="14.583333333333334" PS="1.0801393728222997" SM="3">When Donald Duck is splashed with water, the audience is likewise sprinkled.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="8.133333333333333" PS="1.0801393728222997" SM="15">The scent of cherries fills the theater when a dessert dish shows up on screen.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="20.257142857142856" PS="1.6202090592334495" SM="81">Mickey Mouse, Donald Duck and Goofy certainly aren't alien to the children of Westernized Hong Kong, but the average person in mainland China, a major target market for Hong Kong Disneyland, is less Disney-savvy.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="7.875" PS="1.6202090592334495" SM="0">So Disney has launched a massive marketing campaign.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="14.88888888888889" PS="1.0801393728222997" SM="48">It tapped clean-cut Hong Kong pop star Jacky Cheung _ a singer and actor who is one of the biggest acts in the Chinese-speaking world _ as park spokesman.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="13.0" PS="1.6202090592334495" SM="33">Since July 2004, Chan has hosted a TV program aired in both Hong Kong and China that shows classic Disney movies.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="7.466666666666667" PS="1.6202090592334495" SM="35">Disney has also introduced a fashion line at bargain clothing retailer Giordano, which has 1,500 outlets in Asia, Australia and the Middle East, 644 of which are in mainland China.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="10.583333333333334" PS="1.0801393728222997" SM="13">The clothing features pictures of Disney characters ranging from Mickey to Nemo.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="12.636363636363637" PS="1.6202090592334495" SM="66">A heavy dosage of all things Disney aside, Hong Kong Disneyland offers a rare expanse of space and lush greenery in a densely populated territory better known for its towering skyscrapers than wildlife.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="12.714285714285714" PS="1.6202090592334495" SM="14">The park is a landscaping achievement, reproducing a slice of America with Asian accents.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="9.488372093023257" PS="1.6202090592334495" SM="32">The driveway leading to the park entrance is lined with tall palm trees, and Adventureland mixes palm trees with bamboo fences, torches, rock formations, straw-thatched roofs and a fake jungle river in what resembles the set of the TV show &quot;Survivor.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="7.454545454545454" PS="1.6202090592334495" SM="30">Long open-air shelters that make up the bus depot are decorated by old-style lamps and rotating fan blades hanging from the ceiling, creating the feel of a saloon in the old American West.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="25.59090909090909" PS="1.6202090592334495" SM="48">At 126 hectares (310 acres), Hong Kong Disneyland is the smallest Disney park in the world, but Disney says expansions are planned.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="9.083333333333334" PS="1.0801393728222997" SM="13">One addition already lined up is the Autopia car ride in Tomorrowland.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="29.210526315789473" PS="1.6202090592334495" SM="26">Pricing at the park is affordable by Hong Kong standards but on the higher end for visitors from China.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="6.625" PS="1.0801393728222997" SM="37">Even in the commercial hub of Shanghai, which enjoys a much higher standard of living than most Chinese cities, the minimum monthly wage is a paltry 690 Chinese yuan (US$85;euro70).</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="19.29032258064516" PS="1.6202090592334495" SM="57">At the Emporium souvenir shop, a Mickey Mouse key chain costs 60 Hong Kong dollars (US$7.70;euro6.4); a standard Hong Kong Disneyland cap is priced HK$100 (US$13;euro11).</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="15.2" PS="1.6202090592334495" SM="6">Admission is HK$350 (US$45;euro37) for the weekend and public holidays, HK$295 (US$38;euro31) on weekdays _ the cheapest among Disney's five parks around the world.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="7.9" PS="1.0801393728222997" SM="2">Children under 11 pay HK$250 (US$32;euro27) on weekends and HK$210 (US$27;euro22) during the week.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="22.333333333333332" PS="1.6202090592334495" SM="49">The park houses two hotels _ Victorian-style Hong Kong Disneyland Hotel, with lots of towers and fussy architecture, and the sleek-looking Disney's Hollywood Hotel.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="16.96875" PS="1.6202090592334495" SM="33">These accommodations are steeply priced: Hong Kong Disneyland Hotel starts at HK$1,600 (US$205;euro170) a night and Disney's Hollywood Hotel's cheapest room costs HK$1,000 (US$128;euro106).</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="14.666666666666666" PS="1.6202090592334495" SM="13">For budget travelers, staying in the city is recommended.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="23.72" PS="1.0801393728222997" SM="57">Hong Kong offers hotels in many different price ranges, and the park is only about a 20-plus minute subway train ride from downtown Hong Kong.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="1.0" PS="1.6202090592334495" SM="0">___</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="7" FQ="1.5" PS="1.6202090592334495" SM="0">If You Go...@</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="17.103448275862068" PS="2.508710801393728" SM="55">Hong Kong Disneyland said Thursday it won't cut its daily maximum capacity of 30,000 people despite complaints of large crowds and long queues from visitors during rehearsal days.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="14.978260869565217" PS="1.6724738675958188" SM="59">Many of the 29,000 visitors who visited Hong Kong Disneyland for a charity day last weekend complained of excessively long queues to enter the park as well as to get on rides, and critics have urged Disney to reduce its maximum daily capacity, local newspapers reported.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="17.225" PS="1.6724738675958188" SM="50">But a Disney spokeswoman, Esther Wong, said the company is &quot;confident we can manage peak day attendance in the future and have designed our marketing and sales plan to manage attendance at Hong Kong Disneyland throughout the year.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="20.875" PS="1.6724738675958188" SM="50">Earlier, Disney said it was considering extending opening hours and adding more shows at the park _ due to open Monday _ as Hong Kong's financial chief expressed concern about the large crowds when the park is operating at its capacity.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="16.775" PS="1.6724738675958188" SM="62">The park, a joint venture between the Hong Kong government and The Walt Disney Co., is expected to draw 5.6 million people in its first year of operation, with mainland Chinese tourists accounting for about a third of that number.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="18.545454545454547" PS="1.6724738675958188" SM="37">But mainland travel agents said ticket sales for Hong Kong Disneyland are poor as the long queues and expensive hotel rates are driving mainland tourists away, the South China Morning Post reported Thursday.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="10.566666666666666" PS="1.6724738675958188" SM="26">&quot;We only managed to sell roughly 300 tickets during the first week after the park opens,&quot; Huang Feiyueh, executive director of Amsito Travel Service, was quoted as saying.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="21.704545454545453" PS="1.6724738675958188" SM="103">A survey released Wednesday by Hong Kong's top pro-China political party, the Democratic Alliance for the Betterment and Progress of Hong Kong, also showed that about three out of 10 people who had visited Hong Kong Disneyland said they won't go back.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="8" FQ="16.42105263157895" PS="1.6724738675958188" SM="2">Wong, however, disputed the criticisms and said &quot;we are confident that our park will be very popular.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="23.930232558139537" PS="2.508710801393728" SM="107">All of the 16,000 tickets for  the opening day of Hong Kong Disneyland have been sold out and the park will open to the public from 1:00 p.m. (0300 GMT) on Sept.  12, said Eva Cheng, Hong Kong commissioner for Tourism here  Thursday.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="23.92105263157895" PS="1.6724738675958188" SM="114">Speaking at a press conference for arrangements of Hong Kong  Disneyland's opening, she said the Transport Department,  Immigration Department, Police and some other government  departments have made full preparations for the smooth opening of  Hong Kong Disneyland.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="28.8" PS="1.6724738675958188" SM="91">The opening of Hong Kong Disneyland is expected to turn on a  new page of Hong Kong tourism, with focus on family tourists, she  said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="15.48936170212766" PS="1.6724738675958188" SM="74">Simon Peh, assistant director of Immigration Department, said  as one thirds of the Hong Kong Disneyland visitors are expected to come from the Chinese mainland, the Immigration Department is  ready to dispatch more staff members to various cross-border check points during the opening day and other holidays.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="19.384615384615383" PS="1.6724738675958188" SM="56">He suggested Chinese mainland passengers arrive in Hong Kong  via Lo Wu Check Point, Hong Kong's largest cross boundary check  point with 233 clearance counters.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="19.227272727272727" PS="1.6724738675958188" SM="79">Apart from the six franchised bus routes that operate to and  from Hong Kong Disneyland as of Aug. 16, 60 additional quotas for  cross-boundary coach services to and from Hong Kong Disneyland via Lok Ma Chau Control Point will become operational from Sept. 12.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="16.666666666666668" PS="1.6724738675958188" SM="37">In addition, the Kwoloon-Canton Railway Corporation will also  operate a &quot;rail-bus&quot; service for mainland visitors to travel  between the Lo Wu Check Point and Hong Kong Disneyland via Sheung  Shui Station from Sept. 12.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="17.38888888888889" PS="1.6724738675958188" SM="90">Cheng said, a sample survey made among 3,000 Guangdong citizens in August showed that over half of the people, who are ready to  visit Hong Kong in September and October, plan to visit Hong Kong  Disneyland.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="9" FQ="10.35483870967742" PS="1.6724738675958188" SM="39">To receive more tourists, the total number of hotel rooms will  be increased from 40,000 at the end of last year to about 54,000  at the end of 2006, she added.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="19.88888888888889" PS="2.508710801393728" SM="44">Many in Hong Kong are ready to give Mickey Mouse a big hug for bringing Disneyland to them.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="5.428571428571429" PS="1.6724738675958188" SM="0">But not dog-lovers, shark-defenders and fireworks foes.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="8.533333333333333" PS="1.6724738675958188" SM="14">The opposition may seem odd, in a Chinese city where fireworks are a fixture, shark fin soup is hugely popular, and stray dogs are summarily dealt with as health hazards.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="10.26923076923077" PS="1.6724738675958188" SM="6">But eight years after the British colony was returned to China, the capitalist city is much freer than the Communist mainland, and advocacy groups are vocal.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="15.178571428571429" PS="1.6724738675958188" SM="38">To start with the sharks: Disneyland said it was merely trying to honor local custom by selling shark fin soup at weddings in the park that opens Monday.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="8.96551724137931" PS="1.1149825783972125" SM="8">But environmentalists protested that shark populations are being depleted by the fishing industry, which usually hacks off the fins before tossing the fish back into the sea to die.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="10.238095238095237" PS="1.6724738675958188" SM="17">A top-level decision was made to take the soup off the menu, said Robert Iger, president of the Walt Disney Co.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="8.192307692307692" PS="1.6724738675958188" SM="24">Disney made more headlines when it asked dog-catchers to round up dozens of stray mutts near the park, sending many of them to a certain death.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="24.2" PS="1.6724738675958188" SM="26">And then there were the plans for nightly fireworks displays at the park on Lantau, Hong Kong's largest island.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="17.88888888888889" PS="1.1149825783972125" SM="5">Neighbors said they were worried about the noise and smoke, but the park stuck with its original plans.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="11.658536585365853" PS="1.6724738675958188" SM="19">In the months before the park's opening, the media sometimes sounded as though Disney were building a shoddy nuclear plant, rather than a cheerful amusement park with cuddly cartoon characters and a pink Sleeping Beauty Castle with a mountain backdrop.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="21.65714285714286" PS="1.6724738675958188" SM="81">Hong Kong Disneyland became a target because it involved high-profile marriage of big business and Hong Kong's government, the biggest investor in the US$3 billion park, said David Ketchum, a public relations expert.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="13.868421052631579" PS="1.6724738675958188" SM="21">&quot;As the Australians say, 'The tall poppy gets the chop,' and Disney's high profile worldwide and the lead-up to the opening has meant that many are looking for ways the venture will fail,&quot; Ketchum said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="14.928571428571429" PS="1.6724738675958188" SM="68">Michael DeGolyer, professor of government and international studies at Hong Kong Baptist University, said Disneyland apparently underestimated environmental cares in the crowded territory of about 7 million people.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="10.18918918918919" PS="1.6724738675958188" SM="13">&quot;If they thought that a huge commitment of government money would cushion them from public criticism, I think they will, and seem already, to be discovering that is not, definitely not, the case,&quot; DeGolyer said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="16.176470588235293" PS="1.6724738675958188" SM="14">But Disneyland's Iger said construction went smoothly with no major harm to the environment or public.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="6.902439024390244" PS="1.6724738675958188" SM="39">&quot;None of the issues really rose to the level of what I call a major concern in our minds, because they were either exaggerated _ and I won't be specific _ or they were fixable,&quot; Iger told The Associated Press.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="25.72222222222222" PS="1.6724738675958188" SM="38">Hong Kong's leader, Donald Tsang, dismissed the complaints about the fireworks, saying Disneyland is complying with regulations.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="11.052631578947368" PS="1.1149825783972125" SM="5">&quot;They have passed the test and I am satisfied with those tests,&quot; the chief executive told reporters.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="18.875" PS="1.6724738675958188" SM="35">Tsang's administration says the park will create thousands of new jobs and help turn Hong Kong into a regional tourist destination for families.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="14.48" PS="1.6724738675958188" SM="22">Christine Loh, a former lawmaker who runs her own think tank, Civic Exchange, said, &quot;Hong Kong people as a whole don't hate Disney.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="15.675" PS="1.1149825783972125" SM="59">They don't think it's the most awful thing to have a Disney theme park in Hong Kong _ unlike other parts of the world where citizens got together and said they don't want this kind of trash.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="16.862068965517242" PS="1.6724738675958188" SM="17">But Loh said there's unease and suspicion over the government being the park's prime investor as well as its regulator, and over the size of its stake.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="15.1" PS="1.6724738675958188" SM="2">&quot;The initial reaction was quite positive,&quot; she said.</sentence>
		<sentence CW="0" DocIndex="10" FQ="17.0" PS="1.1149825783972125" SM="22">&quot;But as it rolled out, Hong Kong people felt, is this a reasonable deal for us, or are we giving away pretty much everything to have them?&quot;</sentence>
	</Sentences>
</Topic>
