<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<Topic id="D0913C">
	<Title>Ten Commandments</Title>
	<Narrative>Describe developments in the two cases before the U.S. Supreme Court regarding the public display of the Ten Commandments.</Narrative>
	<DocSetA id="D0913C-A">
		<doc id="NYT_ENG_20050302.0107">JUSTICES EXAMINE 10 COMMANDMENTS CASE</doc>
		<doc id="LTW_ENG_20050302.0134">Supreme Court Wrestles With Ten Commandments Issue</doc>
		<doc id="LTW_ENG_20050302.0144">bc-times-front-1stld-writethru</doc>
		<doc id="NYT_ENG_20050302.0156">HIGH COURT HEARS ARGUMENTS IN 10 COMMANDMENTS CASE</doc>
		<doc id="NYT_ENG_20050302.0164">SUPREME COURT WRESTLES WITH TEN COMMANDMENTS</doc>
		<doc id="NYT_ENG_20050302.0169">HIGH COURT ARGUES TEN COMMANDMENTS CASES</doc>
		<doc id="NYT_ENG_20050302.0225">TEXAS SEEKS TO KEEP TEN COMMANDMENTS DISPLAY ON CAPITOL GROUNDS</doc>
		<doc id="NYT_ENG_20050302.0256">AN UNLIKELY JOURNEY UP THE LEGAL LADDER</doc>
		<doc id="AFP_ENG_20050302.0458">US Supreme Court examines issue of displaying Ten Commandments</doc>
		<doc id="AFP_ENG_20050302.0577">US Supreme Court examines Ten Commandments displays
by Gersende Rambourg</doc>
	</DocSetA>
	<Sentences>
		<sentence doc="1" line="1" para="1">A granite monument of the Ten Commandments outside the Texas Capitol amounts to an unconstitutional government endorsement of religion, a lawyer favoring a high wall between church and state told the Supreme Court on Wednesday.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="1" line="1" para="2">Arguments in the Texas case and a similar one from Kentucky pose the question of whether and how the Ten Commandments can be displayed on government property.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="1" line="2" para="2">Rulings in the cases could decide the shape of church-state relations for decades to come.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="1" line="1" para="3">The high court's decisions -- probably issued by the end of June -- could significantly raise or lower the wall separating government and religion.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="1" line="2" para="3">In doing so, they could clarify decades of confusing, muddled jurisprudence on what constitutes government endorsement of religion.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="1" line="1" para="4">In the Texas case, a homeless man filed suit challenging the constitutionality of a 6-foot by 3-foot monument in the shape of two tablets, inscribed with the Ten Commandments, two Stars of David and other symbols.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="1" line="1" para="5">The 43-year-old granite monument -- one of 38 on the Texas Capitol grounds in Austin -- was donated by the Fraternal Order of Eagles.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="1" line="2" para="5">The tablets are located roughly 75 feet from the Capitol building and 123 feet from the state Supreme Court.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="1" line="1" para="6">Opponents say that because the monument is on the Capitol grounds under the authority of the Texas legislature, it constitutes government endorsement of Christianity -- and in particular Protestant faiths, from which the display's Ten Commandments text is derived.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="1" line="1" para="7">&quot;Here you have a monument that claims not only is there a God, but God has dictated 10 rules for behavior,&quot; said Erwin Chemerinsky, a lawyer for the Texas man who wants the tablet removed.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="1" line="2" para="7">&quot;Imagine the Buddhist or Muslim who walks into the Supreme Court.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="1" line="3" para="7">He will realize this is not his government.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence doc="1" line="1" para="8">But lawyers supporting the monument and other similar displays argued that the Ten Commandments are a historically recognized symbol of law.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="1" line="2" para="8">And they noted that in a 1983 case, the Supreme Court found it was constitutional for a state legislature to begin its session with prayer.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="1" line="1" para="9">&quot;I don't see why one is good and the other is bad,&quot; said Justice Antonin Scalia.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="1" line="1" para="10">Justice Sandra Day O'Connor, often a swing vote when the justices are closely divided, questioned how appropriate it would be if &quot;the legislature itself wants to have the Ten Commandments displayed in its legislative halls.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence doc="1" line="1" para="11">When Chemerinsky said that would be unconstitutional, O'Connor complained &quot;it's so hard to draw that line.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence doc="1" line="1" para="12">If legislatures can open their sessions with prayers, O'Connor wondered how displaying the Ten Commandments in the same hall could be unconstitutional.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="1" line="1" para="13">The Kentucky case involves the constitutionality of Ten Commandments displays in two county courthouses.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="1" line="2" para="13">The displays have been modified twice in response to lower court rulings against the exhibits.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="1" line="1" para="14">The first ones consisted of a framed copy of the Ten Commandments.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="1" line="2" para="14">In its current version, the Ten Commandments are surrounded by historic American and British political and patriotic documents.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="1" line="3" para="14">A description in the final displays asserts the exhibits are of &quot;documents that played a significant role in the foundation of our system of law and government.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence doc="1" line="1" para="15">Opponents of the Kentucky exhibits argue county officials clearly had a religious purpose in posting the Ten Commandments and that the subsequent modifications were little more than a &quot;sham&quot; designed to insulate the displays from scrutiny.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="1" line="1" para="16">Justice David Souter said it seemed clear the displays were religious in nature.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="1" line="2" para="16">&quot;There's no reason the intent of this display has changed as the context has changed,&quot; Souter said.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="1" line="1" para="17">But supporters argue the court should not give too much weight to the original intent of county officials in erecting the displays.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="1" line="1" para="18">Kentucky authorities were only trying &quot;to do the best they could&quot; to follow previous court decisions, said Mathew Staver, who represented the Kentucky counties.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="1" line="2" para="18">&quot;They have got to be able to adjust their missteps whenever they step on a constitutional land mine that is blurry and confusing.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence doc="1" line="1" para="19">Acting Solicitor General Paul Clement, who represented the Bush administration in defending the Texas and Kentucky displays, said &quot;municipalities should be rewarded, not punished, for trying to change the context to try and get it right.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence doc="1" line="1" para="20">During the arguments Wednesday, justices appeared to struggle with how to judge the Texas and Kentucky displays -- and whether a single test could be constructed to decide when government-sponsored religious exhibits or actions run afoul of the Constitution.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="1" line="1" para="21">Justice Stephen Breyer doubted the high court could fashion a one-size-fits-all solution.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="1" line="1" para="22">&quot;We are a religious nation,&quot; Breyer said.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="1" line="2" para="22">&quot;I think the only way to do it is to look at the divisive quality of the display on a case-by-case basis.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence doc="1" line="1" para="23">Even as justices weighed the issue, they noted that religious symbols are displayed throughout the Supreme Court building.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="1" line="2" para="23">Above the dais, a large frieze depicts Moses holding the Ten Commandments -- without text displayed.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="1" line="3" para="23">Other historic lawgivers -- including Chinese philosopher Confucius, Roman Emperor Caesar Augustus, and former Chief Justice John Marshall -- also are depicted on the panel.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="1" line="1" para="24">Supreme Court sessions also open with a clerk proclaiming: &quot;God save the United States and this honorable court.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence doc="1" line="1" para="25">(Jennifer A. Dlouhy can be reached at 202-263-6400 or at the e-mail address jdlouhyhearstdc.com)</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="1" para="1">The Supreme Court struggled Wednesday with the politically charged issue of whether prominent display of the Ten Commandments at government buildings violates separation of church and state.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="1" para="2">In a Texas case, the court heard a challenge to a granite monument depicting the biblical Ten Commandments that sits near the entrance to the state Capitol in Austin.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="2" para="2">A second case tests whether Kentucky judges went too far when they posted framed copies of the Ten Commandments on the walls of their county courthouse.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="1" para="3">Defenders of the displays say they merely acknowledge the nation's religious heritage and the historical role of the Ten Commandments as a source of law and morality.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="2" para="3">The challengers say the biblical commands show the government to be endorsing religion, a violation of the First Amendment's ban on an ``establishment of religion.''</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="1" para="4">The questions asked by the justices suggested they are headed for a split decision.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="1" para="5">``It's so hard to draw the line,'' said Justice Sandra Day O'Connor, the frequent centrist who is likely to draw the line in both cases.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="1" para="6">State lawmakers may open their sessions with a prayer delivered by a chaplain, O'Connor noted, citing a past ruling that upheld this practice.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="2" para="6">How then can it be unconstitutional to have a monument with Ten Commandments sitting outside the Capitol, she asked.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="1" para="7">Because placing the Ten Commandments in front of the Capitol ``conveys a powerful message'' that the government itself ``is endorsing religion,'' said Duke law professor Erwin Chemerinsky on behalf of Thomas Van Orden, a homeless Texas man who sued to have the monument removed.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="2" para="7">``This is a sacred and solemn text.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="3" para="7">These are God's words to God's followers.''</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="1" para="8">To which Justice Antonin Scalia replied, in effect, what's wrong with that?</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="1" para="9">``It's a symbol that the government derives its authority from God,'' he said.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="2" para="9">``That's what this is about.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="3" para="9">Our laws are derived from God.''</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="1" para="10">Scalia said he believed 90 percent of the American people supported having the Ten Commandments on display, even if ``85 percent of them couldn't tell you what they say.''</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="1" para="11">Justice Anthony M. Kennedy said he too saw no problem with the display of the Ten Commandments.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="2" para="11">He said he did not understand ``this obsessive concern with anything religious.''</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="3" para="11">Those who do not wish to see the Ten Commandments at the Capitol grounds ``can avert their eyes.''</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="4" para="11">Demands to remove the Ten Commandments show ``hostility to religion,'' he added.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="1" para="12">The justices heard two hours of argument, and they sounded closely split.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="2" para="12">Four justices -- John Paul Stevens, David H. Souter, Ruth Bader Ginsburg and Stephen G. Breyer -- support a distinct separation of church and state, and signaled they are likely to vote to strike down the religious displays in Texas and Kentucky.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="1" para="13">When Mathew Staver, a lawyer representing the Kentucky judges, described the Ten Commandments as secular, not just religious, Ginsburg stopped him.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="1" para="14">``Have you read the first four Commandments?''</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="2" para="14">she asked.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="1" para="15">They begin with the words, ``I Am the Lord Thy God.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="2" para="15">Thou shalt have no other gods before me.''</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="3" para="15">Followers are also told not to have ``any graven images,'' to ``take the Name of the Lord Thy God in vain,'' and are reminded to keep the Sabbath Day holy.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="1" para="16">Four others -- Chief Justice William H. Rehnquist and Justices Clarence Thomas, Scalia and Kennedy -- have upheld religious displays and invocations at public buildings.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="1" para="17">None of the lawyers took an all-or-nothing stand on the issue.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="1" para="18">Chemerinsky, for example, said he saw no problem with a display in the courtroom where the justices met Wednesday -- high on the wall carved in marble is a depiction of Moses holding the stone tablets.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="2" para="18">The marble frieze depicts ``lawgivers'' throughout history, from Hammurabi and Solomon to Napoleon and John Marshall, the fourth chief justice of the Supreme Court.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="1" para="19">Lawyers on the opposite side of the case from Chemerinsky agreed that religious presentations by government could go too far.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="2" para="19">Acting Solicitor General Paul Clement, arguing on behalf of the Bush administration, was asked about Alabama Justice Roy Moore, whose display of the Ten Commandments in the center of the state's Supreme Court building has been rejected by lower courts.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="3" para="19">That ``crosses a constitutional line,'' Clement replied.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="1" para="20">Texas Attorney General Greg Abbott was asked whether the state could display a crucifix.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="1" para="21">``I seriously question whether a crucifix would be acceptable,'' he said.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="1" para="22">By contrast, the Ten Commandments are not just a religious symbol, he said.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="2" para="22">They ``are a historically recognized symbol of law,'' Abbott said.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="1" para="23">(Optional add end)</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="1" para="24">O'Connor could decide to split the difference on the issue by upholding the Ten Commandments in one case and striking them down in the other.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="2" para="24">For example, she could vote to uphold the Texas monument because it sits among other statutes and monuments on the Capitol grounds -- at one point, she described it ``as a park-like setting.''</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="1" para="25">However, she could also agree with her more liberal colleagues that the Kentucky judges went too far because they were determined to post the Ten Commandments so visitors would be all but obliged to read them.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="2" para="25">She sharply questioned the lawyer in the Kentucky case because officials there said they were trying to ``demonstrate America's Christian heritage'' when they first posted the Ten Commandments five years ago.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="1" para="26">The Supreme Court, including the ailing Rehnquist, will vote on the two cases behind closed doors later this week.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="2" para="26">The justices will issue a written opinion by late June.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="4" line="1" para="1">WASHINGTON - The Supreme Court Wednesday wrestled with whether the Constitution allows displays of the Ten Commandments on government property, bringing to a climax the latest battle in the culture war over the role of Christianity in the nation's public life and the exact line between church and state.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="4" line="1" para="2">Lawyers with the American Civil Liberties Union and a Texas plaintiff argued that the Ten Commandments presuppose the existence of a God.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="4" line="2" para="2">Although the tablets can be displayed on government property in a secular context, they said, displays in Texas and Kentucky went too far, violating the First Amendment's prohibition on establishing an official state religion.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="4" line="1" para="3">But supporters of the displays argued that the Ten Commandments serve a secular historic function as well as a religious one.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="4" line="2" para="3">They said the displays should be allowed to stay on the Texas state capitol grounds and in a Kentucky county courthouse.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="4" line="1" para="4">The arguments signaled little chance that the perennially contentious issue will be definitively resolved.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="4" line="2" para="4">The justices showed no appetite for creating a clear rule that state exhibits of the Ten Commandments will henceforth either always be allowed or always be forbidden.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="4" line="1" para="5">Instead, the arguments revolved around which legal doctrine should be used to decide on a case-by-case basis, how the details of the two cases before the court fit those tests, and whether those tests should be kept or modified.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="4" line="1" para="6">&quot;Because of our religious traditions, there's no way to do it other than to look at divisive qualities on a case-by-case basis,&quot; said Justice Stephen G. Breyer said.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="4" line="2" para="6">&quot;When I do that, I don't find divisiveness here.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence doc="4" line="1" para="7">Not so, responded Erwin Chemerinsky, a lawyer arguing against the Texas display.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="4" line="2" para="7">He noted that the chief justice of the Alabama Supreme Court lost his job in 2003 for defying a federal order to remove a Ten Commandments monument from his state courthouse.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="4" line="1" para="8">&quot;The Ten Commandments is enormously divisive today,&quot; he said.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="4" line="2" para="8">He also noted the hundreds of evangelical Christian protesters praying outside the Supreme Court walls and said he had received hate messages in the past week.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="4" line="1" para="9">The Texas case involves a Ten Commandments monument on the capitol grounds that was donated to the state four decades ago.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="4" line="2" para="9">The only one of 17 monuments on the grounds that has a religious theme, it was formally endorsed by the Legislature.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="4" line="1" para="10">The Kentucky case involves a recent effort to exhibit the Ten Commandments in a county courthouse as part of a &quot;Foundations Display&quot; along with political and patriotic texts that are not religious in nature.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="4" line="2" para="10">The first version contained only the commandments, and a second added excerpts from speeches and public documents that made specific reference to Christianity.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="4" line="3" para="10">The display in dispute, the third version, dropped the Christian references and added such documents as the Magna Carta.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="4" line="1" para="11">The courthouse changed the display in response to a lawsuit by the American Civil Liberties Union.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="4" line="2" para="11">A judge ruled that the new display was unconstitutional, because the history showed that officials' clear intent was to post a religious document.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="4" line="3" para="11">The counties asked the Supreme Court for a new test that looks at the effects of the display, not the intent of its sponsors.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="4" line="1" para="12">The dispute also had personal overtones for the Supreme Court.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="4" line="2" para="12">Its courtroom is replete with Ten Commandments imagery, from a frieze that includes Moses holding the tablets to several images of twin tablets with Roman numbers from 1 to 10.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="4" line="1" para="13">Lawyers challenging the constitutionality of the Texas and Kentucky displays showed no desire to confront the high court about its own use of the iconography.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="4" line="2" para="13">They said the Supreme Court's use of the image was obviously of a secular nature, to acknowledge one source of law among many, while insisting that the Texas and Kentucky displays went too far.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="4" line="1" para="14">Nevertheless, the Supreme Court's use of commandments imagery was a regular theme.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="4" line="1" para="15">Justice Ruth Bader Ginsberg pointed to the frieze on the south wall of the courtroom, which depicts Moses with eight other ancient lawgivers.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="4" line="2" para="15">The tablets of Moses are tilted so only the second five commandments, all secular rules, such as &quot;Thou shalt not kill,&quot; are visible.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="4" line="3" para="15">Religious rules, such as &quot;Thou shalt not take the name of the Lord thy God in vain,&quot; are hidden.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="4" line="1" para="16">Ginsberg asked whether an inscription of the secular rules without the tablets would be acceptable on government property.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="4" line="2" para="16">Chemerinsky said they would be since those rules are also found in Texas statutes.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="4" line="3" para="16">That led Justice Antonin Scalia to interrupt with a scoff: &quot;Who are you kidding?</sentence>
		<sentence doc="4" line="4" para="16">Everyone knows these come from the Ten Commandments.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence doc="4" line="1" para="17">Scalia, a devout Catholic, also took issue with the argument by Attorney General Greg Abbott of Texas that the display from that state serves a secular function.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="4" line="2" para="17">Scalia denounced the idea of &quot;watering down&quot; the religious message of the Ten Commandments, which he said was &quot;government derives its authority from God,&quot; and suggested that it would be a &quot;Pyrrhic victory&quot; if Texas won on those grounds.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="4" line="1" para="18">Atheists should &quot;turn your eyes away if it's such a big deal to you,&quot; he added.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="4" line="1" para="19">The court's two swing voters, Justices Anthony M. Kennedy and Sandra Day O'Connor, both appeared uneasy about the prospect of ordering governments to take down all of the thousands of Ten Commandments displays around the country.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="4" line="1" para="20">Kennedy talked about &quot;an obsessive concern with any mention of religion&quot; that would amount to impermissible &quot;hostility to religion.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence doc="4" line="2" para="20">O'Connor suggested that for older monuments and displays, the state's &quot;interest in preserving old objects&quot; in a &quot;museumlike setting&quot; could be an alternative justification for not tearing down Ten Commandments monuments.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="4" line="1" para="21">The court last addressed the issue in a Kentucky case in 1980, striking down a state mandate that schools post copies of the commandments.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="1" para="1">The justices of the Supreme Court appeared to wrestle with contradictory impulses as they heard arguments on Wednesday in two cases challenging government displays of the Ten Commandments.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="1" para="2">On the one hand, they were searching for a broad principle that could decide not only these particular disputes, but future ones as well.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="2" para="2">On the other hand, they appeared powerfully drawn to deciding the two cases on their specific facts, even at the risk of inviting an endless parade of future cases.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="1" para="3">Was the 22-acre park surrounding the Texas Capitol, where a Ten Commandments monument sits among 16 other displays, all of them nonreligious, the equivalent of an outdoor museum or sculpture garden?</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="2" para="3">Fine: maybe just such a mixed display might pass constitutional muster, even if a stand-alone Ten Commandments in a future case might prove more troublesome.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="1" para="4">Did it matter that the two Kentucky courthouses now seeking to display a framed Ten Commandments surrounded by nine nonreligious historical documents had at first hung unadorned copies of the Commandments and did not add the other documents until after a lawsuit was filed?</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="2" para="4">If so, if that history provided the constitutional taint that led a federal appeals court to order removal of the entire displays, then the answer to whether a display without such a history would be acceptable could wait for another day.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="1" para="5">By the end of two hours of argument, it was not clear how the justices would resolve the problem they created for themselves when, after 25 years of silence on the Ten Commandments, they agreed to decide these two cases.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="2" para="5">Justice Antonin Scalia, unsurprisingly, expressed a definitive view, consistent with his long-held position in religion cases.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="3" para="5">He called the Ten Commandments &quot;a symbol of the fact that government derives its authority from God,&quot; adding, &quot;That seems to me an appropriate symbol to put on government grounds.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="1" para="6">But Justice Sandra Day O'Connor, who may well be in a position to cast the deciding vote, appeared uncertain as she tried out various approaches to resolving the cases on narrow grounds.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="2" para="6">Referring to the Texas monument, erected in 1961 by the Fraternal Order of Eagles, she wondered aloud whether &quot;at some point&quot; the preservation of an &quot;old object&quot; might itself provide an independent, nonreligious justification for keeping the Ten Commandments on the Capitol grounds.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="1" para="7">The justices' visible struggle reflected the fact that the Supreme Court's own precedents provide relatively little guidance on how to tell the difference between religious displays that amount to an unconstitutional &quot;establishment&quot; of religion and those that acknowledge religion in such a minimal or contextual way that the Constitution is not offended, even if some individuals are.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="1" para="8">In 1980, the court invalidated a Kentucky law that required the posting of the Ten Commandments in every public school classroom, but no one seemed to suggest that the old case, Stone v. Graham, provided an answer to the new ones.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="2" para="8">In the new cases, one federal appeals court upheld the Texas display even as another struck down the two in Kentucky.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="1" para="9">Would it be permissible for the Texas Legislature to post the Ten Commandments, not in an outdoor park, but in the halls of the Capitol, O'Connor asked Erwin Chemerinsky, who was representing the Austin man who challenged the Texas display.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="1" para="10">No, replied Chemerinsky, a professor at Duke University Law School, because that would be a sign of government endorsement of religion.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="1" para="11">But the Supreme Court itself has upheld the practice of beginning a legislative session with a prayer, O'Connor pointed out.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="1" para="12">&quot;It can't be that just because a prayer is permissible, everything becomes permissible,&quot; Chemerinsky replied, adding that a Legislature could not mount a large Latin cross on the top of a state Capitol.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="1" para="13">&quot;It's so hard to draw the line!&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="2" para="13">O'Connor exclaimed.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="1" para="14">Justice Stephen G. Breyer said he had reluctantly and tentatively come to the conclusion that there was no way for the court to decide religious display cases other than by evaluating the divisive nature of the display on a case-by-case basis.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="1" para="15">The Ten Commandments are &quot;enormously divisive,&quot; Chemerinsky responded, urging that the court &quot;not ignore social reality.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="2" para="15">He mentioned the crowds that the arguments themselves drew to the court, as well as the dispute in Alabama two years ago over Chief Justice Roy Moore's display of a large Ten Commandments monument in the courthouse rotunda.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="1" para="16">Scalia asked whether the marshal's invocation that begins each Supreme Court session, &quot;God save the United States and this honorable court,&quot; was not also &quot;divisive, because there are people who don't believe in God.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="1" para="17">Chemerinsky replied that it was important to draw a distinction between &quot;minimal and maximum religious content.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="2" para="17">The message of the Ten Commandments was deeply religious he said: &quot;All of these are God's commands to his people.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="1" para="18">Justice David H. Souter asked whether a tablet containing only the last five commandments, the injunctions against killing, stealing, and so on, might be constitutional because, unlike the first five, they did not necessarily imply religious belief.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="1" para="19">That would be a harder case, Chemerinsky replied, but such a tablet would still be unconstitutional because it would still convey the Ten Commandments' message.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="1" para="20">(STORY CAN END HERE.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="2" para="20">OPTIONAL MATERIAL FOLLOWS.)</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="1" para="21">What about a &quot;piece of stone&quot; simply carved with the various &quot;thou shalt nots,&quot; Souter asked.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="1" para="22">That would be acceptable as a &quot;reflection of law&quot; rather than religion, Chemerinsky replied.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="1" para="23">&quot;Who are you kidding?&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="2" para="23">Scalia broke in, adding that &quot;everyone knows&quot; that the reference would be to the Ten Commandments.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="1" para="24">&quot;Context matters enormously,&quot; Chemerinsky said.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="1" para="25">Greg Abbott, the Texas attorney general, described the Ten Commandments as a &quot;recognized symbol of law&quot; and defended the state's display as having the secular purpose of &quot;recognizing historic influences&quot; on the legal system.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="1" para="26">The attorney general's argument distressed Scalia.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="2" para="26">&quot;You're watering it down to say the only message is a secular message,&quot; the justice said.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="3" para="26">&quot;I can't agree with you.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="4" para="26">'Our laws come from God.'</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="5" para="26">If you don't believe it sends that message, you're kidding yourself.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="6" para="26">Later, Scalia told Abbott: &quot;I would consider it a Pyrrhic victory for you to win on the grounds you're arguing.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="1" para="27">In both the Texas case, Van Orden v. Perry, No.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="2" para="27">03-1500, and the Kentucky case, McCreary County v. American Civil Liberties Union, No.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="3" para="27">03-1693, the Bush administration argued on behalf of the displays.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="4" para="27">&quot;The Ten Commandments have an undeniable religious significance, but also a secular significance as a code of law and a well recognized symbol of law,&quot; Paul D. Clement, the acting solicitor general, told the justices.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="5" para="27">He added: &quot;The Establishment Clause should not be interpreted to force the state to send a message of hostility toward religion.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="1" para="28">The question was one of degree, Clement suggested.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="2" para="28">In answer to a question from Justice Anthony M. Kennedy, he said that Moore in Alabama &quot;probably&quot; crossed the constitutional line when he turned the courthouse rotunda into the equivalent of a &quot;religious sanctuary.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="3" para="28">Clement added: &quot;The state can have a permissible acknowledgment of religion, and I don't think in this case the state of Texas has gone too far.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="1" para="29">In defending the Kentucky courthouse displays, Mathew D. Staver, a lawyer with Liberty Counsel, a Florida-based group associated with the Rev.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="2" para="29">Jerry Falwell, said the appeals court had &quot;ignored the overall context&quot; when it ordered the removal of courthouse displays that contained the Ten Commandments surrounded by the text of nine historic documents, including the Mayflower Compact.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="1" para="30">But it was the context that the justices probed, several dwelling on the original 1999 displays that contained the Ten Commandments alone.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="2" para="30">The two counties, McCreary and Pulaski, had decided to &quot;switch rather than fight,&quot; Staver said, and should be &quot;rewarded, not punished, for trying to get things right.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="1" para="31">But &quot;the courts cannot turn a blind eye to a sham secular purpose,&quot; David A. Friedman, general counsel of the American Civil Liberties Union of Kentucky, told the justices.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="2" para="31">He said a &quot;reasonable observer&quot; would know the history and understand the counties' real purpose.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="1" para="1">The marshal yelled &quot;God Save the United States and this honorable court&quot; and the U.S. Supreme Court justices took their seats in a room bearing a sculpted depiction of Moses holding a Ten Commandments tablet.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="1" para="2">That backdrop became part of the questioning Wednesday as the justices considered the ways in which government and religion intertwine during oral arguments in two closely-watched cases from Texas and Kentucky.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="2" para="2">Their ruling, due by the end of June, is expected to clarify when government may acknowledge religion and more specifically, under what circumstances it can display the Ten Commandments.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="1" para="3">One of the cases originated when Thomas Van Orden, a homeless former lawyer, sued Texas officials in 2001, claiming that a Ten Commandments monument near the rear entrance to the state Capitol violated the constitutional separation between church and state.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="2" para="3">He lost at trial and then on appeal and the monument remains.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="1" para="4">His lawyer, Duke University Law Professor Erwin Chemerinsky, was the first to field questions from the justices.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="1" para="5">&quot;What happens if (the Ten Commandments) are packaged in a museum-like setting?&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="2" para="5">asked Justice Sandra Day O'Connor, echoing an argument by Texas Attorney General Greg Abbott that the monument is one of many on the grounds that shows different influences on Texas culture.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="1" para="6">&quot;This isn't a museum-like setting,&quot; Chemerinsky said, dismissing Abbott's argument with one one of his own -- that the monument is in a uniquely prominent place on the Capitol grounds, away from any other display.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="1" para="7">&quot;Doesn't the venue count?&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="2" para="7">asked Justice Ruth Bader Ginsburg, noting that there is a difference between prayer in schools -- which the court has struck down -- and a prayer to open a legislative session, which the court has allowed.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="1" para="8">Chemerinsky agreed, saying that &quot;monument standing alone does convey the government's endorsement for religion.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="1" para="9">Justice Anthony Kennedy said he would be worried that any ruling by the court that showed &quot;obsessive concern with any message of religion&quot; would suggest a &quot;hostility towards religion.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="1" para="10">&quot;This is a classic avert your eyes,&quot; Kennedy said.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="2" para="10">&quot;If an atheist walks by he can avert his eyes.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="1" para="11">&quot;I don't think so, your honor,&quot; Chemerinsky said, arguing that the message conveyed by the monument is that the Texas government favors Judeo-Christian religions above others.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="1" para="12">That, Chemerinsky said, would be a violation of the Establishment Clause, the part of the First Amendment that says &quot;Congress shall make no law respecting an establishment of religion.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="1" para="13">After Chemerinsky sat down, Abbott argued that the Ten Commandments are a historically recognized &quot;symbol of law&quot; that are part of an integrated display erected to honor a service organization's work with juveniles.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="2" para="13">The monument, he added, has stood for 40 years unchallenged before Van Orden brought his case.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="1" para="14">The Supreme Court decided to hear the Texas and Kentucky cases amid a national debate on religion's role in government.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="2" para="14">Ten Commandments displays that have stood for decades in and near courthouses and other public buildings across the country have come under frequent attack by people and groups saying they violate the Constitution.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="1" para="15">Defenders of the Ten Commandments displays, including the Bush Administration, say the religious text has been important in developing the country's legal and civic traditions.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="1" para="16">In the Kentucky case, two counties posted framed copies of the Ten Commandments on the walls of two different courthouses.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="2" para="16">They later added other documents, including copies of the Magna Carta and the Declaration of Independence.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="3" para="16">An appeals court ordered those Ten Commandments displays removed.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="1" para="17">Lower courts have issued conflicting rulings in dozens of cases involving Ten Commandments displays in recent years.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="1" para="18">Those include a 2003 Alabama case that led Chief Justice Roy Moore to be removed from office for refusing to comply with a court order to remove a Ten Commandments monument from the state judicial building.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="1" para="19">Moore supporters were among several hundred people who assembled Wednesday morning outside the nation's highest court as temperatures hovered around freezing with a stiff wind that made it feel ten degrees cooler.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="1" para="20">&quot;The Ten Commandments is part of our history; it's a Christian history,&quot; said Rod McDougal of San Diego, a Moore supporter who has been traveling with the monument removed from the Alabama court building.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="1" para="21">Chris Clipper, a former Austinite who moved to a Washington suburb last year, paced the sidewalk as crowds lined up for the few public seats in the white-columned Supreme Court building, carrying a sign proclaiming himself an atheist.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="1" para="22">&quot;I think there should be a public forum where all views should be heard, respected,&quot; said Clipper, 41.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="1" para="23">Inside the courtroom, Justice Antonin Scalia joined Kennedy in signaling clear support of the government's right to acknowledge religion.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="1" para="24">Scalia suggested during Chemerinsky's argument that there is no difference between referencing God at the opening of Supreme Court hearings and erecting a Ten Commandments monument.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="1" para="25">&quot;I think 90 percent (of Americans) believe in the Ten Commandments and I think 85 percent can't tell you what they are,&quot; Scalia said, drawing laughs from people in the packed chamber.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="2" para="25">&quot;It's a symbol that government derives its authority from God.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="1" para="26">Chemerinsky countered that while the inclusion of &quot;God&quot; in a prayer may be a symbol, displaying a religious text like the Ten Commandments conveys a &quot;profound religious message.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="1" para="27">As for the depiction of Moses -- who Christians believe received the Ten Commandments from God on Mount Sinai -- on a frieze on a wall to the left of the justices inside the Supreme Court chambers.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="2" para="27">Chemerinsky said it is constitutional because it is included in a display of 15 &quot;great lawgivers.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="3" para="27">The Texas monument would be constitutional if it were displayed similarly.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="1" para="28">When it was Abbott's turn, Justice John Paul Stevens asked him whether he would consider a crucifix of the same size and shape on the Capitol grounds constitutionally acceptable.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="1" para="29">Probably not, Abbott said, because it is &quot;not a historically recognized symbol of law .</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="2" para="29">.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="3" para="29">.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="4" para="29">and does not send a message to all people.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="1" para="30">Abbott fielded several questions about his legal argument that the Ten Commandments are secular.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="1" para="31">&quot;You are asking us to ignore the religious purpose?&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="2" para="31">Kennedy asked.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="1" para="32">There is both a secular and a religious interpretation of the commandments, Abbott said.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="1" para="33">O'Connor, widely believed to be the swing vote in the case, asked how the state could erect a monument on state grounds and purport to not endorse its message.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="1" para="34">&quot;Every monument on the Capitol grounds enjoys a state endorsement, doesn't it?&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="2" para="34">she asked.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="1" para="35">Abbott replied that only nine of 17 monuments bear the state seal.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="2" para="35">The Ten Commandments monument does not, he said.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="1" para="36">Later, Acting U.S.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="2" para="36">Solicitor General Paul Clement -- who spoke on behalf of the Bush Administration -- echoed Abbott's claims.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="1" para="37">&quot;The Ten Commandments have undeniable religious significance,&quot; he said.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="2" para="37">&quot;But they also have secular significance as a code of law.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="1" para="38">Steven Kreytak writes for the Austin American-Statesman.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="2" para="38">E-mail: skreytak@statesman.com</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="1" para="1">The Ten Commandments monument on the Texas Capitol grounds should remain because it is a cultural and historical symbol that does not violate the separation of church and state, Texas Attorney General Greg Abbott told the U.S. Supreme Court Wednesday.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="1" para="2">But an attorney representing Thomas Van Orden, an Austin, Texas, homeless lawyer challenging the law, countered that the 40-year-old pink granite slab sends a &quot;powerful religious message&quot; and defies years of legal doctrine prohibiting a government endorsement of religion.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="1" para="3">Justices peppered both sides with pointed questions as the court confronted church-state cases that could affect the display of religious symbols at public sites across the country.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="2" para="3">The justices also heard a challenge to Ten Commandments exhibits in Kentucky courthouses.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="1" para="4">&quot;I think 90 percent of Americans believe in the Ten Commandments,&quot; said Justice Antonin Scalia, &quot;but 85 percent probably couldn't tell you what they are.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="1" para="5">The cases constituted the first Ten Commandments dispute to come before the court in a quarter-century and attracted dozens of third-party participants, from atheists to religious groups.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="2" para="5">Hundreds of protesters from at least a half-dozen states mustered on the Supreme Court steps, often kneeling in impromptu prayer services.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="1" para="6">More than a dozen onlookers, including out-of-town law students, spent the night in windy, freezing temperatures to get seats to the landmark arguments.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="2" para="6">Protesters, bundled against the biting chill, displayed their sentiments with signs declaring, &quot;Keep Church and State Separate&quot; or &quot;No Religious Test for Patriotism.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="1" para="7">The challenge to the Texas monument drew an extra burst of attention because of the man who waged it -- Van Orden, a Southern Methodist University graduate who is no longer eligible to practice law.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="2" para="7">He slept in an Austin park while spending his days in the Texas State Library preparing the case.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="1" para="8">Van Orden, who filed his suit in 2002, was not present for the Supreme Court arguments, but his chief attorney, Duke University law school professor Erwin Chemerinsky, said he and Van Orden have stayed in touch through almost daily e-mail exchanges.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="2" para="8">Chemerinsky agreed to handle the case for free after Van Orden called and asked his help.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="1" para="9">The Ten Commandments monument was donated to the Texas Legislature in 1961 by the Fraternal Order of Eagles, a century-old civic organization, to commemorate youth and denounce juvenile delinquency.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="2" para="9">The monument is one of 17 memorials on the State Capitol grounds and sits halfway between the Capitol and the State Supreme Court building.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="1" para="10">Abbott, making his first argument before the high court, contended that the Ten Commandments monument, while containing a sacred religious text, constitutes a cultural, historical and legal symbol by being clustered with a diverse array of other monuments.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="2" para="10">He described the setting as an outdoor museum.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="1" para="11">But Chemerinsky argued that the monument serves no secular purpose and &quot;impermissibly&quot; endorses religion.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="2" para="11">The 51-year-old law professor, acknowledging the emotional intensity of the issue, also told the justices that he has received hate mail because of his legal opposition to the Texas monument.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="1" para="12">At issue is the Establishment Clause in the Constitution's First Amendment, prohibiting Congress from enacting any law establishing a government-sanctioned religion.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="2" para="12">The 10-word clause is the cornerstone of more than two centuries of legal doctrine on the separation of church and state.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="1" para="13">Justices interrupted frequently as the hourlong argument veered into hypothetical discussions on whether other religious-oriented expressions, such as an opening prayer before Congress or a Thanksgiving proclamation, would be banned under a strict interpretation of what constitutes religion.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="2" para="13">They also noted that Moses and the Ten Commandments are part of a decorative historical carving along the ceiling of the Supreme Court chambers.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="1" para="14">&quot;I don't know why the one is good and the other is bad,&quot; said Scalia, contrasting the Ten Commandments monument with a congressional prayer.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="2" para="14">During the subsequent arguments on the Kentucky case, Scalia said sardonically: &quot;I don't know who we're addressing when we say, 'God Save this honorable court.'</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="3" para="14">&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="1" para="15">Justice Anthony Kennedy complained about &quot;an obsessive concern to any mention of religion&quot; on public sites.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="2" para="15">&quot;This is a classic 'avert your eyes,' &quot; he said.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="3" para="15">&quot;If an atheist walks by, he can avert his eyes.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="1" para="16">Justice John Paul Stevens raised the possibility of posting a disclaimer that the Ten Commandments and similar displays might have a religious connotation.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="2" para="16">Abbott said a disclaimer might help fend off legal challenges but he later told reporters that he felt it would be unnecessary under Texas' argument that the Austin monument is non-religious.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="1" para="17">Abbott, who was partially paralyzed when he was struck by a falling tree while jogging two decades ago, made his arguments from his wheelchair.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="2" para="17">Stevens told Abbott that his presentation demonstrated &quot;that it's not necessary to stand at the lectern in order to do a fine job.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="1" para="18">Ailing Chief Justice William Rehnquist was absent but Stevens, second in seniority, said Rehnquist &quot;reserves the right&quot; to participate in the decision.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="1" para="19">Abbott, 47, a former state Supreme Court justice, declined to predict the outcome of the case but several attorneys on both sides of the issue said the justices' comments suggested that the court might support the state's arguments.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="1" para="20">&quot;In the Texas case, they seemed more inclined to find the display OK,&quot; said Steven Freeman of New York, an attorney with the Anti-Defamation League, which supported Van Orden's challenge.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="1" para="21">(Visit the Star-Telegram's online services at www.star-telegram.com) nn</sentence>
		<sentence doc="8" line="1" para="1">Win or lose, Thomas Van Orden savored the moment on Wednesday as the lawsuit he brought here three years ago was preoccupying the highest judges of the land in Washington.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="8" line="1" para="2">&quot;What are the chances of this case making it to the Supreme Court?&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence doc="8" line="2" para="2">he asked from behind a borrowed computer at the University of Texas law library.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="8" line="3" para="2">&quot;My God!</sentence>
		<sentence doc="8" line="4" para="2">My little case.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence doc="8" line="1" para="3">It is hardly little -- a constitutional challenge to displaying the Ten Commandments on the grounds of the Texas Capitol, and so, a case that could rewrite aspects of church-state relations when the high court rules, perhaps this summer.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="8" line="2" para="3">But at any point in its journey up the legal ladder, Van Orden said, it might have failed for the unlikeliest of reasons: a lack of paper, or postage.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="8" line="1" para="4">Van Orden, a suspended lawyer who put his age at 60, compiled the case while homeless, living in a tent on a wooded tract in Austin, surviving on food stamps, while writing his briefs at the law library and scrounging for writing materials.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="8" line="1" para="5">&quot;You can find paper and pens on the college campus,&quot; he said.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="8" line="2" para="5">&quot;Just look down.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence doc="8" line="1" para="6">At times, he said, he lacked the 10 cents to print out even one page of his briefs and did not have the money to mail his appeal to the federal appeals court in New Orleans.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="8" line="1" para="7">But he disdained what he portrayed as the caricaturing of his story by journalists.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="8" line="1" para="8">&quot;OK, so I did crawl in out of the woods,&quot; he said, &quot;but I brought some knowledge with me.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence doc="8" line="1" para="9">It is not about him, Van Orden said again and again in an interview on Wednesday, deflecting personal questions while talking animatedly about the legal issues and yet volunteering intriguing snippets of biography that included a stint as a pilot.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="8" line="1" para="10">&quot;It's not my lawsuit,&quot; he said.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="8" line="2" para="10">&quot;It's every American's.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence doc="8" line="1" para="11">Van Orden said he had turned down an offer by a lawyer who argued his case, Erwin Chemerinsky, to pay for a trip to Washington to witness the argument.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="8" line="1" para="12">&quot;I don't think I should accept anyone's money to go,&quot; he said.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="8" line="1" para="13">He also said that he had overcome an unspecified psychological problem, that he was eager for a steady job -- &quot;You don't actually think I like living in a tent, do you?&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence doc="8" line="2" para="13">-- and that he had gotten, and laughed off, offers from Hollywood for his story.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="8" line="1" para="14">&quot;How do you do a movie of a guy at his desk researching legal briefs?&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence doc="8" line="2" para="14">he asked.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="8" line="3" para="14">&quot;There's no car chases, no exploding bombs.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence doc="8" line="1" para="15">But he said that if anyone persisted, &quot;I would say, 'Bring cash and tell me what time to meet your plane.&quot;'</sentence>
		<sentence doc="8" line="1" para="16">Tall, with lanky, center-parted hair and a thick brush mustache -- Van Orden, who declined to be photographed as well -- said he had not gone looking for a cause.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="8" line="2" para="16">&quot;This one found me,&quot; he said.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="8" line="1" para="17">He said he had come across the Ten Commandments monument on the Capitol grounds several years ago and, based on his readings of separation of powers cases thought: &quot;Something ought to be done, and why not me?</sentence>
		<sentence doc="8" line="2" para="17">So I did it.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence doc="8" line="1" para="18">He said he was drawn to the case not by any antipathy toward religion -- he was brought up Southern Baptist, he said -- but raised questions with a state preservation office and was told the display would not come down.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="8" line="1" para="19">&quot;I never said, 'I demand you take it down,&quot;' Van Orden said.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="8" line="2" para="19">&quot;I'm not rude.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence doc="8" line="1" para="20">But he did begin researching a federal lawsuit that he filed in 2002.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="8" line="1" para="21">&quot;I was demonstrating what you could do with a pencil and paper and a law book,&quot; Van Orden said.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="8" line="1" para="22">A graduate of Southern Methodist University's law school in Dallas, Van Orden said he had practiced criminal law in Houston, principally defending drug dealers, until &quot;something happened to me&quot; that he said &quot;destroyed me.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence doc="8" line="1" para="23">Previously published articles said he fell prey to acute anxiety and did not complete some cases he had been engaged to handle, accounts he declined to discuss beyond saying, &quot;I never stole a dime from anybody.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence doc="8" line="1" para="24">Texas State Bar records list him as suspended for &quot;disciplinary sanctions&quot; and &quot;default in payment of Occupation Tax.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence doc="8" line="1" para="25">He said he had been divorced for 15 years and had a son and a daughter.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="8" line="1" para="26">Little by little, other details of Van Orden's life emerged.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="8" line="2" para="26">He said he had served in the Vietnam-era Army and had narrowly avoided duty as a helicopter gunner by signing up as a lawyer in the judge advocate general's corps.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="8" line="3" para="26">But he said his brother, a Navy pilot who served on the same aircraft carrier as Sen. John McCain, was shot down and killed.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="8" line="4" para="26">Van Orden said he himself later became a pilot flying light planes and training flight students and walked away from at least one serious crash.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="8" line="1" para="27">He was always drawn to constitutional law, he said, and was so enamored of Benjamin Nathan Cardozo, the former Supreme Court justice, that he named his son after him.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="8" line="1" para="28">In the Ten Commandments case, Van Orden said, the central questions were: What was the government's purpose in putting up the display in 1961, and what message did it send to people?</sentence>
		<sentence doc="8" line="2" para="28">If religious, it was unacceptable, he said.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="8" line="3" para="28">Moreover, he said, the version of the commandments at the Capitol omits part of the Hebrew text referring to God's covenant with the Jews, raising another religious issue, he said.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="8" line="1" para="29">Van Orden lost in the district court and, after managing to pay for enough copies and postage, appealed to the 5th U.S.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="8" line="2" para="29">Circuit Court of Appeals in New Orleans, where he also lost.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="8" line="3" para="29">Then, he said, seizing on conflicting opinions by different federal appeals courts, he asked the Supreme Court to resolve the issue.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="8" line="1" para="30">&quot;That's what the Supreme Court does for a living,&quot; he said.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="8" line="1" para="31">Chemerinsky, a law professor at Duke University, said that after the high court agreed to hear the case in late 2003, Van Orden called him -- one of the rare times Van Orden used a telephone -- and the two agreed to collaborate.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="8" line="2" para="31">Chemerinsky flew to Austin last November and with Van Orden walked the Capitol grounds, seeing the monument and discussing the case.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="8" line="1" para="32">&quot;He was extremely knowledgeable in the law in this case,&quot; Chemerinsky said.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="8" line="1" para="33">They did not discuss Van Orden's homelessness, he said, adding, &quot;It was none of my business.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence doc="8" line="1" para="34">They exchanged drafts by e-mail, Van Orden working at the University of Texas law library and the state law library, using his own e-mail accounts honoring his favorite Roman philosopher, Seneca.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="8" line="1" para="35">Van Orden derided the cliches of homelessness that he said reporters had unfairly stuck to him over the years.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="8" line="2" para="35">He did not travel with bundles, he said, and he took pride in his clean clothes and grooming, which he attended to in ways he did not detail.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="8" line="1" para="36">&quot;I'm surprised they don't have me trailing a yellow dog,&quot; he said, exaggerating.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="8" line="1" para="37">He ate on food stamps at the upscale Central Market, pitched his tent nightly and took it down each morning in a wooded location he did not specify, traveled on a free bus pass granted for a veteran's disability and read newspapers and magazines free at newsstands.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="8" line="1" para="38">He said his happiest moment was not when he heard the Supreme Court was taking his case but when his teenage daughter read the story and tracked him down by e-mail, breaking a long estrangement.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="9" line="1" para="1">The US Supreme Court on Wednesday  was to review the displaying in public spaces of the Ten  Commandments, the fundamental moral precepts of Judeo-Christian  religions, in a case that could define the extent of separation of  church and state in American society.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="9" line="1" para="2">Following challenges to the use of public property for  displaying the commandments in Texas and Kentucky, the court will  decide under what conditions, if at all, such explicitly religious  displays are permitted.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="9" line="1" para="3">The first amendment to the US Constitution establishes the  principle of separation of church and state, but the details of this  principle remain unclear in the face of numerous contradictory  decisions by courts over many decades.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="9" line="1" para="4">Jews and Christians believe the Ten Commandments are the basic  moral guidelines given to Moses directly by God on Mount Sinai.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="9" line="1" para="5">The court will review, in the Kentucky case, the legality of  displaying framed copies of the Ten Commandments in two courthouses  among copies of other documents that form the basis of US laws.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="9" line="1" para="6">The Texas case involves the legality of a stone monument  inscribed with the commandments installed on the grounds of the  state legislature.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="9" line="1" para="7">Last October, the Supreme Court declined to review a third case,  concerning the installation of a stone replica of the commandments  in front of the state Supreme Court of Alabama.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="9" line="1" para="8">The case has drawn extremely high interest from both religious  groups and secular society advocates across the United States.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="10" line="1" para="1">The US Supreme Court heard arguments  Wednesday on the constitutionality of displaying in public spaces  the Ten Commandments, in a case on the officially mandated  separation of church and state in US society.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="10" line="1" para="2">While about 100 people from opposing groups protested outside  the court, lawyers and court justices debated two challenges to the  use of public property for displaying the commandments, fundamental  moral precepts Jews and Christians believe God gave to Moses on  Mount Sinai.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="10" line="1" para="3">In the coming weeks, the court is expected to decide under what  conditions, if at all, such displays are permitted under the US  Constitution.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="10" line="1" para="4">The Constitution's first amendment establishes the principle of  separation of church and state, but how this should be interpreted  remains unclear in the face of numerous contradictory decisions by  courts over recent decades.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="10" line="1" para="5">Wednesday, the Supreme Court reviewed two cases, one a challenge  to the display of framed copies of the Ten Commandments in two  Kentucky courthouses, among other documents that form the basis of  US laws.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="10" line="1" para="6">The second addressed the legality of a stone monument inscribed  with the commandments, nationalist and and other religious symbols  installed on the grounds of the Texas state legislature.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="10" line="1" para="7">The hearings were marked by intense discussion of the meaning of  the Ten Commandments in US traditions, examining whether they are  essentially religious edicts or cultural norms.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="10" line="1" para="8">Defenders cited the example of the commandment &quot;Thou shalt not  kill&quot; as demonstrating that they do not contradict or surmount  secular laws.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="10" line="1" para="9">However, justice Ruth Bader Ginsburg challenged that view by  noting that other commandments are specifically religious, one  requiring observation of the sabbath.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="10" line="1" para="10">&quot;Have you read the first four commandments?&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence doc="10" line="2" para="10">she demanded of one  of her colleagues.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="10" line="1" para="11">Appearing to endorse the displays -- while noting most Americans  could not recite the commandments -- conservative justice Antonin  Scalia called them &quot;the symbol that government derives its authority  from God.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence doc="10" line="1" para="12">&quot;I see nothing wrong with the government reflecting that.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="10" line="2" para="12">We're  a tolerant society,&quot; Scalia said.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="10" line="1" para="13">Liberal justice Stephen Breyer countered that, although the US  is a highly religious country, &quot;we are also committed to  secularism.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence doc="10" line="1" para="14">The case has drawn extremely high interest from both religious  groups and secular society advocates across the United States.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="10" line="1" para="15">&quot;Government supports Christianity, but we want it to be  neutral,&quot; said Eric Heirman, who joined a group of atheists outside  the court protesting against religious displays.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="10" line="1" para="16">A young teenager, one of a group of people praying outside the  court in support of the displays, argued to the contrary.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="10" line="1" para="17">&quot;I think religion has to be shown everywhere.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="10" line="2" para="17">I think people  should start to believe,&quot; he said.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="10" line="1" para="18">While there were no clear indications of how the justices might  rule, arguments frequently returned to the issue of the context of  the display, with justices making reference to the  73-year-old  marble frieze in their own courtroom, which depicts Moses holding  the commandments among numerous other historical figures of law.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="10" line="1" para="19">The emphasis on context could possibly lead to the court  avoiding making a categorical decision and instead ruling in favor  of one of the displays and against the other.</sentence>
	</Sentences>
	<Words>
		<word count="158" text="``"/>
		<word count="154" text="''"/>
		<word count="117" text="command"/>
		<word count="100" text="said"/>
		<word count="97" text="ten"/>
		<word count="93" text="court"/>
		<word count="89" text="display"/>
		<word count="85" text="on"/>
		<word count="81" text="he"/>
		<word count="66" text="case"/>
		<word count="66" text="justic"/>
		<word count="64" text="the"/>
		<word count="60" text="'s"/>
		<word count="58" text="it"/>
		<word count="54" text="texa"/>
		<word count="54" text="state"/>
		<word count="53" text="not"/>
		<word count="52" text="with"/>
		<word count="51" text="be"/>
		<word count="48" text="monument"/>
		<word count="48" text="religi"/>
		<word count="45" text="for"/>
		<word count="44" text="wa"/>
		<word count="44" text="is"/>
		<word count="42" text="suprem"/>
		<word count="42" text="are"/>
		<word count="40" text="from"/>
		<word count="40" text="by"/>
		<word count="39" text="they"/>
		<word count="39" text="law"/>
		<word count="38" text="hi"/>
		<word count="38" text="as"/>
		<word count="34" text="religion"/>
		<word count="34" text="--"/>
		<word count="33" text="an"/>
		<word count="33" text="govern"/>
		<word count="33" text="but"/>
		<word count="32" text="kentucki"/>
		<word count="32" text="at"/>
		<word count="31" text="chemerinski"/>
		<word count="31" text="I"/>
		<word count="30" text="one"/>
		<word count="29" text="van"/>
		<word count="29" text="orden"/>
		<word count="28" text="other"/>
		<word count="28" text="god"/>
		<word count="28" text="who"/>
		<word count="28" text="would"/>
		<word count="26" text="capitol"/>
		<word count="26" text="argument"/>
		<word count="26" text="constitut"/>
		<word count="25" text="could"/>
		<word count="25" text="two"/>
		<word count="25" text="have"/>
		<word count="24" text="ground"/>
		<word count="24" text="thi"/>
		<word count="23" text="do"/>
		<word count="22" text="you"/>
		<word count="22" text="ask"/>
		<word count="21" text="He"/>
		<word count="20" text="scalia"/>
		<word count="20" text="abbott"/>
		<word count="19" text="what"/>
		<word count="19" text="symbol"/>
		<word count="19" text="n't"/>
		<word count="19" text="had"/>
		<word count="19" text="secular"/>
		<word count="18" text="lawyer"/>
		<word count="18" text="when"/>
		<word count="17" text="issu"/>
		<word count="17" text="becaus"/>
		<word count="17" text="also"/>
		<word count="17" text="down"/>
		<word count="16" text="whether"/>
		<word count="16" text="rule"/>
		<word count="16" text="challeng"/>
		<word count="16" text="ha"/>
		<word count="16" text="courthous"/>
		<word count="16" text="first"/>
		<word count="16" text="no"/>
		<word count="16" text="messag"/>
		<word count="15" text="histor"/>
		<word count="15" text="legal"/>
		<word count="14" text="wednesday"/>
		<word count="14" text="question"/>
		<word count="14" text="or"/>
		<word count="14" text="argu"/>
		<word count="14" text="o'connor"/>
		<word count="14" text="should"/>
		<word count="14" text="did"/>
		<word count="13" text="endors"/>
		<word count="13" text="can"/>
		<word count="13" text="decid"/>
		<word count="13" text="In"/>
		<word count="13" text="so"/>
		<word count="13" text="public"/>
		<word count="12" text="church"/>
		<word count="12" text="how"/>
		<word count="12" text="separ"/>
		<word count="12" text="tablet"/>
		<word count="12" text="say"/>
		<word count="12" text="there"/>
		<word count="12" text="support"/>
		<word count="12" text="if"/>
		<word count="12" text="counti"/>
		<word count="12" text="gener"/>
		<word count="12" text="ad"/>
		<word count="11" text="christian"/>
		<word count="11" text="which"/>
		<word count="11" text="prayer"/>
		<word count="11" text="american"/>
		<word count="11" text="document"/>
		<word count="11" text="were"/>
		<word count="11" text="think"/>
		<word count="11" text="mose"/>
		<word count="11" text="about"/>
		<word count="11" text="peopl"/>
		<word count="11" text="year"/>
		<word count="11" text="such"/>
		<word count="11" text="while"/>
		<word count="10" text="high"/>
		<word count="10" text="told"/>
		<word count="10" text="order"/>
		<word count="10" text="build"/>
		<word count="10" text="legislatur"/>
		<word count="10" text="onli"/>
		<word count="10" text="remov"/>
		<word count="10" text="their"/>
		<word count="10" text="copi"/>
		<word count="10" text="post"/>
		<word count="10" text="includ"/>
		<word count="10" text="establish"/>
		<word count="10" text="It"/>
		<word count="10" text="she"/>
		<word count="10" text="believ"/>
		<word count="10" text="kennedi"/>
		<word count="10" text="attorney"/>
		<word count="10" text="appeal"/>
		<word count="9" text="come"/>
		<word count="9" text="austin"/>
		<word count="9" text="text"/>
		<word count="9" text="note"/>
		<word count="9" text="depict"/>
		<word count="9" text="that"/>
		<word count="9" text="me"/>
		<word count="9" text="ani"/>
		<word count="9" text="all"/>
		<word count="9" text="might"/>
		<word count="9" text="US"/>
		<word count="8" text="wall"/>
		<word count="8" text="between"/>
		<word count="8" text="under"/>
		<word count="8" text="day"/>
		<word count="8" text="line"/>
		<word count="8" text="context"/>
		<word count="8" text="too"/>
		<word count="8" text="chief"/>
		<word count="8" text="suggest"/>
		<word count="8" text="both"/>
		<word count="8" text="repli"/>
		<word count="8" text="those"/>
		<word count="8" text="him"/>
		<word count="8" text="agre"/>
		<word count="8" text="use"/>
		<word count="8" text="univers"/>
		<word count="8" text="group"/>
		<word count="7" text="outsid"/>
		<word count="7" text="unconstitut"/>
		<word count="7" text="decad"/>
		<word count="7" text="decis"/>
		<word count="7" text="homeless"/>
		<word count="7" text="author"/>
		<word count="7" text="deriv"/>
		<word count="7" text="erwin"/>
		<word count="7" text="will"/>
		<word count="7" text="recogn"/>
		<word count="7" text="session"/>
		<word count="7" text="antonin"/>
		<word count="7" text="exhibit"/>
		<word count="7" text="offici"/>
		<word count="7" text="purpos"/>
		<word count="7" text="littl"/>
		<word count="7" text="more"/>
		<word count="7" text="than"/>
		<word count="7" text="paul"/>
		<word count="7" text="clement"/>
		<word count="7" text="defend"/>
		<word count="7" text="judg"/>
		<word count="7" text="divis"/>
		<word count="7" text="even"/>
		<word count="7" text="honor"/>
		<word count="7" text="violat"/>
		<word count="7" text="heard"/>
		<word count="7" text="acknowledg"/>
		<word count="7" text="show"/>
		<word count="7" text="eye"/>
		<word count="7" text="steven"/>
		<word count="7" text="histori"/>
		<word count="7" text="alabama"/>
		<word count="7" text="differ"/>
		<word count="7" text="among"/>
		<word count="7" text="part"/>
		<word count="7" text="new"/>
		<word count="7" text="after"/>
		<word count="7" text="doe"/>
		<word count="6" text="A"/>
		<word count="6" text="properti"/>
		<word count="6" text="protest"/>
		<word count="6" text="vote"/>
		<word count="6" text="draw"/>
		<word count="6" text="If"/>
		<word count="6" text="open"/>
		<word count="6" text="been"/>
		<word count="6" text="against"/>
		<word count="6" text="frame"/>
		<word count="6" text="clear"/>
		<word count="6" text="tri"/>
		<word count="6" text="appear"/>
		<word count="6" text="test"/>
		<word count="6" text="breyer"/>
		<word count="6" text="way"/>
		<word count="6" text="basi"/>
		<word count="6" text="friez"/>
		<word count="6" text="john"/>
		<word count="6" text="e-mail"/>
		<word count="6" text="far"/>
		<word count="6" text="amend"/>
		<word count="6" text="professor"/>
		<word count="6" text="percent"/>
		<word count="6" text="read"/>
		<word count="6" text="befor"/>
		<word count="6" text="stone"/>
		<word count="6" text="moor"/>
		<word count="6" text="accept"/>
		<word count="6" text="point"/>
		<word count="6" text="ago"/>
		<word count="6" text="later"/>
		<word count="6" text="well"/>
		<word count="6" text="feder"/>
		<word count="6" text="refer"/>
		<word count="6" text="sever"/>
		<word count="6" text="atheist"/>
		<word count="6" text="school"/>
		<word count="5" text="end"/>
		<word count="5" text="man"/>
		<word count="5" text="david"/>
		<word count="5" text="walk"/>
		<word count="5" text="begin"/>
		<word count="5" text="sandra"/>
		<word count="5" text="involv"/>
		<word count="5" text="signific"/>
		<word count="5" text="souter"/>
		<word count="5" text="erect"/>
		<word count="5" text="follow"/>
		<word count="5" text="repres"/>
		<word count="5" text="bush"/>
		<word count="5" text="administr"/>
		<word count="5" text="stephen"/>
		<word count="5" text="nation"/>
		<word count="5" text="look"/>
		<word count="5" text="hold"/>
		<word count="5" text="former"/>
		<word count="5" text="unit"/>
		<word count="5" text="sit"/>
		<word count="5" text="second"/>
		<word count="5" text="convey"/>
		<word count="5" text="duke"/>
		<word count="5" text="thoma"/>
		<word count="5" text="these"/>
		<word count="5" text="them"/>
		<word count="5" text="tell"/>
		<word count="5" text="anthoni"/>
		<word count="5" text="concern"/>
		<word count="5" text="four"/>
		<word count="5" text="just"/>
		<word count="5" text="thou"/>
		<word count="5" text="shalt"/>
		<word count="5" text="take"/>
		<word count="5" text="took"/>
		<word count="5" text="courtroom"/>
		<word count="5" text="greg"/>
		<word count="5" text="set"/>
		<word count="5" text="cultur"/>
		<word count="5" text="over"/>
		<word count="5" text="liberti"/>
		<word count="5" text="serv"/>
		<word count="5" text="contain"/>
		<word count="5" text="disput"/>
		<word count="5" text="lawsuit"/>
		<word count="5" text="own"/>
		<word count="5" text="know"/>
		<word count="5" text="turn"/>
		<word count="5" text="your"/>
		<word count="5" text="countri"/>
		<word count="5" text="last"/>
		<word count="5" text="drawn"/>
		<word count="5" text="'re"/>
		<word count="5" text="send"/>
		<word count="5" text="make"/>
		<word count="5" text="across"/>
		<word count="5" text="up"/>
		<word count="5" text="librari"/>
		<word count="5" text="discuss"/>
		<word count="5" text="societi"/>
		<word count="4" text="granit"/>
		<word count="4" text="probabl"/>
		<word count="4" text="rais"/>
		<word count="4" text="lower"/>
		<word count="4" text="file"/>
		<word count="4" text="constitution"/>
		<word count="4" text="here"/>
		<word count="4" text="see"/>
		<word count="4" text="itself"/>
		<word count="4" text="version"/>
		<word count="4" text="surround"/>
		<word count="4" text="role"/>
		<word count="4" text="our"/>
		<word count="4" text="seem"/>
		<word count="4" text="natur"/>
		<word count="4" text="intent"/>
		<word count="4" text="chang"/>
		<word count="4" text="staver"/>
		<word count="4" text="act"/>
		<word count="4" text="solicitor"/>
		<word count="4" text="right"/>
		<word count="4" text="dure"/>
		<word count="4" text="case-by-cas"/>
		<word count="4" text="lawgiv"/>
		<word count="4" text="marshal"/>
		<word count="4" text="save"/>
		<word count="4" text="address"/>
		<word count="4" text="went"/>
		<word count="4" text="moral"/>
		<word count="4" text="frequent"/>
		<word count="4" text="like"/>
		<word count="4" text="may"/>
		<word count="4" text="upheld"/>
		<word count="4" text="practic"/>
		<word count="4" text="then"/>
		<word count="4" text="power"/>
		<word count="4" text="behalf"/>
		<word count="4" text="problem"/>
		<word count="4" text="obsess"/>
		<word count="4" text="avert"/>
		<word count="4" text="hostil"/>
		<word count="4" text="ruth"/>
		<word count="4" text="bader"/>
		<word count="4" text="ginsburg"/>
		<word count="4" text="describ"/>
		<word count="4" text="rehnquist"/>
		<word count="4" text="where"/>
		<word count="4" text="demonstr"/>
		<word count="4" text="five"/>
		<word count="4" text="washington"/>
		<word count="4" text="allow"/>
		<word count="4" text="civil"/>
		<word count="4" text="union"/>
		<word count="4" text="resolv"/>
		<word count="4" text="detail"/>
		<word count="4" text="lost"/>
		<word count="4" text="specif"/>
		<word count="4" text="kill"/>
		<word count="4" text="principl"/>
		<word count="4" text="provid"/>
		<word count="4" text="call"/>
		<word count="4" text="out"/>
		<word count="4" text="some"/>
		<word count="4" text="permiss"/>
		<word count="4" text="No"/>
		<word count="4" text="sign"/>
		<word count="4" text="mount"/>
		<word count="4" text="tent"/>
		<word count="4" text="stori"/>
		<word count="4" text="claus"/>
		<word count="4" text="interpret"/>
		<word count="4" text="remain"/>
		<word count="4" text="brought"/>
		<word count="4" text="hear"/>
		<word count="4" text="we"/>
		<word count="4" text="declin"/>
		<word count="4" text="review"/>
		<word count="3" text="amount"/>
		<word count="3" text="favor"/>
		<word count="3" text="similar"/>
		<word count="3" text="shape"/>
		<word count="3" text="church-stat"/>
		<word count="3" text="june"/>
		<word count="3" text="inscrib"/>
		<word count="3" text="donat"/>
		<word count="3" text="fratern"/>
		<word count="3" text="eagl"/>
		<word count="3" text="claim"/>
		<word count="3" text="10"/>
		<word count="3" text="want"/>
		<word count="3" text="into"/>
		<word count="3" text="found"/>
		<word count="3" text="whi"/>
		<word count="3" text="swing"/>
		<word count="3" text="close"/>
		<word count="3" text="legisl"/>
		<word count="3" text="hall"/>
		<word count="3" text="hard"/>
		<word count="3" text="same"/>
		<word count="3" text="polit"/>
		<word count="3" text="patriot"/>
		<word count="3" text="reason"/>
		<word count="3" text="origin"/>
		<word count="3" text="mathew"/>
		<word count="3" text="get"/>
		<word count="3" text="struggl"/>
		<word count="3" text="larg"/>
		<word count="3" text="without"/>
		<word count="3" text="roman"/>
		<word count="3" text="near"/>
		<word count="3" text="split"/>
		<word count="3" text="90"/>
		<word count="3" text="85"/>
		<word count="3" text="M."/>
		<word count="3" text="demand"/>
		<word count="3" text="H."/>
		<word count="3" text="G."/>
		<word count="3" text="signal"/>
		<word count="3" text="strike"/>
		<word count="3" text="lord"/>
		<word count="3" text="imag"/>
		<word count="3" text="name"/>
		<word count="3" text="keep"/>
		<word count="3" text="stand"/>
		<word count="3" text="exampl"/>
		<word count="3" text="carv"/>
		<word count="3" text="marbl"/>
		<word count="3" text="side"/>
		<word count="3" text="present"/>
		<word count="3" text="roy"/>
		<word count="3" text="cross"/>
		<word count="3" text="crucifix"/>
		<word count="3" text="week"/>
		<word count="3" text="prohibit"/>
		<word count="3" text="alway"/>
		<word count="3" text="around"/>
		<word count="3" text="doctrin"/>
		<word count="3" text="tradit"/>
		<word count="3" text="find"/>
		<word count="3" text="job"/>
		<word count="3" text="2003"/>
		<word count="3" text="enorm"/>
		<word count="3" text="hundr"/>
		<word count="3" text="receiv"/>
		<word count="3" text="17"/>
		<word count="3" text="recent"/>
		<word count="3" text="made"/>
		<word count="3" text="mani"/>
		<word count="3" text="led"/>
		<word count="3" text="kid"/>
		<word count="3" text="away"/>
		<word count="3" text="mention"/>
		<word count="3" text="interest"/>
		<word count="3" text="preserv"/>
		<word count="3" text="old"/>
		<word count="3" text="contradictori"/>
		<word count="3" text="futur"/>
		<word count="3" text="fact"/>
		<word count="3" text="park"/>
		<word count="3" text="nonreligi"/>
		<word count="3" text="outdoor"/>
		<word count="3" text="nine"/>
		<word count="3" text="answer"/>
		<word count="3" text="anoth"/>
		<word count="3" text="view"/>
		<word count="3" text="put"/>
		<word count="3" text="1961"/>
		<word count="3" text="reflect"/>
		<word count="3" text="everi"/>
		<word count="3" text="v."/>
		<word count="3" text="struck"/>
		<word count="3" text="ca"/>
		<word count="3" text="ignor"/>
		<word count="3" text="consid"/>
		<word count="3" text="toward"/>
		<word count="3" text="seat"/>
		<word count="3" text="congress"/>
		<word count="3" text="servic"/>
		<word count="3" text="dozen"/>
		<word count="3" text="travel"/>
		<word count="3" text="chamber"/>
		<word count="3" text="counter"/>
		<word count="3" text="sinai"/>
		<word count="3" text="write"/>
		<word count="3" text="southern"/>
		<word count="3" text="free"/>
		<word count="3" text="paper"/>
		<word count="3" text="live"/>
		<word count="3" text="wood"/>
		<word count="3" text="brief"/>
		<word count="3" text="time"/>
		<word count="3" text="pilot"/>
		<word count="3" text="advoc"/>
		<word count="3" text="jew"/>
		<word count="3" text="extrem"/>
		<word count="3" text="numer"/>
		<word count="3" text="instal"/>
		<word count="2" text="relat"/>
		<word count="2" text="clarifi"/>
		<word count="2" text="confus"/>
		<word count="2" text="suit"/>
		<word count="2" text="locat"/>
		<word count="2" text="feet"/>
		<word count="2" text="oppon"/>
		<word count="2" text="particular"/>
		<word count="2" text="good"/>
		<word count="2" text="bad"/>
		<word count="2" text="often"/>
		<word count="2" text="appropri"/>
		<word count="2" text="complain"/>
		<word count="2" text="wonder"/>
		<word count="2" text="modifi"/>
		<word count="2" text="respons"/>
		<word count="2" text="consist"/>
		<word count="2" text="foundat"/>
		<word count="2" text="system"/>
		<word count="2" text="subsequ"/>
		<word count="2" text="sham"/>
		<word count="2" text="step"/>
		<word count="2" text="land"/>
		<word count="2" text="reward"/>
		<word count="2" text="punish"/>
		<word count="2" text="We"/>
		<word count="2" text="qualiti"/>
		<word count="2" text="throughout"/>
		<word count="2" text="abov"/>
		<word count="2" text="philosoph"/>
		<word count="2" text="proclaim"/>
		<word count="2" text="A."/>
		<word count="2" text="promin"/>
		<word count="2" text="biblic"/>
		<word count="2" text="entranc"/>
		<word count="2" text="heritag"/>
		<word count="2" text="sourc"/>
		<word count="2" text="ban"/>
		<word count="2" text="cite"/>
		<word count="2" text="past"/>
		<word count="2" text="place"/>
		<word count="2" text="front"/>
		<word count="2" text="su"/>
		<word count="2" text="sacr"/>
		<word count="2" text="word"/>
		<word count="2" text="effect"/>
		<word count="2" text="wrong"/>
		<word count="2" text="saw"/>
		<word count="2" text="understand"/>
		<word count="2" text="hour"/>
		<word count="2" text="distinct"/>
		<word count="2" text="vain"/>
		<word count="2" text="sabbath"/>
		<word count="2" text="william"/>
		<word count="2" text="invoc"/>
		<word count="2" text="none"/>
		<word count="2" text="opposit"/>
		<word count="2" text="go"/>
		<word count="2" text="By"/>
		<word count="2" text="contrast"/>
		<word count="2" text="option"/>
		<word count="2" text="add"/>
		<word count="2" text="uphold"/>
		<word count="2" text="statut"/>
		<word count="2" text="howev"/>
		<word count="2" text="her"/>
		<word count="2" text="liber"/>
		<word count="2" text="colleagu"/>
		<word count="2" text="ail"/>
		<word count="2" text="behind"/>
		<word count="2" text="opinion"/>
		<word count="2" text="late"/>
		<word count="2" text="wrestl"/>
		<word count="2" text="life"/>
		<word count="2" text="although"/>
		<word count="2" text="function"/>
		<word count="2" text="stay"/>
		<word count="2" text="chanc"/>
		<word count="2" text="definit"/>
		<word count="2" text="creat"/>
		<word count="2" text="instead"/>
		<word count="2" text="respond"/>
		<word count="2" text="defi"/>
		<word count="2" text="pray"/>
		<word count="2" text="hate"/>
		<word count="2" text="theme"/>
		<word count="2" text="along"/>
		<word count="2" text="third"/>
		<word count="2" text="magna"/>
		<word count="2" text="carta"/>
		<word count="2" text="person"/>
		<word count="2" text="imageri"/>
		<word count="2" text="confront"/>
		<word count="2" text="ginsberg"/>
		<word count="2" text="visibl"/>
		<word count="2" text="interrupt"/>
		<word count="2" text="everyon"/>
		<word count="2" text="denounc"/>
		<word count="2" text="water"/>
		<word count="2" text="pyrrhic"/>
		<word count="2" text="victori"/>
		<word count="2" text="talk"/>
		<word count="2" text="impermiss"/>
		<word count="2" text="object"/>
		<word count="2" text="justif"/>
		<word count="2" text="1980"/>
		<word count="2" text="mandat"/>
		<word count="2" text="On"/>
		<word count="2" text="hand"/>
		<word count="2" text="equival"/>
		<word count="2" text="museum"/>
		<word count="2" text="fine"/>
		<word count="2" text="pass"/>
		<word count="2" text="muster"/>
		<word count="2" text="matter"/>
		<word count="2" text="until"/>
		<word count="2" text="themselv"/>
		<word count="2" text="express"/>
		<word count="2" text="posit"/>
		<word count="2" text="variou"/>
		<word count="2" text="independ"/>
		<word count="2" text="minim"/>
		<word count="2" text="requir"/>
		<word count="2" text="crowd"/>
		<word count="2" text="drew"/>
		<word count="2" text="rotunda"/>
		<word count="2" text="each"/>
		<word count="2" text="import"/>
		<word count="2" text="still"/>
		<word count="2" text="materi"/>
		<word count="2" text="rather"/>
		<word count="2" text="influenc"/>
		<word count="2" text="win"/>
		<word count="2" text="mccreari"/>
		<word count="2" text="undeni"/>
		<word count="2" text="code"/>
		<word count="2" text="D."/>
		<word count="2" text="degre"/>
		<word count="2" text="gone"/>
		<word count="2" text="counsel"/>
		<word count="2" text="alon"/>
		<word count="2" text="observ"/>
		<word count="2" text="u.s."/>
		<word count="2" text="bear"/>
		<word count="2" text="becam"/>
		<word count="2" text="expect"/>
		<word count="2" text="field"/>
		<word count="2" text="happen"/>
		<word count="2" text="museum-lik"/>
		<word count="2" text="echo"/>
		<word count="2" text="classic"/>
		<word count="2" text="judeo-christian"/>
		<word count="2" text="respect"/>
		<word count="2" text="organ"/>
		<word count="2" text="work"/>
		<word count="2" text="juvenil"/>
		<word count="2" text="stood"/>
		<word count="2" text="debat"/>
		<word count="2" text="civic"/>
		<word count="2" text="declar"/>
		<word count="2" text="conflict"/>
		<word count="2" text="offic"/>
		<word count="2" text="morn"/>
		<word count="2" text="highest"/>
		<word count="2" text="temperatur"/>
		<word count="2" text="freez"/>
		<word count="2" text="clipper"/>
		<word count="2" text="himself"/>
		<word count="2" text="insid"/>
		<word count="2" text="join"/>
		<word count="2" text="laugh"/>
		<word count="2" text="15"/>
		<word count="2" text="u."/>
		<word count="2" text="site"/>
		<word count="2" text="particip"/>
		<word count="2" text="least"/>
		<word count="2" text="student"/>
		<word count="2" text="bundl"/>
		<word count="2" text="methodist"/>
		<word count="2" text="graduat"/>
		<word count="2" text="2002"/>
		<word count="2" text="exchang"/>
		<word count="2" text="handl"/>
		<word count="2" text="help"/>
		<word count="2" text="intens"/>
		<word count="2" text="mail"/>
		<word count="2" text="At"/>
		<word count="2" text="possibl"/>
		<word count="2" text="disclaim"/>
		<word count="2" text="off"/>
		<word count="2" text="report"/>
		<word count="2" text="OK"/>
		<word count="2" text="moment"/>
		<word count="2" text="My"/>
		<word count="2" text="lack"/>
		<word count="2" text="postag"/>
		<word count="2" text="suspend"/>
		<word count="2" text="food"/>
		<word count="2" text="stamp"/>
		<word count="2" text="money"/>
		<word count="2" text="orlean"/>
		<word count="2" text="knowledg"/>
		<word count="2" text="again"/>
		<word count="2" text="my"/>
		<word count="2" text="offer"/>
		<word count="2" text="pay"/>
		<word count="2" text="anyon"/>
		<word count="2" text="research"/>
		<word count="2" text="plane"/>
		<word count="2" text="someth"/>
		<word count="2" text="never"/>
		<word count="2" text="'m"/>
		<word count="2" text="account"/>
		<word count="2" text="son"/>
		<word count="2" text="daughter"/>
		<word count="2" text="avoid"/>
		<word count="2" text="central"/>
		<word count="2" text="teenag"/>
		<word count="2" text="space"/>
		<word count="2" text="fundament"/>
		<word count="2" text="precept"/>
		<word count="2" text="condit"/>
		<word count="2" text="permit"/>
		<word count="2" text="unclear"/>
		<word count="2" text="face"/>
		<word count="2" text="form"/>
		<word count="1" text="pose"/>
		<word count="1" text="significantli"/>
		<word count="1" text="muddl"/>
		<word count="1" text="jurisprud"/>
		<word count="1" text="6-foot"/>
		<word count="1" text="3-foot"/>
		<word count="1" text="star"/>
		<word count="1" text="43-year-old"/>
		<word count="1" text="38"/>
		<word count="1" text="roughli"/>
		<word count="1" text="75"/>
		<word count="1" text="123"/>
		<word count="1" text="faith"/>
		<word count="1" text="dictat"/>
		<word count="1" text="behavior"/>
		<word count="1" text="imagin"/>
		<word count="1" text="buddhist"/>
		<word count="1" text="muslim"/>
		<word count="1" text="realiz"/>
		<word count="1" text="and"/>
		<word count="1" text="1983"/>
		<word count="1" text="divid"/>
		<word count="1" text="twice"/>
		<word count="1" text="current"/>
		<word count="1" text="british"/>
		<word count="1" text="descript"/>
		<word count="1" text="final"/>
		<word count="1" text="assert"/>
		<word count="1" text="play"/>
		<word count="1" text="clearli"/>
		<word count="1" text="modif"/>
		<word count="1" text="design"/>
		<word count="1" text="insul"/>
		<word count="1" text="scrutini"/>
		<word count="1" text="give"/>
		<word count="1" text="much"/>
		<word count="1" text="weight"/>
		<word count="1" text="best"/>
		<word count="1" text="previou"/>
		<word count="1" text="got"/>
		<word count="1" text="abl"/>
		<word count="1" text="adjust"/>
		<word count="1" text="misstep"/>
		<word count="1" text="whenev"/>
		<word count="1" text="mine"/>
		<word count="1" text="blurri"/>
		<word count="1" text="municip"/>
		<word count="1" text="singl"/>
		<word count="1" text="construct"/>
		<word count="1" text="government-sponsor"/>
		<word count="1" text="action"/>
		<word count="1" text="run"/>
		<word count="1" text="afoul"/>
		<word count="1" text="doubt"/>
		<word count="1" text="fashion"/>
		<word count="1" text="one-size-fits-al"/>
		<word count="1" text="solut"/>
		<word count="1" text="weigh"/>
		<word count="1" text="dai"/>
		<word count="1" text="chines"/>
		<word count="1" text="confuciu"/>
		<word count="1" text="emperor"/>
		<word count="1" text="caesar"/>
		<word count="1" text="augustu"/>
		<word count="1" text="panel"/>
		<word count="1" text="clerk"/>
		<word count="1" text="jennif"/>
		<word count="1" text="dlouhi"/>
		<word count="1" text="reach"/>
		<word count="1" text="202-263-6400"/>
		<word count="1" text="jdlouhyhearstdc.com"/>
		<word count="1" text="charg"/>
		<word count="1" text="mere"/>
		<word count="1" text="head"/>
		<word count="1" text="centrist"/>
		<word count="1" text="lawmak"/>
		<word count="1" text="deliv"/>
		<word count="1" text="chaplain"/>
		<word count="1" text="solemn"/>
		<word count="1" text="To"/>
		<word count="1" text="anyth"/>
		<word count="1" text="wish"/>
		<word count="1" text="sound"/>
		<word count="1" text="stop"/>
		<word count="1" text="Am"/>
		<word count="1" text="graven"/>
		<word count="1" text="remind"/>
		<word count="1" text="holi"/>
		<word count="1" text="clarenc"/>
		<word count="1" text="all-or-noth"/>
		<word count="1" text="met"/>
		<word count="1" text="hammurabi"/>
		<word count="1" text="solomon"/>
		<word count="1" text="napoleon"/>
		<word count="1" text="fourth"/>
		<word count="1" text="whose"/>
		<word count="1" text="center"/>
		<word count="1" text="reject"/>
		<word count="1" text="serious"/>
		<word count="1" text="park-lik"/>
		<word count="1" text="determin"/>
		<word count="1" text="visitor"/>
		<word count="1" text="oblig"/>
		<word count="1" text="sharpli"/>
		<word count="1" text="america"/>
		<word count="1" text="door"/>
		<word count="1" text="written"/>
		<word count="1" text="bring"/>
		<word count="1" text="climax"/>
		<word count="1" text="latest"/>
		<word count="1" text="battl"/>
		<word count="1" text="war"/>
		<word count="1" text="exact"/>
		<word count="1" text="plaintiff"/>
		<word count="1" text="presuppos"/>
		<word count="1" text="exist"/>
		<word count="1" text="perenni"/>
		<word count="1" text="contenti"/>
		<word count="1" text="appetit"/>
		<word count="1" text="henceforth"/>
		<word count="1" text="either"/>
		<word count="1" text="forbidden"/>
		<word count="1" text="revolv"/>
		<word count="1" text="fit"/>
		<word count="1" text="kept"/>
		<word count="1" text="today"/>
		<word count="1" text="evangel"/>
		<word count="1" text="formal"/>
		<word count="1" text="effort"/>
		<word count="1" text="excerpt"/>
		<word count="1" text="speech"/>
		<word count="1" text="drop"/>
		<word count="1" text="sponsor"/>
		<word count="1" text="overton"/>
		<word count="1" text="replet"/>
		<word count="1" text="twin"/>
		<word count="1" text="number"/>
		<word count="1" text="1"/>
		<word count="1" text="desir"/>
		<word count="1" text="iconographi"/>
		<word count="1" text="obvious"/>
		<word count="1" text="insist"/>
		<word count="1" text="nevertheless"/>
		<word count="1" text="regular"/>
		<word count="1" text="south"/>
		<word count="1" text="eight"/>
		<word count="1" text="ancient"/>
		<word count="1" text="tilt"/>
		<word count="1" text="hidden"/>
		<word count="1" text="inscript"/>
		<word count="1" text="sinc"/>
		<word count="1" text="scoff"/>
		<word count="1" text="devout"/>
		<word count="1" text="cathol"/>
		<word count="1" text="idea"/>
		<word count="1" text="won"/>
		<word count="1" text="big"/>
		<word count="1" text="deal"/>
		<word count="1" text="voter"/>
		<word count="1" text="uneasi"/>
		<word count="1" text="prospect"/>
		<word count="1" text="thousand"/>
		<word count="1" text="older"/>
		<word count="1" text="museumlik"/>
		<word count="1" text="altern"/>
		<word count="1" text="tear"/>
		<word count="1" text="impuls"/>
		<word count="1" text="search"/>
		<word count="1" text="broad"/>
		<word count="1" text="risk"/>
		<word count="1" text="invit"/>
		<word count="1" text="endless"/>
		<word count="1" text="parad"/>
		<word count="1" text="22-acr"/>
		<word count="1" text="16"/>
		<word count="1" text="sculptur"/>
		<word count="1" text="garden"/>
		<word count="1" text="mayb"/>
		<word count="1" text="mix"/>
		<word count="1" text="stand-alon"/>
		<word count="1" text="prove"/>
		<word count="1" text="troublesom"/>
		<word count="1" text="now"/>
		<word count="1" text="seek"/>
		<word count="1" text="hung"/>
		<word count="1" text="unadorn"/>
		<word count="1" text="taint"/>
		<word count="1" text="entir"/>
		<word count="1" text="wait"/>
		<word count="1" text="25"/>
		<word count="1" text="silenc"/>
		<word count="1" text="unsurprisingli"/>
		<word count="1" text="long-held"/>
		<word count="1" text="cast"/>
		<word count="1" text="uncertain"/>
		<word count="1" text="approach"/>
		<word count="1" text="narrow"/>
		<word count="1" text="aloud"/>
		<word count="1" text="preced"/>
		<word count="1" text="rel"/>
		<word count="1" text="guidanc"/>
		<word count="1" text="contextu"/>
		<word count="1" text="offend"/>
		<word count="1" text="individu"/>
		<word count="1" text="invalid"/>
		<word count="1" text="classroom"/>
		<word count="1" text="graham"/>
		<word count="1" text="everyth"/>
		<word count="1" text="becom"/>
		<word count="1" text="latin"/>
		<word count="1" text="top"/>
		<word count="1" text="exclaim"/>
		<word count="1" text="reluctantli"/>
		<word count="1" text="conclus"/>
		<word count="1" text="evalu"/>
		<word count="1" text="urg"/>
		<word count="1" text="social"/>
		<word count="1" text="realiti"/>
		<word count="1" text="maximum"/>
		<word count="1" text="content"/>
		<word count="1" text="deepli"/>
		<word count="1" text="injunct"/>
		<word count="1" text="steal"/>
		<word count="1" text="unlik"/>
		<word count="1" text="necessarili"/>
		<word count="1" text="impli"/>
		<word count="1" text="belief"/>
		<word count="1" text="harder"/>
		<word count="1" text="piec"/>
		<word count="1" text="simpli"/>
		<word count="1" text="broke"/>
		<word count="1" text="distress"/>
		<word count="1" text="'our"/>
		<word count="1" text="yourself"/>
		<word count="1" text="perri"/>
		<word count="1" text="03-1500"/>
		<word count="1" text="03-1693"/>
		<word count="1" text="forc"/>
		<word count="1" text="sanctuari"/>
		<word count="1" text="florida-bas"/>
		<word count="1" text="associ"/>
		<word count="1" text="rev"/>
		<word count="1" text="jerri"/>
		<word count="1" text="falwel"/>
		<word count="1" text="overal"/>
		<word count="1" text="mayflow"/>
		<word count="1" text="compact"/>
		<word count="1" text="probe"/>
		<word count="1" text="dwell"/>
		<word count="1" text="1999"/>
		<word count="1" text="pulaski"/>
		<word count="1" text="switch"/>
		<word count="1" text="fight"/>
		<word count="1" text="thing"/>
		<word count="1" text="blind"/>
		<word count="1" text="friedman"/>
		<word count="1" text="real"/>
		<word count="1" text="yell"/>
		<word count="1" text="room"/>
		<word count="1" text="sculpt"/>
		<word count="1" text="backdrop"/>
		<word count="1" text="intertwin"/>
		<word count="1" text="oral"/>
		<word count="1" text="closely-watch"/>
		<word count="1" text="due"/>
		<word count="1" text="circumst"/>
		<word count="1" text="2001"/>
		<word count="1" text="rear"/>
		<word count="1" text="trial"/>
		<word count="1" text="packag"/>
		<word count="1" text="dismiss"/>
		<word count="1" text="uniqu"/>
		<word count="1" text="venu"/>
		<word count="1" text="count"/>
		<word count="1" text="worri"/>
		<word count="1" text="shall"/>
		<word count="1" text="sat"/>
		<word count="1" text="integr"/>
		<word count="1" text="40"/>
		<word count="1" text="unchalleng"/>
		<word count="1" text="amid"/>
		<word count="1" text="attack"/>
		<word count="1" text="develop"/>
		<word count="1" text="An"/>
		<word count="1" text="refus"/>
		<word count="1" text="compli"/>
		<word count="1" text="judici"/>
		<word count="1" text="assembl"/>
		<word count="1" text="hover"/>
		<word count="1" text="stiff"/>
		<word count="1" text="wind"/>
		<word count="1" text="feel"/>
		<word count="1" text="cooler"/>
		<word count="1" text="rod"/>
		<word count="1" text="mcdougal"/>
		<word count="1" text="san"/>
		<word count="1" text="diego"/>
		<word count="1" text="chri"/>
		<word count="1" text="austinit"/>
		<word count="1" text="move"/>
		<word count="1" text="suburb"/>
		<word count="1" text="pace"/>
		<word count="1" text="sidewalk"/>
		<word count="1" text="few"/>
		<word count="1" text="white-column"/>
		<word count="1" text="carri"/>
		<word count="1" text="forum"/>
		<word count="1" text="41"/>
		<word count="1" text="referenc"/>
		<word count="1" text="pack"/>
		<word count="1" text="inclus"/>
		<word count="1" text="profound"/>
		<word count="1" text="As"/>
		<word count="1" text="left"/>
		<word count="1" text="great"/>
		<word count="1" text="similarli"/>
		<word count="1" text="size"/>
		<word count="1" text="us"/>
		<word count="1" text="wide"/>
		<word count="1" text="purport"/>
		<word count="1" text="enjoy"/>
		<word count="1" text="seal"/>
		<word count="1" text="spoke"/>
		<word count="1" text="kreytak"/>
		<word count="1" text="american-statesman"/>
		<word count="1" text="skreytak"/>
		<word count="1" text="statesman.com"/>
		<word count="1" text="40-year-old"/>
		<word count="1" text="pink"/>
		<word count="1" text="slab"/>
		<word count="1" text="pepper"/>
		<word count="1" text="affect"/>
		<word count="1" text="quarter-centuri"/>
		<word count="1" text="attract"/>
		<word count="1" text="third-parti"/>
		<word count="1" text="half-dozen"/>
		<word count="1" text="kneel"/>
		<word count="1" text="impromptu"/>
		<word count="1" text="onlook"/>
		<word count="1" text="out-of-town"/>
		<word count="1" text="spent"/>
		<word count="1" text="night"/>
		<word count="1" text="windi"/>
		<word count="1" text="landmark"/>
		<word count="1" text="bite"/>
		<word count="1" text="chill"/>
		<word count="1" text="sentiment"/>
		<word count="1" text="extra"/>
		<word count="1" text="burst"/>
		<word count="1" text="attent"/>
		<word count="1" text="wage"/>
		<word count="1" text="longer"/>
		<word count="1" text="elig"/>
		<word count="1" text="slept"/>
		<word count="1" text="spend"/>
		<word count="1" text="prepar"/>
		<word count="1" text="touch"/>
		<word count="1" text="through"/>
		<word count="1" text="almost"/>
		<word count="1" text="daili"/>
		<word count="1" text="century-old"/>
		<word count="1" text="commemor"/>
		<word count="1" text="youth"/>
		<word count="1" text="delinqu"/>
		<word count="1" text="memori"/>
		<word count="1" text="halfway"/>
		<word count="1" text="contend"/>
		<word count="1" text="cluster"/>
		<word count="1" text="divers"/>
		<word count="1" text="array"/>
		<word count="1" text="51-year-old"/>
		<word count="1" text="emot"/>
		<word count="1" text="enact"/>
		<word count="1" text="government-sanct"/>
		<word count="1" text="10-word"/>
		<word count="1" text="cornerston"/>
		<word count="1" text="centuri"/>
		<word count="1" text="hourlong"/>
		<word count="1" text="veer"/>
		<word count="1" text="hypothet"/>
		<word count="1" text="religious-ori"/>
		<word count="1" text="thanksgiv"/>
		<word count="1" text="proclam"/>
		<word count="1" text="strict"/>
		<word count="1" text="decor"/>
		<word count="1" text="ceil"/>
		<word count="1" text="congression"/>
		<word count="1" text="sardon"/>
		<word count="1" text="'god"/>
		<word count="1" text="'avert"/>
		<word count="1" text="connot"/>
		<word count="1" text="fend"/>
		<word count="1" text="felt"/>
		<word count="1" text="unnecessari"/>
		<word count="1" text="non-religi"/>
		<word count="1" text="partial"/>
		<word count="1" text="paralyz"/>
		<word count="1" text="fall"/>
		<word count="1" text="tree"/>
		<word count="1" text="jog"/>
		<word count="1" text="wheelchair"/>
		<word count="1" text="necessari"/>
		<word count="1" text="lectern"/>
		<word count="1" text="absent"/>
		<word count="1" text="senior"/>
		<word count="1" text="reserv"/>
		<word count="1" text="47"/>
		<word count="1" text="predict"/>
		<word count="1" text="outcom"/>
		<word count="1" text="comment"/>
		<word count="1" text="inclin"/>
		<word count="1" text="freeman"/>
		<word count="1" text="york"/>
		<word count="1" text="anti-defam"/>
		<word count="1" text="leagu"/>
		<word count="1" text="visit"/>
		<word count="1" text="star-telegram"/>
		<word count="1" text="onlin"/>
		<word count="1" text="www.star-telegram.com"/>
		<word count="1" text="nn"/>
		<word count="1" text="lose"/>
		<word count="1" text="savor"/>
		<word count="1" text="three"/>
		<word count="1" text="preoccupi"/>
		<word count="1" text="borrow"/>
		<word count="1" text="comput"/>
		<word count="1" text="hardli"/>
		<word count="1" text="rewrit"/>
		<word count="1" text="aspect"/>
		<word count="1" text="perhap"/>
		<word count="1" text="summer"/>
		<word count="1" text="journey"/>
		<word count="1" text="ladder"/>
		<word count="1" text="fail"/>
		<word count="1" text="unlikeliest"/>
		<word count="1" text="age"/>
		<word count="1" text="60"/>
		<word count="1" text="compil"/>
		<word count="1" text="tract"/>
		<word count="1" text="surviv"/>
		<word count="1" text="scroung"/>
		<word count="1" text="pen"/>
		<word count="1" text="colleg"/>
		<word count="1" text="campu"/>
		<word count="1" text="cent"/>
		<word count="1" text="print"/>
		<word count="1" text="page"/>
		<word count="1" text="disdain"/>
		<word count="1" text="portray"/>
		<word count="1" text="caricatur"/>
		<word count="1" text="journalist"/>
		<word count="1" text="crawl"/>
		<word count="1" text="interview"/>
		<word count="1" text="deflect"/>
		<word count="1" text="animatedli"/>
		<word count="1" text="yet"/>
		<word count="1" text="volunt"/>
		<word count="1" text="intrigu"/>
		<word count="1" text="snippet"/>
		<word count="1" text="biographi"/>
		<word count="1" text="stint"/>
		<word count="1" text="trip"/>
		<word count="1" text="wit"/>
		<word count="1" text="overcom"/>
		<word count="1" text="unspecifi"/>
		<word count="1" text="psycholog"/>
		<word count="1" text="eager"/>
		<word count="1" text="steadi"/>
		<word count="1" text="actual"/>
		<word count="1" text="gotten"/>
		<word count="1" text="hollywood"/>
		<word count="1" text="movi"/>
		<word count="1" text="guy"/>
		<word count="1" text="desk"/>
		<word count="1" text="car"/>
		<word count="1" text="chase"/>
		<word count="1" text="explod"/>
		<word count="1" text="bomb"/>
		<word count="1" text="persist"/>
		<word count="1" text="'bring"/>
		<word count="1" text="cash"/>
		<word count="1" text="meet"/>
		<word count="1" text="tall"/>
		<word count="1" text="lanki"/>
		<word count="1" text="center-part"/>
		<word count="1" text="hair"/>
		<word count="1" text="thick"/>
		<word count="1" text="brush"/>
		<word count="1" text="mustach"/>
		<word count="1" text="photograph"/>
		<word count="1" text="caus"/>
		<word count="1" text="base"/>
		<word count="1" text="thought"/>
		<word count="1" text="ought"/>
		<word count="1" text="done"/>
		<word count="1" text="So"/>
		<word count="1" text="antipathi"/>
		<word count="1" text="baptist"/>
		<word count="1" text="'I"/>
		<word count="1" text="rude"/>
		<word count="1" text="pencil"/>
		<word count="1" text="book"/>
		<word count="1" text="dalla"/>
		<word count="1" text="crimin"/>
		<word count="1" text="houston"/>
		<word count="1" text="princip"/>
		<word count="1" text="drug"/>
		<word count="1" text="dealer"/>
		<word count="1" text="destroy"/>
		<word count="1" text="previous"/>
		<word count="1" text="publish"/>
		<word count="1" text="articl"/>
		<word count="1" text="fell"/>
		<word count="1" text="prey"/>
		<word count="1" text="acut"/>
		<word count="1" text="anxieti"/>
		<word count="1" text="complet"/>
		<word count="1" text="engag"/>
		<word count="1" text="beyond"/>
		<word count="1" text="stole"/>
		<word count="1" text="dime"/>
		<word count="1" text="anybodi"/>
		<word count="1" text="bar"/>
		<word count="1" text="record"/>
		<word count="1" text="list"/>
		<word count="1" text="disciplinari"/>
		<word count="1" text="sanction"/>
		<word count="1" text="default"/>
		<word count="1" text="payment"/>
		<word count="1" text="occup"/>
		<word count="1" text="tax"/>
		<word count="1" text="divorc"/>
		<word count="1" text="emerg"/>
		<word count="1" text="vietnam-era"/>
		<word count="1" text="armi"/>
		<word count="1" text="narrowli"/>
		<word count="1" text="duti"/>
		<word count="1" text="helicopt"/>
		<word count="1" text="gunner"/>
		<word count="1" text="corp"/>
		<word count="1" text="brother"/>
		<word count="1" text="navi"/>
		<word count="1" text="aircraft"/>
		<word count="1" text="carrier"/>
		<word count="1" text="sen."/>
		<word count="1" text="mccain"/>
		<word count="1" text="shot"/>
		<word count="1" text="fli"/>
		<word count="1" text="light"/>
		<word count="1" text="train"/>
		<word count="1" text="flight"/>
		<word count="1" text="seriou"/>
		<word count="1" text="crash"/>
		<word count="1" text="enamor"/>
		<word count="1" text="benjamin"/>
		<word count="1" text="nathan"/>
		<word count="1" text="cardozo"/>
		<word count="1" text="unaccept"/>
		<word count="1" text="moreov"/>
		<word count="1" text="omit"/>
		<word count="1" text="hebrew"/>
		<word count="1" text="coven"/>
		<word count="1" text="district"/>
		<word count="1" text="manag"/>
		<word count="1" text="enough"/>
		<word count="1" text="5th"/>
		<word count="1" text="circuit"/>
		<word count="1" text="seiz"/>
		<word count="1" text="rare"/>
		<word count="1" text="telephon"/>
		<word count="1" text="collabor"/>
		<word count="1" text="flew"/>
		<word count="1" text="novemb"/>
		<word count="1" text="busi"/>
		<word count="1" text="draft"/>
		<word count="1" text="favorit"/>
		<word count="1" text="seneca"/>
		<word count="1" text="derid"/>
		<word count="1" text="clich"/>
		<word count="1" text="unfairli"/>
		<word count="1" text="stuck"/>
		<word count="1" text="pride"/>
		<word count="1" text="clean"/>
		<word count="1" text="cloth"/>
		<word count="1" text="groom"/>
		<word count="1" text="attend"/>
		<word count="1" text="surpris"/>
		<word count="1" text="trail"/>
		<word count="1" text="yellow"/>
		<word count="1" text="dog"/>
		<word count="1" text="exagger"/>
		<word count="1" text="ate"/>
		<word count="1" text="upscal"/>
		<word count="1" text="market"/>
		<word count="1" text="pitch"/>
		<word count="1" text="nightli"/>
		<word count="1" text="specifi"/>
		<word count="1" text="bu"/>
		<word count="1" text="grant"/>
		<word count="1" text="veteran"/>
		<word count="1" text="disabl"/>
		<word count="1" text="newspap"/>
		<word count="1" text="magazin"/>
		<word count="1" text="newsstand"/>
		<word count="1" text="happiest"/>
		<word count="1" text="track"/>
		<word count="1" text="break"/>
		<word count="1" text="long"/>
		<word count="1" text="estrang"/>
		<word count="1" text="defin"/>
		<word count="1" text="extent"/>
		<word count="1" text="explicitli"/>
		<word count="1" text="basic"/>
		<word count="1" text="guidelin"/>
		<word count="1" text="given"/>
		<word count="1" text="directli"/>
		<word count="1" text="octob"/>
		<word count="1" text="replica"/>
		<word count="1" text="100"/>
		<word count="1" text="oppos"/>
		<word count="1" text="gave"/>
		<word count="1" text="nationalist"/>
		<word count="1" text="mark"/>
		<word count="1" text="mean"/>
		<word count="1" text="examin"/>
		<word count="1" text="essenti"/>
		<word count="1" text="edict"/>
		<word count="1" text="norm"/>
		<word count="1" text="contradict"/>
		<word count="1" text="surmount"/>
		<word count="1" text="most"/>
		<word count="1" text="recit"/>
		<word count="1" text="conserv"/>
		<word count="1" text="noth"/>
		<word count="1" text="toler"/>
		<word count="1" text="highli"/>
		<word count="1" text="commit"/>
		<word count="1" text="neutral"/>
		<word count="1" text="eric"/>
		<word count="1" text="heirman"/>
		<word count="1" text="young"/>
		<word count="1" text="contrari"/>
		<word count="1" text="shown"/>
		<word count="1" text="everywher"/>
		<word count="1" text="start"/>
		<word count="1" text="indic"/>
		<word count="1" text="return"/>
		<word count="1" text="73-year-old"/>
		<word count="1" text="figur"/>
		<word count="1" text="emphasi"/>
		<word count="1" text="lead"/>
		<word count="1" text="categor"/>
	</Words>
</Topic>
