<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<Topic id="D0929E">
	<Title>Hurricane Rita</Title>
	<Narrative>Describe preparations for Hurricane Rita and estimates of its strength.</Narrative>
	<DocSetA id="D0929E-A">
		<doc id="XIN_ENG_20050919.0201">Evacuation ordered in US island chain ahead of tropical storm</doc>
		<doc id="NYT_ENG_20050920.0246">STATES ON GULF TAKE PRECAUTION AS STORM GROWS</doc>
		<doc id="AFP_ENG_20050920.0413">Oil prices drop amid OPEC output pledge, Hurricane Rita</doc>
		<doc id="AFP_ENG_20050920.0534">Hurricane Rita strengthens to category two</doc>
		<doc id="AFP_ENG_20050920.0545">Airlines suspend flights as Hurricane Rita advances</doc>
		<doc id="AFP_ENG_20050920.0561">Hurricane Rita strengthens to category two
ATTENTION - ADDS details ///</doc>
		<doc id="AFP_ENG_20050920.0614">Katrina refugees forced to flee Texas shelters amid Rita threat</doc>
		<doc id="AFP_ENG_20050920.0630">New Orleans evacuating residents amid Rita threat: mayor</doc>
		<doc id="AFP_ENG_20050920.0633">Governor declares state of emergency in western Louisiana</doc>
		<doc id="AFP_ENG_20050920.0664">Galveston to order mandatory evacuation ahead of Hurricane Rita
ATTENTION - ADDS details ///</doc>
	</DocSetA>
	<Sentences>
		<sentence doc="1" line="1" para="1">An evacuation order was issued Monday for Florida Keys as a tropical storm is moving quickly  towards the southern US island chain.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="1" line="1" para="2">The order will prompt the evacuation of some 40,000 residents  and tourists in the Atlantic archipelago near southeastern US  mainland, US TV network CNN reported.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="1" line="1" para="3">According to latest weather reports, Tropical Storm Rita is  sustaining winds of 97 kph earlier Monday, and is likely to be  upgraded to a level 1 hurricane by the time it passes the Florida  Keys.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="1" line="1" para="4">Earlier, Florida Governor Jeb Bush on Sunday declared a state  of emergency for his state which includes the island chain of  Florida Keys.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="1" line="1" para="5">His order will give the state authority to oversee evacuations  and activate the National Guard.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="1" line="1" para="6">US National Hurricane Center Director Max Mayfield warned that  people in some areas still recovering from Hurricane Katrina  should be watching Rita.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="1" line="1" para="7">&quot;This is definitely becoming a concern for the northwestern  Gulf of Mexico,&quot; he said, noting that Rita could pose a threat to  Texas and Louisiana within days.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="1" line="1" para="8">Rita is the 17th named storm of this year's Atlantic hurricane  season, which started June 1 and will end Nov. 30.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="1" line="1" para="9">It is also the third tropical system to emerge from the  Atlantic in two weeks.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="1" line="1" para="10">Tropical Storm Phillippe was upgraded to a hurricane Sunday  night, while Tropical Storm Ophelia was fading into the North  Atlantic.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="1" para="1">Hurricane Rita brushed past Key West on Tuesday and was forecast to strengthen into a major hurricane later in the week, prompting residents and rescuers to begin evacuating this feeble city, as well as parts of Louisiana and Texas.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="1" para="2">From the tip of the Florida peninsula to Galveston, Texas, thousands left their homes or made plans to, including many who had already fled once, from Hurricane Katrina, and were living in shelters and temporary housing.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="2" para="2">In Houston, officials began moving evacuees from New Orleans out of the Reliant Arena where they had found refuge and sending many of them on to Arkansas.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="1" para="3">In Louisiana, Gov.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="2" para="3">Kathleen Babineaux Blanco asked President Bush on Tuesday to declare a state of emergency for her battered state as it prepares for Hurricane Rita.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="3" para="3">She requested $10 million in assistance.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="1" para="4">Churning undiminished toward the warm and wide Gulf of Mexico, Hurricane Rita could strengthen to Category 4 intensity as it approaches Texas later this week, said Colin McAdie, a meteorologist at the National Hurricane Center in Miami.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="2" para="4">Hurricane Katrina was a Category 4 storm when it devastated parts of the coasts of Louisiana, Mississippi and Alabama on Aug. 29.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="1" para="5">McAdie said western Louisiana could also bear the brunt of the storm depending on changes in steering currents.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="2" para="5">&quot;It's better not to nail it down too precisely,&quot; he said.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="3" para="5">&quot;Over the next day or so we'll have a better idea.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="1" para="6">The official death toll in Louisiana remained at 736.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="2" para="6">In Mississippi, 219 people died from the storm.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="1" para="7">In the city, mostly empty of residents but with its physical core still vulnerable, the possibility of heavy rain and a storm surge prompted officials to make emergency efforts to bolster its weakened levee system, station 500 buses on its outskirts to evacuate remaining residents and establish a military hospital at the convention center, which just weeks ago was the scene of violence and desperation for thousands of trapped evacuees from Hurricane Katrina.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="3" line="1" para="1">World oil prices fell further on  Tuesday, despite a new hurricane powering towards oil facilities in  the Gulf of Mexico, and as OPEC pledged to supply more crude from  the start of October if required.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="3" line="1" para="2">Hurricane Rita was upgraded from a tropical storm as it  threatened the southeastern United States, forcing an alert in  southern Florida and scuttling plans to repopulate New Orleans after  Hurricane Katrina turned it into a ghost city three weeks earlier.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="3" line="1" para="3">The Organization of Petroleum Exporting Countries, meanwhile,  pledged to make an extra two million more barrels per day available  to oil markets from October 1 if there were adequate demand, while  holding its official production ceiling at 28  million barrels per  day.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="3" line="1" para="4">New York's main contract, light sweet crude for delivery in  October, which lapses later Tuesday, sank 1.09 dollars to 66.30  dollars per barrel during early trading.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="3" line="1" para="5">In London, the price of Brent North Sea crude for November  delivery lost 1.29 dollars to 64.32 dollars per barrel.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="3" line="1" para="6">Crude futures extended earlier losses, made on profit taking,  after surging more than four dollars on Monday as Rita looked set to  reach hurricane strength over the oil-rich Gulf Coast.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="4" line="1" para="1">Hurricane Rita strengthened to category  two, packing winds of 160 kilometers per hour (100 mph) early  Tuesday afternoon, the Miami-based National Weather Center  announced.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="4" line="1" para="2">The storm headed from Atlantic waters off Cuba toward the Gulf  of Mexico and was expected to pass about 65 kilometers (40 miles)  off Key West, the southernmost city in a chain of islands linked to  mainland Florida by a single bridge.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="4" line="1" para="3">Forecasters warned that once it hits the warm Gulf of Mexico  waters, Rita could gain further strength and reach category three on  the five-level Saffir-Simpson hurricane intensity scale.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="1" para="1">Iberia and American Airlines said  Tuesday they were suspending flights between Madrid and Miami  because of Hurricane Rita.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="1" para="2">Both companies told AFP they were awaiting information from US  authorities before deciding to restore the flights.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="1" para="3">The Miami-based National Weather Center said the hurricane  strengthened Tuesday, packing winds of 160 kilometers per hour (100  mph).</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="1" para="1">Hurricane Rita strengthened to category  two, packing winds of 160 kilometers per hour (100 mph) early  Tuesday afternoon, the Miami-based National Weather Center  announced.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="1" para="2">The storm headed from Atlantic waters off Cuba toward the Gulf  of Mexico and was expected to pass about 65 kilometers (40 miles)  off Key West, the southernmost city in a chain of islands linked to  mainland Florida by a single bridge.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="1" para="3">Forecasters warned that once it hits the warm Gulf of Mexico  waters, Rita could gain further strength and reach category three on  the five-level Saffir-Simpson hurricane intensity scale.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="1" para="4">Authorities warned people who had not evacuated Key West and the  rest of the Florida Keys to remain indoors and hunker down until the  storm has passed.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="1" para="5">Forecasters said the Florida Keys could experience large and  dangerous waves and storm surge of up to two meters (six feet.)</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="1" para="1">More than 7,000  Hurricane Katrina survivors taking refuge in Texas shelters were  being uprooted again Tuesday as Hurricane Rita threatened the state  neighboring Louisiana, officials said.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="1" para="2">About 4,000 refugees from Louisiana housed in a shelter in  Houston, Texas, are being moved to Arkansas, while 3,000 more are  moving from a San Antonio refuge to Tennessee, said David Passey, a  Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) spokesman.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="1" para="3">Texas is also looking for states to house 360 refugees currently  in Corpus Christi, Passey told reporters in Baton Rouge, in the  state of Louisiana devastated by Katrina on August 29.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="1" para="4">More than 13,000 Katrina survivors are in Texas shelters, but  authorities are only moving those located in vulnerable areas, he  said.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="1" para="5">&quot;Texas right now bears the greatest threat from Hurricane Rita,&quot;  Passey said.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="2" para="5">&quot;Today, the state of Texas is working with other states  to evacuate the remaining Louisiana residents to other places.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="1" para="6">He said he did not know how long the refugees would have to stay  in the new shelters.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="2" para="6">Authorities began relocating them by bus and  plane Tuesday, Passey said.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="1" para="7">Hundreds of thousands of people were forced from their homes by  Katrina, which has left nearly 1,000 people dead.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="2" para="7">Nearly 97,000  Katrina survivors are being housed in shelters across the United  States, according to figures released Tuesday.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="1" para="8">Hurricane Rita barreled near southern Florida islands and headed  toward the Gulf of Mexico, threatening Texas and Louisiana with  winds of 160 kilometers per hour (100 mph).</sentence>
		<sentence doc="8" line="1" para="1">Emergency services began  evacuating residents of hurricane-ravaged New Orleans once again  Tuesday due to the threat posed by Hurricane Rita, Mayor Ray Nagin  said.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="8" line="1" para="2">&quot;We have had an influx of evacuees that have made their way to  the convention center.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="8" line="2" para="2">We've already evacuated two busloads of  individuals,&quot; Nagin said as Rita barreled near southernmost Florida,  heading west on a track that could take it close to the devastated  Louisiana city.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="9" line="1" para="1">Louisiana Governor  Kathleen Blanco declared a state of emergency in western Louisiana  on Tuesday and urged people to evacuate as strengthening Hurricane  Rita headed toward the Gulf of Mexico.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="9" line="1" para="2">&quot;I have put the state on alert.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="9" line="2" para="2">We've declared another emergency  for particularly at this moment for southwest Louisiana,&quot; Blanco  said.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="9" line="1" para="3">&quot;We're urging people to evacuate,&quot; she told a press conference  as Rita barreled near southernmost Florida, heading west on a track  that could take it close to the devastated Louisiana city.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="10" line="1" para="1">The Texas coastal county of  Galveston will order a mandatory evacuation on Wednesday in  preparation for Hurricane Rita, the office of emergency management  said Tuesday.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="10" line="1" para="2">A county judge said he is planning on issuing a mandatory  evacuation of nursing homes and assisted-living facilities beginning  at 6:00 am (9:00 GMT) Wednesday, with a mandatory evacuation of the  general population beginning at 6:00 pm (2100 GMT) and continuing  through Thursday afternoon.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="10" line="1" para="3">Local schools have already closed and government offices will be  closed Wednesday amid fears the hurricane could strike the region.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="10" line="1" para="4">Hurricane Rita pounded the fragile Florida Keys islands Tuesday  as it barreled toward the oil-rich Gulf of Mexico.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="10" line="1" para="5">Those wishing to enter the county to check on their boats or  summer houses were warned to do so no later than noon on Wednesday  as all traffic will be directed northbound after mandatory  evacuation begins.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="10" line="1" para="6">Shelters have been set up in three nearby towns and pets will be  allowed in the shelters, officials said.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="10" line="2" para="6">Many Louisiana residents  were deterred from staying in a shelter during the deadly Hurricane  Katrina because they did not want to abandon their pets.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="10" line="1" para="7">Located just south of Houston, the county of Galveston is home  to some 267,000 people.</sentence>
	</Sentences>
	<Words>
		<word count="33" text="hurrican"/>
		<word count="23" text="rita"/>
		<word count="21" text="on"/>
		<word count="19" text="said"/>
		<word count="18" text="from"/>
		<word count="17" text="louisiana"/>
		<word count="16" text="it"/>
		<word count="15" text="evacu"/>
		<word count="15" text="tuesday"/>
		<word count="14" text="florida"/>
		<word count="14" text="as"/>
		<word count="14" text="storm"/>
		<word count="14" text="state"/>
		<word count="12" text="for"/>
		<word count="12" text="texa"/>
		<word count="11" text="katrina"/>
		<word count="11" text="gulf"/>
		<word count="10" text="key"/>
		<word count="10" text="is"/>
		<word count="10" text="mexico"/>
		<word count="9" text="wa"/>
		<word count="9" text="emerg"/>
		<word count="9" text="could"/>
		<word count="9" text="shelter"/>
		<word count="8" text="toward"/>
		<word count="8" text="be"/>
		<word count="8" text="peopl"/>
		<word count="8" text="``"/>
		<word count="8" text="''"/>
		<word count="8" text="were"/>
		<word count="8" text="barrel"/>
		<word count="8" text="per"/>
		<word count="7" text="the"/>
		<word count="7" text="will"/>
		<word count="7" text="resid"/>
		<word count="7" text="by"/>
		<word count="7" text="center"/>
		<word count="7" text="citi"/>
		<word count="7" text="at"/>
		<word count="7" text="have"/>
		<word count="6" text="tropic"/>
		<word count="6" text="island"/>
		<word count="6" text="atlant"/>
		<word count="6" text="nation"/>
		<word count="6" text="two"/>
		<word count="6" text="west"/>
		<word count="6" text="strengthen"/>
		<word count="6" text="offici"/>
		<word count="6" text="new"/>
		<word count="6" text="categori"/>
		<word count="6" text="more"/>
		<word count="6" text="kilomet"/>
		<word count="6" text="head"/>
		<word count="5" text="move"/>
		<word count="5" text="US"/>
		<word count="5" text="wind"/>
		<word count="5" text="which"/>
		<word count="5" text="author"/>
		<word count="5" text="warn"/>
		<word count="5" text="thi"/>
		<word count="5" text="he"/>
		<word count="5" text="week"/>
		<word count="5" text="their"/>
		<word count="5" text="hous"/>
		<word count="5" text="In"/>
		<word count="5" text="dollar"/>
		<word count="5" text="are"/>
		<word count="4" text="order"/>
		<word count="4" text="chain"/>
		<word count="4" text="near"/>
		<word count="4" text="weather"/>
		<word count="4" text="earlier"/>
		<word count="4" text="pass"/>
		<word count="4" text="declar"/>
		<word count="4" text="day"/>
		<word count="4" text="forecast"/>
		<word count="4" text="later"/>
		<word count="4" text="begin"/>
		<word count="4" text="home"/>
		<word count="4" text="had"/>
		<word count="4" text="onc"/>
		<word count="4" text="they"/>
		<word count="4" text="devast"/>
		<word count="4" text="not"/>
		<word count="4" text="remain"/>
		<word count="4" text="with"/>
		<word count="4" text="crude"/>
		<word count="4" text="three"/>
		<word count="4" text="take"/>
		<word count="4" text="than"/>
		<word count="4" text="160"/>
		<word count="4" text="hour"/>
		<word count="4" text="100"/>
		<word count="4" text="mph"/>
		<word count="4" text="water"/>
		<word count="4" text="off"/>
		<word count="4" text="southernmost"/>
		<word count="4" text="passey"/>
		<word count="4" text="We"/>
		<word count="4" text="close"/>
		<word count="4" text="counti"/>
		<word count="4" text="mandatori"/>
		<word count="4" text="wednesday"/>
		<word count="3" text="monday"/>
		<word count="3" text="southern"/>
		<word count="3" text="prompt"/>
		<word count="3" text="some"/>
		<word count="3" text="mainland"/>
		<word count="3" text="report"/>
		<word count="3" text="upgrad"/>
		<word count="3" text="1"/>
		<word count="3" text="threat"/>
		<word count="3" text="'s"/>
		<word count="3" text="also"/>
		<word count="3" text="while"/>
		<word count="3" text="into"/>
		<word count="3" text="galveston"/>
		<word count="3" text="thousand"/>
		<word count="3" text="or"/>
		<word count="3" text="made"/>
		<word count="3" text="plan"/>
		<word count="3" text="mani"/>
		<word count="3" text="alreadi"/>
		<word count="3" text="houston"/>
		<word count="3" text="began"/>
		<word count="3" text="evacue"/>
		<word count="3" text="orlean"/>
		<word count="3" text="refug"/>
		<word count="3" text="blanco"/>
		<word count="3" text="million"/>
		<word count="3" text="warm"/>
		<word count="3" text="intens"/>
		<word count="3" text="surg"/>
		<word count="3" text="oil"/>
		<word count="3" text="further"/>
		<word count="3" text="octob"/>
		<word count="3" text="threaten"/>
		<word count="3" text="an"/>
		<word count="3" text="after"/>
		<word count="3" text="earli"/>
		<word count="3" text="reach"/>
		<word count="3" text="strength"/>
		<word count="3" text="pack"/>
		<word count="3" text="afternoon"/>
		<word count="3" text="miami-bas"/>
		<word count="3" text="about"/>
		<word count="3" text="told"/>
		<word count="3" text="survivor"/>
		<word count="3" text="refuge"/>
		<word count="2" text="issu"/>
		<word count="2" text="southeastern"/>
		<word count="2" text="accord"/>
		<word count="2" text="governor"/>
		<word count="2" text="bush"/>
		<word count="2" text="sunday"/>
		<word count="2" text="hi"/>
		<word count="2" text="includ"/>
		<word count="2" text="area"/>
		<word count="2" text="still"/>
		<word count="2" text="pose"/>
		<word count="2" text="start"/>
		<word count="2" text="It"/>
		<word count="2" text="system"/>
		<word count="2" text="north"/>
		<word count="2" text="part"/>
		<word count="2" text="left"/>
		<word count="2" text="who"/>
		<word count="2" text="them"/>
		<word count="2" text="arkansa"/>
		<word count="2" text="kathleen"/>
		<word count="2" text="prepar"/>
		<word count="2" text="she"/>
		<word count="2" text="4"/>
		<word count="2" text="mcadi"/>
		<word count="2" text="miami"/>
		<word count="2" text="coast"/>
		<word count="2" text="mississippi"/>
		<word count="2" text="29"/>
		<word count="2" text="western"/>
		<word count="2" text="bear"/>
		<word count="2" text="current"/>
		<word count="2" text="better"/>
		<word count="2" text="down"/>
		<word count="2" text="over"/>
		<word count="2" text="so"/>
		<word count="2" text="but"/>
		<word count="2" text="vulner"/>
		<word count="2" text="make"/>
		<word count="2" text="convent"/>
		<word count="2" text="just"/>
		<word count="2" text="price"/>
		<word count="2" text="facil"/>
		<word count="2" text="pledg"/>
		<word count="2" text="if"/>
		<word count="2" text="unit"/>
		<word count="2" text="forc"/>
		<word count="2" text="alert"/>
		<word count="2" text="deliveri"/>
		<word count="2" text="dure"/>
		<word count="2" text="look"/>
		<word count="2" text="set"/>
		<word count="2" text="oil-rich"/>
		<word count="2" text="announc"/>
		<word count="2" text="cuba"/>
		<word count="2" text="expect"/>
		<word count="2" text="65"/>
		<word count="2" text="40"/>
		<word count="2" text="mile"/>
		<word count="2" text="link"/>
		<word count="2" text="singl"/>
		<word count="2" text="bridg"/>
		<word count="2" text="hit"/>
		<word count="2" text="gain"/>
		<word count="2" text="five-level"/>
		<word count="2" text="saffir-simpson"/>
		<word count="2" text="scale"/>
		<word count="2" text="flight"/>
		<word count="2" text="becaus"/>
		<word count="2" text="ha"/>
		<word count="2" text="up"/>
		<word count="2" text="again"/>
		<word count="2" text="manag"/>
		<word count="2" text="those"/>
		<word count="2" text="locat"/>
		<word count="2" text="other"/>
		<word count="2" text="did"/>
		<word count="2" text="stay"/>
		<word count="2" text="nearli"/>
		<word count="2" text="nagin"/>
		<word count="2" text="'ve"/>
		<word count="2" text="track"/>
		<word count="2" text="urg"/>
		<word count="2" text="offic"/>
		<word count="2" text="6:00"/>
		<word count="2" text="gmt"/>
		<word count="2" text="pet"/>
		<word count="1" text="An"/>
		<word count="1" text="quickli"/>
		<word count="1" text="40,000"/>
		<word count="1" text="tourist"/>
		<word count="1" text="archipelago"/>
		<word count="1" text="TV"/>
		<word count="1" text="network"/>
		<word count="1" text="cnn"/>
		<word count="1" text="latest"/>
		<word count="1" text="sustain"/>
		<word count="1" text="97"/>
		<word count="1" text="kph"/>
		<word count="1" text="like"/>
		<word count="1" text="level"/>
		<word count="1" text="time"/>
		<word count="1" text="jeb"/>
		<word count="1" text="give"/>
		<word count="1" text="overse"/>
		<word count="1" text="activ"/>
		<word count="1" text="guard"/>
		<word count="1" text="director"/>
		<word count="1" text="max"/>
		<word count="1" text="mayfield"/>
		<word count="1" text="recov"/>
		<word count="1" text="should"/>
		<word count="1" text="watch"/>
		<word count="1" text="definit"/>
		<word count="1" text="becom"/>
		<word count="1" text="concern"/>
		<word count="1" text="northwestern"/>
		<word count="1" text="note"/>
		<word count="1" text="within"/>
		<word count="1" text="17th"/>
		<word count="1" text="name"/>
		<word count="1" text="year"/>
		<word count="1" text="season"/>
		<word count="1" text="june"/>
		<word count="1" text="end"/>
		<word count="1" text="nov."/>
		<word count="1" text="30"/>
		<word count="1" text="third"/>
		<word count="1" text="phillipp"/>
		<word count="1" text="night"/>
		<word count="1" text="ophelia"/>
		<word count="1" text="fade"/>
		<word count="1" text="brush"/>
		<word count="1" text="past"/>
		<word count="1" text="major"/>
		<word count="1" text="rescuer"/>
		<word count="1" text="feebl"/>
		<word count="1" text="well"/>
		<word count="1" text="tip"/>
		<word count="1" text="peninsula"/>
		<word count="1" text="fled"/>
		<word count="1" text="live"/>
		<word count="1" text="temporari"/>
		<word count="1" text="out"/>
		<word count="1" text="reliant"/>
		<word count="1" text="arena"/>
		<word count="1" text="where"/>
		<word count="1" text="found"/>
		<word count="1" text="send"/>
		<word count="1" text="gov"/>
		<word count="1" text="babineaux"/>
		<word count="1" text="ask"/>
		<word count="1" text="presid"/>
		<word count="1" text="her"/>
		<word count="1" text="batter"/>
		<word count="1" text="request"/>
		<word count="1" text="10"/>
		<word count="1" text="assist"/>
		<word count="1" text="churn"/>
		<word count="1" text="undiminish"/>
		<word count="1" text="wide"/>
		<word count="1" text="approach"/>
		<word count="1" text="colin"/>
		<word count="1" text="meteorologist"/>
		<word count="1" text="when"/>
		<word count="1" text="alabama"/>
		<word count="1" text="aug."/>
		<word count="1" text="brunt"/>
		<word count="1" text="depend"/>
		<word count="1" text="chang"/>
		<word count="1" text="steer"/>
		<word count="1" text="nail"/>
		<word count="1" text="too"/>
		<word count="1" text="precis"/>
		<word count="1" text="next"/>
		<word count="1" text="we"/>
		<word count="1" text="'ll"/>
		<word count="1" text="idea"/>
		<word count="1" text="death"/>
		<word count="1" text="toll"/>
		<word count="1" text="736"/>
		<word count="1" text="219"/>
		<word count="1" text="die"/>
		<word count="1" text="mostli"/>
		<word count="1" text="empti"/>
		<word count="1" text="physic"/>
		<word count="1" text="core"/>
		<word count="1" text="possibl"/>
		<word count="1" text="heavi"/>
		<word count="1" text="rain"/>
		<word count="1" text="effort"/>
		<word count="1" text="bolster"/>
		<word count="1" text="weaken"/>
		<word count="1" text="leve"/>
		<word count="1" text="station"/>
		<word count="1" text="500"/>
		<word count="1" text="buse"/>
		<word count="1" text="outskirt"/>
		<word count="1" text="establish"/>
		<word count="1" text="militari"/>
		<word count="1" text="hospit"/>
		<word count="1" text="ago"/>
		<word count="1" text="scene"/>
		<word count="1" text="violenc"/>
		<word count="1" text="desper"/>
		<word count="1" text="trap"/>
		<word count="1" text="world"/>
		<word count="1" text="fell"/>
		<word count="1" text="despit"/>
		<word count="1" text="power"/>
		<word count="1" text="opec"/>
		<word count="1" text="suppli"/>
		<word count="1" text="requir"/>
		<word count="1" text="scuttl"/>
		<word count="1" text="repopul"/>
		<word count="1" text="turn"/>
		<word count="1" text="ghost"/>
		<word count="1" text="organ"/>
		<word count="1" text="petroleum"/>
		<word count="1" text="export"/>
		<word count="1" text="countri"/>
		<word count="1" text="meanwhil"/>
		<word count="1" text="extra"/>
		<word count="1" text="avail"/>
		<word count="1" text="market"/>
		<word count="1" text="there"/>
		<word count="1" text="adequ"/>
		<word count="1" text="demand"/>
		<word count="1" text="hold"/>
		<word count="1" text="product"/>
		<word count="1" text="ceil"/>
		<word count="1" text="28"/>
		<word count="1" text="york"/>
		<word count="1" text="main"/>
		<word count="1" text="contract"/>
		<word count="1" text="light"/>
		<word count="1" text="sweet"/>
		<word count="1" text="laps"/>
		<word count="1" text="sank"/>
		<word count="1" text="1.09"/>
		<word count="1" text="66.30"/>
		<word count="1" text="trade"/>
		<word count="1" text="london"/>
		<word count="1" text="brent"/>
		<word count="1" text="sea"/>
		<word count="1" text="novemb"/>
		<word count="1" text="lost"/>
		<word count="1" text="1.29"/>
		<word count="1" text="64.32"/>
		<word count="1" text="futur"/>
		<word count="1" text="extend"/>
		<word count="1" text="loss"/>
		<word count="1" text="profit"/>
		<word count="1" text="four"/>
		<word count="1" text="iberia"/>
		<word count="1" text="american"/>
		<word count="1" text="airlin"/>
		<word count="1" text="suspend"/>
		<word count="1" text="between"/>
		<word count="1" text="madrid"/>
		<word count="1" text="both"/>
		<word count="1" text="compani"/>
		<word count="1" text="afp"/>
		<word count="1" text="await"/>
		<word count="1" text="inform"/>
		<word count="1" text="befor"/>
		<word count="1" text="decid"/>
		<word count="1" text="restor"/>
		<word count="1" text="rest"/>
		<word count="1" text="indoor"/>
		<word count="1" text="hunker"/>
		<word count="1" text="until"/>
		<word count="1" text="experi"/>
		<word count="1" text="larg"/>
		<word count="1" text="danger"/>
		<word count="1" text="wave"/>
		<word count="1" text="meter"/>
		<word count="1" text="six"/>
		<word count="1" text="feet"/>
		<word count="1" text="7,000"/>
		<word count="1" text="uproot"/>
		<word count="1" text="neighbor"/>
		<word count="1" text="4,000"/>
		<word count="1" text="3,000"/>
		<word count="1" text="san"/>
		<word count="1" text="antonio"/>
		<word count="1" text="tennesse"/>
		<word count="1" text="david"/>
		<word count="1" text="feder"/>
		<word count="1" text="agenc"/>
		<word count="1" text="fema"/>
		<word count="1" text="spokesman"/>
		<word count="1" text="360"/>
		<word count="1" text="corpu"/>
		<word count="1" text="christi"/>
		<word count="1" text="baton"/>
		<word count="1" text="roug"/>
		<word count="1" text="august"/>
		<word count="1" text="13,000"/>
		<word count="1" text="onli"/>
		<word count="1" text="right"/>
		<word count="1" text="now"/>
		<word count="1" text="greatest"/>
		<word count="1" text="today"/>
		<word count="1" text="work"/>
		<word count="1" text="place"/>
		<word count="1" text="He"/>
		<word count="1" text="know"/>
		<word count="1" text="how"/>
		<word count="1" text="long"/>
		<word count="1" text="would"/>
		<word count="1" text="reloc"/>
		<word count="1" text="bu"/>
		<word count="1" text="plane"/>
		<word count="1" text="hundr"/>
		<word count="1" text="1,000"/>
		<word count="1" text="dead"/>
		<word count="1" text="97,000"/>
		<word count="1" text="across"/>
		<word count="1" text="figur"/>
		<word count="1" text="releas"/>
		<word count="1" text="servic"/>
		<word count="1" text="hurricane-ravag"/>
		<word count="1" text="due"/>
		<word count="1" text="mayor"/>
		<word count="1" text="ray"/>
		<word count="1" text="influx"/>
		<word count="1" text="way"/>
		<word count="1" text="busload"/>
		<word count="1" text="individu"/>
		<word count="1" text="I"/>
		<word count="1" text="put"/>
		<word count="1" text="anoth"/>
		<word count="1" text="particularli"/>
		<word count="1" text="moment"/>
		<word count="1" text="southwest"/>
		<word count="1" text="'re"/>
		<word count="1" text="press"/>
		<word count="1" text="confer"/>
		<word count="1" text="coastal"/>
		<word count="1" text="A"/>
		<word count="1" text="judg"/>
		<word count="1" text="nurs"/>
		<word count="1" text="assisted-liv"/>
		<word count="1" text="am"/>
		<word count="1" text="9:00"/>
		<word count="1" text="gener"/>
		<word count="1" text="popul"/>
		<word count="1" text="pm"/>
		<word count="1" text="2100"/>
		<word count="1" text="continu"/>
		<word count="1" text="through"/>
		<word count="1" text="thursday"/>
		<word count="1" text="local"/>
		<word count="1" text="school"/>
		<word count="1" text="govern"/>
		<word count="1" text="amid"/>
		<word count="1" text="fear"/>
		<word count="1" text="strike"/>
		<word count="1" text="region"/>
		<word count="1" text="pound"/>
		<word count="1" text="fragil"/>
		<word count="1" text="wish"/>
		<word count="1" text="enter"/>
		<word count="1" text="check"/>
		<word count="1" text="boat"/>
		<word count="1" text="summer"/>
		<word count="1" text="do"/>
		<word count="1" text="no"/>
		<word count="1" text="noon"/>
		<word count="1" text="all"/>
		<word count="1" text="traffic"/>
		<word count="1" text="direct"/>
		<word count="1" text="northbound"/>
		<word count="1" text="been"/>
		<word count="1" text="nearbi"/>
		<word count="1" text="town"/>
		<word count="1" text="allow"/>
		<word count="1" text="deter"/>
		<word count="1" text="deadli"/>
		<word count="1" text="want"/>
		<word count="1" text="abandon"/>
		<word count="1" text="south"/>
		<word count="1" text="267,000"/>
	</Words>
</Topic>
