<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<Topic id="D0937G">
	<Title>Vice President Cheney shooting Harry Whittington</Title>
	<Narrative>Discuss the shooting of Harry Whittington by Vice President Cheney and the results and reactions to this incident.</Narrative>
	<DocSetA id="D0937G-A">
		<doc id="LTW_ENG_20060212.0053">Cheney Accidentally Sprays Hunting Companion With Birdshot</doc>
		<doc id="NYT_ENG_20060212.0196">CHENEY ACCIDENTALLY SHOOTS HUNTING PARTNER  BY MICHAEL KRANISH,</doc>
		<doc id="XIN_ENG_20060212.0242">Cheney accidentally shoots, injures fellow hunter</doc>
		<doc id="APW_ENG_20060212.0608">Vice President Dick Cheney accidentally shoots fellow hunter in Texas</doc>
		<doc id="LTW_ENG_20060213.0135">Cheney Lacked Proper Hunting Credentials</doc>
		<doc id="NYT_ENG_20060213.0144">WHITE HOUSE DEFENDS INFORMATION DELAY ABOUT CHENEY'S HUNTING ACCIDENT</doc>
		<doc id="NYT_ENG_20060213.0277">ONE SHOOTING BRINGS A BARRELFUL OF QUESTIONS ELISABETH BUMILLER AND GLEN JUSTICE CONTRIBUTED REPORTING FOR THIS ARTICLE</doc>
		<doc id="AFP_ENG_20060213.0487">Cheney hunting partner in good condition: hospital</doc>
		<doc id="AFP_ENG_20060213.0664">White House under fire over Cheney shooting
by Olivier Knox
ATTENTION - ADDS details, quotes ///</doc>
		<doc id="AFP_ENG_20060213.0741">Cheney lacked license when he accidently shot another hunter
by Olivier Knox
ATTENTION - RECASTS, UPDATES with details ///</doc>
	</DocSetA>
	<Sentences>
		<sentence doc="1" line="1" para="1">Vice President Dick Cheney accidentally sprayed a companion with birdshot while hunting quail on a private Texas ranch, injuring the man in the face, neck and chest, the vice president's office confirmed yesterday after a Texas newspaper reported the incident.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="1" line="1" para="2">The shooting occurred late Saturday afternoon while Cheney was hunting with Harry Whittington, 78, a prominent Austin lawyer, on the Armstrong Ranch in south Texas.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="1" line="2" para="2">Hearing a covey of birds, Cheney shot at one, not realizing that Whittington had startled the quail and that he was in the line of fire.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="1" line="1" para="3">Whittington was treated on the scene by Cheney's traveling medical detail before being taken by helicopter to a Corpus Christi hospital.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="1" line="2" para="3">He was in the intensive care unit at Christus Spohn Health System and listed in stable condition yesterday evening.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="1" line="1" para="4">Katharine Armstrong, the ranch's owner, saw what happened Saturday and told reporters Sunday that Cheney was using a 28-gauge shotgun, which shoots fewer pellets and has a smaller shot pattern than a 12-gauge shotgun, making hitting the target more challenging.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="1" line="2" para="4">Whittington was about 30 yards away when he was hit in the cheek, neck and chest, she said.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="1" line="1" para="5">PICK UP 5th graf: According to Armstrong's xxx</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="1" para="1">Globe Staff</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="1" para="2">WASHINGTON - Vice President Dick Cheney accidentally shot a hunting partner Saturday in Texas, and the White House did not confirm the shooting until nearly 20 hours later.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="2" para="2">The victim was described as being &quot;peppered pretty good&quot; with birdshot and was in stable condition Sunday.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="1" para="3">Cheney shot Harry Whittington, 78, a multimillionaire Austin lawyer, spraying his friend and hunting partner with shotgun pellets from head to chest.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="2" para="3">He was being treated in the intensive care unit at a Corpus Christi hospital.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="1" para="4">Whittington, bloodied but still conscious, tumbled to the ground after he was hit.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="2" para="4">Cheney thought he was shooting at a covey of quail, according to an owner of the ranch.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="1" para="5">Cheney is a longtime hunter and delivered the keynote address in 2004 to the National Rifle Association, from which he accepted a rifle as a gift.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="1" para="6">The accident happened in south Texas at the famed Armstrong Ranch, co-owned by members of a family long close to Cheney.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="2" para="6">Tobin Armstrong was a major financial backer of the Bush-Cheney team who died last October, with Cheney attending the funeral.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="3" para="6">Anne Armstrong, a former counselor to President Nixon, has served on the board of the Halliburton Corp., where Cheney was chief executive before becoming vice president.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="1" para="7">Whittington is a longtime friend of President Bush from their days together in Austin when Bush was Texas governor.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="2" para="7">He was described in an article published two weeks ago in the Austin-American Statesman as being &quot;very rich, very stubborn, and very patient.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="1" para="8">The Associated Press quoted Katharine Armstrong, one of the ranch owners, as saying she watched the shooting from her vantage in a nearby car.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="2" para="8">She said that Whittington shot a quail and went to look for it in the grass.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="3" para="8">Cheney then went to search for more quail.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="1" para="9">Cheney was using a 28-gauge shotgun and was about 30 yards away from Whittington, she said.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="2" para="9">Both men were wearing orange vests.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="1" para="10">Whittington &quot;came up from behind the vice president and the other hunter and didn't signal them or indicate to them or announce himself,&quot; Armstrong told the Associated Press.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="2" para="10">&quot;The vice president didn't see him.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="3" para="10">The covey flushed and the vice president picked out a bird and was following it and shot.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="4" para="10">And, by God, Harry was in the line of fire and got peppered pretty good.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="1" para="11">Armstrong said Whittington was injured mostly on his right side, from cheek to chest.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="2" para="11">Cheney was described as apologetic for shooting Whittington.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="3" para="11">He was taken by medical helicopter to the Christus Spohn Health System in Corpus Christi, about an hour away.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="1" para="12">Cheney was described as apologetic for shooting Whittington.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="2" para="12">The vice president visited Whittington in the hospital Sunday, Armstrong said.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="1" para="13">&quot;It broke the skin,&quot; Armstrong said, referring to the birdshot.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="2" para="13">&quot;It knocked him silly.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="3" para="13">But he was fine.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="4" para="13">He was talking.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="5" para="13">His eyes were open.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="6" para="13">It didn't get in his eyes or anything like that.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="1" para="14">The shooting occurred about 5:30 p.m. local time Saturday and was first reported on the website of the Corpus Christi Caller-Times at midday Sunday, according to a reporter at the newspaper.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="2" para="14">The White House confirmed the shooting after being contacted by the media.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="1" para="15">White House spokeswoman Lea Anne McBride, asked in a telephone interview why the shooting was not announced sooner, referred questions to Katharine Armstrong.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="2" para="15">McBride said Armstrong talked to &quot;her local paper and when we were asked about the account she had provided, [we] confirmed that.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="1" para="16">Armstrong did not return a call seeking comment on McBride's statement.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="1" para="17">After the hospital visit, McBride said Cheney &quot;was pleased to see that he was doing fine and in good spirits.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="1" para="18">Cheney, who suffered four heart attacks before he was elected vice president and has been hospitalized for heart problems while in office, always travels with a medical team.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="2" para="18">His team treated Whittington before he was taken to the hospital.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="1" para="19">Bush, who owns a ranch in Texas, and Cheney, who grew up in Wyoming, are both enthusiastic hunters, a fact they have frequently mentioned during political campaigns.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="2" para="19">McBride said Cheney has a Texas hunting license.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="1" para="20">Cheney's hunting trips have included one with Supreme Court Justice Antonin Scalia, who went duck hunting in January 2004 with the vice president in Louisiana, a trip criticized because Scalia participates in decisions that affect the administration.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="1" para="21">Tobin Armstrong was quoted by the Associated Press as saying in 2000 that he frequently went hunting on the ranch with Cheney, who turned 65 last month.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="1" para="22">When Armstrong died in October, his funeral was attended by Cheney and former President George H. W. Bush.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="2" para="22">&quot;Tobin is one of our dearest and most respected friends,&quot; former President Bush said.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="3" para="22">&quot;Barbara and I loved Tobin Armstrong.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="1" para="23">The 50,000-acre Armstrong Ranch was purchased in 1852 by Tobin Armstrong's grandfather, John Armstrong III, who became known for capturing outlaw John Wesley Hardin, according to a profile of the ranch in the Caller-Times.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="1" para="24">Whittington has long been active in Republican Party politics and was appointed by then-Governor George W. Bush to the Texas Funeral Service Commission.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="1" para="25">In the final stages of the 2004 campaign, Cheney mocked the way Democratic presidential nominee Senator John F. Kerry went on a hunting trip.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="1" para="26">&quot;He wore a brand new camouflage jacket for the occasion, which makes you wonder just how often he does really go goose hunting,&quot; Cheney said, according to a White House transcript.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="2" para="26">&quot;My personal opinion was his camo jacket was an October disguise.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="3" para="26">...</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="4" para="26">But, my fellow sportsmen, this coverup isn't going to work because you and I know the Second Amendment is more than just another photo opportunity.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="1" para="27">The Houston Chronicle has reported that there were 29 hunting-related accidents in Texas in 2004, with four fatalities.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="3" line="1" para="1">U.S. Vice President Dick Cheney accidentally shot and injured a hunting companion in Texas over  the weekend, U.S. media reported Sunday.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="3" line="1" para="2">Harry Whittington, Cheney's hunting companion during a quail  hunting trip in Texas on Saturday, was mostly injured on his right side, with shotgun pellets hitting his cheek, neck and chest, the  reports said.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="3" line="1" para="3">Whittington, 78, was &quot;alert and doing fine&quot; in the hospital,  Katharine Armstrong, owner of the Armstrong Ranch in south Texas,  was quoted by CNN as saying.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="3" line="1" para="4">Cheney spent time with Whittington, a lawyer from Austin, and  his wife at the hospital on Sunday, CNN said.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="3" line="1" para="5">Whittington shot a bird and was looking for it in the tall  grass, while Cheney and the third hunter walked to another spot  and found a second covey, Armstrong said.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="3" line="1" para="6">She said Cheney didn't see Whittington, and when he chose a  bird to shoot, he accidentally hit Whittington, who was &quot;in the in the line of fire.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence doc="3" line="1" para="7">Whittington was bleeding, but he was not very seriously injured, she said.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="3" line="1" para="8">Cheney was very apologetic, she added.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="4" line="1" para="1">Vice President Dick Cheney accidentally shot and wounded a companion during a weekend quail hunting trip in Texas, spraying the fellow hunter in the face and chest with shotgun pellets.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="4" line="1" para="2">Harry Whittington, a millionaire attorney from Austin, was &quot;alert and doing fine&quot; in a Corpus Christi hospital Sunday, a day after he was shot by Cheney on a ranch in south Texas, said Katharine Armstrong, the property's owner.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="4" line="1" para="3">He was described as in stable condition by Yvonne Wheeler, spokeswoman for the Christus Spohn Health System in Corpus Christi.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="4" line="1" para="4">Armstrong in an interview with The Associated Press said Whittington, 78, was mostly injured on his right side, with the pellets hitting his cheek, neck and chest during the incident which occurred late afternoon on Saturday</sentence>
		<sentence doc="4" line="1" para="5">She said emergency personnel traveling with Cheney tended to Whittington until the ambulance arrived.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="4" line="1" para="6">Cheney's spokeswoman, Lea Anne McBride, said the vice president was with Whittington and his wife at the hospital on Sunday.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="4" line="1" para="7">The shooting was first reported by the Corpus Christi Caller-Times.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="4" line="2" para="7">The vice president's office did not disclose the accident until nearly 24 hours after it happened.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="4" line="1" para="8">Armstrong said she was watching from a car while Cheney, Whittington and another hunter got out of the vehicle to shoot at a covey of quail.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="4" line="1" para="9">Whittington shot a bird and went to look for it in the tall grass, while Cheney and the third hunter walked to another spot and discovered a second covey.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="4" line="1" para="10">Whittington &quot;came up from behind the vice president and the other hunter and didn't signal them or indicate to them or announce himself,&quot; Armstrong said.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="4" line="1" para="11">&quot;The vice president didn't see him,&quot; she continued.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="4" line="2" para="11">&quot;The covey flushed and the vice president picked out a bird and was following it and shot.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="4" line="3" para="11">And by god, Harry was in the line of fire and got peppered pretty good.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence doc="4" line="1" para="12">Whittington has been a private practice attorney in Austin since 1950 and has long been active in Texas Republican politics.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="4" line="2" para="12">He has been appointed to several state boards, including when then-Gov.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="4" line="3" para="12">George W. Bush named him to the Texas Funeral Service Commission.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="4" line="1" para="13">Whittington owns property in Travis County, which includes the state capital Austin, worth at least $11 million, the Austin American-Statesman reported last year, not counting a downtown block at the center of a long-running dispute with the city over a condemnation issue.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="4" line="1" para="14">Armstrong, owner of the Armstrong Ranch where the accident occurred, said Whittington was bleeding and Cheney was very apologetic.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="4" line="1" para="15">&quot;It broke the skin,&quot; she said of the shotgun pellets.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="4" line="2" para="15">&quot;It knocked him silly.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="4" line="3" para="15">But he was fine.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="4" line="4" para="15">He was talking.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="4" line="5" para="15">His eyes were open.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="4" line="6" para="15">It didn't get in his eyes or anything like that.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence doc="4" line="1" para="16">&quot;Fortunately, the vice president has got a lot of medical people around him and so they were right there and probably more cautious than we would have been,&quot; she said.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="4" line="2" para="16">&quot;The vice president has got an ambulance on call, so the ambulance came.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence doc="4" line="1" para="17">Cheney is an avid hunter who makes annual hunting trips to South Dakota to hunt pheasants.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="4" line="2" para="17">He also travels frequently to Arkansas to hunt ducks.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="4" line="1" para="18">Armstrong said Cheney is a longtime friend who comes to the ranch to hunt about once a year and is &quot;a very safe sportsman.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence doc="4" line="2" para="18">She said Whittington is a regular, too, but she thought it was the first time the two men hunted together.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="4" line="1" para="19">&quot;This is something that happens from time to time.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="4" line="2" para="19">You now, I've been peppered pretty well myself,&quot; said Armstrong.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="4" line="1" para="20">___</sentence>
		<sentence doc="4" line="1" para="21">Associated Press writer Paul Weber in Dallas contributed to this report.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="1" para="1">Although he broke no laws, Vice President Dick Cheney did not have proper hunting credentials when he accidentally shot a fellow hunter at a private ranch last weekend, authorities said Monday.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="1" para="2">Cheney, an experienced outdoorsman who had a valid out-of-state hunting license, will receive a warning citation for failing to purchase the required $7 stamp for bird hunting, the Texas Department of Parks and Wildlife said in a statement.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="2" para="2">The stamp is a new requirement, and the department has issued verbal warnings to many hunters who were unaware they needed it.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="1" para="3">In a statement Monday night, Cheney's office said his staffers had not known about the stamp requirement and that Cheney had sent a $7 check to Texas to cover the cost.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="1" para="4">The accident occurred Saturday when the vice president wheeled to shoot at a covey of quail and accidentally sprayed his hunting partner, 78-year-old attorney Harry Whittington, with bird shot, authorities said.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="2" para="4">Whittington was moved out of the intensive care unit at a hospital here Monday and reported to be in good spirits.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="1" para="5">``This was a hunting accident,'' said Gilbert San Miguel, chief deputy of the Kenedy County Sheriff's office.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="2" para="5">``There was no alcohol or misconduct.''</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="1" para="6">But the incident has reverberated worldwide: ``Cheney bags a lawyer,'' was the headline in the Glasgow, Scotland-based Herald.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="1" para="7">And it has forced a White House already under fire for secrecy to explain why it made no mention of the shooting until the ranch owner disclosed it to a local newspaper, 18 hours after the incident.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="1" para="8">White House press secretary Scott McClellan said Monday that the ``first priority was making sure that Harry Whittington ... was getting the medical care that he needed.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="2" para="8">And I think that's where everybody's attention should have been focused, and was focused, when the hunting accident took place.''</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="1" para="9">Still, McClellan blamed Whittington for the accident, noting that the attorney left the hunt line to retrieve a downed quail and was approaching Cheney from behind.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="2" para="9">``The protocol was not followed by Mr. Whittington when it came to notifying the others that he was there,'' McClellan said.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="3" para="9">``And so, you know, unfortunately these type of hunting accidents happen from time to time.''</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="1" para="10">But hunting experts said that, although Whittington should have made his location clear, the vice president is also to blame for not keeping track of his companions.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="1" para="11">``You're hunting together -- you need to know where everyone is,'' said Larry Keane, general counsel of the National Shooting Sports Foundation.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="1" para="12">Said Jeff Hart, an Austin lawyer who hunts for quail in Texas: ``If you pull the trigger, you're responsible for it, no matter what.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="2" para="12">...</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="3" para="12">In hunting, the shooter is responsible for knowing where the shot is going.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="4" para="12">That's the bottom line.''</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="1" para="13">Cheney, well-known for having testy relations with the media, on Monday came under criticism from Democrats and Republicans who said the White House should have disclosed the incident immediately.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="1" para="14">``It's news, and it reflects an attitude in this White House of holding back information, of being too clever by half and being secretive,'' conservative columnist Robert Novak said on Fox News.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="1" para="15">``On the face of it, this looks like something the administration felt the public had no right to know,'' Joe Lockhart, who was President Clinton's press secretary, said in an interview.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="2" para="15">``I don't think there's going to be a bunch of people sitting around saying: `I wonder why they waited to tell us.'</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="3" para="15">But what they will be saying is: `I wonder what else they're not telling us.'</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="4" para="15">''</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="1" para="16">Whittington -- a prominent Austin attorney -- and the vice president arrived for a weekend hunting trip Friday night at the 50,000-acre Armstrong ranch, a well-known retreat for wealthy Texas Republicans 95 miles south of Corpus Christi.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="1" para="17">The party of 11 hunters set out in two trucks Saturday morning, driving around the mesquite-dotted property and shooting quail until about 12:30 p.m., said Anne Armstrong, co-owner of the ranch.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="2" para="17">Then they broke for a lunch of antelope, jicama salad and camp bread, washed down with Dr Pepper.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="1" para="18">After lunch, the group split up.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="2" para="18">Cheney, Whittington and Pamela Willeford, a former Texas energy executive who is now the U.S. ambassador to Switzerland, went with two of Armstrong's daughters and pursued quail for several more hours.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="3" para="18">It was at dusk that Whittington shot his bird and went to retrieve it, taking him behind the vice president.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="1" para="19">The medical team that travels with Cheney immediately began ministering to Whittington, who was bleeding profusely from pellets in his face, neck and chest, according to witnesses.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="2" para="19">They packed the wounded attorney into Cheney's ambulance and drove him to a nearby hospital.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="1" para="20">It was evident that the injuries were not life-threatening, Armstrong said, because the ambulance paused on the road for several minutes to allow Whittington's wife to join them.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="1" para="21">After being stabilized at the hospital in Kingsville, Whittington was evacuated by helicopter to a larger facility in Corpus Christi -- where he was placed in the intensive care unit.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="2" para="21">The Secret Service reported the shooting to the Kenedy County sheriff's office, although no one from that agency interviewed Cheney until Sunday morning.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="1" para="22">When asked whether the Secret Service had prevented him from talking to the vice president right after the shooting, San Miguel said: ``I'd rather not say.''</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="1" para="23">Anne Armstrong said that on Saturday evening, Cheney spoke with her about disclosing the incident to the public.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="2" para="23">``We knew word would get out,'' she said.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="3" para="23">The vice president urged her to tell friends and family first, before word leaked out to the media.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="1" para="24">Late Sunday morning, her daughter, Katharine Armstrong, called a reporter from the Corpus Christi Caller, which then reported the shooting on its Web site.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="1" para="25">Peter Binko, administrator of Christos Spohn hospital in Corpus Christi where Whittington was recuperating, said the injured hunter was cracking jokes -- and was baffled by all the publicity.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="2" para="25">``He's a true Southern gentleman,'' Binko said of Whittington at a Monday news conference.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="3" para="25">``He's really amazed, I think, at all the hoopla over this.''</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="1" para="26">Whittington is a fixture in Texas politics, having worked in Republican campaigns dating back to John Tower's senatorial run in the 1960s.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="2" para="26">He's best known nowadays for a decades-long battle to prevent the city of Austin from building a parking lot over a downtown block that he owns.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="3" para="26">The dispute is still being litigated.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="1" para="27">Riccardi reported from Corpus Christi and Gerstenzang from Washington.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="2" para="27">Times staff writers Lianne Hart in Corpus Christi and Peter Wallsten in Washington contributed to this report.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="1" para="1">The White House on Monday carefully distanced itself from Vice President Dick Cheney's delayed notification about his accidental shooting of a hunting companion.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="1" para="2">White House Press Secretary McClellan said he had privately urged Cheney's staff to quickly disclose details about the 5:30 p.m. CST accident on Saturday rather than wait for the Texas ranch owner to telephone the local newspaper more than 18 hours later, on Sunday.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="2" para="2">McClellan said he was informed late Saturday night that there had been a hunting accident but didn't learn that Cheney had shot the victim until 6 a.m. EST Sunday.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="1" para="3">McClellan said President Bush learned there had been a hunting accident from White House Chief of Staff Andrew Card about 7:30 p.m. EST Saturday and learned that Cheney had been the shooter shortly before 8 p.m. EST when updated by Deputy White House Chief of Staff Karl Rove.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="1" para="4">Cheney's staff did not publicly confirm the accidental shooting until 3:30 p.m. EST on Sunday, more than 20 hours after the accident, when the Corpus Christi Caller-Times posted a story on its Web site.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="1" para="5">McClellan said spoke with Katharine Armstrong, one of the ranch owners and an eyewitness to the accident, and she agreed to relay word of the accident to the local newspaper on Sunday.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="1" para="6">McClellan said he had urged speedy public disclosure following the incident at the 50,000-acre Armstrong Ranch some 60 miles outside Corpus Christi, Texas.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="1" para="7">&quot;I think it's always important to get information out as quickly as possible,&quot; McClellan said.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="2" para="7">&quot;Of course in a position like mine, I was urging that that information be made available as quickly as possible.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="1" para="8">McClellan attributed some of the delay to Cheney's aides trying to &quot;get the facts together (to) provide that information to the public&quot; as well as making sure that Cheney's victim, 78-year-old Texas lawyer Harry Whittington, had adequate medical attention.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="1" para="9">But McClellan sought to deflect criticism about the slow disclosure by suggesting that Cheney's staff was responsible.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="1" para="10">&quot;It was the vice president's office that took the lead on this,&quot; he said, when asked about whether he had been told that Cheney's staff was relying on a private citizen to report the accident.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="1" para="11">Whittington, an Austin lawyer, was listed Monday in &quot;very stable&quot; condition at Christus Spohn Hospital Memorial in Corpus Christi, Texas, where he was undergoing treatment for multiple pellet wounds on the right side of his lower face, neck, shoulder and chest.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="2" para="11">Hospital administrator Peter Banko said Whittington was moved out of intensive care on Monday.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="1" para="12">Cheney, 65, was using a .28 gauge shotgun when he accidentally peppered Whittington with bird shot at a distance of about 30 yards while trying to shoot flushed quail.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="2" para="12">The Corpus Christi Caller-Times reported Monday that Cheney and Whittington had been hunting with Pam Willeford, the U.S. ambassador to Switzerland and Liechtenstein who had served for eight years on the Texas Higher Education Coordinating Board.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="1" para="13">The vice president's office did not publicly report the accident until mid-afternoon Sunday after the Corpus Christi Caller-Times had asked about it.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="1" para="14">McClellan contrasted the delayed notification by a private citizen with his own quick actions last July when he notified the news media that Bush had collided with a member of his Scottish security detail while bicycling in Scotland during an international summit.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="1" para="15">McClellan immediately disclosed that Bush had suffered &quot;mild to moderate&quot; scrapes on his arms and hands that required bandages by the White House physician.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="1" para="16">McClellan, drawing a distinction with the response by Cheney's staff, told reporters Monday: &quot;I think you can always look back at these issues and look at how to do a better job.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="1" para="17">OPTIONAL TRIM -- STORY MAY END HERE</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="1" para="18">McClellan and the Corpus Christi Caller-Times provided the following timeline:</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="1" para="19">Saturday, Feb. 11:</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="1" para="20">5:30 p.m. CST -- Cheney accidentally shoots Whittington.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="2" para="20">He is flown by helicopter to a hospital in Corpus Christi and admitted to the trauma-intensive care unit.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="1" para="21">7:30 p.m. EST -- White House Chief of Staff Andrew Card in Washington alerts Bush at the White House about an unspecified shooting accident within Cheney's quail hunting party but does not specify that Cheney was the shooter.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="1" para="22">8 p.m. EST -- Deputy White House Chief of Staff Karl Rove updates Bush, telling the president that Cheney was the shooter.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="1" para="23">Sunday, Feb. 12:</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="1" para="24">6 a.m. EST -- McClellan is awakened at home and told that Cheney was the shooter.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="2" para="24">He says he began urging vice presidential staff to release details of the incident.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="1" para="25">Sunday morning -- Katharine Armstrong, the host and an eyewitness to the accident, says she and her mother, former U.S.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="2" para="25">Ambassador to Britain Anne Armstrong, ask Cheney about notifying the news media.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="1" para="26">&quot;The vice president spoke with (Katharine Armstrong) directly and agreed that she should make it public and that they would provide additional information,&quot; McClellan said.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="1" para="27">Katharine Armstrong starts trying to telephone Jaime Powell, a reporter at the Corpus Christi Caller Times, to describe the accident.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="1" para="28">Asked whether it was appropriate to have a private citizen relay information about the vice president, McClellan quipped: &quot;That's one way to provide information to the public.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="1" para="29">Sunday morning -- Cheney talks by telephone with Merce Whittington, Whittington's wife, to check on the victim's condition.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="1" para="30">Sunday afternoon -- Cheney visits Whittington at the Corpus Christi hospital before returning to Washington, D.C.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="1" para="31">3:30 p.m. EST -- News organizations confirm the Corpus Christi Caller-Times account with vice president's office at the White House.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="1" para="32">Monday morning -- Cheney arrives at the White House complex in his motorcade, with escorting police vehicles forgoing the usual sirens.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="2" para="32">He ducks from his limousine into the White House wearing a black jacket with the collar raised against the early morning chill.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="1" para="33">Armstrong did not immediately return a telephone call seeking additional comment.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="1" para="34">She told the Corpus Christi Caller Times that Whittington had come up behind Cheney without alerting him that he was here.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="2" para="34">&quot;The reason that you stay in line is so that you know where everybody is at all times,&quot; Armstrong told the newspaper.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="3" para="34">&quot;If you drop out of line, you say you are coming up behind to indicate to other shooters so (they) know you are there.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="1" para="35">(Stewart M. Powell can be reached at 202-263-6400 or at the e-mail address (stewart@hearstdc.com)</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="1" para="1">The White House sought with little success on Monday to quell an uproar over why it took the better part of a day to disclose that Vice President Dick Cheney had accidentally wounded a fellow hunter in Texas on Saturday and why even President Bush initially got an incomplete report on the shooting.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="1" para="2">The victim, Harry Whittington, a 78-year-old lawyer, was transferred from the intensive care unit to a private room in a Corpus Christi hospital on Monday.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="2" para="2">His condition remained listed as stable, with wounds to his face, neck, chest and rib cage from the pellets sprayed at him from 30 yards away by Cheney's shotgun.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="1" para="3">Calls to his room were routed to the hospital's marketing department, which said it was taking messages for him.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="2" para="3">Texas officials said on Monday night that Cheney would be issued a warning citation for hunting without a proper game stamp on his license.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="3" para="3">The local sheriff said an investigation had concluded that the episode was &quot;no more than an accident.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="1" para="4">At the White House, Cheney made no statement and remained out of public view on Monday.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="2" para="4">At the end of a meeting with U.N. Secretary-General Kofi Annan, Cheney and Bush exchanged remarks that reporters were about to enter the room, and the vice president left before the journalists arrived.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="1" para="5">But Scott McClellan, the White House press secretary, was battered at his daily news briefing by journalists demanding answers to why Cheney had not been faster to make public what happened and why he had chosen a local newspaper in Texas as his vehicle for doing so.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="1" para="6">The pressure came in part from questions about whether Cheney might have been trying to play down the incident, a suggestion that was rejected by those who were with Cheney over the weekend.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="1" para="7">Among the people with him at the Armstrong Ranch in south Texas was his host Katharine Armstrong, a lobbyist and longtime friend of Cheney.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="2" para="7">Her lobbying clients include several that do business with the federal government, though Armstrong said she did not believe that she had ever lobbied Cheney.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="1" para="8">In an interview, Armstrong said that it did not occur to anyone in the hunting party to make news of the shooting public immediately, but that no one, including Cheney, had called for holding it back.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="2" para="8">She said Cheney participated in discussions on Sunday morning about disclosing the incident, agreeing that it should be made public but deferring to the Armstrong family on how to do so.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="1" para="9">On Sunday morning, Armstrong tipped off her local newspaper to the story.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="2" para="9">It was later picked up by national wire services and confirmed by Cheney's office.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="1" para="10">The incident provided a wealth of material for Democrats, gun control activists and critics of the Bush administration, not to mention late night comedians.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="1" para="11">McClellan struggled at times to explain even the most basic details in the case, including when and how Bush was informed about it.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="1" para="12">In the end, White House officials said Bush learned about the shooting accident at 7:30 p.m. Eastern time, about an hour after it happened, in a call from Andrew H. Card Jr., his chief of staff.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="2" para="12">But Bush did not find out that Cheney was the shooter until about half an hour later in a subsequent call from Karl Rove, his senior adviser and deputy chief of staff, who had called Armstrong to ask about the incident.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="1" para="13">The local sheriff, Ramon Salinas 3rd, said the Secret Service called him shortly after the shooting occurred.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="1" para="14">Salinas said he sent his chief deputy, Gilbert Sanmiguel, to the Armstrong ranch that night.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="2" para="14">He said Sanmiguel interviewed the Cheney and reported that shooting was an accident.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="1" para="15">The sheriff said Sunday that they had yet to speak to &quot;the victim.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="2" para="15">&quot;But you could say it's closed,&quot; Salinas said of the case.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="1" para="16">On Monday, a news release from the sheriff's office said that &quot; Whittington's interview collaborated Vice President Cheney's statement&quot; and that the department was &quot;fully satisfied that this was no more than a hunting accident.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="1" para="17">There is no requirement to report nonfatal hunting accidents in Texas, said Lydia Saldana, the communications director for the Texas Parks and Wildlife Department.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="1" para="18">In a statement on Monday night, Cheney's office said a member of his staff had asked the Parks and Wildlife Department for all of the necessary permits for the vice president to go quail hunting in Texas and had paid $140.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="2" para="18">But, the statement said, the staff member was not informed of the need for an additional stamp, costing $7, to allow hunting of upland game birds.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="1" para="19">The statement said Cheney has now sent a $7 check to the department.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="1" para="20">Cheney has often gone hunting as vice president, sometimes with other prominent officials, including Justice Antonin Scalia.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="2" para="20">During the 2004 presidential campaign, Cheney mocked Sen. John Kerry, the Democratic nominee, for having worn camouflage on a duck-hunting trip, saying Kerry's &quot;new camo jacket is an October disguise, an effort he's making to hide the fact that he votes against gun-owner rights at every turn.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="1" para="21">(BEGIN OPTIONAL TRIM.)</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="1" para="22">This past weekend brought Cheney together with a group of old friends, friends of friends and political supporters in the kind of private setting he relishes.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="2" para="22">The guests included Pamela Pitzer Willeford, a Texan who was appointed ambassador to Switzerland and Liechtenstein in 2003.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="3" para="22">She was with Cheney at the time of the shooting, as was Armstrong, whose mother, Anne, is a prominent Republican supporter and whose family ranch is a familiar destination for Republican politicians.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="1" para="23">According to public documents, Armstrong registered in 2004 as a lobbyist for Parsons, an engineering and construction firm that has done extensive work in Iraq, and listed the size of the contract at more than $100,000, according to lobbying records from the Texas Ethics Commission provided by Texans for Public Justice, a watchdog group.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="1" para="24">Armstrong's business partner, Karen Johnson, spent several years lobbying for Parsons, doing work on &quot;business development&quot; before the State Department, the Department of Transportation and the U.S. Agency for International Development, according to PoliticalMoneyLine, which tracks federal lobbying.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="2" para="24">Johnson also lobbies for major corporations, including Lockheed Martin, and has been one of Bush's leading fund-raisers.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="1" para="25">Armstrong has a relatively limited list of lobbying clients in Texas and in Washington.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="2" para="25">Public records show that she has worked for Baker Botts, the law firm; Prionics AG, a biotechnology company; Trajen, a firm that performs aviation technical support for the U.S. military; and the King ranch, the property next to her family's ranch.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="1" para="26">Records in Texas indicate that she has lobbied at the state level for three companies: Avex Group, the Dannenbaum Engineering Corporation and Ecocreto USA.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="1" para="27">Armstrong played down her role as a lobbyist and suggested that she had not brought up business during Cheney's visit.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="2" para="27">She was appointed to the Texas Parks and Wildlife Commission in 1999 by Bush, who was then the Texas governor.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="1" para="28">&quot;You need to understand that the Cheneys are our friends maybe for a couple of decades, maybe 30 years,&quot; Armstrong said, adding that she did not personally represent Parsons.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="2" para="28">&quot;I represent a couple of Texas companies, not a large lobbying practice,&quot; she said.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="1" para="29">Armstrong said she does more public relations and consulting work than lobbying, but she declined to disclose her clients.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="2" para="29">She none were involved in Iraq &quot;that I know of.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="1" para="30">Asked if she was concerned that Cheney's visit could create the appearance of impropriety during the lobbying investigation involving Jack Abramoff, which has brought to light the often close personal and professional ties between lobbyists and public officials, she said: &quot;Oh my God, he's a friend.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="2" para="30">I don't believe I've ever lobbied the vice president, nor would I be comfortable doing so.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="1" para="31">(END OPTIONAL TRIM.)</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="1" para="32">According to Armstrong and Willeford, the accident was largely the fault of Whittington, who reappeared alongside two of his hunting companions without giving proper warning.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="2" para="32">Cheney, who was carrying a 28-gauge shotgun, had already begun to fire and sprayed Whittington.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="1" para="33">&quot;He got peppered pretty good,&quot; Armstrong said.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="2" para="33">&quot;He fell with his head toward me.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="3" para="33">She said she ran over to Whittington, who had fallen to the ground, but stayed out of the way while Secret Service agents tended to him.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="1" para="34">&quot;There was some bleeding, but it wasn't horrible,&quot; she said.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="2" para="34">&quot;He was more bruised.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="1" para="35">Willeford, whose husband was also at the ranch, said in an interview that Whittington accepted responsibility for the accident.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="1" para="36">&quot;He understands that he could have handled it better,&quot; Willeford said.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="2" para="36">&quot;Harry should have let us know he was back there.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="1" para="37">Willeford and her husband are substantial Republican donors; they gave more than $11,000 to Republican causes, including the Bush campaign and the Republican National Committee, in the 2004 election cycle.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="8" line="1" para="1">The man accidentally shot by US  Vice President Dick Cheney while the two were hunting on a southern  Texas ranch is in stable condition, a hospital spokeswoman said  Monday.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="8" line="1" para="2">Harry Whittington, 78, was peppered with shotgun pellets after  Cheney turned to shoot quail that had just been flushed out of the  brush, Cheney spokeswoman Lea Anne McBride confirmed Sunday.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="8" line="1" para="3">&quot;He remains in stable condition in our ICU (intensive care  unit),&quot; Michele Mora-Trevino, a spokeswoman for Christus Spohn  Hospital Memorial in Corpus Christi, Texas told AFP.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="8" line="1" para="4">&quot;The area affected was his shoulder, upper body, chest and some  of the neck area,&quot; she said.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="8" line="1" para="5">&quot;It was like a spraying.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="8" line="2" para="5">It wasn't a direct hit.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence doc="8" line="1" para="6">Whittington was admitted at 8:15 pm on Saturday following the  accident and remained in the intensive care unit on Monday morning.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="8" line="1" para="7">&quot;He's in good health, he's doing well,&quot; Mora-Trevino said,  adding that a release date had not yet been set for the prominent  Texas lawyer.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="9" line="1" para="1">The White House drew fire  Monday for not immediately disclosing that Vice President Dick  Cheney had shot a 78-year-old hunting partner in a weekend incident  not reported until a day after it took place.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="9" line="1" para="2">There was still no official account of the events on Katherine  Armstrong's south-Texas ranch on Saturday, when Cheney missed his  quail quarry but hit prominent lawyer Harry Whittington in the neck  and chest with birdshot.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="9" line="1" para="3">And Bush spokesman Scott McClellan battled criticism over the  decision by Cheney's office to let Armstrong -- a private citizen  with no official White House role -- make the news public by  informing her local newspaper.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="9" line="1" para="4">&quot;I think you can always look back at these issues and look at  how to do a better job,&quot; mused McClellan, who said he had advocated  full disclosure and left little doubt that he would have handled the  situation differently.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="9" line="1" para="5">Bush knew an hour after the fact that a hunting accident had  taken place at 5:30 pm (2330 GMT), and it took him another 30  minutes to find out that Cheney had pulled the trigger, said  McClellan.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="9" line="1" para="6">Breaking with precedent, the White House did not disclose the  information to the national media that cover Bush and Cheney.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="9" line="2" para="6">The  news first came to light on Sunday at 1:48 pm (1948 GMT), when the  Corpus Christi Caller-Times published Armstrong's account on its  Internet site.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="9" line="1" para="7">Cheney and Armstrong &quot;agreed that she should make that  information public.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="9" line="2" para="7">She was an eyewitness, she saw what occurred  and she called her local paper to provide those facts,&quot; said  McClellan.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="9" line="1" para="8">Whittington was in stable condition in the intensive care unit  at Christus Spohn Hospital Memorial, were he was treated for wounds  to his shoulder, upper body, chest and neck, said hospital  spokeswoman Michele Mora-Trevino.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="9" line="1" para="9">Cheney aides continued to decline requests for an official  timeline and details of the incident, pointing reporters to  Armstrong's account and vouching for its accuracy.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="9" line="1" para="10">McClellan as well as Cheney spokeswoman Lea Anne McBride  insisted that the time gap between the incident and its confirmation  by the White House was due to a focus on getting Whittington the  medical care he needed.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="9" line="1" para="11">McClellan also said that details about the shooting were  trickling in throughout the night and that the White House needed  &quot;to get the facts together.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence doc="9" line="1" para="12">&quot;It was an accident.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="9" line="2" para="12">Unfortunately, these types of hunting  accidents do happen from time to time,&quot; the spokesman told a  frequently contentious briefing with reporters.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="9" line="1" para="13">Asked why getting Whittington medical attention was incompatible  with releasing details of the incident, McClellan said that the vice  president's office had &quot;worked to get that information out.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence doc="9" line="1" para="14">But the Caller-Times reported Monday that McBride, after  confirming the incident around noon (1800 GMT) on Sunday, had  refused to say whether the vice president's office would have  disclosed the incident if the daily had not contacted her after  getting a tip from an unnamed Armstrong family member.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="9" line="1" para="15">&quot;I'm not going to speculate,&quot; the daily quoted her as saying.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="9" line="2" para="15">&quot;When you put the call into me, I was able to confirm that  account.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence doc="9" line="1" para="16">Armstrong has said that Whittington came up noiselessly behind  the vice president, who spun around to target a bird and shot his  fellow hunter instead.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="9" line="1" para="17">The incident made the front pages of The Washington Post, The  New York Times, USA Today and The Wall Street Journal, most of which  noted soberly that Cheney's office had not gone public with the  information when it happened.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="9" line="1" para="18">Late-night talk show hosts, who typically mine such incidents  for laughs, were not broadcasting over the weekend, making Monday  night the first time they will be able to train their sights on the  mishap.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="10" line="1" para="1">US Vice President Dick Cheney  did not have a legal permit to hunt quail when he accidentally shot  a 78-year old hunting partner over the weekend, the White House said  on Monday.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="10" line="1" para="2">The Texas Parks and Wildlife Department informed Cheney that he  lacked a stamp for hunting &quot;upland game birds&quot; in the state when the  shooting incident occurred, the vice president's office said in a  statement.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="10" line="1" para="3">Texas authorities said they would issue a warning citation to  Cheney but impose no penalty or fine for failing to have the  seven-dollar stamp.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="10" line="1" para="4">The revelation was sure to aggravate a public relations headache  for the White House, already under criticism for waiting a day to  disclose the shooting incident.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="10" line="1" para="5">Cheney shot prominent lawyer Harry Whittington in the neck and  chest with birdshot on Saturday as the two were out quail hunting on  a Texas ranch.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="10" line="1" para="6">Whittington's condition was improving and described as &quot;stable&quot;  by doctors at Christus Spohn Hospital Memorial, where he was treated  for wounds to his shoulder, upper body, chest and neck.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="10" line="1" para="7">News of the shooting was first revealed not by the White House  but by the owner of the south-Texas ranch, Katharine Armstrong,  where the incident took place.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="10" line="2" para="7">Armstrong spoke to the local  newspaper, the Corpus Christi Caller-Times, which had called her  after getting a tip.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="10" line="1" para="8">President George W. Bush's spokesman Scott McClellan as well as  Cheney spokeswoman Lea Anne McBride insisted that the delay between  the incident and its confirmation by the White House was due to a  focus on securing Whittington medical care.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="10" line="1" para="9">McClellan also said that details about the shooting were  trickling in throughout the night and that the White House needed  &quot;to get the facts together.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence doc="10" line="1" para="10">&quot;It was an accident.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="10" line="2" para="10">Unfortunately, these types of hunting  accidents do happen from time to time,&quot; the spokesman told a  frequently contentious briefing with reporters.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="10" line="1" para="11">Asked why getting Whittington medical attention was incompatible  with releasing details of the incident, McClellan said that the vice  president's office had &quot;worked to get that information out.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence doc="10" line="1" para="12">But the Caller-Times reported Monday that McBride, after  confirming the incident around noon (1800 GMT) on Sunday, had  refused to say whether the vice president's office would have  disclosed the incident if the daily had not contacted her after  getting a tip from an unnamed Armstrong family member.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="10" line="1" para="13">&quot;I'm not going to speculate,&quot; the daily quoted her as saying.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="10" line="1" para="14">Confirming Armstrong's account, local police and state game  officials said the vice president had spun around to target a bird  and shot his fellow hunter instead.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="10" line="1" para="15">&quot;The investigation reveals that there was no alcohol, or  misconduct involved in the incident,&quot; the Kenedy County sheriff's  office said in a statement.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="10" line="1" para="16">An interview with Whittington had confirmed Cheney's account,  the sheriff's office said.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="10" line="1" para="17">The Caller-Times also reported Monday that the US ambassador to  Switzerland and Liechtenstein, Pamela Willeford, was part of the  hunting party.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="10" line="1" para="18">An incident report by the Texas Parks and Wildlife Department  said that Whittington had gone to retrieve a downed bird when Cheney  wheeled around with his 28-gauge Perazzi shotgun and shot him by  accident.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="10" line="1" para="19">The weather was sunny and &quot;clear&quot; when the accident occurred and  both men were wearing blaze orange hats and vests, the report said.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="10" line="1" para="20">The Dallas Morning News reported that Whittington also lacked  the proper stamp for hunting quail.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="10" line="1" para="21">Gaming officials said they had been issuing oral warnings  instead of fines to hunters who had failed to update their licenses  under the new rule.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="10" line="1" para="22">Cheney's staff members had asked state authorities for all  necessary permits beforehand and were never informed about the need  for a seven-dollar stamp for quail hunting, his office said in its  statement.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="10" line="1" para="23">While awaiting a warning from game wardens, &quot;the Vice President  has sent a 7 dollar check to the Texas Parks and Wildlife  Department, which is the cost of an upland game bird stamp,&quot; it  said.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="10" line="1" para="24">The incident made the front pages of The Washington Post, The  New York Times, USA Today and The Wall Street Journal, most of which  noted soberly that Cheney's office had not gone public with the  information when it happened.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="10" line="1" para="25">Late-night talk show hosts, who typically mine such incidents  for laughs, were not broadcasting over the weekend, making Monday  night the first time they will be able to train their sights on the  mishap.</sentence>
	</Sentences>
	<Words>
		<word count="142" text="wa"/>
		<word count="121" text="cheney"/>
		<word count="106" text="said"/>
		<word count="87" text="``"/>
		<word count="87" text="''"/>
		<word count="79" text="'s"/>
		<word count="79" text="whittington"/>
		<word count="73" text="armstrong"/>
		<word count="66" text="for"/>
		<word count="63" text="on"/>
		<word count="58" text="presid"/>
		<word count="58" text="with"/>
		<word count="57" text="hunt"/>
		<word count="57" text="the"/>
		<word count="55" text="had"/>
		<word count="51" text="at"/>
		<word count="50" text="vice"/>
		<word count="49" text="texa"/>
		<word count="49" text="hi"/>
		<word count="48" text="he"/>
		<word count="43" text="by"/>
		<word count="43" text="she"/>
		<word count="42" text="it"/>
		<word count="41" text="not"/>
		<word count="38" text="from"/>
		<word count="37" text="shoot"/>
		<word count="37" text="an"/>
		<word count="35" text="report"/>
		<word count="35" text="accid"/>
		<word count="33" text="white"/>
		<word count="33" text="hous"/>
		<word count="31" text="ranch"/>
		<word count="31" text="incid"/>
		<word count="30" text="about"/>
		<word count="30" text="who"/>
		<word count="30" text="mcclellan"/>
		<word count="29" text="as"/>
		<word count="29" text="is"/>
		<word count="28" text="corpu"/>
		<word count="28" text="christi"/>
		<word count="27" text="monday"/>
		<word count="26" text="sunday"/>
		<word count="26" text="when"/>
		<word count="26" text="but"/>
		<word count="25" text="shot"/>
		<word count="25" text="hospit"/>
		<word count="25" text="bush"/>
		<word count="24" text="ha"/>
		<word count="23" text="offic"/>
		<word count="23" text="He"/>
		<word count="23" text="time"/>
		<word count="22" text="quail"/>
		<word count="22" text="after"/>
		<word count="21" text="did"/>
		<word count="21" text="were"/>
		<word count="21" text="public"/>
		<word count="19" text="be"/>
		<word count="19" text="her"/>
		<word count="19" text="been"/>
		<word count="19" text="have"/>
		<word count="19" text="I"/>
		<word count="19" text="you"/>
		<word count="19" text="inform"/>
		<word count="18" text="out"/>
		<word count="17" text="saturday"/>
		<word count="17" text="staff"/>
		<word count="17" text="hunter"/>
		<word count="17" text="him"/>
		<word count="17" text="--"/>
		<word count="16" text="bird"/>
		<word count="16" text="get"/>
		<word count="16" text="they"/>
		<word count="15" text="chest"/>
		<word count="15" text="confirm"/>
		<word count="15" text="say"/>
		<word count="15" text="It"/>
		<word count="15" text="do"/>
		<word count="15" text="no"/>
		<word count="14" text="accident"/>
		<word count="14" text="harri"/>
		<word count="14" text="care"/>
		<word count="14" text="disclos"/>
		<word count="13" text="which"/>
		<word count="13" text="make"/>
		<word count="13" text="more"/>
		<word count="13" text="n't"/>
		<word count="13" text="local"/>
		<word count="13" text="caller-tim"/>
		<word count="13" text="ask"/>
		<word count="13" text="call"/>
		<word count="13" text="there"/>
		<word count="12" text="neck"/>
		<word count="12" text="austin"/>
		<word count="12" text="katharin"/>
		<word count="12" text="shotgun"/>
		<word count="12" text="depart"/>
		<word count="12" text="lobbi"/>
		<word count="11" text="while"/>
		<word count="11" text="lawyer"/>
		<word count="11" text="medic"/>
		<word count="11" text="happen"/>
		<word count="11" text="than"/>
		<word count="11" text="until"/>
		<word count="11" text="friend"/>
		<word count="11" text="where"/>
		<word count="11" text="p.m."/>
		<word count="11" text="mcbride"/>
		<word count="11" text="statement"/>
		<word count="11" text="thi"/>
		<word count="11" text="over"/>
		<word count="11" text="night"/>
		<word count="11" text="morn"/>
		<word count="10" text="dick"/>
		<word count="10" text="privat"/>
		<word count="10" text="newspap"/>
		<word count="10" text="occur"/>
		<word count="10" text="detail"/>
		<word count="10" text="condit"/>
		<word count="10" text="owner"/>
		<word count="10" text="told"/>
		<word count="10" text="pellet"/>
		<word count="10" text="accord"/>
		<word count="10" text="hour"/>
		<word count="10" text="ann"/>
		<word count="10" text="or"/>
		<word count="10" text="includ"/>
		<word count="10" text="republican"/>
		<word count="10" text="new"/>
		<word count="10" text="weekend"/>
		<word count="10" text="stamp"/>
		<word count="9" text="one"/>
		<word count="9" text="befor"/>
		<word count="9" text="intens"/>
		<word count="9" text="unit"/>
		<word count="9" text="stabl"/>
		<word count="9" text="chief"/>
		<word count="9" text="press"/>
		<word count="9" text="up"/>
		<word count="9" text="first"/>
		<word count="9" text="spokeswoman"/>
		<word count="9" text="interview"/>
		<word count="9" text="whi"/>
		<word count="9" text="know"/>
		<word count="9" text="would"/>
		<word count="9" text="need"/>
		<word count="9" text="news"/>
		<word count="9" text="offici"/>
		<word count="8" text="covey"/>
		<word count="8" text="line"/>
		<word count="8" text="spohn"/>
		<word count="8" text="hit"/>
		<word count="8" text="washington"/>
		<word count="8" text="pepper"/>
		<word count="8" text="veri"/>
		<word count="8" text="went"/>
		<word count="8" text="look"/>
		<word count="8" text="came"/>
		<word count="8" text="right"/>
		<word count="8" text="account"/>
		<word count="8" text="provid"/>
		<word count="8" text="dure"/>
		<word count="8" text="trip"/>
		<word count="8" text="work"/>
		<word count="8" text="around"/>
		<word count="8" text="so"/>
		<word count="8" text="also"/>
		<word count="8" text="park"/>
		<word count="8" text="sheriff"/>
		<word count="8" text="willeford"/>
		<word count="8" text="est"/>
		<word count="7" text="spray"/>
		<word count="7" text="companion"/>
		<word count="7" text="injur"/>
		<word count="7" text="promin"/>
		<word count="7" text="south"/>
		<word count="7" text="fire"/>
		<word count="7" text="christu"/>
		<word count="7" text="describ"/>
		<word count="7" text="good"/>
		<word count="7" text="2004"/>
		<word count="7" text="member"/>
		<word count="7" text="famili"/>
		<word count="7" text="togeth"/>
		<word count="7" text="two"/>
		<word count="7" text="behind"/>
		<word count="7" text="got"/>
		<word count="7" text="fine"/>
		<word count="7" text="talk"/>
		<word count="7" text="media"/>
		<word count="7" text="fact"/>
		<word count="7" text="servic"/>
		<word count="7" text="go"/>
		<word count="7" text="wound"/>
		<word count="7" text="state"/>
		<word count="7" text="issu"/>
		<word count="7" text="warn"/>
		<word count="7" text="wildlif"/>
		<word count="7" text="made"/>
		<word count="7" text="should"/>
		<word count="7" text="shooter"/>
		<word count="7" text="game"/>
		<word count="6" text="face"/>
		<word count="6" text="what"/>
		<word count="6" text="30"/>
		<word count="6" text="partner"/>
		<word count="6" text="victim"/>
		<word count="6" text="associ"/>
		<word count="6" text="follow"/>
		<word count="6" text="and"/>
		<word count="6" text="critic"/>
		<word count="6" text="In"/>
		<word count="6" text="fellow"/>
		<word count="6" text="u.s."/>
		<word count="6" text="attorney"/>
		<word count="6" text="think"/>
		<word count="6" text="took"/>
		<word count="6" text="immedi"/>
		<word count="6" text="back"/>
		<word count="6" text="whether"/>
		<word count="5" text="birdshot"/>
		<word count="5" text="late"/>
		<word count="5" text="78"/>
		<word count="5" text="treat"/>
		<word count="5" text="travel"/>
		<word count="5" text="list"/>
		<word count="5" text="pretti"/>
		<word count="5" text="nation"/>
		<word count="5" text="tobin"/>
		<word count="5" text="last"/>
		<word count="5" text="former"/>
		<word count="5" text="day"/>
		<word count="5" text="quot"/>
		<word count="5" text="other"/>
		<word count="5" text="them"/>
		<word count="5" text="visit"/>
		<word count="5" text="like"/>
		<word count="5" text="lea"/>
		<word count="5" text="telephon"/>
		<word count="5" text="are"/>
		<word count="5" text="frequent"/>
		<word count="5" text="polit"/>
		<word count="5" text="campaign"/>
		<word count="5" text="administr"/>
		<word count="5" text="john"/>
		<word count="5" text="parti"/>
		<word count="5" text="how"/>
		<word count="5" text="anoth"/>
		<word count="5" text="ambul"/>
		<word count="5" text="sever"/>
		<word count="5" text="year"/>
		<word count="5" text="well"/>
		<word count="5" text="requir"/>
		<word count="5" text="7"/>
		<word count="5" text="deputi"/>
		<word count="5" text="place"/>
		<word count="5" text="down"/>
		<word count="5" text="these"/>
		<word count="5" text="respons"/>
		<word count="5" text="secret"/>
		<word count="5" text="ambassador"/>
		<word count="5" text="urg"/>
		<word count="5" text="all"/>
		<word count="5" text="releas"/>
		<word count="5" text="daili"/>
		<word count="4" text="taken"/>
		<word count="4" text="helicopt"/>
		<word count="4" text="health"/>
		<word count="4" text="even"/>
		<word count="4" text="28-gaug"/>
		<word count="4" text="yard"/>
		<word count="4" text="away"/>
		<word count="4" text="cheek"/>
		<word count="4" text="pick"/>
		<word count="4" text="later"/>
		<word count="4" text="still"/>
		<word count="4" text="longtim"/>
		<word count="4" text="team"/>
		<word count="4" text="octob"/>
		<word count="4" text="funer"/>
		<word count="4" text="their"/>
		<word count="4" text="then"/>
		<word count="4" text="indic"/>
		<word count="4" text="see"/>
		<word count="4" text="flush"/>
		<word count="4" text="side"/>
		<word count="4" text="apologet"/>
		<word count="4" text="broke"/>
		<word count="4" text="eye"/>
		<word count="4" text="5:30"/>
		<word count="4" text="alway"/>
		<word count="4" text="own"/>
		<word count="4" text="licens"/>
		<word count="4" text="georg"/>
		<word count="4" text="W."/>
		<word count="4" text="most"/>
		<word count="4" text="appoint"/>
		<word count="4" text="commiss"/>
		<word count="4" text="democrat"/>
		<word count="4" text="jacket"/>
		<word count="4" text="alert"/>
		<word count="4" text="wife"/>
		<word count="4" text="bleed"/>
		<word count="4" text="properti"/>
		<word count="4" text="arriv"/>
		<word count="4" text="counti"/>
		<word count="4" text="proper"/>
		<word count="4" text="author"/>
		<word count="4" text="will"/>
		<word count="4" text="sent"/>
		<word count="4" text="check"/>
		<word count="4" text="78-year-old"/>
		<word count="4" text="under"/>
		<word count="4" text="secretari"/>
		<word count="4" text="scott"/>
		<word count="4" text="attent"/>
		<word count="4" text="tell"/>
		<word count="4" text="group"/>
		<word count="4" text="switzerland"/>
		<word count="4" text="spoke"/>
		<word count="4" text="delay"/>
		<word count="4" text="learn"/>
		<word count="4" text="agre"/>
		<word count="4" text="some"/>
		<word count="4" text="tri"/>
		<word count="4" text="citizen"/>
		<word count="4" text="memori"/>
		<word count="4" text="shoulder"/>
		<word count="4" text="better"/>
		<word count="4" text="end"/>
		<word count="4" text="host"/>
		<word count="4" text="remain"/>
		<word count="4" text="lobbyist"/>
		<word count="4" text="busi"/>
		<word count="4" text="tip"/>
		<word count="4" text="gone"/>
		<word count="4" text="spokesman"/>
		<word count="4" text="gmt"/>
		<word count="3" text="afternoon"/>
		<word count="3" text="system"/>
		<word count="3" text="use"/>
		<word count="3" text="target"/>
		<word count="3" text="long"/>
		<word count="3" text="close"/>
		<word count="3" text="board"/>
		<word count="3" text="grass"/>
		<word count="3" text="both"/>
		<word count="3" text="men"/>
		<word count="3" text="wear"/>
		<word count="3" text="announc"/>
		<word count="3" text="god"/>
		<word count="3" text="mostli"/>
		<word count="3" text="contact"/>
		<word count="3" text="we"/>
		<word count="3" text="return"/>
		<word count="3" text="mention"/>
		<word count="3" text="justic"/>
		<word count="3" text="scalia"/>
		<word count="3" text="duck"/>
		<word count="3" text="becaus"/>
		<word count="3" text="turn"/>
		<word count="3" text="our"/>
		<word count="3" text="50,000-acr"/>
		<word count="3" text="known"/>
		<word count="3" text="way"/>
		<word count="3" text="presidenti"/>
		<word count="3" text="kerri"/>
		<word count="3" text="wonder"/>
		<word count="3" text="just"/>
		<word count="3" text="often"/>
		<word count="3" text="doe"/>
		<word count="3" text="person"/>
		<word count="3" text="..."/>
		<word count="3" text="second"/>
		<word count="3" text="ad"/>
		<word count="3" text="vehicl"/>
		<word count="3" text="11"/>
		<word count="3" text="peopl"/>
		<word count="3" text="come"/>
		<word count="3" text="now"/>
		<word count="3" text="although"/>
		<word count="3" text="citat"/>
		<word count="3" text="fail"/>
		<word count="3" text="cost"/>
		<word count="3" text="here"/>
		<word count="3" text="kenedi"/>
		<word count="3" text="alreadi"/>
		<word count="3" text="sure"/>
		<word count="3" text="note"/>
		<word count="3" text="left"/>
		<word count="3" text="retriev"/>
		<word count="3" text="notifi"/>
		<word count="3" text="unfortun"/>
		<word count="3" text="type"/>
		<word count="3" text="'re"/>
		<word count="3" text="relat"/>
		<word count="3" text="On"/>
		<word count="3" text="wait"/>
		<word count="3" text="us"/>
		<word count="3" text="set"/>
		<word count="3" text="pamela"/>
		<word count="3" text="into"/>
		<word count="3" text="word"/>
		<word count="3" text="caller"/>
		<word count="3" text="site"/>
		<word count="3" text="peter"/>
		<word count="3" text="quickli"/>
		<word count="3" text="andrew"/>
		<word count="3" text="card"/>
		<word count="3" text="7:30"/>
		<word count="3" text="updat"/>
		<word count="3" text="karl"/>
		<word count="3" text="rove"/>
		<word count="3" text="post"/>
		<word count="3" text="stori"/>
		<word count="3" text="eyewit"/>
		<word count="3" text="disclosur"/>
		<word count="3" text="mine"/>
		<word count="3" text="suggest"/>
		<word count="3" text="liechtenstein"/>
		<word count="3" text="can"/>
		<word count="3" text="option"/>
		<word count="3" text="trim"/>
		<word count="3" text="addit"/>
		<word count="3" text="without"/>
		<word count="3" text="part"/>
		<word count="3" text="room"/>
		<word count="3" text="investig"/>
		<word count="3" text="brief"/>
		<word count="3" text="client"/>
		<word count="3" text="salina"/>
		<word count="3" text="could"/>
		<word count="3" text="permit"/>
		<word count="3" text="upland"/>
		<word count="3" text="brought"/>
		<word count="3" text="support"/>
		<word count="3" text="whose"/>
		<word count="3" text="parson"/>
		<word count="3" text="firm"/>
		<word count="3" text="record"/>
		<word count="3" text="show"/>
		<word count="3" text="compani"/>
		<word count="3" text="usa"/>
		<word count="3" text="involv"/>
		<word count="3" text="if"/>
		<word count="3" text="between"/>
		<word count="3" text="US"/>
		<word count="3" text="mora-trevino"/>
		<word count="3" text="upper"/>
		<word count="3" text="bodi"/>
		<word count="3" text="pm"/>
		<word count="3" text="abl"/>
		<word count="3" text="instead"/>
		<word count="2" text="man"/>
		<word count="2" text="yesterday"/>
		<word count="2" text="saw"/>
		<word count="2" text="nearli"/>
		<word count="2" text="20"/>
		<word count="2" text="head"/>
		<word count="2" text="ground"/>
		<word count="2" text="thought"/>
		<word count="2" text="address"/>
		<word count="2" text="rifl"/>
		<word count="2" text="accept"/>
		<word count="2" text="co-own"/>
		<word count="2" text="major"/>
		<word count="2" text="die"/>
		<word count="2" text="attend"/>
		<word count="2" text="serv"/>
		<word count="2" text="execut"/>
		<word count="2" text="governor"/>
		<word count="2" text="publish"/>
		<word count="2" text="watch"/>
		<word count="2" text="nearbi"/>
		<word count="2" text="car"/>
		<word count="2" text="orang"/>
		<word count="2" text="vest"/>
		<word count="2" text="signal"/>
		<word count="2" text="himself"/>
		<word count="2" text="skin"/>
		<word count="2" text="refer"/>
		<word count="2" text="knock"/>
		<word count="2" text="silli"/>
		<word count="2" text="open"/>
		<word count="2" text="anyth"/>
		<word count="2" text="question"/>
		<word count="2" text="paper"/>
		<word count="2" text="seek"/>
		<word count="2" text="comment"/>
		<word count="2" text="spirit"/>
		<word count="2" text="suffer"/>
		<word count="2" text="four"/>
		<word count="2" text="heart"/>
		<word count="2" text="elect"/>
		<word count="2" text="antonin"/>
		<word count="2" text="particip"/>
		<word count="2" text="decis"/>
		<word count="2" text="affect"/>
		<word count="2" text="65"/>
		<word count="2" text="H."/>
		<word count="2" text="purchas"/>
		<word count="2" text="activ"/>
		<word count="2" text="mock"/>
		<word count="2" text="nomine"/>
		<word count="2" text="camouflag"/>
		<word count="2" text="realli"/>
		<word count="2" text="camo"/>
		<word count="2" text="disguis"/>
		<word count="2" text="my"/>
		<word count="2" text="cnn"/>
		<word count="2" text="spent"/>
		<word count="2" text="tall"/>
		<word count="2" text="third"/>
		<word count="2" text="walk"/>
		<word count="2" text="spot"/>
		<word count="2" text="tend"/>
		<word count="2" text="continu"/>
		<word count="2" text="practic"/>
		<word count="2" text="downtown"/>
		<word count="2" text="block"/>
		<word count="2" text="disput"/>
		<word count="2" text="citi"/>
		<word count="2" text="lot"/>
		<word count="2" text="too"/>
		<word count="2" text="someth"/>
		<word count="2" text="'ve"/>
		<word count="2" text="writer"/>
		<word count="2" text="dalla"/>
		<word count="2" text="contribut"/>
		<word count="2" text="law"/>
		<word count="2" text="cover"/>
		<word count="2" text="wheel"/>
		<word count="2" text="move"/>
		<word count="2" text="gilbert"/>
		<word count="2" text="san"/>
		<word count="2" text="miguel"/>
		<word count="2" text="alcohol"/>
		<word count="2" text="misconduct"/>
		<word count="2" text="explain"/>
		<word count="2" text="18"/>
		<word count="2" text="everybodi"/>
		<word count="2" text="focus"/>
		<word count="2" text="blame"/>
		<word count="2" text="clear"/>
		<word count="2" text="track"/>
		<word count="2" text="hart"/>
		<word count="2" text="If"/>
		<word count="2" text="pull"/>
		<word count="2" text="trigger"/>
		<word count="2" text="that"/>
		<word count="2" text="well-known"/>
		<word count="2" text="hold"/>
		<word count="2" text="half"/>
		<word count="2" text="`I"/>
		<word count="2" text="mile"/>
		<word count="2" text="lunch"/>
		<word count="2" text="daughter"/>
		<word count="2" text="take"/>
		<word count="2" text="began"/>
		<word count="2" text="minut"/>
		<word count="2" text="allow"/>
		<word count="2" text="agenc"/>
		<word count="2" text="prevent"/>
		<word count="2" text="rather"/>
		<word count="2" text="knew"/>
		<word count="2" text="web"/>
		<word count="2" text="binko"/>
		<word count="2" text="southern"/>
		<word count="2" text="date"/>
		<word count="2" text="battl"/>
		<word count="2" text="distanc"/>
		<word count="2" text="notif"/>
		<word count="2" text="cst"/>
		<word count="2" text="6"/>
		<word count="2" text="a.m."/>
		<word count="2" text="shortli"/>
		<word count="2" text="8"/>
		<word count="2" text="publicli"/>
		<word count="2" text="3:30"/>
		<word count="2" text="relay"/>
		<word count="2" text="possibl"/>
		<word count="2" text="aid"/>
		<word count="2" text="sought"/>
		<word count="2" text="lead"/>
		<word count="2" text="secur"/>
		<word count="2" text="intern"/>
		<word count="2" text="job"/>
		<word count="2" text="timelin"/>
		<word count="2" text="feb."/>
		<word count="2" text="admit"/>
		<word count="2" text="mother"/>
		<word count="2" text="powel"/>
		<word count="2" text="polic"/>
		<word count="2" text="against"/>
		<word count="2" text="stay"/>
		<word count="2" text="stewart"/>
		<word count="2" text="littl"/>
		<word count="2" text="At"/>
		<word count="2" text="journalist"/>
		<word count="2" text="play"/>
		<word count="2" text="those"/>
		<word count="2" text="feder"/>
		<word count="2" text="believ"/>
		<word count="2" text="ever"/>
		<word count="2" text="case"/>
		<word count="2" text="find"/>
		<word count="2" text="sanmiguel"/>
		<word count="2" text="yet"/>
		<word count="2" text="necessari"/>
		<word count="2" text="old"/>
		<word count="2" text="texan"/>
		<word count="2" text="engin"/>
		<word count="2" text="iraq"/>
		<word count="2" text="johnson"/>
		<word count="2" text="develop"/>
		<word count="2" text="corpor"/>
		<word count="2" text="role"/>
		<word count="2" text="understand"/>
		<word count="2" text="mayb"/>
		<word count="2" text="coupl"/>
		<word count="2" text="repres"/>
		<word count="2" text="larg"/>
		<word count="2" text="declin"/>
		<word count="2" text="light"/>
		<word count="2" text="me"/>
		<word count="2" text="husband"/>
		<word count="2" text="handl"/>
		<word count="2" text="let"/>
		<word count="2" text="michel"/>
		<word count="2" text="area"/>
		<word count="2" text="south-texa"/>
		<word count="2" text="insist"/>
		<word count="2" text="due"/>
		<word count="2" text="focu"/>
		<word count="2" text="trickl"/>
		<word count="2" text="throughout"/>
		<word count="2" text="contenti"/>
		<word count="2" text="incompat"/>
		<word count="2" text="noon"/>
		<word count="2" text="1800"/>
		<word count="2" text="refus"/>
		<word count="2" text="unnam"/>
		<word count="2" text="'m"/>
		<word count="2" text="specul"/>
		<word count="2" text="spun"/>
		<word count="2" text="front"/>
		<word count="2" text="page"/>
		<word count="2" text="york"/>
		<word count="2" text="today"/>
		<word count="2" text="wall"/>
		<word count="2" text="street"/>
		<word count="2" text="journal"/>
		<word count="2" text="soberli"/>
		<word count="2" text="late-night"/>
		<word count="2" text="typic"/>
		<word count="2" text="such"/>
		<word count="2" text="laugh"/>
		<word count="2" text="broadcast"/>
		<word count="2" text="train"/>
		<word count="2" text="sight"/>
		<word count="2" text="mishap"/>
		<word count="2" text="lack"/>
		<word count="2" text="seven-dollar"/>
		<word count="2" text="reveal"/>
		<word count="2" text="An"/>
		<word count="1" text="hear"/>
		<word count="1" text="realiz"/>
		<word count="1" text="startl"/>
		<word count="1" text="scene"/>
		<word count="1" text="fewer"/>
		<word count="1" text="smaller"/>
		<word count="1" text="pattern"/>
		<word count="1" text="12-gaug"/>
		<word count="1" text="challeng"/>
		<word count="1" text="UP"/>
		<word count="1" text="5th"/>
		<word count="1" text="graf"/>
		<word count="1" text="xxx"/>
		<word count="1" text="globe"/>
		<word count="1" text="multimillionair"/>
		<word count="1" text="bloodi"/>
		<word count="1" text="consciou"/>
		<word count="1" text="tumbl"/>
		<word count="1" text="deliv"/>
		<word count="1" text="keynot"/>
		<word count="1" text="gift"/>
		<word count="1" text="fame"/>
		<word count="1" text="financi"/>
		<word count="1" text="backer"/>
		<word count="1" text="bush-cheney"/>
		<word count="1" text="counselor"/>
		<word count="1" text="nixon"/>
		<word count="1" text="halliburton"/>
		<word count="1" text="corp."/>
		<word count="1" text="becom"/>
		<word count="1" text="articl"/>
		<word count="1" text="week"/>
		<word count="1" text="ago"/>
		<word count="1" text="austin-american"/>
		<word count="1" text="statesman"/>
		<word count="1" text="rich"/>
		<word count="1" text="stubborn"/>
		<word count="1" text="patient"/>
		<word count="1" text="vantag"/>
		<word count="1" text="search"/>
		<word count="1" text="websit"/>
		<word count="1" text="midday"/>
		<word count="1" text="sooner"/>
		<word count="1" text="pleas"/>
		<word count="1" text="attack"/>
		<word count="1" text="problem"/>
		<word count="1" text="grew"/>
		<word count="1" text="wyom"/>
		<word count="1" text="enthusiast"/>
		<word count="1" text="suprem"/>
		<word count="1" text="court"/>
		<word count="1" text="januari"/>
		<word count="1" text="louisiana"/>
		<word count="1" text="2000"/>
		<word count="1" text="month"/>
		<word count="1" text="dearest"/>
		<word count="1" text="respect"/>
		<word count="1" text="barbara"/>
		<word count="1" text="love"/>
		<word count="1" text="1852"/>
		<word count="1" text="grandfath"/>
		<word count="1" text="iii"/>
		<word count="1" text="becam"/>
		<word count="1" text="captur"/>
		<word count="1" text="outlaw"/>
		<word count="1" text="wesley"/>
		<word count="1" text="hardin"/>
		<word count="1" text="profil"/>
		<word count="1" text="then-governor"/>
		<word count="1" text="final"/>
		<word count="1" text="stage"/>
		<word count="1" text="senat"/>
		<word count="1" text="F."/>
		<word count="1" text="wore"/>
		<word count="1" text="brand"/>
		<word count="1" text="occas"/>
		<word count="1" text="goos"/>
		<word count="1" text="transcript"/>
		<word count="1" text="My"/>
		<word count="1" text="opinion"/>
		<word count="1" text="sportsmen"/>
		<word count="1" text="coverup"/>
		<word count="1" text="amend"/>
		<word count="1" text="photo"/>
		<word count="1" text="opportun"/>
		<word count="1" text="houston"/>
		<word count="1" text="chronicl"/>
		<word count="1" text="29"/>
		<word count="1" text="hunting-rel"/>
		<word count="1" text="fatal"/>
		<word count="1" text="found"/>
		<word count="1" text="chose"/>
		<word count="1" text="serious"/>
		<word count="1" text="millionair"/>
		<word count="1" text="yvonn"/>
		<word count="1" text="wheeler"/>
		<word count="1" text="emerg"/>
		<word count="1" text="personnel"/>
		<word count="1" text="24"/>
		<word count="1" text="discov"/>
		<word count="1" text="sinc"/>
		<word count="1" text="1950"/>
		<word count="1" text="then-gov"/>
		<word count="1" text="name"/>
		<word count="1" text="travi"/>
		<word count="1" text="capit"/>
		<word count="1" text="worth"/>
		<word count="1" text="least"/>
		<word count="1" text="million"/>
		<word count="1" text="american-statesman"/>
		<word count="1" text="count"/>
		<word count="1" text="center"/>
		<word count="1" text="long-run"/>
		<word count="1" text="condemn"/>
		<word count="1" text="fortun"/>
		<word count="1" text="probabl"/>
		<word count="1" text="cautiou"/>
		<word count="1" text="avid"/>
		<word count="1" text="annual"/>
		<word count="1" text="dakota"/>
		<word count="1" text="pheasant"/>
		<word count="1" text="arkansa"/>
		<word count="1" text="onc"/>
		<word count="1" text="safe"/>
		<word count="1" text="sportsman"/>
		<word count="1" text="regular"/>
		<word count="1" text="myself"/>
		<word count="1" text="___"/>
		<word count="1" text="paul"/>
		<word count="1" text="weber"/>
		<word count="1" text="credenti"/>
		<word count="1" text="experienc"/>
		<word count="1" text="outdoorsman"/>
		<word count="1" text="valid"/>
		<word count="1" text="out-of-st"/>
		<word count="1" text="receiv"/>
		<word count="1" text="verbal"/>
		<word count="1" text="mani"/>
		<word count="1" text="unawar"/>
		<word count="1" text="staffer"/>
		<word count="1" text="reverber"/>
		<word count="1" text="worldwid"/>
		<word count="1" text="bag"/>
		<word count="1" text="headlin"/>
		<word count="1" text="glasgow"/>
		<word count="1" text="scotland-bas"/>
		<word count="1" text="herald"/>
		<word count="1" text="forc"/>
		<word count="1" text="secreci"/>
		<word count="1" text="prioriti"/>
		<word count="1" text="approach"/>
		<word count="1" text="protocol"/>
		<word count="1" text="mr."/>
		<word count="1" text="expert"/>
		<word count="1" text="locat"/>
		<word count="1" text="keep"/>
		<word count="1" text="everyon"/>
		<word count="1" text="larri"/>
		<word count="1" text="kean"/>
		<word count="1" text="gener"/>
		<word count="1" text="counsel"/>
		<word count="1" text="sport"/>
		<word count="1" text="foundat"/>
		<word count="1" text="jeff"/>
		<word count="1" text="matter"/>
		<word count="1" text="bottom"/>
		<word count="1" text="testi"/>
		<word count="1" text="reflect"/>
		<word count="1" text="attitud"/>
		<word count="1" text="clever"/>
		<word count="1" text="conserv"/>
		<word count="1" text="columnist"/>
		<word count="1" text="robert"/>
		<word count="1" text="novak"/>
		<word count="1" text="fox"/>
		<word count="1" text="felt"/>
		<word count="1" text="joe"/>
		<word count="1" text="lockhart"/>
		<word count="1" text="clinton"/>
		<word count="1" text="bunch"/>
		<word count="1" text="sit"/>
		<word count="1" text="els"/>
		<word count="1" text="friday"/>
		<word count="1" text="retreat"/>
		<word count="1" text="wealthi"/>
		<word count="1" text="95"/>
		<word count="1" text="truck"/>
		<word count="1" text="drive"/>
		<word count="1" text="mesquite-dot"/>
		<word count="1" text="12:30"/>
		<word count="1" text="antelop"/>
		<word count="1" text="jicama"/>
		<word count="1" text="salad"/>
		<word count="1" text="camp"/>
		<word count="1" text="bread"/>
		<word count="1" text="wash"/>
		<word count="1" text="Dr"/>
		<word count="1" text="split"/>
		<word count="1" text="energi"/>
		<word count="1" text="pursu"/>
		<word count="1" text="dusk"/>
		<word count="1" text="minist"/>
		<word count="1" text="profus"/>
		<word count="1" text="wit"/>
		<word count="1" text="pack"/>
		<word count="1" text="drove"/>
		<word count="1" text="evid"/>
		<word count="1" text="injuri"/>
		<word count="1" text="life-threaten"/>
		<word count="1" text="paus"/>
		<word count="1" text="road"/>
		<word count="1" text="join"/>
		<word count="1" text="stabil"/>
		<word count="1" text="kingsvil"/>
		<word count="1" text="evacu"/>
		<word count="1" text="larger"/>
		<word count="1" text="facil"/>
		<word count="1" text="'d"/>
		<word count="1" text="We"/>
		<word count="1" text="leak"/>
		<word count="1" text="christo"/>
		<word count="1" text="recuper"/>
		<word count="1" text="crack"/>
		<word count="1" text="joke"/>
		<word count="1" text="baffl"/>
		<word count="1" text="true"/>
		<word count="1" text="gentleman"/>
		<word count="1" text="confer"/>
		<word count="1" text="amaz"/>
		<word count="1" text="hoopla"/>
		<word count="1" text="fixtur"/>
		<word count="1" text="tower"/>
		<word count="1" text="senatori"/>
		<word count="1" text="run"/>
		<word count="1" text="1960"/>
		<word count="1" text="best"/>
		<word count="1" text="nowaday"/>
		<word count="1" text="decades-long"/>
		<word count="1" text="build"/>
		<word count="1" text="litig"/>
		<word count="1" text="riccardi"/>
		<word count="1" text="gerstenzang"/>
		<word count="1" text="liann"/>
		<word count="1" text="wallsten"/>
		<word count="1" text="itself"/>
		<word count="1" text="speedi"/>
		<word count="1" text="60"/>
		<word count="1" text="outsid"/>
		<word count="1" text="import"/>
		<word count="1" text="Of"/>
		<word count="1" text="cours"/>
		<word count="1" text="posit"/>
		<word count="1" text="avail"/>
		<word count="1" text="attribut"/>
		<word count="1" text="adequ"/>
		<word count="1" text="deflect"/>
		<word count="1" text="slow"/>
		<word count="1" text="reli"/>
		<word count="1" text="undergo"/>
		<word count="1" text="treatment"/>
		<word count="1" text="multipl"/>
		<word count="1" text="lower"/>
		<word count="1" text="banko"/>
		<word count="1" text=".28"/>
		<word count="1" text="gaug"/>
		<word count="1" text="pam"/>
		<word count="1" text="eight"/>
		<word count="1" text="higher"/>
		<word count="1" text="educ"/>
		<word count="1" text="coordin"/>
		<word count="1" text="mid-afternoon"/>
		<word count="1" text="contrast"/>
		<word count="1" text="quick"/>
		<word count="1" text="action"/>
		<word count="1" text="juli"/>
		<word count="1" text="collid"/>
		<word count="1" text="scottish"/>
		<word count="1" text="bicycl"/>
		<word count="1" text="scotland"/>
		<word count="1" text="summit"/>
		<word count="1" text="mild"/>
		<word count="1" text="moder"/>
		<word count="1" text="scrape"/>
		<word count="1" text="arm"/>
		<word count="1" text="hand"/>
		<word count="1" text="bandag"/>
		<word count="1" text="physician"/>
		<word count="1" text="draw"/>
		<word count="1" text="distinct"/>
		<word count="1" text="may"/>
		<word count="1" text="flown"/>
		<word count="1" text="trauma-intens"/>
		<word count="1" text="unspecifi"/>
		<word count="1" text="within"/>
		<word count="1" text="specifi"/>
		<word count="1" text="12"/>
		<word count="1" text="awaken"/>
		<word count="1" text="home"/>
		<word count="1" text="u."/>
		<word count="1" text="britain"/>
		<word count="1" text="directli"/>
		<word count="1" text="start"/>
		<word count="1" text="jaim"/>
		<word count="1" text="appropri"/>
		<word count="1" text="quip"/>
		<word count="1" text="merc"/>
		<word count="1" text="d.c"/>
		<word count="1" text="organ"/>
		<word count="1" text="complex"/>
		<word count="1" text="motorcad"/>
		<word count="1" text="escort"/>
		<word count="1" text="forgo"/>
		<word count="1" text="usual"/>
		<word count="1" text="siren"/>
		<word count="1" text="limousin"/>
		<word count="1" text="black"/>
		<word count="1" text="collar"/>
		<word count="1" text="rais"/>
		<word count="1" text="earli"/>
		<word count="1" text="chill"/>
		<word count="1" text="reason"/>
		<word count="1" text="drop"/>
		<word count="1" text="M."/>
		<word count="1" text="reach"/>
		<word count="1" text="202-263-6400"/>
		<word count="1" text="e-mail"/>
		<word count="1" text="hearstdc.com"/>
		<word count="1" text="success"/>
		<word count="1" text="quell"/>
		<word count="1" text="uproar"/>
		<word count="1" text="initi"/>
		<word count="1" text="incomplet"/>
		<word count="1" text="transfer"/>
		<word count="1" text="rib"/>
		<word count="1" text="cage"/>
		<word count="1" text="rout"/>
		<word count="1" text="market"/>
		<word count="1" text="messag"/>
		<word count="1" text="conclud"/>
		<word count="1" text="episod"/>
		<word count="1" text="view"/>
		<word count="1" text="meet"/>
		<word count="1" text="u.n."/>
		<word count="1" text="secretary-gener"/>
		<word count="1" text="kofi"/>
		<word count="1" text="annan"/>
		<word count="1" text="exchang"/>
		<word count="1" text="remark"/>
		<word count="1" text="enter"/>
		<word count="1" text="batter"/>
		<word count="1" text="demand"/>
		<word count="1" text="answer"/>
		<word count="1" text="faster"/>
		<word count="1" text="chosen"/>
		<word count="1" text="pressur"/>
		<word count="1" text="might"/>
		<word count="1" text="reject"/>
		<word count="1" text="among"/>
		<word count="1" text="govern"/>
		<word count="1" text="though"/>
		<word count="1" text="anyon"/>
		<word count="1" text="discuss"/>
		<word count="1" text="defer"/>
		<word count="1" text="off"/>
		<word count="1" text="wire"/>
		<word count="1" text="wealth"/>
		<word count="1" text="materi"/>
		<word count="1" text="gun"/>
		<word count="1" text="control"/>
		<word count="1" text="activist"/>
		<word count="1" text="comedian"/>
		<word count="1" text="struggl"/>
		<word count="1" text="basic"/>
		<word count="1" text="eastern"/>
		<word count="1" text="jr."/>
		<word count="1" text="subsequ"/>
		<word count="1" text="senior"/>
		<word count="1" text="advis"/>
		<word count="1" text="ramon"/>
		<word count="1" text="3rd"/>
		<word count="1" text="speak"/>
		<word count="1" text="collabor"/>
		<word count="1" text="fulli"/>
		<word count="1" text="satisfi"/>
		<word count="1" text="nonfat"/>
		<word count="1" text="lydia"/>
		<word count="1" text="saldana"/>
		<word count="1" text="commun"/>
		<word count="1" text="director"/>
		<word count="1" text="paid"/>
		<word count="1" text="140"/>
		<word count="1" text="sometim"/>
		<word count="1" text="sen."/>
		<word count="1" text="worn"/>
		<word count="1" text="duck-hunt"/>
		<word count="1" text="effort"/>
		<word count="1" text="hide"/>
		<word count="1" text="vote"/>
		<word count="1" text="gun-own"/>
		<word count="1" text="everi"/>
		<word count="1" text="begin"/>
		<word count="1" text="past"/>
		<word count="1" text="kind"/>
		<word count="1" text="relish"/>
		<word count="1" text="guest"/>
		<word count="1" text="pitzer"/>
		<word count="1" text="2003"/>
		<word count="1" text="familiar"/>
		<word count="1" text="destin"/>
		<word count="1" text="politician"/>
		<word count="1" text="document"/>
		<word count="1" text="regist"/>
		<word count="1" text="construct"/>
		<word count="1" text="done"/>
		<word count="1" text="extens"/>
		<word count="1" text="size"/>
		<word count="1" text="contract"/>
		<word count="1" text="100,000"/>
		<word count="1" text="ethic"/>
		<word count="1" text="watchdog"/>
		<word count="1" text="karen"/>
		<word count="1" text="transport"/>
		<word count="1" text="politicalmoneylin"/>
		<word count="1" text="lockhe"/>
		<word count="1" text="martin"/>
		<word count="1" text="fund-rais"/>
		<word count="1" text="rel"/>
		<word count="1" text="limit"/>
		<word count="1" text="baker"/>
		<word count="1" text="bott"/>
		<word count="1" text="prionic"/>
		<word count="1" text="AG"/>
		<word count="1" text="biotechnolog"/>
		<word count="1" text="trajen"/>
		<word count="1" text="perform"/>
		<word count="1" text="aviat"/>
		<word count="1" text="technic"/>
		<word count="1" text="militari"/>
		<word count="1" text="king"/>
		<word count="1" text="next"/>
		<word count="1" text="level"/>
		<word count="1" text="three"/>
		<word count="1" text="avex"/>
		<word count="1" text="dannenbaum"/>
		<word count="1" text="ecocreto"/>
		<word count="1" text="1999"/>
		<word count="1" text="decad"/>
		<word count="1" text="consult"/>
		<word count="1" text="none"/>
		<word count="1" text="concern"/>
		<word count="1" text="creat"/>
		<word count="1" text="appear"/>
		<word count="1" text="improprieti"/>
		<word count="1" text="jack"/>
		<word count="1" text="abramoff"/>
		<word count="1" text="profession"/>
		<word count="1" text="tie"/>
		<word count="1" text="Oh"/>
		<word count="1" text="nor"/>
		<word count="1" text="comfort"/>
		<word count="1" text="fault"/>
		<word count="1" text="reappear"/>
		<word count="1" text="alongsid"/>
		<word count="1" text="give"/>
		<word count="1" text="carri"/>
		<word count="1" text="begun"/>
		<word count="1" text="fell"/>
		<word count="1" text="toward"/>
		<word count="1" text="ran"/>
		<word count="1" text="fallen"/>
		<word count="1" text="agent"/>
		<word count="1" text="horribl"/>
		<word count="1" text="bruis"/>
		<word count="1" text="substanti"/>
		<word count="1" text="donor"/>
		<word count="1" text="gave"/>
		<word count="1" text="11,000"/>
		<word count="1" text="caus"/>
		<word count="1" text="committe"/>
		<word count="1" text="cycl"/>
		<word count="1" text="brush"/>
		<word count="1" text="icu"/>
		<word count="1" text="afp"/>
		<word count="1" text="direct"/>
		<word count="1" text="8:15"/>
		<word count="1" text="drew"/>
		<word count="1" text="event"/>
		<word count="1" text="katherin"/>
		<word count="1" text="miss"/>
		<word count="1" text="quarri"/>
		<word count="1" text="muse"/>
		<word count="1" text="advoc"/>
		<word count="1" text="full"/>
		<word count="1" text="doubt"/>
		<word count="1" text="situat"/>
		<word count="1" text="differ"/>
		<word count="1" text="2330"/>
		<word count="1" text="break"/>
		<word count="1" text="preced"/>
		<word count="1" text="1:48"/>
		<word count="1" text="1948"/>
		<word count="1" text="internet"/>
		<word count="1" text="request"/>
		<word count="1" text="point"/>
		<word count="1" text="vouch"/>
		<word count="1" text="accuraci"/>
		<word count="1" text="gap"/>
		<word count="1" text="put"/>
		<word count="1" text="noiselessli"/>
		<word count="1" text="legal"/>
		<word count="1" text="78-year"/>
		<word count="1" text="impos"/>
		<word count="1" text="penalti"/>
		<word count="1" text="revel"/>
		<word count="1" text="aggrav"/>
		<word count="1" text="headach"/>
		<word count="1" text="improv"/>
		<word count="1" text="doctor"/>
		<word count="1" text="perazzi"/>
		<word count="1" text="weather"/>
		<word count="1" text="sunni"/>
		<word count="1" text="blaze"/>
		<word count="1" text="hat"/>
		<word count="1" text="oral"/>
		<word count="1" text="rule"/>
		<word count="1" text="beforehand"/>
		<word count="1" text="never"/>
		<word count="1" text="await"/>
		<word count="1" text="warden"/>
		<word count="1" text="dollar"/>
	</Words>
</Topic>
