<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<Topic id="D0943H">
	<Title>trial for two suspects in Air India bombings</Title>
	<Narrative>Trace developments in the trial of Ripudaman Singh Malik and Ajaib Singh Bagri, two suspects in the Air India bombings.</Narrative>
	<DocSetA id="D0943H-A">
		<doc id="APW_ENG_20041019.0465">Defense arguments herald beginning of end to lengthy Air India
terrorist bombing case</doc>
		<doc id="AFP_ENG_20041019.0488">Final arguments to begin in Air India bombing trial by Deborah Jones</doc>
		<doc id="APW_ENG_20041101.0367">Prosecution begins final arguments to conclude Air India bombing
trial in Canada</doc>
		<doc id="AFP_ENG_20041101.0711">Canadian prosecutors finalize arguments against accused Air India
bombers</doc>
		<doc id="NYT_ENG_20041102.0198">BOTCHED TERROR TRIAL CONCLUDES IN CANADA</doc>
		<doc id="APW_ENG_20041108.0397">Canadian prosecutor says revenge drove 1985 Air India bombings that
killed 331</doc>
		<doc id="APW_ENG_20041116.0013">Prosecutor says defendant in Air India bombings that killed 331 had
history of inciting Sikhs</doc>
		<doc id="APW_ENG_20041204.0008">Air India bombing trial wraps up; verdict due next spring</doc>
		<doc id="AFP_ENG_20041204.0020">Judge reserves decision in Air India terrorism trial by Deborah Jones</doc>
		<doc id="AFP_ENG_20041205.0062">Justice at last in sight over Air India terror bombings by Deborah
Jones</doc>
	</DocSetA>
	<Sentences>
		<sentence doc="1" line="1" para="1">The trial of two men accused of bombing an Air India jumbo jet and killing 329 people almost 20 years ago entered its final stretch Tuesday with the defense attacking the credibility of a star government witness.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="1" line="1" para="2">Vancouver millionaire Ripudaman Singh Malik, 57, and Kamloops, British Columbia mill worker Ajaib Singh Bagri, 55, are charged with multiple counts of conspiracy and first degree murder in the world's worst airline terrorism act prior to the Sept. 11, 2001 attacks on the United States.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="1" line="1" para="3">Air India flight 182, a Boeing 747 on its way from Toronto to India via London, blew up off the Irish coast on June 23, 1985, killing all aboard.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="1" line="1" para="4">Malik and Bagri, who have been in custody since their arrest in late 2000, are also charged in connection with a blast on the same day that killed two baggage handlers at Tokyo's Narita Airport.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="1" line="1" para="5">The case in British Columbia Supreme Court has stretched for 13 months since hearings began in April 2003.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="1" line="2" para="5">More than 32 lawyers are working on the case, which is believed to have cost more than US$80 million (euro64 million).</sentence>
		<sentence doc="1" line="1" para="6">Perviz Madon lost her husband, Sam, on flight 182.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="1" line="2" para="6">She wants to see the trial over by the end of the year.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="1" line="1" para="7">&quot;It's time we had a closure,&quot; she said.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="1" line="2" para="7">&quot;It's been 20 years, for God's sake.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="1" line="3" para="7">We're tired.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence doc="1" line="1" para="8">Final arguments are expected to last into December.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="1" line="2" para="8">The case is being heard in a US$5 million (euro4 million) courtroom specifically built for security precautions.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="1" line="1" para="9">The defense argument hinges on attacking the credibility of a star witness for the government, and asserting that at least one of the defendants lacked a motive.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="1" line="1" para="10">Defense lawyer David Crossin argued Tuesday that the witness had an ulterior motive to testify against Malik because she is a former disgruntled employee of his.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="1" line="2" para="10">The woman is in a government witness protection program and a court order bars the publication of her name.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="1" line="1" para="11">The woman, who testified that she had a close personal relationship with Malik, wrote in her diary that he had said: &quot;We had Air India crash.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="1" line="2" para="11">Nobody, nobody can do anything.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence doc="1" line="1" para="12">Crossin said the prosecution's case &quot;stands or falls on the evidence of this woman.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence doc="1" line="1" para="13">&quot;We suggest the nature of that false evidence is profound,&quot; he said.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="1" line="1" para="14">Another prosecution witness, a man who was a member of a Sikh militant group in New York, testified that Bagri as much as confessed to him outside a New Jersey gas station.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="1" line="1" para="15">&quot;We did this,&quot; the man, whom the Canadian government paid US$365,000 (euro293,000) to testify, said Bagri told him.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="1" line="2" para="15">His identity is also protected by the court.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="1" line="1" para="16">Prosecutors believe Malik and Bagri were part of a conspiracy by British Columbia-based Sikh extremists to take revenge against the Indian government, which owns Air India planes, for attacking a Sikh temple in 1984.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="1" line="1" para="17">But the defense argued Tuesday there is no evidence Malik was at all interested in Indian politics.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="1" line="2" para="17">Defense lawyers also contended that he had substantial dealings with the state bank of India, which militant Sikhs would have boycotted.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="1" line="1" para="18">&quot;In our view, it is inconceivable that anyone would have participated in this crime without a political motive,&quot; Crossin said.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="1" line="1" para="19">Bagri's political motivation appears more concrete.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="1" line="2" para="19">A month after the temple raid, thousands of Sikhs gathered at Madison Square Garden in New York City where Bagri reportedly told The World Sikh Organization: &quot;Until we kill 50,000 Hindus we will not rest.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence doc="1" line="1" para="20">He proposed the creation of a Sikh homeland called Khalistan and &quot;spoke of the need for Sikhs to wage a war of independence to exact revenge against the Indian government,&quot; according to documents released by the court.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="1" line="1" para="21">Bagri has also been accused of inciting people at Sikh temples in British Columbia and Ontario, and for calling for the death of then Indian prime minister Indira Gandhi.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="1" line="2" para="21">She was assassinated in 1984.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="1" line="1" para="22">Much of the case, however, hinges on the position of the bomb on Flight 182, which originated in Vancouver.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="1" line="2" para="22">Prosecutors have argued the bomb was in luggage originating in Vancouver.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="1" line="3" para="22">But Bagri's lawyers contend the luggage containing the bomb joined the flight in Toronto.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="1" line="1" para="23">If Judge Ian Josephson accepts that defense, Bagri may be acquitted.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="1" line="1" para="24">Prosecutors maintain that Talwinder Singh Parmar, founder of the militant Babbar Khalsa Sikh militant group, was the mastermind behind the bombings.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="1" line="2" para="24">He died in a shootout with Indian police in 1992.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="1" line="1" para="25">Mysterious deaths have dogged the case from the start.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="1" line="2" para="25">Tara Singh Hayer, a Vancouver-area Sikh newspaper publisher and outspoken critic of Sikh extremism, was crippled after being shot in 1988.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="1" line="3" para="25">He was killed in November 1998 after another shooting.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="1" line="1" para="26">In 1995, Bagri also allegedly confessed his involvement to Tarsem Singh Purewal, publisher of Britain's biggest Punjabi weekly newspaper.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="1" line="2" para="26">Purewal, who was murdered in 1995, had been friends with Hayer.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="1" line="1" para="27">___</sentence>
		<sentence doc="1" line="1" para="28">On the Net:</sentence>
		<sentence doc="1" line="1" para="29">Air India Trial: http//www.airindiatrial.ca</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="1" para="1">Lawyers were set to begin crucial final arguments Tuesday in the case of two Sikh immigrants from India accused of the 1985 mid-air bombing of an Air India plane which left 329 people dead.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="1" para="2">Closing arguments were expected to start with the defence of Ripudaman Singh Malik, a millionaire businessman in Vancouver.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="2" para="2">Lawyers for rural mill worker Ajaib Singh Bagri then were to present their defence, followed by the prosecution team.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="1" para="3">The men, Sikhs who immigrated to Canada from India's northern state of Punjab, are each charged with eight counts of murder and conspiracy in what was the world's worst airborne terrorist act before September 11, 2001.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="1" para="4">On June 23, 1985, a suitcase exploded at Japan's Narita airport, killing two baggage handlers as they transferred it to Air India Flight 301 for Bangkok and Delhi.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="1" para="5">Less than an hour later, off the coast of Ireland, a second bomb ripped through Air India Flight 182 as it flew to London from Montreal.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="2" para="5">All 329 people on board died.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="1" para="6">Though separated by long years and thousands of miles, both the 2001 hijackings of four US jets, two of which crashed into New York's World Trade Center, and the 1985 Air India bombings, were allegedly carried out by fundamentalists bent on revenge against a foreign government.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="1" para="7">Prosecutors contend Malik and Bagri, with others, planted bombs on Air India jets to punish the Indian government for its 1983 army attack on Sikhdom's most holy place, the Golden Temple at Amritsar.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="2" para="7">At the time, Sikh separatists were fighting for an independent homeland in India's Punjab.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="1" para="8">By the time Justice Ian Bruce Josephson of the British Columbia Supreme Court renders a decision on Malik and Bagri, the Air India case will be nearly 20 years old.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="1" para="9">The verdict is unlikely to be the final chapter in the bombings case, however, because police continue to investigate other suspects.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="1" para="10">Since the trial began in April 2003, Canadian prosecutors have constructed a complex case against the pair, based on witness testimony, police interviews, phone records and surveillance.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="1" para="11">The trial is being held in a 7.5 million Canadian dollar (5.6 million US) bunker-like, bomb-proof, bullet-resistant court built especially for this case.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="1" para="12">The court also designated as a remote annex a vast warehouse in a secret location.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="2" para="12">Within it is a skeleton of a Boeing 747 Jumbo Jet, named the Kanishka by Air India.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="1" para="13">Parts of the plane were hauled from the bed of the Atlantic Ocean, shipped to Canada and reconstructed by police.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="1" para="14">Prosecutors say Sikh extremists in Canada built two suitcase bombs, bought airline tickets and checked the suitcase bombs onto Vancouver flights connecting with Air India.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="1" para="15">A third man, Inderjit Singh Reyat, has been sentenced to 10 years in prison for a conviction in the Narita explosion, and was also charged with Bagri and Malik.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="1" para="16">In 2003, Reyat pleaded guilty to manslaughter for supplying bomb materials and received a five-year sentence.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="1" para="17">Both prosecution cases hinge partly on women who were allegedly close to Malik and Bagri.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="1" para="18">The first woman to testify once worked for Malik and says the pair were in love.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="2" para="18">She told the court Malik once confided to her, &quot;We had Air India crash.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="3" para="18">Malik's lawyers are expected to reiterate arguments that the woman's testimony is not credible.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="1" para="19">The second woman alleged that Bagri asked to borrow her car about the time the suitcase bombs were delivered to the airport.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="1" para="20">The identity of both women, as with many other witnesses in the case, is shielded under a publication ban.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="2" para="20">Two potential witnesses in the case, both Sikh journalists, were assassinated.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="3" para="20">Other witnesses allege they have received threats.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="3" line="1" para="1">The prosecution began final arguments Monday in the case of an Air India jumbo jet bombing that killing 329 people almost 20 years ago, saying the two men accused in the Canadian trial were guilty beyond a reasonable doubt.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="3" line="1" para="2">Vancouver millionaire Ripudaman Singh Malik, 57, and Kamloops, British Columbia mill worker Ajaib Singh Bagri, 55, are charged with multiple counts of conspiracy and first-degree murder in the world's worst airline terrorism act prior to the September 11, 2001, attacks on the United States.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="3" line="1" para="3">Air India flight 182, a Boeing 747 named The Emperor Kanishka for the Indian ruler at the time of Christ, blew up off the Irish coast on June 23, 1985, killing all aboard.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="3" line="2" para="3">The plane was traveling from Toronto to India via London.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="3" line="1" para="4">Malik and Bagri, who have been in custody since their arrest in late 2000, are also charged in connection with a blast on the same June day that killed two baggage handlers at Tokyo's Narita Airport.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="3" line="1" para="5">More than 32 lawyers are working on the case believed to have cost more than US$80 million (euro64 million) since hearings began in April 2003.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="3" line="2" para="5">It is being heard in a US$5 million (euro3.9 million) British Columbia Supreme Court room specifically built for security precautions.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="3" line="1" para="6">Prosecutors believe Malik and Bagri were part of a conspiracy by British Columbia-based Sikh extremists to take revenge against the Indian government, which owns Air India planes, for attacking a Sikh temple in 1984.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="3" line="1" para="7">Prosecution lawyer Robert Wright on Monday opened final arguments expected to last two weeks, saying the guilt of Bagri and Malik &quot;has been proven beyond a reasonable doubt.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence doc="3" line="1" para="8">&quot;This is, in our submission, a politically motivated and terrorist event ... consistent only with a political and religious zealotry,&quot; Wright said.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="3" line="1" para="9">The prosecution has noted that Bagri reportedly told The World Sikh Organization in 1984 at Madison Square Garden in New York City: &quot;Until we kill 50,000 Hindus we will not rest.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence doc="3" line="1" para="10">He proposed the creation of a Sikh homeland called Khalistan and &quot;spoke of the need for Sikhs to wage a war of independence to exact revenge against the Indian government&quot;, according to documents released by the court.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="3" line="1" para="11">Bagri has also been accused of inciting people at Sikh temples in British Columbia and Ontario, and for calling for the death of then Indian prime minister Indira Gandhi.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="3" line="2" para="11">She was assassinated in 1984.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="3" line="1" para="12">&quot;Who would do something so terrible to kill so many innocent people?</sentence>
		<sentence doc="3" line="2" para="12">There is no doubt these people were murdered,&quot; Wright said.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="3" line="1" para="13">The prosecution's case is largely based on the testimony of three witnesses who said the defendants had confessed the crimes to them.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="3" line="1" para="14">&quot;These admissions are the ultimate piece of evidence against the accused,&quot; Wright said.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="3" line="1" para="15">The defense has attacked the credibility of these witnesses and asserted that Malik lacked a motive because he was not interested in Indian politics.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="3" line="1" para="16">Defense lawyer David Crossin argued two weeks ago that one witness was a former disgruntled employee, another was paid $US365,000 (euro285,000) by the government to testify and the third denied evidence on the stand she had given to investigators years ago.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="3" line="1" para="17">Much of the case, however, hinges on the position of the bomb on flight 182, which originated in Vancouver.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="3" line="2" para="17">Prosecutors have argued the bomb was in luggage originating in Vancouver.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="3" line="3" para="17">But Bagri's lawyers contend the luggage containing the bomb joined the flight in Toronto.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="3" line="1" para="18">&quot;There was a murder plot in which two planes were supposed to explode simultaneously.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="3" line="2" para="18">The two bombs originated here in the city of Vancouver,&quot; Wright said.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="3" line="1" para="19">He said Malik booked and paid for the tickets while Bagri arranged for bags containing the bombs to be delivered to the airport.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="3" line="1" para="20">Expert prosecution witnesses who testified also worked on the investigation into the bombing of Pan Am Flight 103 which blew up over Lockerbie, Scotland in 1988, killing 270 people.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="3" line="1" para="21">At a secret Vancouver warehouse, salvaged parts of the plane have been reassembled with other parts fabricated using film footage of pieces still on the ocean floor.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="4" line="1" para="1">Canadian prosecutors began wrapping up their final arguements here Monday in the trial of two Sikh immigrants from India charged with conspiring to bomb Air India passenger jets in 1985, resulting in the deaths of 331 people.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="4" line="1" para="2">The two Sikh immigrants, Ajaib Singh Bagri and Ripudaman Singh Malik, are each charged with eight counts of murder and conspiracy in the bombing, the deadliest single terrorist act until the September 11, 2001 attacks in the United States.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="4" line="1" para="3">Prosecutors have argued that Bagri and Malik were among a group of orthodox Sikh immigrants to Canada who, in the turbulent 1980s, waged a campaign against India for its crackdown on religious Sikhs.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="4" line="1" para="4">Bagri's lawyer says his client was the innocent victim in the case.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="4" line="1" para="5">Prosecutor Robin Wright said his team will drive home an arguement that the pair were part of a plot to check two suitcase bombs onto Air India aircraft departing Vancouver.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="4" line="1" para="6">He said proof of their guilt ranges from providing financial assistance to a man convicted in the case, attempting to interfere with police investigations and admissions to people they trusted.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="4" line="1" para="7">Two bombs blew up on June 23, 1985, with the first killing two baggage handlers at Japan's Narita airport as they transferred baggage to an Air India plane.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="4" line="2" para="7">The second bomb killed 329 passengers aboard Air India Flight 182 off the Irish Coast.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="4" line="1" para="8">&quot;There is no doubt these people were murdered,&quot; said Wright, adding that the only explanation for the bombing was &quot;political and religious zealotry.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence doc="4" line="1" para="9">The case against Bagri and Malik relies on key witnesses who say the accused confessed details of their involvement, circumstantial evidence, and motives.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="4" line="1" para="10">Prosecutors say both men were part of a group of extremist Sikhs bent on avenging India's attack on the Sikh Golden Temple at Amritsar in 1984.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="4" line="1" para="11">The prosecution team will spend the next three weeks finalizing their case before Justice Ian Bruce Josephson.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="4" line="1" para="12">Josephson is hearing the complicated trial alone without a jury.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="4" line="2" para="12">Earlier this month, defence teams for both accused wrapped up their closing arguments.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="4" line="1" para="13">The judge is expected to reserve his ruling in the case, possibly for several months.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="1" para="1">Nearly 20 years after an Air India Boeing 747 from Canada exploded in the air and plunged into waters off the Irish coast, killing all 329 people on board, the trial to finally resolve what happened entered its climactic phase this week.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="1" para="2">More than 100 witnesses have testified during nearly two years of proceedings in the most serious terrorism trial in Canadian history.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="2" para="2">A special high-security courtroom was built for the case, at a cost of $6 million, complete with a prisoner dock encased in bulletproof glass.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="3" para="2">Aging relatives of the victims came from as far away as Sri Lanka to watch from the court gallery.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="1" para="3">But as prosecutors began their final arguments Monday to convict two Canadian Sikh activists accused of plotting the bombing, the outcome of the trial is far from settled because of years of bungled police work and the unexplained killings of an important witness and suspect.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="1" para="4">In addition, key witnesses offered vague and contradictory recollections, and key evidence is circumstantial.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="2" para="4">Both defendants -- Ripudaman Singh Malik, a 57-year-old millionaire real estate entrepreneur, and Ajaib Singh Bagri, a 56-year-old sawmill worker and Sikh preacher -- pleaded not guilty to charges of first-degree murder and conspiracy in the bombing of the jet, Air India Flight 182 en route from Toronto and Montreal to India, on June 23, 1985.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="1" para="5">The two are also charged with conspiring in an explosion that killed two baggage handlers at Narita airport outside Tokyo 54 minutes before Flight 182 went down.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="2" para="5">Prosecutors said both bombs were placed on Air India aircraft in Vancouver.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="1" para="6">(BEGIN OPTIONAL TRIM.)</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="1" para="7">&quot;This was a murder plot in which two planes were to explode simultaneously,&quot; said Robert H. Wright, the chief prosecutor as he began to sum up his case.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="2" para="7">&quot;It is difficult to comprehend how this would happen.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="3" para="7">Who would do something so terrible?&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="4" para="7">Answering his own question, Wright told the court that only &quot;political and religious zealotry&quot; could motivate such a crime.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="1" para="8">Prosecutors say Malik, who has worn a white tunic at the trial, recruited members of the plot and gave $3,000 to a friend to pick up tickets for the flight with the ultimate aim of planting the bomb on Flight 182.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="2" para="8">Bagri, who wears a dark turban, is accused of taking luggage with the explosives to the Vancouver airport.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="1" para="9">Neither Malik nor Bagri chose to testify.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="1" para="10">Prosecutors have alleged that Malik and Bagri were motivated to revenge the 1984 Indian army storming of the Golden Temple of Amritsar after the holy shrine was taken over by militant Sikhs.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="2" para="10">That attack sparked a cascade of violence and revenge killings that included the assassination of Prime Minister Indira Gandhi.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="1" para="11">(END OPTIONAL TRIM.)</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="1" para="12">With no physical evidence or firsthand testimony linking the accused to the bombing, the outcome of the trial is in doubt.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="2" para="12">The prosecution wraps up its case in the next few weeks, and Justice Ian Bruce Josephson is expected to reach a decision early next year.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="1" para="13">(STORY CAN END HERE.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="2" para="13">OPTIONAL MATERIAL FOLLOWS.)</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="1" para="14">The prosecution has shown a video of Bagri giving an incendiary speech at a New York Sikh rally in July 1984 in which he said, &quot;We will not take rest until we kill 50,000 Hindus.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="1" para="15">But most of the prosecution's case is based on supposed confessions Malik and Bagri gave to several associates that they deny making.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="1" para="16">The government has highlighted statements made by a Canadian Security Intelligence Service agent that a friend of Bagri said he had visited the night before the bombing to ask to borrow her car to drop off some bags at the airport.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="2" para="16">By court order, the woman, like other key witnesses, cannot be identified.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="3" para="16">The agent testified that the woman said that Bagri implied that wrongdoing would be done, but, during the trial, she said she did not remember making such statements.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="4" para="16">Josephson ruled that her prior testimony should be admitted as evidence after the prosecution argued that witnesses were coming under pressure from Sikh activists.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="1" para="17">The key prosecution witness against Malik is a former employee at a religious school that Malik directed.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="2" para="17">She testified that he told her in 1996 and 1997, while they were involved in a strong personal, but platonic relationship, that he helped organize the conspiracy and detailed his role in arranging for the purchase and pickup of airline tickets that were used to check in the baggage with the explosives.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="1" para="18">The witness said she distanced herself from him after the admissions, after which she was subjected to threats.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="2" para="18">She was eventually fired.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="3" para="18">Malik's lawyer questioned her credibility as a disgruntled employee.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="1" para="19">The prosecution has also been hampered by the fact that the suspected main ringleader of the plot, a former Canadian resident, Talwinder Singh Parmar, was killed by Indian authorities when they caught him clandestinely crossing from Pakistan in 1992.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="1" para="20">Tara Singh Hayer, the publisher of a Sikh newspaper in Vancouver, told police in 1995 that he had overheard Bagri admit to his role in the attacks.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="2" para="20">But three years later, Hayer was gunned down outside his home in a Vancouver suburb.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="1" para="21">Prosecutors were also held back by numerous errors made by investigators.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="2" para="21">The Canadian intelligence service withdrew an agent who had infiltrated Sikh activist ranks only days before the attacks and erased hours of tape recordings of conversations by several of the prime suspects intercepted before the plane bombings.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="3" para="21">They later said they had not realized the significance of the tapes.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="4" para="21">Meanwhile, the Royal Canadian Mounted Police failed to follow up on crucial evidence for years, apparently because of internal politics.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="1" para="22">&quot;We feel a deep sense of betrayal on the part of the Canadian government,&quot; said Lata Pada, a 56-year-old choreographer from Toronto who lost her husband and two daughters on the flight.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="2" para="22">&quot;Canada has still not woken up to the reality that global terrorism is still in our back yard.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="1" para="1">One of two men accused in the 1985 Air India bombings that claimed 331 lives was driven by ambition and revenge, a prosecutor told a Canadian court in his closing arguments Monday.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="1" para="2">Vancouver millionaire Ripudaman Singh Malik, 57, and Kamloops, British Columbia, mill worker Ajaib Singh Bagri, 55, are charged with multiple counts of conspiracy and first degree murder in the world's worst airline terrorism act prior to the September 11, 2001, attacks on the United States.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="1" para="3">Air India Flight 182, a Boeing 747 on its way from Toronto to India via London, blew up off the Irish coast on June 23, 1985, killing all aboard.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="2" para="3">A second bomb exploded at Tokyo's Narita Airport, killing two baggage handlers.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="1" para="4">&quot;It has been shown (Malik) has a powerful and pervasive motive,&quot; prosecutor Joe Bellows said in British Columbia Supreme Court.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="1" para="5">He told Judge Ian Josephson that the Indian government's 1984 attack on the Golden Temple in Amritsar, Sikhism's holiest shrine, was a pivotal event in Malik's desire for revenge.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="2" para="5">Hundreds died in the attack.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="1" para="6">&quot;All Sikhs .</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="2" para="6">.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="3" para="6">.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="4" para="6">felt a terrible sacrilege had been committed against their religion,&quot; Bellows said.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="5" para="6">&quot;They ignited in Malik emotions of both ambition and revenge,&quot; he said.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="6" para="6">&quot;Malik and his co-conspirators chose to destroy not one but two Air India planes.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="7" para="6">The message to be conveyed was: If we can do this, we can do anything.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="1" para="7">Bellows said the 1984 assassination of Indian Prime Minister Indira Gandhi by her Sikh bodyguards was also part of the reaction to the temple raid.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="1" para="8">As Bellows spoke, Malik, dressed in traditional Sikh garb, dozed in the prisoners' box protected by bulletproof glass.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="1" para="9">Bellows said Malik's praise for convicted bomb-maker Inderjit Singh Reyat and his financial support for Reyat's family while in prison is further proof of his involvement in the plot.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="1" para="10">Bellows said Malik wanted to teach the Indian government a lesson as Sikhs fought for the creation of an independent Sikh homeland, Khalistan, in India's Punjab state.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="1" para="11">Bellows recounted the testimony of one man who said Malik had approached him to carry an attache case containing a time bomb to Vancouver's airport.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="1" para="12">&quot;If a child dies for Sikhism, so what?&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="2" para="12">Bellows recalled, quoting from the witness' testimony of what Malik told him.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="3" para="12">&quot;To Malik, the death of a child means nothing, the death of 329 people means nothing.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="4" para="12">What matters is Khalistan.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="1" para="13">The witness, whose name is protected by a court ordered publication ban, said Malik had been asked to approach him for the task by Talwinder Singh Parmar, the suspected mastermind behind the plot and a leader of the extremist Babbar Khalsa Sikh separatist group.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="2" para="13">Parmar died in a shootout with Indian police in 1992.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="1" para="14">Bellows showed the court a Canadian intelligence photograph of Malik outside Parmar's home five days before the bombings.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="1" para="15">The defense has tried to discredit Malik's alleged confession of his involvement in the bombings to an intimate female friend whose name is also protected by the court.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="2" para="15">She was a disgruntled former employee motivated by revenge, defense lawyers argued.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="1" para="16">Bellows, however, said the Crown witness was highly credible and that the case against Malik &quot;is proven on her evidence alone.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="1" para="17">The woman, who testified that she had a close personal relationship with Malik, wrote in her diary that he had said: &quot;We had Air India crash.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="2" para="17">Nobody, nobody can do anything.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="1" para="18">Malik and Bagri, who have been in custody since their arrest in late 2000, are also charged with the Narita blast.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="1" para="19">Bellows was expected to continue his closing arguments on Tuesday, and the case is likely to go to the judge for a verdict in mid-December.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="1" para="20">The defense concluded its case last month.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="2" para="20">Malik's legal team said their client is innocent and accused the witnesses against him of being motivated by a desire for revenge.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="1" para="21">The case has stretched for 13 months since hearings began in April 2003.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="2" para="21">More than 32 lawyers are working on the case, which is believed to have cost more than $US80 million (euro62 million).</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="1" para="1">Two fiery speeches delivered to Sikh groups in the early 1980s show Ajaib Singh Bagri had a motive to plant bombs on Air India jets killing 331 people, a prosecutor said in closing arguments Monday.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="1" para="2">Bagri, a 55-year-old mill worker in Kamloops, British Columbia, and Vancouver millionaire Ripudaman Singh Malik, 57, are charged with multiple counts of conspiracy and first degree murder in the world's worst airline terrorism act before the September 11, 2001, attacks in the United States.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="1" para="3">Air India Flight 182, a Boeing 747 on its way from Toronto to India via London, blew up off the Irish coast on June 23, 1985, killing all aboard.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="2" para="3">A second bomb exploded at Tokyo's Narita Airport, killing two baggage handlers.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="1" para="4">Prosecutor Richard Cairns argued that Bargris was a high-ranking member of a terrorist group.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="2" para="4">&quot;Revenge, revenge, revenge.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="3" para="4">That's what he wants.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="1" para="5">Cairns said Bagri gave two speeches calling for retribution for the 1984 raids on India's Golden Temple, Sikhisms holiest shrine.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="2" para="5">Cairns also said Bagri made pointed references to Air India, saying the Indian government used proceeds from the airline to purchase weapons to use against Sikhs.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="1" para="6">&quot;Bagri is exhorting the crowd to take revenge on the Indian government and Hindus,&quot; Cairns said.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="2" para="6">He said that in the speech, Bagri &quot;identifies his targets and he advocates revenge.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="1" para="7">The defense has argued that Bagri's speeches amount only to fiery oratory, and has questioned the credibility of witnesses in the case, including that the star witness against Bagri, who was paid to testify by Canadian authorities.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="1" para="8">That witness, a member of a militant Sikh group whose identity is protected by the court, said Bagri told him that he was responsible for the bombings.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="2" para="8">Bagri allegedly made the comment following a speech he gave at New York's Madison Square Gardens.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="1" para="9">&quot;'We have stuff that can blow like, like a (city) block,&quot; Cairns said, repeating the witnesses' testimony of what Bagri told him.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="1" para="10">The witness, who is not charged with a crime, was paid US$386,000 (euro298,000) to testify.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="2" para="10">Cairns also noted that another protected witness testified that Bagri asked her if he could borrow her car to take some bags to Vancouver International Airport.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="3" para="10">The bags would be going on the plane, he would not, the woman testified.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="1" para="11">A verdict in the trial which began in April 2003 isn't expected until early 2005.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="8" line="1" para="1">Final arguments in the murder trial of two Sikhs charged with the 1985 bombing of an Air India jumbo jet concluded, ending one of the most exhaustive and expensive trials in Canadian history.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="8" line="1" para="2">The trial against a millionaire and a mill worker charged with multiple counts of conspiracy and first-degree murder hinges on the testimony of three star witnesses and contradicting bombing experts.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="8" line="1" para="3">British Columbia Supreme Court Justice Ian Josephson announced Friday he will deliver a decision on March 16, 2005.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="8" line="1" para="4">The case has called 115 witnesses since it began in April 2003.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="8" line="2" para="4">With a specially built courtroom, the trial cost more than US$100 million (euro75 million).</sentence>
		<sentence doc="8" line="1" para="5">Ripudaman Singh Malik, a 57-year-old millionaire, and Ajaib Singh Bagri, 55, are charged with planting bombs that exploded June 23, 1985, aboard Flight 182, killing 329 people, and 53 minutes earlier at Tokyo's Narita Airport, killing two baggage handlers.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="8" line="1" para="6">Alleged bombmaker Inderjit Singh Reyat has already pleaded guilty to manslaughter and is in prison.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="8" line="1" para="7">Perviz Madon lost her husband, Sam, on Flight 182.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="8" line="2" para="7">She and her son, Eddie, have attended the trial regularly.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="8" line="1" para="8">&quot;I think the waiting is going to be hard,&quot; she said of the case going to the judge.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="8" line="2" para="8">&quot;Let's just hope the wait will be worth it.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence doc="8" line="1" para="9">The prosecution alleges the motive was revenge against the Indian government's 1984 attack against separatists who had taken refuge in the Golden Temple of Amritsar, Sikhism's holiest shrine.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="8" line="1" para="10">The attack also led to the 1984 assassination of Indian Prime Minister Indira Gandhi by her Sikh bodyguards.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="8" line="1" para="11">The prosecution said the accused were zealots driven by a desire to create an independent Sikh state of Khalistan in the Punjab region of northern India and wanted to teach the Indian government a lesson.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="8" line="1" para="12">&quot;All Sikhs ... felt a terrible sacrilege had been committed against their religion,&quot; prosecutor Joe Bellows said during closing arguments.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="8" line="1" para="13">While the defense maintains there is no evidence Malik was interested in Indian politics, Bagri's political motivation appeared more concrete.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="8" line="1" para="14">A month after the temple raid, thousands of Sikhs gathered at Madison Square Garden in New York City where Bagri reportedly told The World Sikh Organization: &quot;Until we kill 50,000 Hindus we will not rest.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence doc="8" line="1" para="15">The prosecution has alleged Malik and Bagri were members of the Babbar Khalsa Sikh terrorist group led by Talwinder Singh Parmar, the alleged mastermind of the bombing.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="8" line="1" para="16">Parmar died in a shootout with Indian police in 1992.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="8" line="1" para="17">A prosecution witness who testified that she had a close personal relationship with Malik, wrote in her diary that he had said: &quot;We had Air India crash.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="8" line="2" para="17">Nobody, nobody can do anything.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence doc="8" line="1" para="18">The defense has tried to discredit the testimony, saying she was a disgruntled former employee motivated by revenge.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="8" line="1" para="19">The judge must also decide between the conflicting testimony of two bombing experts who testified earlier this year.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="8" line="1" para="20">Bagri's lawyer, Richard Peck, said Friday: &quot;This case has been a trek across a vast expanse of knowledge, experience, and law.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence doc="8" line="1" para="21">The defense lawyer for Malik, David Crossin, called the case a &quot;logistical nightmare&quot; and said, &quot;I don't think there will ever be such a case like this again, in this country, or perhaps the world.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence doc="8" line="1" para="22">&quot;It was a long haul, I'm glad it's over,&quot; Crossin said.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="8" line="1" para="23">Crown spokesman Geoffrey Gaul said the trial lasted 202 days total and included 113 witnesses.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="8" line="2" para="23">In all, 178 family members attended, many coming from around the world to view the trial, said Gaul.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="8" line="1" para="24">Mysterious deaths have dogged the case from the start.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="8" line="2" para="24">Tara Singh Hayer, a Vancouver-area Sikh newspaper publisher and outspoken critic of Sikh extremism, was crippled after being shot in 1988.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="8" line="3" para="24">He was killed later that year in another shooting.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="8" line="1" para="25">In 1995, Bagri allegedly confessed his involvement to Tarsem Singh Purewal, a publisher of Britain's biggest Punjabi weekly newspaper who was murdered later that year.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="9" line="1" para="1">Two men charged with murder and conspiracy in the Air India bombings, the world's most lethal terror strike prior to September 11, 2001, will wait until March to hear a verdict, a judge said Friday.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="9" line="1" para="2">After 19 months of complex hearings, the massive trial of Ajaib Singh Bagri and Ripudaman Singh Malik ended Friday with lawyers on all sides trying to score a few last points.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="9" line="1" para="3">Justice Ian Bruce Josephson, who heard the case without a jury in this western Canadian city, said he will reveal his decision March 16.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="9" line="1" para="4">Bagri and Malik, who were arrested in 2000, are each charged with eight counts related to two bombings on June 23, 1985.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="9" line="1" para="5">On that day a suitcase bomb exploded at Japan's Narita airport, killing two Japanese baggage handlers as they transferred it to an Air India jet.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="9" line="1" para="6">Less than an hour later, Air India Flight 182 exploded off the Irish coast, killing all 329 aboard.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="9" line="1" para="7">John Ward of the Royal Canadian Mounted Police told reporters that 250 officers have worked on the case since 1985.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="9" line="2" para="7">The investigation into more suspects continues, he said.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="9" line="1" para="8">&quot;We still have 12 RCMP officers working on this case.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="9" line="2" para="8">We're not done yet.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence doc="9" line="1" para="9">Prosecution spokesperson Geoffrey Gaul said 113 witnesses testified for the government and for Bagri and Malik's defence teams.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="9" line="1" para="10">The trial was held behind bullet-resistant glass in a specially-built, secure, 7.5-million-dollar (6.3 million US) underground courtroom.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="9" line="1" para="11">Bagri, a Sikh preacher and rural millworker, and Malik, a millionaire Vancouver businessman, maintained their innocence.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="9" line="1" para="12">The pair is accused of taking part in a plot by Sikh fundamentalists to build two bombs and plant them on two flights leaving Vancouver that connected with Air India flights to London and Delhi.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="9" line="1" para="13">Government prosecutors contend that Malik arranged and paid for the airline tickets used to check the suitcase bombs onto planes, and that Bagri arranged to get the bombs to the airport.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="9" line="1" para="14">The motive in targetting the Indian planes, said Gaul, was to fight for the cause of an independent Sikh homeland, to be called Khalistan, and avenge India's 1984 attack on the Sikh Golden Temple at Amritsar.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="9" line="1" para="15">The alleged mastermind of the plot, Talwinder Singh Parmar, was killed in a police shootout in India in 1992.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="9" line="1" para="16">Nearly 20 years will have elapsed by the time Josephson rules on the guilt of the two men, who emigrated to Canada from Punjab.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="9" line="1" para="17">A third man in Canada, Inderjit Singh Reyat, pled guilty in 2003 to manslaughter for his role in providing material for the bomb on Flight 182, and was sentenced to five years.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="9" line="1" para="18">The Air India bombing stood as the worst terror attack in modern history, until it was overtaken by the carnage of the attacks on the World Trade Center and the Pentagon in the United States in 2001.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="10" line="1" para="1">Nearly 20 years after their loved ones died in the worst terror strike prior to the September 11 attacks, relatives of 329 people killed in an Air India jet bombing are at last in sight of justice.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="10" line="1" para="2">Two orthodox Sikhs will learn in March whether they will be found guilty of the 1985 outrage.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="10" line="2" para="2">Their trial ended Friday after sapping millions of dollars from Canadian coffers.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="10" line="1" para="3">Justice Ian Bruce Josephson, who heard the case without a jury, will rule on March 16.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="10" line="1" para="4">That will be nearly two decades after suitcase bombs, which allegedly originated in western Canada, killed two baggage handlers in Japan and 329 passengers on Air India Flight 182 off the Irish coast.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="10" line="1" para="5">Even before the verdict is pronounced, relatives of the 331 victims are calling for a public inquiry.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="10" line="1" para="6">Earlier calls for an official probe were stymied by the criminal investigation, and eventual trial of Ajaib Singh Bagri and Ripudaman Singh Malik.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="10" line="2" para="6">The two accused, immigrants from Punjab, were each charged with eight charges of murder and conspiracy.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="10" line="1" para="7">The massive case was the largest and most complex in Canadian history, with 18 months of pre-trial hearings, numerous related court hearings and a 19-month trial involving 113 witnesses and millions of documents.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="10" line="1" para="8">The trial itself took place behind bullet-resistant glass in a specially-built underground bunker of a courtroom in this west coast city.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="10" line="1" para="9">Prosecutors said Bagri and Malik were religious Sikh fundamentalists who used violence to achieve their political goals.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="10" line="1" para="10">Their motive in the bombings, said prosecution spokesman Geoffrey Gaul, was to avenge India's 1984 attack on the Golden Temple in Amritsar, and fight for an independent Sikh homeland to be called Khalistan.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="10" line="1" para="11">Prosecutors say two suitcase bombs were checked onto planes leaving Vancouver, connecting with Air India flights to London and Bangkok and New Delhi.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="10" line="1" para="12">On June 23, 1985, the first bomb killed two baggage handlers at Japan's Narita airport, as they transferred it to Air India Flight 201.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="10" line="2" para="12">The second exploded 54 minutes later aboard Air India Flight 182, killing all 329 aboard.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="10" line="1" para="13">Defence lawyers maintain their clients are innocent and prosecution witnesses were either lying or delusional.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="10" line="1" para="14">&quot;The witnesses weren't credible,&quot; said Malik's lawyer David Crossin.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="10" line="2" para="14">&quot;Their case collapsed.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence doc="10" line="1" para="15">So far, only Inderjit Singh Reyat, an immigrant to Canada, has been punished for the 1985 terrorism.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="10" line="2" para="15">He was convicted in 1991 for providing materials for the bomb at Tokyo's Narita airport.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="10" line="1" para="16">In 2003, he also pled guilty to manslaughter in the Flight 182 bombing.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="10" line="2" para="16">He is serving two sentences totalling 15 years.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="10" line="3" para="16">The alleged mastermind of the plot, Tarwinder Singh Parma, died in a 1992 police shootout in India.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="10" line="1" para="17">With the trial of Bagri and Malik now over, it's past time for an inquiry into the bombings, said Perviz Madon, whose husband Sam, a college professor, died aboard Air India on June 23, 1985.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="10" line="1" para="18">&quot;I am so tired, but we need the answers,&quot; said Madon.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="10" line="1" para="19">Relatives believe that if the details of the Air India bombings had emerged immediately, global airline practices would have changed before the 1988 bombing of Pan Am Flight 103 over Lockerbie, Scotland, in which 270 people died.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="10" line="1" para="20">In both disasters, critics blamed lax airport and airline security.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="10" line="1" para="21">A public inquiry would also investigate how police and intelligence agents handled the Air India case, which was plagued by infighting between agencies and the erasure of evidence.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="10" line="1" para="22">Meanwhile, two potential witnesses were assassinated even before charges were laid.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="10" line="2" para="22">Fear of intimidation in Canada's immigrant Sikh community has led to police protection for several prosecution witnesses.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="10" line="1" para="23">Some observers believe that even though the trial is over, more details of the case are lurking unseen.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="10" line="1" para="24">&quot;There are more people involved than the two people who are charged,&quot; said Dave Hayer, an British Columbia provincial legislator.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="10" line="1" para="25">Hayers father, Tara Singh Hayer, publisher of a local Sikh newspaper, was assassinated in 1998 before he could give evidence involving Bagri.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="10" line="2" para="25">No one has been charged with the murder.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="10" line="1" para="26">&quot;Many people are not willing to talk, theyre still afraid,&quot; Hayer said.</sentence>
	</Sentences>
	<Words>
		<word count="70" text="on"/>
		<word count="67" text="the"/>
		<word count="67" text="bagri"/>
		<word count="65" text="bomb"/>
		<word count="65" text="india"/>
		<word count="64" text="malik"/>
		<word count="63" text="said"/>
		<word count="63" text="sikh"/>
		<word count="62" text="'s"/>
		<word count="59" text="for"/>
		<word count="54" text="wa"/>
		<word count="52" text="``"/>
		<word count="52" text="''"/>
		<word count="48" text="two"/>
		<word count="48" text="with"/>
		<word count="48" text="case"/>
		<word count="48" text="is"/>
		<word count="47" text="air"/>
		<word count="41" text="wit"/>
		<word count="38" text="by"/>
		<word count="37" text="singh"/>
		<word count="37" text="were"/>
		<word count="36" text="kill"/>
		<word count="32" text="who"/>
		<word count="31" text="flight"/>
		<word count="30" text="trial"/>
		<word count="29" text="at"/>
		<word count="27" text="an"/>
		<word count="27" text="from"/>
		<word count="27" text="had"/>
		<word count="26" text="ha"/>
		<word count="26" text="prosecutor"/>
		<word count="25" text="are"/>
		<word count="25" text="indian"/>
		<word count="24" text="attack"/>
		<word count="24" text="charg"/>
		<word count="24" text="have"/>
		<word count="24" text="he"/>
		<word count="24" text="prosecut"/>
		<word count="22" text="vancouv"/>
		<word count="22" text="also"/>
		<word count="22" text="be"/>
		<word count="21" text="peopl"/>
		<word count="21" text="year"/>
		<word count="21" text="govern"/>
		<word count="21" text="court"/>
		<word count="21" text="hi"/>
		<word count="20" text="it"/>
		<word count="20" text="their"/>
		<word count="20" text="lawyer"/>
		<word count="20" text="she"/>
		<word count="20" text="against"/>
		<word count="20" text="canadian"/>
		<word count="19" text="182"/>
		<word count="19" text="1985"/>
		<word count="19" text="airport"/>
		<word count="19" text="her"/>
		<word count="19" text="testifi"/>
		<word count="19" text="reveng"/>
		<word count="18" text="murder"/>
		<word count="18" text="been"/>
		<word count="18" text="which"/>
		<word count="18" text="million"/>
		<word count="18" text="motiv"/>
		<word count="18" text="will"/>
		<word count="17" text="thi"/>
		<word count="17" text="as"/>
		<word count="16" text="accus"/>
		<word count="16" text="not"/>
		<word count="15" text="defens"/>
		<word count="15" text="plane"/>
		<word count="15" text="templ"/>
		<word count="15" text="1984"/>
		<word count="15" text="polic"/>
		<word count="14" text="british"/>
		<word count="14" text="argument"/>
		<word count="14" text="evid"/>
		<word count="14" text="told"/>
		<word count="14" text="after"/>
		<word count="13" text="conspiraci"/>
		<word count="13" text="world"/>
		<word count="13" text="up"/>
		<word count="13" text="all"/>
		<word count="13" text="baggag"/>
		<word count="13" text="narita"/>
		<word count="13" text="more"/>
		<word count="13" text="they"/>
		<word count="12" text="329"/>
		<word count="12" text="columbia"/>
		<word count="12" text="june"/>
		<word count="12" text="polit"/>
		<word count="12" text="befor"/>
		<word count="12" text="bellow"/>
		<word count="11" text="jet"/>
		<word count="11" text="final"/>
		<word count="11" text="23"/>
		<word count="11" text="handler"/>
		<word count="11" text="than"/>
		<word count="11" text="we"/>
		<word count="11" text="We"/>
		<word count="11" text="He"/>
		<word count="11" text="call"/>
		<word count="11" text="josephson"/>
		<word count="11" text="canada"/>
		<word count="11" text="testimoni"/>
		<word count="11" text="say"/>
		<word count="11" text="plot"/>
		<word count="10" text="ripudaman"/>
		<word count="10" text="ajaib"/>
		<word count="10" text="airlin"/>
		<word count="10" text="terror"/>
		<word count="10" text="state"/>
		<word count="10" text="off"/>
		<word count="10" text="coast"/>
		<word count="10" text="aboard"/>
		<word count="10" text="began"/>
		<word count="10" text="US"/>
		<word count="10" text="argu"/>
		<word count="10" text="woman"/>
		<word count="10" text="close"/>
		<word count="10" text="him"/>
		<word count="10" text="part"/>
		<word count="10" text="but"/>
		<word count="10" text="would"/>
		<word count="10" text="A"/>
		<word count="10" text="die"/>
		<word count="10" text="explod"/>
		<word count="10" text="both"/>
		<word count="10" text="alleg"/>
		<word count="9" text="millionair"/>
		<word count="9" text="2001"/>
		<word count="9" text="sinc"/>
		<word count="9" text="month"/>
		<word count="9" text="2003"/>
		<word count="9" text="group"/>
		<word count="9" text="new"/>
		<word count="9" text="hayer"/>
		<word count="9" text="involv"/>
		<word count="9" text="suitcas"/>
		<word count="9" text="wright"/>
		<word count="8" text="credibl"/>
		<word count="8" text="count"/>
		<word count="8" text="11"/>
		<word count="8" text="toronto"/>
		<word count="8" text="irish"/>
		<word count="8" text="hear"/>
		<word count="8" text="work"/>
		<word count="8" text="time"/>
		<word count="8" text="expect"/>
		<word count="8" text="one"/>
		<word count="8" text="protect"/>
		<word count="8" text="can"/>
		<word count="8" text="do"/>
		<word count="8" text="In"/>
		<word count="8" text="until"/>
		<word count="8" text="assassin"/>
		<word count="8" text="ian"/>
		<word count="8" text="parmar"/>
		<word count="8" text="immigr"/>
		<word count="8" text="golden"/>
		<word count="8" text="investig"/>
		<word count="7" text="men"/>
		<word count="7" text="20"/>
		<word count="7" text="worker"/>
		<word count="7" text="worst"/>
		<word count="7" text="london"/>
		<word count="7" text="tokyo"/>
		<word count="7" text="believ"/>
		<word count="7" text="over"/>
		<word count="7" text="crossin"/>
		<word count="7" text="york"/>
		<word count="7" text="confess"/>
		<word count="7" text="take"/>
		<word count="7" text="there"/>
		<word count="7" text="citi"/>
		<word count="7" text="khalistan"/>
		<word count="7" text="independ"/>
		<word count="7" text="death"/>
		<word count="7" text="judg"/>
		<word count="7" text="what"/>
		<word count="7" text="septemb"/>
		<word count="7" text="later"/>
		<word count="7" text="amritsar"/>
		<word count="7" text="justic"/>
		<word count="7" text="reyat"/>
		<word count="7" text="guilti"/>
		<word count="6" text="mill"/>
		<word count="6" text="first"/>
		<word count="6" text="act"/>
		<word count="6" text="prior"/>
		<word count="6" text="unit"/>
		<word count="6" text="boe"/>
		<word count="6" text="747"/>
		<word count="6" text="blew"/>
		<word count="6" text="day"/>
		<word count="6" text="april"/>
		<word count="6" text="end"/>
		<word count="6" text="It"/>
		<word count="6" text="last"/>
		<word count="6" text="into"/>
		<word count="6" text="built"/>
		<word count="6" text="former"/>
		<word count="6" text="employe"/>
		<word count="6" text="nobodi"/>
		<word count="6" text="man"/>
		<word count="6" text="member"/>
		<word count="6" text="milit"/>
		<word count="6" text="paid"/>
		<word count="6" text="homeland"/>
		<word count="6" text="prime"/>
		<word count="6" text="origin"/>
		<word count="6" text="1992"/>
		<word count="6" text="newspap"/>
		<word count="6" text="publish"/>
		<word count="6" text="allegedli"/>
		<word count="6" text="team"/>
		<word count="6" text="punjab"/>
		<word count="6" text="second"/>
		<word count="6" text="other"/>
		<word count="6" text="most"/>
		<word count="6" text="nearli"/>
		<word count="6" text="suspect"/>
		<word count="6" text="monday"/>
		<word count="6" text="onli"/>
		<word count="6" text="religi"/>
		<word count="6" text="use"/>
		<word count="6" text="speech"/>
		<word count="6" text="cairn"/>
		<word count="5" text="tuesday"/>
		<word count="5" text="multipl"/>
		<word count="5" text="connect"/>
		<word count="5" text="suprem"/>
		<word count="5" text="cost"/>
		<word count="5" text="courtroom"/>
		<word count="5" text="secur"/>
		<word count="5" text="hing"/>
		<word count="5" text="becaus"/>
		<word count="5" text="disgruntl"/>
		<word count="5" text="public"/>
		<word count="5" text="name"/>
		<word count="5" text="crash"/>
		<word count="5" text="anoth"/>
		<word count="5" text="extremist"/>
		<word count="5" text="no"/>
		<word count="5" text="contend"/>
		<word count="5" text="hindu"/>
		<word count="5" text="minist"/>
		<word count="5" text="indira"/>
		<word count="5" text="gandhi"/>
		<word count="5" text="luggag"/>
		<word count="5" text="talwind"/>
		<word count="5" text="mastermind"/>
		<word count="5" text="shootout"/>
		<word count="5" text="defenc"/>
		<word count="5" text="terrorist"/>
		<word count="5" text="japan"/>
		<word count="5" text="plant"/>
		<word count="5" text="bruce"/>
		<word count="5" text="verdict"/>
		<word count="5" text="ticket"/>
		<word count="5" text="check"/>
		<word count="5" text="inderjit"/>
		<word count="5" text="prison"/>
		<word count="5" text="convict"/>
		<word count="5" text="doubt"/>
		<word count="5" text="week"/>
		<word count="5" text="so"/>
		<word count="5" text="innoc"/>
		<word count="5" text="still"/>
		<word count="5" text="key"/>
		<word count="5" text="like"/>
		<word count="5" text="friday"/>
		<word count="5" text="march"/>
		<word count="5" text="gaul"/>
		<word count="4" text="jumbo"/>
		<word count="4" text="ago"/>
		<word count="4" text="star"/>
		<word count="4" text="57"/>
		<word count="4" text="kamloop"/>
		<word count="4" text="55"/>
		<word count="4" text="via"/>
		<word count="4" text="arrest"/>
		<word count="4" text="2000"/>
		<word count="4" text="madon"/>
		<word count="4" text="husband"/>
		<word count="4" text="want"/>
		<word count="4" text="heard"/>
		<word count="4" text="david"/>
		<word count="4" text="person"/>
		<word count="4" text="relationship"/>
		<word count="4" text="anyth"/>
		<word count="4" text="or"/>
		<word count="4" text="outsid"/>
		<word count="4" text="crime"/>
		<word count="4" text="without"/>
		<word count="4" text="raid"/>
		<word count="4" text="madison"/>
		<word count="4" text="squar"/>
		<word count="4" text="garden"/>
		<word count="4" text="organ"/>
		<word count="4" text="50,000"/>
		<word count="4" text="rest"/>
		<word count="4" text="howev"/>
		<word count="4" text="contain"/>
		<word count="4" text="maintain"/>
		<word count="4" text="behind"/>
		<word count="4" text="tara"/>
		<word count="4" text="1988"/>
		<word count="4" text="1995"/>
		<word count="4" text="friend"/>
		<word count="4" text="On"/>
		<word count="4" text="follow"/>
		<word count="4" text="each"/>
		<word count="4" text="eight"/>
		<word count="4" text="transfer"/>
		<word count="4" text="decis"/>
		<word count="4" text="pair"/>
		<word count="4" text="onto"/>
		<word count="4" text="sentenc"/>
		<word count="4" text="explos"/>
		<word count="4" text="manslaught"/>
		<word count="4" text="materi"/>
		<word count="4" text="ask"/>
		<word count="4" text="deliv"/>
		<word count="4" text="mani"/>
		<word count="4" text="terribl"/>
		<word count="4" text="these"/>
		<word count="4" text="three"/>
		<word count="4" text="while"/>
		<word count="4" text="arrang"/>
		<word count="4" text="bag"/>
		<word count="4" text="331"/>
		<word count="4" text="detail"/>
		<word count="4" text="earlier"/>
		<word count="4" text="rule"/>
		<word count="4" text="sever"/>
		<word count="4" text="histori"/>
		<word count="4" text="glass"/>
		<word count="4" text="rel"/>
		<word count="4" text="gave"/>
		<word count="4" text="shrine"/>
		<word count="4" text="that"/>
		<word count="4" text="made"/>
		<word count="4" text="intellig"/>
		<word count="4" text="agent"/>
		<word count="4" text="sikhism"/>
		<word count="4" text="whose"/>
		<word count="4" text="go"/>
		<word count="4" text="I"/>
		<word count="3" text="stretch"/>
		<word count="3" text="degre"/>
		<word count="3" text="way"/>
		<word count="3" text="custodi"/>
		<word count="3" text="late"/>
		<word count="3" text="blast"/>
		<word count="3" text="32"/>
		<word count="3" text="perviz"/>
		<word count="3" text="lost"/>
		<word count="3" text="sam"/>
		<word count="3" text="defend"/>
		<word count="3" text="order"/>
		<word count="3" text="wrote"/>
		<word count="3" text="diari"/>
		<word count="3" text="much"/>
		<word count="3" text="ident"/>
		<word count="3" text="own"/>
		<word count="3" text="interest"/>
		<word count="3" text="our"/>
		<word count="3" text="thousand"/>
		<word count="3" text="reportedli"/>
		<word count="3" text="creation"/>
		<word count="3" text="spoke"/>
		<word count="3" text="need"/>
		<word count="3" text="wage"/>
		<word count="3" text="document"/>
		<word count="3" text="then"/>
		<word count="3" text="If"/>
		<word count="3" text="babbar"/>
		<word count="3" text="khalsa"/>
		<word count="3" text="start"/>
		<word count="3" text="critic"/>
		<word count="3" text="purew"/>
		<word count="3" text="delhi"/>
		<word count="3" text="hour"/>
		<word count="3" text="fundamentalist"/>
		<word count="3" text="place"/>
		<word count="3" text="separatist"/>
		<word count="3" text="fight"/>
		<word count="3" text="continu"/>
		<word count="3" text="complex"/>
		<word count="3" text="base"/>
		<word count="3" text="held"/>
		<word count="3" text="bullet-resist"/>
		<word count="3" text="third"/>
		<word count="3" text="plead"/>
		<word count="3" text="borrow"/>
		<word count="3" text="car"/>
		<word count="3" text="first-degre"/>
		<word count="3" text="guilt"/>
		<word count="3" text="zealotri"/>
		<word count="3" text="admiss"/>
		<word count="3" text="here"/>
		<word count="3" text="expert"/>
		<word count="3" text="wrap"/>
		<word count="3" text="passeng"/>
		<word count="3" text="client"/>
		<word count="3" text="victim"/>
		<word count="3" text="home"/>
		<word count="3" text="provid"/>
		<word count="3" text="aveng"/>
		<word count="3" text="next"/>
		<word count="3" text="juri"/>
		<word count="3" text="dure"/>
		<word count="3" text="far"/>
		<word count="3" text="activist"/>
		<word count="3" text="minut"/>
		<word count="3" text="option"/>
		<word count="3" text="question"/>
		<word count="3" text="could"/>
		<word count="3" text="such"/>
		<word count="3" text="includ"/>
		<word count="3" text="earli"/>
		<word count="3" text="some"/>
		<word count="3" text="role"/>
		<word count="3" text="holiest"/>
		<word count="3" text="desir"/>
		<word count="3" text="tri"/>
		<word count="3" text="n't"/>
		<word count="3" text="16"/>
		<word count="3" text="wait"/>
		<word count="3" text="led"/>
		<word count="3" text="geoffrey"/>
		<word count="3" text="113"/>
		<word count="3" text="even"/>
		<word count="3" text="inquiri"/>
		<word count="2" text="almost"/>
		<word count="2" text="enter"/>
		<word count="2" text="same"/>
		<word count="2" text="13"/>
		<word count="2" text="80"/>
		<word count="2" text="euro64"/>
		<word count="2" text="'re"/>
		<word count="2" text="tire"/>
		<word count="2" text="5"/>
		<word count="2" text="specif"/>
		<word count="2" text="precaut"/>
		<word count="2" text="assert"/>
		<word count="2" text="lack"/>
		<word count="2" text="stand"/>
		<word count="2" text="did"/>
		<word count="2" text="columbia-bas"/>
		<word count="2" text="view"/>
		<word count="2" text="appear"/>
		<word count="2" text="concret"/>
		<word count="2" text="gather"/>
		<word count="2" text="where"/>
		<word count="2" text="propos"/>
		<word count="2" text="war"/>
		<word count="2" text="exact"/>
		<word count="2" text="accord"/>
		<word count="2" text="releas"/>
		<word count="2" text="incit"/>
		<word count="2" text="ontario"/>
		<word count="2" text="posit"/>
		<word count="2" text="join"/>
		<word count="2" text="mysteri"/>
		<word count="2" text="dog"/>
		<word count="2" text="vancouver-area"/>
		<word count="2" text="outspoken"/>
		<word count="2" text="extrem"/>
		<word count="2" text="crippl"/>
		<word count="2" text="shot"/>
		<word count="2" text="1998"/>
		<word count="2" text="shoot"/>
		<word count="2" text="tarsem"/>
		<word count="2" text="britain"/>
		<word count="2" text="biggest"/>
		<word count="2" text="punjabi"/>
		<word count="2" text="weekli"/>
		<word count="2" text="begin"/>
		<word count="2" text="crucial"/>
		<word count="2" text="businessman"/>
		<word count="2" text="rural"/>
		<word count="2" text="northern"/>
		<word count="2" text="bangkok"/>
		<word count="2" text="less"/>
		<word count="2" text="montreal"/>
		<word count="2" text="board"/>
		<word count="2" text="though"/>
		<word count="2" text="long"/>
		<word count="2" text="trade"/>
		<word count="2" text="center"/>
		<word count="2" text="carri"/>
		<word count="2" text="bent"/>
		<word count="2" text="punish"/>
		<word count="2" text="armi"/>
		<word count="2" text="holi"/>
		<word count="2" text="At"/>
		<word count="2" text="By"/>
		<word count="2" text="record"/>
		<word count="2" text="dollar"/>
		<word count="2" text="vast"/>
		<word count="2" text="warehous"/>
		<word count="2" text="secret"/>
		<word count="2" text="kanishka"/>
		<word count="2" text="haul"/>
		<word count="2" text="ocean"/>
		<word count="2" text="receiv"/>
		<word count="2" text="women"/>
		<word count="2" text="onc"/>
		<word count="2" text="love"/>
		<word count="2" text="under"/>
		<word count="2" text="ban"/>
		<word count="2" text="potenti"/>
		<word count="2" text="threat"/>
		<word count="2" text="beyond"/>
		<word count="2" text="reason"/>
		<word count="2" text="robert"/>
		<word count="2" text="proven"/>
		<word count="2" text="event"/>
		<word count="2" text="..."/>
		<word count="2" text="note"/>
		<word count="2" text="someth"/>
		<word count="2" text="them"/>
		<word count="2" text="ultim"/>
		<word count="2" text="piec"/>
		<word count="2" text="deni"/>
		<word count="2" text="suppos"/>
		<word count="2" text="simultan"/>
		<word count="2" text="pan"/>
		<word count="2" text="Am"/>
		<word count="2" text="103"/>
		<word count="2" text="lockerbi"/>
		<word count="2" text="scotland"/>
		<word count="2" text="270"/>
		<word count="2" text="arguement"/>
		<word count="2" text="conspir"/>
		<word count="2" text="orthodox"/>
		<word count="2" text="1980"/>
		<word count="2" text="aircraft"/>
		<word count="2" text="proof"/>
		<word count="2" text="financi"/>
		<word count="2" text="circumstanti"/>
		<word count="2" text="alon"/>
		<word count="2" text="happen"/>
		<word count="2" text="100"/>
		<word count="2" text="special"/>
		<word count="2" text="bulletproof"/>
		<word count="2" text="outcom"/>
		<word count="2" text="--"/>
		<word count="2" text="57-year-old"/>
		<word count="2" text="56-year-old"/>
		<word count="2" text="preacher"/>
		<word count="2" text="54"/>
		<word count="2" text="down"/>
		<word count="2" text="trim"/>
		<word count="2" text="how"/>
		<word count="2" text="answer"/>
		<word count="2" text="chose"/>
		<word count="2" text="taken"/>
		<word count="2" text="violenc"/>
		<word count="2" text="few"/>
		<word count="2" text="shown"/>
		<word count="2" text="give"/>
		<word count="2" text="make"/>
		<word count="2" text="statement"/>
		<word count="2" text="servic"/>
		<word count="2" text="identifi"/>
		<word count="2" text="done"/>
		<word count="2" text="admit"/>
		<word count="2" text="come"/>
		<word count="2" text="purchas"/>
		<word count="2" text="eventu"/>
		<word count="2" text="author"/>
		<word count="2" text="back"/>
		<word count="2" text="numer"/>
		<word count="2" text="tape"/>
		<word count="2" text="meanwhil"/>
		<word count="2" text="royal"/>
		<word count="2" text="mount"/>
		<word count="2" text="intern"/>
		<word count="2" text="global"/>
		<word count="2" text="driven"/>
		<word count="2" text="ambit"/>
		<word count="2" text="joe"/>
		<word count="2" text="felt"/>
		<word count="2" text="sacrileg"/>
		<word count="2" text="commit"/>
		<word count="2" text="religion"/>
		<word count="2" text="bodyguard"/>
		<word count="2" text="famili"/>
		<word count="2" text="teach"/>
		<word count="2" text="lesson"/>
		<word count="2" text="approach"/>
		<word count="2" text="child"/>
		<word count="2" text="mean"/>
		<word count="2" text="noth"/>
		<word count="2" text="show"/>
		<word count="2" text="five"/>
		<word count="2" text="discredit"/>
		<word count="2" text="crown"/>
		<word count="2" text="conclud"/>
		<word count="2" text="fieri"/>
		<word count="2" text="richard"/>
		<word count="2" text="point"/>
		<word count="2" text="target"/>
		<word count="2" text="if"/>
		<word count="2" text="2005"/>
		<word count="2" text="attend"/>
		<word count="2" text="think"/>
		<word count="2" text="between"/>
		<word count="2" text="spokesman"/>
		<word count="2" text="total"/>
		<word count="2" text="strike"/>
		<word count="2" text="massiv"/>
		<word count="2" text="western"/>
		<word count="2" text="relat"/>
		<word count="2" text="offic"/>
		<word count="2" text="specially-built"/>
		<word count="2" text="underground"/>
		<word count="2" text="leav"/>
		<word count="2" text="pled"/>
		<word count="1" text="sept."/>
		<word count="1" text="see"/>
		<word count="1" text="closur"/>
		<word count="1" text="god"/>
		<word count="1" text="sake"/>
		<word count="1" text="decemb"/>
		<word count="1" text="euro4"/>
		<word count="1" text="least"/>
		<word count="1" text="ulterior"/>
		<word count="1" text="program"/>
		<word count="1" text="bar"/>
		<word count="1" text="fall"/>
		<word count="1" text="suggest"/>
		<word count="1" text="natur"/>
		<word count="1" text="fals"/>
		<word count="1" text="profound"/>
		<word count="1" text="jersey"/>
		<word count="1" text="ga"/>
		<word count="1" text="station"/>
		<word count="1" text="whom"/>
		<word count="1" text="365,000"/>
		<word count="1" text="euro293,000"/>
		<word count="1" text="substanti"/>
		<word count="1" text="deal"/>
		<word count="1" text="bank"/>
		<word count="1" text="boycot"/>
		<word count="1" text="inconceiv"/>
		<word count="1" text="anyon"/>
		<word count="1" text="particip"/>
		<word count="1" text="accept"/>
		<word count="1" text="may"/>
		<word count="1" text="acquit"/>
		<word count="1" text="founder"/>
		<word count="1" text="novemb"/>
		<word count="1" text="___"/>
		<word count="1" text="net"/>
		<word count="1" text="http//www.airindiatrial.ca"/>
		<word count="1" text="set"/>
		<word count="1" text="mid-air"/>
		<word count="1" text="left"/>
		<word count="1" text="dead"/>
		<word count="1" text="present"/>
		<word count="1" text="airborn"/>
		<word count="1" text="301"/>
		<word count="1" text="ireland"/>
		<word count="1" text="rip"/>
		<word count="1" text="through"/>
		<word count="1" text="flew"/>
		<word count="1" text="separ"/>
		<word count="1" text="mile"/>
		<word count="1" text="hijack"/>
		<word count="1" text="four"/>
		<word count="1" text="out"/>
		<word count="1" text="foreign"/>
		<word count="1" text="1983"/>
		<word count="1" text="sikhdom"/>
		<word count="1" text="render"/>
		<word count="1" text="old"/>
		<word count="1" text="unlik"/>
		<word count="1" text="chapter"/>
		<word count="1" text="construct"/>
		<word count="1" text="interview"/>
		<word count="1" text="phone"/>
		<word count="1" text="surveil"/>
		<word count="1" text="7.5"/>
		<word count="1" text="5.6"/>
		<word count="1" text="bunker-lik"/>
		<word count="1" text="bomb-proof"/>
		<word count="1" text="especi"/>
		<word count="1" text="design"/>
		<word count="1" text="remot"/>
		<word count="1" text="annex"/>
		<word count="1" text="locat"/>
		<word count="1" text="within"/>
		<word count="1" text="skeleton"/>
		<word count="1" text="bed"/>
		<word count="1" text="atlant"/>
		<word count="1" text="ship"/>
		<word count="1" text="reconstruct"/>
		<word count="1" text="bought"/>
		<word count="1" text="10"/>
		<word count="1" text="suppli"/>
		<word count="1" text="five-year"/>
		<word count="1" text="partli"/>
		<word count="1" text="confid"/>
		<word count="1" text="reiter"/>
		<word count="1" text="about"/>
		<word count="1" text="shield"/>
		<word count="1" text="journalist"/>
		<word count="1" text="emperor"/>
		<word count="1" text="ruler"/>
		<word count="1" text="christ"/>
		<word count="1" text="travel"/>
		<word count="1" text="euro3.9"/>
		<word count="1" text="room"/>
		<word count="1" text="open"/>
		<word count="1" text="submiss"/>
		<word count="1" text="consist"/>
		<word count="1" text="larg"/>
		<word count="1" text="us365,000"/>
		<word count="1" text="euro285,000"/>
		<word count="1" text="given"/>
		<word count="1" text="book"/>
		<word count="1" text="salvag"/>
		<word count="1" text="reassembl"/>
		<word count="1" text="fabric"/>
		<word count="1" text="film"/>
		<word count="1" text="footag"/>
		<word count="1" text="floor"/>
		<word count="1" text="result"/>
		<word count="1" text="deadliest"/>
		<word count="1" text="singl"/>
		<word count="1" text="among"/>
		<word count="1" text="turbul"/>
		<word count="1" text="campaign"/>
		<word count="1" text="crackdown"/>
		<word count="1" text="robin"/>
		<word count="1" text="drive"/>
		<word count="1" text="depart"/>
		<word count="1" text="rang"/>
		<word count="1" text="assist"/>
		<word count="1" text="attempt"/>
		<word count="1" text="interfer"/>
		<word count="1" text="trust"/>
		<word count="1" text="ad"/>
		<word count="1" text="explan"/>
		<word count="1" text="reli"/>
		<word count="1" text="spend"/>
		<word count="1" text="complic"/>
		<word count="1" text="reserv"/>
		<word count="1" text="possibl"/>
		<word count="1" text="plung"/>
		<word count="1" text="water"/>
		<word count="1" text="resolv"/>
		<word count="1" text="climact"/>
		<word count="1" text="phase"/>
		<word count="1" text="proceed"/>
		<word count="1" text="seriou"/>
		<word count="1" text="high-secur"/>
		<word count="1" text="6"/>
		<word count="1" text="complet"/>
		<word count="1" text="dock"/>
		<word count="1" text="encas"/>
		<word count="1" text="age"/>
		<word count="1" text="came"/>
		<word count="1" text="away"/>
		<word count="1" text="sri"/>
		<word count="1" text="lanka"/>
		<word count="1" text="watch"/>
		<word count="1" text="galleri"/>
		<word count="1" text="settl"/>
		<word count="1" text="bungl"/>
		<word count="1" text="unexplain"/>
		<word count="1" text="import"/>
		<word count="1" text="addit"/>
		<word count="1" text="offer"/>
		<word count="1" text="vagu"/>
		<word count="1" text="contradictori"/>
		<word count="1" text="recollect"/>
		<word count="1" text="real"/>
		<word count="1" text="estat"/>
		<word count="1" text="entrepreneur"/>
		<word count="1" text="sawmil"/>
		<word count="1" text="en"/>
		<word count="1" text="rout"/>
		<word count="1" text="went"/>
		<word count="1" text="H."/>
		<word count="1" text="chief"/>
		<word count="1" text="sum"/>
		<word count="1" text="difficult"/>
		<word count="1" text="comprehend"/>
		<word count="1" text="worn"/>
		<word count="1" text="white"/>
		<word count="1" text="tunic"/>
		<word count="1" text="recruit"/>
		<word count="1" text="3,000"/>
		<word count="1" text="pick"/>
		<word count="1" text="aim"/>
		<word count="1" text="wear"/>
		<word count="1" text="dark"/>
		<word count="1" text="turban"/>
		<word count="1" text="neither"/>
		<word count="1" text="nor"/>
		<word count="1" text="storm"/>
		<word count="1" text="spark"/>
		<word count="1" text="cascad"/>
		<word count="1" text="physic"/>
		<word count="1" text="firsthand"/>
		<word count="1" text="link"/>
		<word count="1" text="reach"/>
		<word count="1" text="stori"/>
		<word count="1" text="video"/>
		<word count="1" text="incendiari"/>
		<word count="1" text="ralli"/>
		<word count="1" text="juli"/>
		<word count="1" text="associ"/>
		<word count="1" text="highlight"/>
		<word count="1" text="visit"/>
		<word count="1" text="night"/>
		<word count="1" text="drop"/>
		<word count="1" text="impli"/>
		<word count="1" text="wrongdo"/>
		<word count="1" text="rememb"/>
		<word count="1" text="should"/>
		<word count="1" text="pressur"/>
		<word count="1" text="school"/>
		<word count="1" text="direct"/>
		<word count="1" text="1996"/>
		<word count="1" text="1997"/>
		<word count="1" text="strong"/>
		<word count="1" text="platon"/>
		<word count="1" text="help"/>
		<word count="1" text="pickup"/>
		<word count="1" text="distanc"/>
		<word count="1" text="herself"/>
		<word count="1" text="subject"/>
		<word count="1" text="fire"/>
		<word count="1" text="hamper"/>
		<word count="1" text="fact"/>
		<word count="1" text="main"/>
		<word count="1" text="ringlead"/>
		<word count="1" text="resid"/>
		<word count="1" text="when"/>
		<word count="1" text="caught"/>
		<word count="1" text="clandestin"/>
		<word count="1" text="cross"/>
		<word count="1" text="pakistan"/>
		<word count="1" text="overheard"/>
		<word count="1" text="gun"/>
		<word count="1" text="suburb"/>
		<word count="1" text="error"/>
		<word count="1" text="withdrew"/>
		<word count="1" text="infiltr"/>
		<word count="1" text="rank"/>
		<word count="1" text="eras"/>
		<word count="1" text="convers"/>
		<word count="1" text="intercept"/>
		<word count="1" text="realiz"/>
		<word count="1" text="signific"/>
		<word count="1" text="fail"/>
		<word count="1" text="appar"/>
		<word count="1" text="feel"/>
		<word count="1" text="deep"/>
		<word count="1" text="sens"/>
		<word count="1" text="betray"/>
		<word count="1" text="lata"/>
		<word count="1" text="pada"/>
		<word count="1" text="choreograph"/>
		<word count="1" text="daughter"/>
		<word count="1" text="woken"/>
		<word count="1" text="realiti"/>
		<word count="1" text="yard"/>
		<word count="1" text="claim"/>
		<word count="1" text="live"/>
		<word count="1" text="power"/>
		<word count="1" text="pervas"/>
		<word count="1" text="pivot"/>
		<word count="1" text="hundr"/>
		<word count="1" text="ignit"/>
		<word count="1" text="emot"/>
		<word count="1" text="co-conspir"/>
		<word count="1" text="destroy"/>
		<word count="1" text="messag"/>
		<word count="1" text="convey"/>
		<word count="1" text="reaction"/>
		<word count="1" text="As"/>
		<word count="1" text="dress"/>
		<word count="1" text="tradit"/>
		<word count="1" text="garb"/>
		<word count="1" text="doze"/>
		<word count="1" text="box"/>
		<word count="1" text="prais"/>
		<word count="1" text="bomb-mak"/>
		<word count="1" text="support"/>
		<word count="1" text="further"/>
		<word count="1" text="fought"/>
		<word count="1" text="recount"/>
		<word count="1" text="attach"/>
		<word count="1" text="recal"/>
		<word count="1" text="quot"/>
		<word count="1" text="To"/>
		<word count="1" text="matter"/>
		<word count="1" text="task"/>
		<word count="1" text="leader"/>
		<word count="1" text="photograph"/>
		<word count="1" text="intim"/>
		<word count="1" text="femal"/>
		<word count="1" text="highli"/>
		<word count="1" text="mid-decemb"/>
		<word count="1" text="legal"/>
		<word count="1" text="us80"/>
		<word count="1" text="euro62"/>
		<word count="1" text="55-year-old"/>
		<word count="1" text="bargri"/>
		<word count="1" text="high-rank"/>
		<word count="1" text="retribut"/>
		<word count="1" text="refer"/>
		<word count="1" text="proce"/>
		<word count="1" text="weapon"/>
		<word count="1" text="exhort"/>
		<word count="1" text="crowd"/>
		<word count="1" text="advoc"/>
		<word count="1" text="amount"/>
		<word count="1" text="oratori"/>
		<word count="1" text="respons"/>
		<word count="1" text="comment"/>
		<word count="1" text="'we"/>
		<word count="1" text="stuff"/>
		<word count="1" text="blow"/>
		<word count="1" text="block"/>
		<word count="1" text="repeat"/>
		<word count="1" text="386,000"/>
		<word count="1" text="euro298,000"/>
		<word count="1" text="exhaust"/>
		<word count="1" text="expens"/>
		<word count="1" text="contradict"/>
		<word count="1" text="announc"/>
		<word count="1" text="115"/>
		<word count="1" text="euro75"/>
		<word count="1" text="53"/>
		<word count="1" text="bombmak"/>
		<word count="1" text="alreadi"/>
		<word count="1" text="son"/>
		<word count="1" text="eddi"/>
		<word count="1" text="regularli"/>
		<word count="1" text="hard"/>
		<word count="1" text="let"/>
		<word count="1" text="just"/>
		<word count="1" text="hope"/>
		<word count="1" text="worth"/>
		<word count="1" text="refug"/>
		<word count="1" text="zealot"/>
		<word count="1" text="creat"/>
		<word count="1" text="region"/>
		<word count="1" text="must"/>
		<word count="1" text="decid"/>
		<word count="1" text="conflict"/>
		<word count="1" text="peck"/>
		<word count="1" text="trek"/>
		<word count="1" text="across"/>
		<word count="1" text="expans"/>
		<word count="1" text="knowledg"/>
		<word count="1" text="experi"/>
		<word count="1" text="law"/>
		<word count="1" text="logist"/>
		<word count="1" text="nightmar"/>
		<word count="1" text="ever"/>
		<word count="1" text="again"/>
		<word count="1" text="countri"/>
		<word count="1" text="perhap"/>
		<word count="1" text="'m"/>
		<word count="1" text="glad"/>
		<word count="1" text="202"/>
		<word count="1" text="178"/>
		<word count="1" text="around"/>
		<word count="1" text="lethal"/>
		<word count="1" text="19"/>
		<word count="1" text="side"/>
		<word count="1" text="score"/>
		<word count="1" text="reveal"/>
		<word count="1" text="japanes"/>
		<word count="1" text="john"/>
		<word count="1" text="ward"/>
		<word count="1" text="report"/>
		<word count="1" text="250"/>
		<word count="1" text="12"/>
		<word count="1" text="rcmp"/>
		<word count="1" text="yet"/>
		<word count="1" text="spokesperson"/>
		<word count="1" text="7.5-million-dollar"/>
		<word count="1" text="6.3"/>
		<word count="1" text="millwork"/>
		<word count="1" text="build"/>
		<word count="1" text="get"/>
		<word count="1" text="caus"/>
		<word count="1" text="elaps"/>
		<word count="1" text="emigr"/>
		<word count="1" text="stood"/>
		<word count="1" text="modern"/>
		<word count="1" text="overtaken"/>
		<word count="1" text="carnag"/>
		<word count="1" text="pentagon"/>
		<word count="1" text="sight"/>
		<word count="1" text="learn"/>
		<word count="1" text="whether"/>
		<word count="1" text="found"/>
		<word count="1" text="outrag"/>
		<word count="1" text="sap"/>
		<word count="1" text="coffer"/>
		<word count="1" text="decad"/>
		<word count="1" text="pronounc"/>
		<word count="1" text="offici"/>
		<word count="1" text="probe"/>
		<word count="1" text="stymi"/>
		<word count="1" text="crimin"/>
		<word count="1" text="largest"/>
		<word count="1" text="18"/>
		<word count="1" text="pre-trial"/>
		<word count="1" text="19-month"/>
		<word count="1" text="itself"/>
		<word count="1" text="took"/>
		<word count="1" text="bunker"/>
		<word count="1" text="west"/>
		<word count="1" text="achiev"/>
		<word count="1" text="goal"/>
		<word count="1" text="201"/>
		<word count="1" text="either"/>
		<word count="1" text="lie"/>
		<word count="1" text="delusion"/>
		<word count="1" text="collaps"/>
		<word count="1" text="So"/>
		<word count="1" text="1991"/>
		<word count="1" text="serv"/>
		<word count="1" text="15"/>
		<word count="1" text="tarwind"/>
		<word count="1" text="parma"/>
		<word count="1" text="now"/>
		<word count="1" text="past"/>
		<word count="1" text="colleg"/>
		<word count="1" text="professor"/>
		<word count="1" text="am"/>
		<word count="1" text="emerg"/>
		<word count="1" text="immedi"/>
		<word count="1" text="practic"/>
		<word count="1" text="chang"/>
		<word count="1" text="disast"/>
		<word count="1" text="blame"/>
		<word count="1" text="lax"/>
		<word count="1" text="handl"/>
		<word count="1" text="plagu"/>
		<word count="1" text="infight"/>
		<word count="1" text="agenc"/>
		<word count="1" text="erasur"/>
		<word count="1" text="laid"/>
		<word count="1" text="fear"/>
		<word count="1" text="intimid"/>
		<word count="1" text="commun"/>
		<word count="1" text="observ"/>
		<word count="1" text="lurk"/>
		<word count="1" text="unseen"/>
		<word count="1" text="dave"/>
		<word count="1" text="provinci"/>
		<word count="1" text="legisl"/>
		<word count="1" text="father"/>
		<word count="1" text="local"/>
		<word count="1" text="No"/>
		<word count="1" text="talk"/>
		<word count="1" text="theyr"/>
		<word count="1" text="afraid"/>
	</Words>
</Topic>
