<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<Topic id="D0942H">
	<Title>PRC's anti-secession law</Title>
	<Narrative>Report the developments in the PRC's enactment of an anti-secession law and reactions to that law.</Narrative>
	<DocSetA id="D0942H-A">
		<doc id="CNA_ENG_20050105.0024">TAIWAN TO MONITOR BEIJING-WASHINGTON TALKS ON ANTI-SECESSION LAW</doc>
		<doc id="CNA_ENG_20050121.0002">ANTI-SECESSION LAW A UNILATERAL ATTEMPT TO CHANGE STATUS QUO: CHEN</doc>
		<doc id="CNA_ENG_20050124.0045">BEIJING'S PROPOSED ANTI-SECESSION LAW HARMFUL TO CROSS-STRAIT TIES</doc>
		<doc id="CNA_ENG_20050214.0032">ANTI-SECESSION LAW COUNTERPRODUCTIVE TO CROSS-STRAIT PEACE: MINISTER</doc>
		<doc id="CNA_ENG_20050215.0032">OFFICIAL WARNS BEIJING AGAINST PUSHING TAIWAN TO REFERENDUM</doc>
		<doc id="CNA_ENG_20050222.0027">U.S. HOPES CHINA WILL PUT OFF 'ANTI-SECESSION LAW': AIT OFFICIAL</doc>
		<doc id="CNA_ENG_20050303.0008">LEGISLATURE TO PASS RESOLUTION AGAINST ANTI-SECESSION LAW</doc>
		<doc id="XIN_ENG_20050303.0410">URGENT: Anti-secession law not a &quot;war mobilization order&quot;: spokesman</doc>
		<doc id="XIN_ENG_20050307.0330">URGENT: Anti-Secession Law focuses on opposing, checking secessionist activities: lawmaker</doc>
		<doc id="AFP_ENG_20050307.0705">URGENT China says one-country, two systems its basic approach 
to Taiwan</doc>
	</DocSetA>
	<Sentences>
		<sentence doc="1" line="1" para="1">An official of the Cabinet-level Mainland Affairs Council (MAC) said Wednesday that the government will closely monitor developments in mainland China's communications with the United States about its plan to enact an anti-secession law.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="1" line="1" para="2">MAC Deputy Chairman Chiu Tai-shan made the remarks a day after Chen Yunlin, director of the Taiwan Affairs Office under Beijing's State Council, arrived in Washington to discuss with U.S. officials the details of the planned anti-secession law targeting Taiwan.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="1" line="1" para="3">The mainland's plan to promulgate an anti-secession law is not only a tremendous provocation of Taiwan but also a unilateral move to change the status quo across the Taiwan Strait, Chiu told reporters.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="1" line="1" para="4">Chiu said that the MAC, the top agency in charge of Taiwan's policies toward the mainland, has expressed on public occasions its strong opposition to the legislation aimed at legalizing Beijing's invasion of the country.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="1" line="1" para="5">Stressing that Taiwan is not part of the People's Republic of China as the Beijing authorities claim, Chiu said this is also the feeling of a majority of the people of Taiwan.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="1" line="1" para="6">Meanwhile, Michel Lu, spokesman of the Ministry of Foreign Affairs, said that officials of the Republic of China representative office in the United States will keep a close eye on developments.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="1" line="1" para="7">The government will also continue to express its opposition to the proposed anti-secession law, which, if passed, would offer a legal basis for Beijing to use force against Taiwan, Lu went on.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="1" line="1" para="8">The Standing Committee of the National People's Congress (NPC) agreed in late December to submit the draft bill to a NPC plenary session for deliberation in March this year.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="1" para="1">President Chen Shui-bian called for the nation Friday to seriously face Beijing's proposed anti-secession law which he said would undermine stability across the Taiwan Strait if enacted.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="1" para="2">The president made the remarks while reviewing the operations and capability of an army unit in Pingtung, southern Taiwan.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="1" para="3">Chen said that Beijing has been actively engaging in &quot;psychological, legal and media warfare&quot; in pushing to enact the anti-secession law, which he said is aimed at establishing a legal justification for a military invasion of Taiwan.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="1" para="4">The National People's Congress (NPC) Standing Committee late last year placed the anti-secession bill on the agenda for the annual session of the NPC set for this March.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="1" para="5">The president reiterated remarks he made in his New Year's address in which he condemned Beijing's plans to enact an anti-secession law as a unilateral attempt to change the status quo in the Taiwan Strait.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="2" line="2" para="5">Chen called the proposed law the biggest threat to regional stability and peace in the world.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="3" line="1" para="1">The enacting of an anti-secession law by Beijing will diminish cross-Taiwan Strait exchanges and thus will be harmful to the development of bilateral ties, a scholar said Monday.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="3" line="1" para="2">Shu Yung-ming, an assistant researcher with Academia Sinica, Taiwan's highest research institute, said in a seminar that the people of Taiwan will be afraid of visiting the mainland after the legislation is approved due to its ambiguous definition of secessionist activities.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="3" line="1" para="3">The people of Taiwan could be arrested when visiting the mainland because of remarks they might make in Taiwan and other areas that are considered by the Beijing authorities as violations of the proposed law, he explained.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="3" line="1" para="4">Besides, he went on, none of the candidates running for public office in Taiwan can avoid expressing their opposition to the proposed law during their campaigns under the country's current political circumstances.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="3" line="1" para="5">Furthermore, he continued, the enacting of the anti-secession law will squeeze the political space of those who actually support Taiwan's reunification with the mainland.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="4" line="1" para="1">Both the United States and the European Union think mainland China's planned anti-secession legislation is counterproductive to peace across the Taiwan Strait, Minister of Foreign Affairs Tan Sun Chen said Monday.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="4" line="1" para="2">Chen made the remarks after presiding over a Lunar New Year gathering at the Ministry of Foreign Affairs (MOFA) auditorium.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="4" line="1" para="3">He said the government sent six delegations to the United States, Japan and EU countries last year to brief officials, academics and opinion leaders on the adverse impact on cross-strait relations of Beijing's planned anti-secession law, which targets Taiwan.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="4" line="1" para="4">The MOFA has also instructed embassies and representative offices abroad to express to their host governments Taiwan's opposition to the proposed legislation, Chen said.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="4" line="1" para="5">The mainland's rubber-stamp parliament -- the National People's Congress -- is scheduled to screen the so-called anti-secession law in March.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="4" line="2" para="5">Chen said such a move could draw a backlash and protests from the people of Taiwan and could hinder cross-strait rapprochement.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="1" para="1">Mainland China is pushing Taiwan to decide through a referendum whether to &quot;separate from the mainland&quot; if it makes the &quot;one country, two systems&quot; or &quot;one China&quot; principle a part of its proposed anti-secession law, Mainland Affairs Council Chairman Joseph Wu said Tuesday.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="1" para="2">Speaking with a group of pro-Taiwan independence activists, Wu said Taiwan will have no choice other than to ask its people to decide in a referendum whether to unite with the mainland on Beijing's terms of &quot;one country, two systems&quot; or whether to accept the &quot;one China&quot; principle if Beijing enshrines either of them in its proposed law.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="1" para="3">He warned Beijing that the enactment of the so-called &quot;anti-secession law&quot; is a provocation and an attempt to change the status quo across the Taiwan Strait, which Taiwan will not tolerate.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="5" line="1" para="4">The pro-independence activists called on the government to respond strongly to Beijing's proposal to enact an anti-secession law designed to frighten Taiwan into giving up moves toward independence.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="1" para="1">The United States hopes mainland China will put off its plan to enact an &quot;anti-secession law&quot; to help temper the tension across the Taiwan Strait, an American Institute in Taiwan (AIT) official said Tuesday.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="1" para="2">Raymond F. Greene, chief of the political section at the AIT's Taipei office, made the remarks during a visit to the legislative caucus of the ruling Democratic Progressive Party (DPP), according to Lai Ching-teh, one of the caucus leaders.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="1" para="3">Greene expressed concern about the DPP's attitude toward the &quot;anti-secession law&quot; and whether it will promote a law to counteract it, Lai said.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="1" para="4">He also expressed worry that cross-strait tension will escalate as a result of the enactment of the law and any move by Taiwan to retaliate, Lai said.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="1" para="5">Lai told Greene that the DPP has repeatedly displayed goodwill to Beijing to try to improve cross-strait relations but it has to show its resolve to defend Taiwan's sovereignty in the face of the mainland's plan to introduce the &quot;anti-secession law.&quot;</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="1" para="6">While the DPP and its ally, the Taiwan Solidarity Union, will organize a demonstration for this purpose Feb. 28, they are likely to cooperate to propose a piece of counteracting legislation after the &quot;anti-secession law&quot; is passed, Lai said.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="1" para="7">Asked whether the &quot;anti-secession law&quot; is the reason behind the United States' and Japan's recent decision to list &quot;encouraging the peaceful resolution of issues concerning the Taiwan Strait through dialogue&quot; part of their common strategic objectives in the region, Greene said Washington has a long-standing concern over peace in the Asia-Pacific region and that this concern will not change because of the &quot;anti-secession law,&quot; according to Lai.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="6" line="1" para="8">Also during the visit, Greene expressed the hope that the Legislative Yuan will pass the budget for a NT$610.8 billion (US$18.23 billion) arms procurement package from the United States within this session.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="1" para="1">The Legislative Yuan will pass a resolution against Beijing's anti-secession legislation, Legislative Yuan Speaker Wang Jin-pyng said Thursday.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="1" para="2">Wang made the announcement after a cross-party consultative meeting to discuss certain critical legislative bills.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="7" line="1" para="3">During the meeting, Wang said, legislative whips of ruling and opposition parties reached a consensus on adopting a resolution to voice opposition to Beijing's so-called anti-secession law targeting Taiwan.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="8" line="1" para="1">The proposed anti-secession law,  which will be deliberated by China's top legislature, the National People's Congress (NPC), at its upcoming annual full session, is  by no means a so-called &quot;law on the use of force against Taiwan&quot;,  nor a so-called &quot;war mobilization order&quot;, a spokesman for the NPC  session said here Friday.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="9" line="1" para="1">China's enactment of the Anti- Secession Law, as part of the overarching principle, is to closely focus on the theme of opposing and checking the secessionist  activities of the &quot;Taiwan independence&quot; forces and promoting China 's peaceful reunification, a senior Chinese lawmaker said here  Tuesday.</sentence>
		<sentence doc="10" line="1" para="1">China Tuesday said that &quot;one country,  two systems&quot; is its basic approach to Taiwan as it outlined for the  first time its anti-secession law aimed at the island.</sentence>
	</Sentences>
	<Words>
		<word count="37" text="taiwan"/>
		<word count="32" text="'s"/>
		<word count="31" text="law"/>
		<word count="26" text="anti-secess"/>
		<word count="25" text="said"/>
		<word count="18" text="it"/>
		<word count="18" text="``"/>
		<word count="18" text="''"/>
		<word count="17" text="will"/>
		<word count="17" text="beij"/>
		<word count="15" text="mainland"/>
		<word count="14" text="the"/>
		<word count="14" text="is"/>
		<word count="12" text="china"/>
		<word count="12" text="on"/>
		<word count="12" text="legisl"/>
		<word count="11" text="enact"/>
		<word count="11" text="propos"/>
		<word count="11" text="for"/>
		<word count="10" text="an"/>
		<word count="10" text="peopl"/>
		<word count="9" text="unit"/>
		<word count="8" text="state"/>
		<word count="8" text="plan"/>
		<word count="8" text="chen"/>
		<word count="8" text="strait"/>
		<word count="7" text="express"/>
		<word count="7" text="which"/>
		<word count="7" text="he"/>
		<word count="6" text="affair"/>
		<word count="6" text="with"/>
		<word count="6" text="made"/>
		<word count="6" text="remark"/>
		<word count="6" text="also"/>
		<word count="6" text="ha"/>
		<word count="6" text="opposit"/>
		<word count="6" text="at"/>
		<word count="6" text="countri"/>
		<word count="6" text="as"/>
		<word count="6" text="thi"/>
		<word count="6" text="npc"/>
		<word count="6" text="one"/>
		<word count="6" text="lai"/>
		<word count="5" text="offici"/>
		<word count="5" text="govern"/>
		<word count="5" text="after"/>
		<word count="5" text="offic"/>
		<word count="5" text="across"/>
		<word count="5" text="nation"/>
		<word count="5" text="session"/>
		<word count="5" text="year"/>
		<word count="5" text="peac"/>
		<word count="5" text="by"/>
		<word count="5" text="so-cal"/>
		<word count="5" text="whether"/>
		<word count="5" text="green"/>
		<word count="4" text="chiu"/>
		<word count="4" text="not"/>
		<word count="4" text="move"/>
		<word count="4" text="chang"/>
		<word count="4" text="legal"/>
		<word count="4" text="part"/>
		<word count="4" text="if"/>
		<word count="4" text="pass"/>
		<word count="4" text="congress"/>
		<word count="4" text="presid"/>
		<word count="4" text="be"/>
		<word count="4" text="visit"/>
		<word count="4" text="their"/>
		<word count="4" text="dure"/>
		<word count="4" text="cross-strait"/>
		<word count="4" text="tuesday"/>
		<word count="4" text="dpp"/>
		<word count="4" text="concern"/>
		<word count="3" text="council"/>
		<word count="3" text="mac"/>
		<word count="3" text="close"/>
		<word count="3" text="develop"/>
		<word count="3" text="target"/>
		<word count="3" text="statu"/>
		<word count="3" text="quo"/>
		<word count="3" text="toward"/>
		<word count="3" text="aim"/>
		<word count="3" text="foreign"/>
		<word count="3" text="forc"/>
		<word count="3" text="against"/>
		<word count="3" text="bill"/>
		<word count="3" text="march"/>
		<word count="3" text="call"/>
		<word count="3" text="activ"/>
		<word count="3" text="region"/>
		<word count="3" text="could"/>
		<word count="3" text="polit"/>
		<word count="3" text="He"/>
		<word count="3" text="from"/>
		<word count="3" text="two"/>
		<word count="3" text="system"/>
		<word count="3" text="principl"/>
		<word count="3" text="independ"/>
		<word count="3" text="resolut"/>
		<word count="3" text="yuan"/>
		<word count="3" text="wang"/>
		<word count="2" text="about"/>
		<word count="2" text="chairman"/>
		<word count="2" text="under"/>
		<word count="2" text="washington"/>
		<word count="2" text="discuss"/>
		<word count="2" text="provoc"/>
		<word count="2" text="but"/>
		<word count="2" text="unilater"/>
		<word count="2" text="told"/>
		<word count="2" text="top"/>
		<word count="2" text="public"/>
		<word count="2" text="invas"/>
		<word count="2" text="republ"/>
		<word count="2" text="author"/>
		<word count="2" text="Lu"/>
		<word count="2" text="spokesman"/>
		<word count="2" text="ministri"/>
		<word count="2" text="repres"/>
		<word count="2" text="continu"/>
		<word count="2" text="would"/>
		<word count="2" text="use"/>
		<word count="2" text="went"/>
		<word count="2" text="stand"/>
		<word count="2" text="committe"/>
		<word count="2" text="late"/>
		<word count="2" text="deliber"/>
		<word count="2" text="friday"/>
		<word count="2" text="face"/>
		<word count="2" text="stabil"/>
		<word count="2" text="while"/>
		<word count="2" text="push"/>
		<word count="2" text="last"/>
		<word count="2" text="annual"/>
		<word count="2" text="new"/>
		<word count="2" text="attempt"/>
		<word count="2" text="monday"/>
		<word count="2" text="research"/>
		<word count="2" text="institut"/>
		<word count="2" text="secessionist"/>
		<word count="2" text="becaus"/>
		<word count="2" text="they"/>
		<word count="2" text="make"/>
		<word count="2" text="other"/>
		<word count="2" text="are"/>
		<word count="2" text="reunif"/>
		<word count="2" text="union"/>
		<word count="2" text="over"/>
		<word count="2" text="mofa"/>
		<word count="2" text="japan"/>
		<word count="2" text="leader"/>
		<word count="2" text="relat"/>
		<word count="2" text="--"/>
		<word count="2" text="decid"/>
		<word count="2" text="through"/>
		<word count="2" text="referendum"/>
		<word count="2" text="or"/>
		<word count="2" text="Wu"/>
		<word count="2" text="activist"/>
		<word count="2" text="no"/>
		<word count="2" text="ask"/>
		<word count="2" text="hope"/>
		<word count="2" text="tension"/>
		<word count="2" text="ait"/>
		<word count="2" text="caucu"/>
		<word count="2" text="rule"/>
		<word count="2" text="parti"/>
		<word count="2" text="accord"/>
		<word count="2" text="promot"/>
		<word count="2" text="counteract"/>
		<word count="2" text="billion"/>
		<word count="2" text="meet"/>
		<word count="2" text="here"/>
		<word count="1" text="An"/>
		<word count="1" text="cabinet-level"/>
		<word count="1" text="wednesday"/>
		<word count="1" text="monitor"/>
		<word count="1" text="commun"/>
		<word count="1" text="deputi"/>
		<word count="1" text="tai-shan"/>
		<word count="1" text="day"/>
		<word count="1" text="yunlin"/>
		<word count="1" text="director"/>
		<word count="1" text="arriv"/>
		<word count="1" text="u.s."/>
		<word count="1" text="detail"/>
		<word count="1" text="promulg"/>
		<word count="1" text="onli"/>
		<word count="1" text="tremend"/>
		<word count="1" text="report"/>
		<word count="1" text="agenc"/>
		<word count="1" text="charg"/>
		<word count="1" text="polici"/>
		<word count="1" text="occas"/>
		<word count="1" text="strong"/>
		<word count="1" text="stress"/>
		<word count="1" text="claim"/>
		<word count="1" text="feel"/>
		<word count="1" text="major"/>
		<word count="1" text="meanwhil"/>
		<word count="1" text="michel"/>
		<word count="1" text="keep"/>
		<word count="1" text="eye"/>
		<word count="1" text="offer"/>
		<word count="1" text="basi"/>
		<word count="1" text="agre"/>
		<word count="1" text="decemb"/>
		<word count="1" text="submit"/>
		<word count="1" text="draft"/>
		<word count="1" text="plenari"/>
		<word count="1" text="shui-bian"/>
		<word count="1" text="serious"/>
		<word count="1" text="undermin"/>
		<word count="1" text="review"/>
		<word count="1" text="oper"/>
		<word count="1" text="capabl"/>
		<word count="1" text="armi"/>
		<word count="1" text="pingtung"/>
		<word count="1" text="southern"/>
		<word count="1" text="been"/>
		<word count="1" text="engag"/>
		<word count="1" text="psycholog"/>
		<word count="1" text="media"/>
		<word count="1" text="warfar"/>
		<word count="1" text="establish"/>
		<word count="1" text="justif"/>
		<word count="1" text="militari"/>
		<word count="1" text="place"/>
		<word count="1" text="agenda"/>
		<word count="1" text="set"/>
		<word count="1" text="reiter"/>
		<word count="1" text="hi"/>
		<word count="1" text="address"/>
		<word count="1" text="condemn"/>
		<word count="1" text="biggest"/>
		<word count="1" text="threat"/>
		<word count="1" text="world"/>
		<word count="1" text="diminish"/>
		<word count="1" text="cross-taiwan"/>
		<word count="1" text="exchang"/>
		<word count="1" text="thu"/>
		<word count="1" text="harm"/>
		<word count="1" text="bilater"/>
		<word count="1" text="tie"/>
		<word count="1" text="scholar"/>
		<word count="1" text="shu"/>
		<word count="1" text="yung-m"/>
		<word count="1" text="assist"/>
		<word count="1" text="academia"/>
		<word count="1" text="sinica"/>
		<word count="1" text="highest"/>
		<word count="1" text="seminar"/>
		<word count="1" text="afraid"/>
		<word count="1" text="approv"/>
		<word count="1" text="due"/>
		<word count="1" text="ambigu"/>
		<word count="1" text="definit"/>
		<word count="1" text="arrest"/>
		<word count="1" text="when"/>
		<word count="1" text="might"/>
		<word count="1" text="area"/>
		<word count="1" text="consid"/>
		<word count="1" text="violat"/>
		<word count="1" text="explain"/>
		<word count="1" text="besid"/>
		<word count="1" text="none"/>
		<word count="1" text="candid"/>
		<word count="1" text="run"/>
		<word count="1" text="can"/>
		<word count="1" text="avoid"/>
		<word count="1" text="campaign"/>
		<word count="1" text="current"/>
		<word count="1" text="circumst"/>
		<word count="1" text="furthermor"/>
		<word count="1" text="squeez"/>
		<word count="1" text="space"/>
		<word count="1" text="those"/>
		<word count="1" text="who"/>
		<word count="1" text="actual"/>
		<word count="1" text="support"/>
		<word count="1" text="both"/>
		<word count="1" text="european"/>
		<word count="1" text="think"/>
		<word count="1" text="counterproduct"/>
		<word count="1" text="minist"/>
		<word count="1" text="tan"/>
		<word count="1" text="sun"/>
		<word count="1" text="lunar"/>
		<word count="1" text="gather"/>
		<word count="1" text="auditorium"/>
		<word count="1" text="sent"/>
		<word count="1" text="six"/>
		<word count="1" text="deleg"/>
		<word count="1" text="EU"/>
		<word count="1" text="brief"/>
		<word count="1" text="academ"/>
		<word count="1" text="opinion"/>
		<word count="1" text="advers"/>
		<word count="1" text="impact"/>
		<word count="1" text="instruct"/>
		<word count="1" text="embassi"/>
		<word count="1" text="abroad"/>
		<word count="1" text="host"/>
		<word count="1" text="rubber-stamp"/>
		<word count="1" text="parliament"/>
		<word count="1" text="schedul"/>
		<word count="1" text="screen"/>
		<word count="1" text="such"/>
		<word count="1" text="draw"/>
		<word count="1" text="backlash"/>
		<word count="1" text="protest"/>
		<word count="1" text="hinder"/>
		<word count="1" text="rapproch"/>
		<word count="1" text="separ"/>
		<word count="1" text="joseph"/>
		<word count="1" text="speak"/>
		<word count="1" text="group"/>
		<word count="1" text="pro-taiwan"/>
		<word count="1" text="have"/>
		<word count="1" text="choic"/>
		<word count="1" text="than"/>
		<word count="1" text="term"/>
		<word count="1" text="accept"/>
		<word count="1" text="enshrin"/>
		<word count="1" text="either"/>
		<word count="1" text="them"/>
		<word count="1" text="warn"/>
		<word count="1" text="toler"/>
		<word count="1" text="pro-independ"/>
		<word count="1" text="respond"/>
		<word count="1" text="strongli"/>
		<word count="1" text="design"/>
		<word count="1" text="frighten"/>
		<word count="1" text="into"/>
		<word count="1" text="give"/>
		<word count="1" text="up"/>
		<word count="1" text="put"/>
		<word count="1" text="off"/>
		<word count="1" text="help"/>
		<word count="1" text="temper"/>
		<word count="1" text="american"/>
		<word count="1" text="raymond"/>
		<word count="1" text="F."/>
		<word count="1" text="chief"/>
		<word count="1" text="section"/>
		<word count="1" text="taipei"/>
		<word count="1" text="democrat"/>
		<word count="1" text="progress"/>
		<word count="1" text="ching-teh"/>
		<word count="1" text="attitud"/>
		<word count="1" text="worri"/>
		<word count="1" text="escal"/>
		<word count="1" text="result"/>
		<word count="1" text="ani"/>
		<word count="1" text="retali"/>
		<word count="1" text="repeatedli"/>
		<word count="1" text="display"/>
		<word count="1" text="goodwil"/>
		<word count="1" text="tri"/>
		<word count="1" text="improv"/>
		<word count="1" text="show"/>
		<word count="1" text="resolv"/>
		<word count="1" text="defend"/>
		<word count="1" text="sovereignti"/>
		<word count="1" text="introduc"/>
		<word count="1" text="alli"/>
		<word count="1" text="solidar"/>
		<word count="1" text="organ"/>
		<word count="1" text="demonstr"/>
		<word count="1" text="purpos"/>
		<word count="1" text="feb."/>
		<word count="1" text="28"/>
		<word count="1" text="like"/>
		<word count="1" text="cooper"/>
		<word count="1" text="piec"/>
		<word count="1" text="reason"/>
		<word count="1" text="behind"/>
		<word count="1" text="recent"/>
		<word count="1" text="decis"/>
		<word count="1" text="list"/>
		<word count="1" text="encourag"/>
		<word count="1" text="issu"/>
		<word count="1" text="dialogu"/>
		<word count="1" text="common"/>
		<word count="1" text="strateg"/>
		<word count="1" text="object"/>
		<word count="1" text="long-stand"/>
		<word count="1" text="asia-pacif"/>
		<word count="1" text="budget"/>
		<word count="1" text="NT"/>
		<word count="1" text="610.8"/>
		<word count="1" text="US"/>
		<word count="1" text="18.23"/>
		<word count="1" text="arm"/>
		<word count="1" text="procur"/>
		<word count="1" text="packag"/>
		<word count="1" text="within"/>
		<word count="1" text="speaker"/>
		<word count="1" text="jin-pyng"/>
		<word count="1" text="thursday"/>
		<word count="1" text="announc"/>
		<word count="1" text="cross-parti"/>
		<word count="1" text="consult"/>
		<word count="1" text="certain"/>
		<word count="1" text="critic"/>
		<word count="1" text="whip"/>
		<word count="1" text="reach"/>
		<word count="1" text="consensu"/>
		<word count="1" text="adopt"/>
		<word count="1" text="voic"/>
		<word count="1" text="legislatur"/>
		<word count="1" text="upcom"/>
		<word count="1" text="full"/>
		<word count="1" text="mean"/>
		<word count="1" text="nor"/>
		<word count="1" text="war"/>
		<word count="1" text="mobil"/>
		<word count="1" text="order"/>
		<word count="1" text="anti-"/>
		<word count="1" text="secess"/>
		<word count="1" text="overarch"/>
		<word count="1" text="focu"/>
		<word count="1" text="theme"/>
		<word count="1" text="oppos"/>
		<word count="1" text="check"/>
		<word count="1" text="senior"/>
		<word count="1" text="chines"/>
		<word count="1" text="lawmak"/>
		<word count="1" text="basic"/>
		<word count="1" text="approach"/>
		<word count="1" text="outlin"/>
		<word count="1" text="first"/>
		<word count="1" text="time"/>
		<word count="1" text="island"/>
	</Words>
</Topic>
